<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-105"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-105"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="105"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_105">
        <num>105</num>
        <heading>Certificates; corrections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 105. Certificates; corrections.\n  Any certificate or other instrument relating to a domestic or foreign\ncorporation filed by the department of state under this chapter may be\ncorrected with respect to any informality or error apparent on the face,\nincorrect statement or defect in the execution thereof including the\ndeletion of any matter not permitted to be stated therein. A\ncertificate, entitled "Certificate of correction of............ (correct\ntitle of certificate and name of corporation)" shall be signed and\ndelivered to the department of state. It shall set forth the name of the\ncorporation, the date the certificate to be corrected was filed by the\ndepartment of state, a statement as to the nature of the informality,\nerror, incorrect statement or defect, the provision in the certificate\nas corrected or eliminated and if the execution was defective, the\nproper execution. The filing of the certificate by the department of\nstate shall not alter the effective time of the instrument being\ncorrected, which shall remain as its original effective time, and shall\nnot affect any right or liability accrued or incurred before such\nfiling. A corporate name may not be changed or corrected under this\nsection. The provisions of this section shall apply to all instruments\nand certificates heretofore and hereafter filed with the department of\nstate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>