<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1104-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1104-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1104-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1104-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1104-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1104-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1104-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1104_A">
        <num>1104-A</num>
        <heading>Petition for judicial dissolution under special circumstances</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The holders of shares representing twenty percent or more of the\nvotes of all outstanding shares of a corporation, other than a\ncorporation registered as an investment company under an act of congress\nentitled "Investment Company Act of 1940", no shares of which are listed\non a national securities exchange or regularly quoted in an\nover-the-counter market by one or more members of a national or an\naffiliated securities association, entitled to vote in an election of\ndirectors may present a petition of dissolution on one or more of the\nfollowing grounds:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1104_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The directors or those in control of the corporation have been\nguilty of illegal, fraudulent or oppressive actions toward the\ncomplaining shareholders;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1104_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The property or assets of the corporation are being looted,\nwasted, or diverted for non-corporate purposes by its directors,\nofficers or those in control of the corporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court, in determining whether to proceed with involuntary\ndissolution pursuant to this section, shall take into account:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1104_A__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether liquidation of the corporation is the only feasible means\nwhereby the petitioners may reasonably expect to obtain a fair return on\ntheir investment; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1104_A__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether liquidation of the corporation is reasonably necessary for\nthe protection of the rights and interests of any substantial number of\nshareholders or of the petitioners.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to all other disclosure requirements, the directors or\nthose in control of the corporation, no later than thirty days after the\nfiling of a petition hereunder, shall make available for inspection and\ncopying to the petitioners under reasonable working conditions the\ncorporate financial books and records for the three preceding years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may order stock valuations be adjusted and may provide\nfor a surcharge upon the directors or those in control of the\ncorporation upon a finding of wilful or reckless dissipation or transfer\nof assets or corporate property without just or adequate compensation\ntherefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>