<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1218"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1218"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1218"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1218">
        <num>1218</num>
        <heading>Special provisions relating to actions or special proceedings against foreign corporations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1218__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any action or special proceeding brought against a foreign\ncorporation under this article, the following provisions shall apply:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Service of the summons in such action may be made personally\nwithin the state of New York, by delivery of the same to any officer or\ndirector of the corporation, or by publication pursuant to an order\nobtained as hereinafter provided.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An order directing service by publication of the summons shall be\nmade upon application of a plaintiff in any such action and shall be\nfounded upon a verified complaint, alleging that the defendant is a\nforeign corporation and has or may have or may be entitled to assets,\ncredits, choses in action or other property, tangible or intangible\nwithin the state and that such corporation has been dissolved,\nnationalized or that its authority or existence has been terminated or\ncancelled in the jurisdiction of its incorporation, or that it has\nceased to do business, and upon an affidavit reciting that personal\nservice of the summons cannot be effected within the state with due\ndiligence and that a temporary receiver of its property within the state\nof New York has been appointed pursuant to this article in such action\nand that a copy of the order appointing the receiver has been served\npersonally by or on behalf of such receiver upon a person, firm or\ncorporation holding property...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The order directing service of the summons shall require the\npublication thereof in a newspaper published in the state of New York in\nthe English language at least once a week for four successive weeks, and\nshall also require the mailing on or before the date of the first\npublication of a copy of the summons, complaint and order to the\ncorporation at its last known principal or head office in the state or\ncountry of its incorporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any such action, the summons shall be served personally or an\norder directing service thereof by publication shall be obtained and the\nfirst publication thereof made within sixty days after the appointment\nof the temporary receiver, and if served by publication, the service\nshall be made complete by the continuance thereof.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If served by publication, service of the summons shall be deemed\ncomplete on the date of the last publication. The action shall be deemed\ncommenced upon the issuance of the summons. The order appointing the\nreceiver and the papers upon which the same is granted shall be filed in\nthe office of the clerk of the court where the action is triable within\nten days after the order is made.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the event that the defendant defaults in answering, or if after\na trial the court is satisfied that the defendant has ceased to do\nbusiness by reason of any thing or matter whatsoever, or that it has\nbeen dissolved, nationalized, or its authority or existence has been\notherwise terminated or cancelled, the court shall thereupon direct\njudgment, appointing a permanent receiver and directing the receiver to\nliquidate the assets, credits, choses in action and property, tangible\nand intangible, in the state of New York of the said defendant, in the\nmanner provided in this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The time between the cessation of business by the corporation or\nits dissolution or nationalization or the termination or cancellation of\nits authority or existence and the appointment of a receiver in this\nstate pursuant to this article, whichever time is longer, plus three\nyears after such appointment, shall not be a part of the time limited by\ndomestic or foreign law for the commencement of an action or for the\nassertion of a claim therein by or on behalf of or against said\ncorporation or by or against said receiver, whether or not said action\nor claim has heretofore been barred by any statute of limitations of\nthis state or of any other state or country.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The existence of and causes of action of or against such\ncorporation existing at the time of its dissolution, nationalization, or\nthe termination or cancellation of its authority or existence, or\narising thereafter, shall not be deemed ended, abated or affected\nthereby, nor shall actions brought by or against such corporation or a\nreceiver appointed hereunder or any remedy therein be deemed to have\nended or abated or to have been affected by reason of such dissolution,\nnationalization, or termination or cancellation of its authority or\nexistence. This provision shall apply to all property, tangible and\nintangible, debts, demands, and choses in action of such corporation\nwithin the state of New York, and to all litigation heretofore or\nhereafter brought in the courts of the state or of the United States to\nwhich the corporation or the receiver of said corporation appointed\npursuant to the provisions of this article is a party. Any receiver\nappointed pursuant to the provisi...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any receiver or trustee has heretofore been appointed in this\nstate for such corporation or its property in any action or proceeding,\neither before or supplementary to judgment, otherwise than in an action\nbrought pursuant to this article, such receiver or trustee may be\nappointed or continued as the receiver in any action brought pursuant to\nthe provisions of this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The appointment of a receiver or the pendency of an action for\nthe appointment of such receiver, shall until such receiver shall be\ndischarged or until such action shall have terminated, be a bar to any\nsubsequent application or action for the appointment of a receiver of\nthe assets of the same corporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1218__subsec_a__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An action shall be commenced within three years from the\ndiscovery by the plaintiff or his predecessor in interest, of any asset\nof said corporation in the state of New York.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>