<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1303"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1303">
        <num>1303</num>
        <heading>Violations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 1303. Violations.\n  The attorney-general may bring an action to restrain a foreign\ncorporation from doing in this state without authority any business for\nthe doing of which it is required to be authorized in this state, or\nfrom doing in this state any business not set forth in its application\nfor authority or certificate of amendment filed by the department of\nstate. The attorney-general may bring an action or special proceeding to\nannul the authority of a foreign corporation doing in this state any\nbusiness not set forth in its application for authority or certificate\nof amendment or the authority of which was obtained through fraudulent\nmisrepresentation or concealment of a material fact or to enjoin or\nannul the authority of any foreign corporation which within this state\ncontrary to law has done or omitted any act which if done by a domestic\ncorporation would be a cause for its dissolution under section 1101\n(Attorney-general's action for judicial dissolution) or to annul the\nauthority of a foreign corporation that has been dissolved or had its\nauthority or existence otherwise terminated or cancelled in the\njurisdiction of its incorporation. The attorney-general shall deliver a\ncertified copy of the order of annulment to the department of state.\nUpon the filing thereof by the department of state the authority of the\nforeign corporation to do business in this state shall be annulled. The\nsecretary of state shall continue as agent of the foreign corporation\nupon whom process against it may be served in any action or special\nproceeding based upon any liability or obligation incurred by the\nforeign corporation within the state prior to the filing of the\ncertified copy of the order of annulment by the department of state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>