<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1304"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1304">
        <num>1304</num>
        <heading>Application for authority; contents</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1304__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign corporation may apply for authority to do business in\nthis state. An application, entitled "Application for authority of\n......  (name of corporation) under section 1304 of the Business\nCorporation Law", shall be signed and delivered to the department of\nstate. It shall set forth:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name of the foreign corporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fictitious name the corporation agrees to use in this state\npursuant to section 1301 of this chapter, if applicable.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The jurisdiction and date of its incorporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The purpose or purposes for which it is formed, it being\nsufficient to state, either alone or with other purposes, that the\npurpose of the corporation is to engage in any lawful act or activity\nfor which corporations may be organized under this chapter, provided\nthat it also state that it is not formed to engage in any act or\nactivity requiring the consent or approval of any state official,\ndepartment, board, agency or other body without such consent or approval\nfirst being obtained. By such statement all lawful acts and activities\nshall be within the purposes of the corporation, except for express\nlimitations therein or in this chapter, if any.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county within this state in which its office is to be located.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A designation of the secretary of state as its agent upon whom\nprocess against it may be served and the post office address within or\nwithout this state to which the secretary of state shall mail a copy of\nany process against it served upon him or her. The corporation may\ninclude an email address to which the secretary of state shall email a\nnotice of the fact that process against it has been electronically\nserved upon him or her.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it is to have a registered agent, his name and address within\nthis state and a statement that the registered agent is to be its agent\nupon whom process against it may be served.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304__subsec_a__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement that the foreign corporation has not since its\nincorporation or since the date its authority to do business in this\nstate was last surrendered, engaged in any activity in this state,\nexcept as set forth in paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1304__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 1301 (Authorization of\nforeign corporations), or in lieu thereof the consent of the state tax\ncommission to the filing of the application, which consent shall be\nattached thereto.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1304__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Attached to the application for authority shall be a certificate\nby an authorized officer of the jurisdiction of its incorporation that\nthe foreign corporation is an existing corporation. If such certificate\nis in a foreign language, a translation thereof under oath of the\ntranslator shall be attached thereto.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>