<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1309-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1309-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1309-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1309-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1309-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1309-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1309-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1309_A">
        <num>1309-A</num>
        <heading>Certificate of change; contents</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In lieu of a certificate of amendment, an authorized foreign\ncorporation, upon compliance with this section, may make any or all of\nthe following changes in its application for authority:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To change the location of its office in this state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To specify or change the post office address to which the\nsecretary of state shall mail a copy of any process against it served\nupon him.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To make, revoke or change the designation of a registered agent or\nspecify or change his address.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To specify, change or delete the email address to which the\nsecretary of state shall email a notice of the fact that process against\nthe corporation has been electronically served upon him or her.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To accomplish such change, a certificate entitled "Certificate of\nchange of application for authority of .......... (name of corporation)\nunder section 1309-A of the Business Corporation Law" shall be signed\nand delivered to the department of state.\n  It shall set forth:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name of the foreign corporation as it appears on the index of\nnames of existing domestic and authorized foreign corporations of any\ntype or kind in the department of state, division of corporations and\nthe fictitious name the corporation has agreed to use in this state\npursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 1301 of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The jurisdiction of its incorporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The date it was authorized to do business in this state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_d__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each change effected thereby.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A certificate of change of application for authority which changes\nonly the post office address to which the secretary of state shall mail\na copy of any process against an authorized foreign corporation served\nupon him or her, and/or the email address to which the secretary of\nstate shall email a notice of the fact that process against it has been\nelectronically served upon the secretary of state and/or which changes\nthe address of its registered agent, provided such address is the\naddress of a person, partnership or other corporation whose address, as\nagent, is the address to be changed, and/or the email address being\nchanged is the email address of a person, partnership or corporation\nwhose email address, as agent, is the email address to be changed,\nand/or who has been designated as registered agent for such authorized\nforeign corporation, may be signed and delivered to the department of\nstate by such agent. The certificate of change of application for\nauthority shall set forth the statements required under subparagraphs\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1309_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section; that a notice of\nthe proposed change was mailed by the party signing the certificate to\nthe authorized foreign corporation not less than thirty days prior to\nthe date of delivery to the department and that such corporation has not\nobjected thereto; and that the party signing the certificate is the\nagent of such foreign corporation to whose address the secretary of\nstate is required to mail copies of process, and/or the agent of such\nforeign corporation to whose email address the secretary of state is\nrequired to mail a notice of the fact that process against it has been\nelectronically served on the secretary of state and/or the registered\nagent, if such be the case. A certificate signed and delivered under\nthis paragraph shall not be deemed to effect a change of location of the\noffice of the corporation in whose behalf such certificate is filed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>