<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1504"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1504"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-11-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1504"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1504/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1504/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1504/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1504/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1504">
        <num>1504</num>
        <heading>Rendering of professional service</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No professional service corporation, including a design\nprofessional service corporation, may render professional services\nexcept through individuals authorized by law to render such professional\nservices as individuals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each final plan and report made or issued by a corporation\npracticing one or more of the professions of professional engineering,\narchitecture, landscape architecture, land surveying or geology shall\nbear the name and seal of one or more professional engineers,\narchitects, landscape architects, land surveyors or professional\ngeologists, respectively, who are in responsible charge of such plan or\nreport.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each report, diagnosis, prognosis, and prescription made or issued\nby a corporation practicing medicine, dentistry, podiatry, optometry,\nophthalmic dispensing, veterinary medicine, pharmacy, nursing,\nphysiotherapy or chiropractic shall bear the signature of one or more\nphysicians, dentists, podiatrists, optometrists, ophthalmic dispensers,\nveterinarians, pharmacists, nurses, physiotherapists, or chiropractors,\nrespectively, who are in responsible charge of such report, diagnosis,\nprognosis, or prescription.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each record, transcript, report and hearing report prepared by a\ncorporation practicing certified shorthand reporting shall bear the\nsignature of one or more certified shorthand reporters who are in\nresponsible charge of such record, transcript, report, or hearing\nreport.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each corporation practicing public accounting or certified public\naccounting shall maintain records indicating the identity of each public\naccountant or certified public accountant, respectively, who was\nresponsible for each report or statement which is issued prepared or\nexamined by such corporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each opinion prepared by a corporation practicing law shall bear\nthe signature of one or more attorneys and counsellors-at-law who are in\nresponsible charge of such opinion.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the requirements in subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>through</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1504__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,\ninclusive, each document prepared by a corporation which under the\nrules, regulations, laws or customs of the applicable profession is\nrequired to bear the signature of an individual in responsible charge of\nsuch document, shall be signed by one or more such individuals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>