<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1505"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1505"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1505"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1505/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1505/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1505/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1505/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1505">
        <num>1505</num>
        <heading>Professional relationships and liabilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1505__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1505__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each shareholder, employee or agent of a professional service\ncorporation and a design professional service corporation shall be\npersonally and fully liable and accountable for any negligent or\nwrongful act or misconduct committed by him or by any person under his\ndirect supervision and control while rendering professional services on\nbehalf of such corporation.\n  (ii) An employee stock ownership plan owning greater than twenty-five\npercent of the outstanding shares of a design professional service\ncorporation organized under paragraph (b-1) of section fifteen hundred\nthree of this article shall be under the supervision of the regents of\nthe university of the state of New York, shall register with the state\neducation department and shall be issued a certificate granting such\nemployee stock ownership plan the authority to hold shares of such\ncorporation. Such certificate shall be subject to professional\nmisconduct provisions as set forth in article one hundred thirty of the\neducation law. In addition, the failure to maintain an active\nregistration with the state education department shall also subject such\ncertificate to discipline as provided above. The secretary of state\nshall be the designated agent for service of process in any disciplinary\nmatter involving a registered employee stock ownership plan.\n  (iii) Any such employee stock ownership plan shall not influence, or\nattempt to influence, any decisions that fall within a design\nprofessional's scope of practice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1505__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The relationship of an individual to a professional service\ncorporation or a design professional service corporation with which such\nindividual is associated, whether as shareholder, director, officer,\nemployee or agent, shall not modify or diminish the jurisdiction over\nhim of the licensing authority and in the case of an attorney and\ncounsellor-at-law, the other courts of this state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>