<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1530"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1530"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1530"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1530">
        <num>1530</num>
        <heading>Filing requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1530__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign professional service corporation may apply for authority\nto do business in this state. An application entitled "Application for\nAuthority of .......... (name of corporation) under Section fifteen\nhundred thirty of the Business Corporation Law," shall be signed and\ndelivered to the department of state. It shall set forth:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name of the foreign professional service corporation. If the\nname does not end with the words "Professional Corporation" or the\nabbreviation "P.C.", it shall in addition to the foregoing set forth the\nname to be used in this state, ending with the words "Professional\nCorporation" or the abbreviation "P.C."\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The jurisdiction and date of its incorporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement of the profession or professions to be practiced in\nthis state and a statement that the foreign professional service\ncorporation is authorized to practice such profession or professions in\nthe jurisdiction of its incorporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name, address and license number of each person within the\nforeign professional service corporation who is licensed to practice the\nprofession or professions in this state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The city, incorporated village or town and the county within this\nstate in which its office is to be located.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A designation of the secretary of state as its agent upon whom\nprocess against it may be served and the post office address within or\nwithout this state to which the secretary of state shall mail a copy of\nany process against it served upon him.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it is to have a registered agent, his name and address within\nthis state and a statement that the registered agent is to be its agent\nupon whom process against it may be served.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_a__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement that the foreign professional service corporation has\nnot since its incorporation or since the date its authority to do\nbusiness in this state was last surrendered, engaged in any activity in\nthis state, or in lieu thereof, the consent of the state tax commission\nto the filing of the application, which consent shall be attached\nthereto.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1530__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Attached to the application for authority shall be:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certificate by an authorized officer of the jurisdiction of its\nincorporation that the foreign professional service corporation is an\nexisting corporation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certificate or certificates issued by the licensing authority\nthat each individual within the corporation intending to practice the\nprofession or professions in this state is licensed to practice said\nprofession or professions in this state. In order to obtain said\ncertificate or certificates, a copy of the certificate of incorporation\nshall be furnished to the licensing authority.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1530__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certificate or certificates issued by the licensing authority in\nthe case of a foreign professional service corporation providing health\nservices that each shareholder, officer and director of the foreign\nprofessional service corporation is licensed to practice said profession\nin this state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1530__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fee for filing the application for authority shall be two\nhundred dollars, payable to the department of state, and the fee for a\ncertificate of authority issued by the state education department shall\nbe fifty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>