<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1532"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1532"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1532"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1532/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1532/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1532/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-1532/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1532">
        <num>1532</num>
        <heading>Regulation of professions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1532__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This article shall not repeal, modify or restrict any provision of\nthe education law or the judiciary law or any rules or regulations\nadopted thereunder regulating the professions referred to therein except\nto the extent in conflict herewith.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1532__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign professional service corporation, other than a foreign\nprofessional service corporation authorized to practice law, shall be\nunder the supervision of the regents of the university of the state of\nNew York and be subject to disciplinary proceedings and penalties, and\nits authority to do business shall be subject to suspension, revocation\nor annulment for cause, in the same manner and to the same extent as is\nprovided with respect to individuals and their licenses, certificates,\nand registrations in title eight of the education law relating to the\napplicable profession. Notwithstanding the provisions of this\nsubdivision, a foreign professional service corporation authorized to\npractice medicine shall be subject to the prehearing procedures and\nhearing procedures as is provided with respect to individual physicians\nand their licenses in Title II-A of article two of the public health\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1532__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign professional service corporation authorized to practice\nlaw shall be subject to the regulation and control of, and its authority\nto do business shall be subject to suspension, revocation or annulment\nfor cause by, the appellate division of the supreme court and the court\nof appeals in the same manner and to the same extent provided in the\njudiciary law with respect to individual attorneys and\ncounselors-at-law. Such corporation need not qualify for any\ncertification under section four hundred sixty-four of the judiciary\nlaw, take an oath of office under section four hundred sixty-six of such\nlaw or register under section four hundred sixty-seven of such law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>