<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BSC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-509"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-509"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="509"/>
          <FRBRname value="BSC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bsc/section-509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_509">
        <num>509</num>
        <heading>Fractions of a share or scrip authorized</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_509__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A corporation may, but shall not be obliged to, issue fractions of\na share either represented by a certificate or uncertificated, which\nshall entitle the holder, in proportion to his fractional holdings, to\nexercise voting rights, receive dividends and participate in liquidating\ndistributions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_509__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As an alternative, a corporation may pay in cash the fair value of\nfractions of a share as of the time when those entitled to receive such\nfractions are determined.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_509__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As an alternative, a corporation may issue scrip in registered or\nbearer form over the manual or facsimile signature of an officer of the\ncorporation or of its agent, exchangeable as therein provided for full\nshares, but such scrip shall not entitle the holder to any rights of a\nshareholder except as therein provided. Such scrip may be issued subject\nto the condition that it shall become void if not exchanged for\ncertificates representing full shares or uncertificated full shares\nbefore a specified date, or subject to the condition that the shares for\nwhich such scrip is exchangeable may be sold by the corporation and the\nproceeds thereof distributed to the holders of such scrip, or subject to\nany other conditions which the board may determine.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_509__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A corporation may provide reasonable opportunity for persons\nentitled to fractions of a share or scrip to sell such fractions of a\nshare or scrip or to purchase such additional fractions of a share or\nscrip as may be needed to acquire a full share.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>