<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1004-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1004-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1004-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1004-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1004-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1004-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1004-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1004_B">
        <num>1004-B</num>
        <heading>Integrated employment opportunities for individuals with severe disabilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1004_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>services are provided fully and equitably;\n  (ii) an array of services is established and appropriate procedures\nare developed to allow persons with severe disabilities timely access to\nappropriate support services;\n  (iii) compatible definitions, program evaluation and accounting\nstandards and reporting documents are implemented;\n  (iv) services and eligibility requirements are integrated and\ncoordinated between agencies, including the manner in which appropriate\nresponsibilities for funding and administering both short-term intensive\nand long-term extended support services for supported employment are to\nbe implemented;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1004_B__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>funding sources are clearly defined and amounts are adequate to\nsupport persons with short-term intensive and long-term extended support\nneeds;\n  (vi) all necessary steps are taken to maximize the success and cost\neffectiveness of such programs and the potential of persons served by\nsuch programs;\n  (vii) continuity of support services is not broken for individuals\nplaced in an integrated employment setting in the event such placement\nis interrupted; and\n  (viii) eligibility standards are consistent regarding the placement of\nindividuals in integrated work settings, including supported employment\nand other competitive work placements.\n  b. In addition, the plan shall address the manner in which continued\nsupport for current programs will be maintained; and establishment\ngrants will be provided. Such establishment grants shall include, but\nnot be limited to, special projects which enhance the provision of\nsupported employment and new integrated employment program initiatives\nwhich would target individuals who have severe disabilities who have\naged-out or have otherwise exited the school system. In addition, such\ngrants may be used to provide additional resources to existing programs\nfor the purposes of increasing the numbers of persons served who have\nbeen determined by the commissioner to have been unserved or\nunderserved. Such grants may also be used for new programs for these\npopulations.\n  c. The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioners of the\noffice of mental health, the office for people with developmental\ndisabilities and the department of social services, shall develop an\naudit protocol to verify the actual costs of providing such programs.\n  3. Reporting. a. It shall be the primary responsibility of the\ncommissioner to provide annual reports on the progress of achieving the\ncomponents of the implementation plan as contained in subdivision two of\nthis section. In addition, such reports shall include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1004_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a current description of individuals served, and services and\ntechnical assistance provided;\n  (ii) employment status of persons transitioned from sheltered\nworkshops, special education programs, day treatment centers, and day\nservices programs into integrated employment programs, including\nsupported employment programs and other competitive work placements;\n  (iii) incidence of persons in reverse transition between integrated\nemployment programs, including supported employment programs and paid\ncompetitive work, and sheltered workshops, day treatment programs and\nday services programs; and\n  (iv) number of persons for whom employment in an integrated work\nsetting has been requested and who are waiting for placement.\n  The commissioners of the office of mental health, the office for\npeople with developmental disabilities, and the department of social\nservices shall provide any information required to assist the\ncommissioner in making such report.\n  b. The implementation plan shall be transmitted to the state's board\nof regents, the governor, the temporary president of the senate, the\nspeaker of the assembly and the senate committee on finance, the\nassembly committee on ways and means, the senate committee on education\nand the assembly committee on education on or before October first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-three with a report on the status of the\nimplementation plan transmitted on or before October first of each\nsucceeding year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>