<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1106"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1106">
        <num>1106</num>
        <heading>Transportation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1106. Transportation.  1. In a county which has a vocational\neducation and extension board which does not furnish transportation to\npupils pursuant to subdivision thirteen of section eleven hundred two of\nthis chapter the cost of the transportation of pupils under twenty-one\nyears of age to schools and classes maintained by such county vocational\neducation and extension board shall be a charge upon the district in\nwhich such pupils reside, or are attending as non-resident pupils.  Such\ntransportation shall be considered as other transportation of school\npupils in accordance with the provisions of part two of article\nseventy-three of the education law and the district of residence, or the\ndistrict in which non-resident pupils are attending, shall be entitled\nto a transportation quota.\n  2. In a county which has a vocational education and extension board\nwhich furnishes transportation to pupils pursuant to subdivision\nthirteen of section eleven hundred two of this chapter, such vocational\neducation and extension board shall receive a transportation quota which\nshall be one-half of the cost of the transportation of pupils under\ntwenty-one years of age to schools and classes maintained by such\nvocational education and extension board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>