<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1111"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1111">
        <num>1111</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of county commission for special education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1111. Powers and duties of county commission for special education.\nThe county commission for special education shall have power:\n  1. To make or cause to be made a survey to determine the special\neducational needs of the district.\n  2. To establish schools or classes for physically handicapped children\nand to provide other necessary educational services, including\ntransportation and home teaching.\n  3. To establish and maintain vocational schools and classes for the\npurpose of providing instruction in agricultural, industrial,\ncommercial, technical and home making subjects.\n  4. To provide vocational and educational guidance service.\n  5. To establish such other special educational services as may meet\nthe approval of the commissioner of education.\n  6. To employ a director of special education, who shall be the\nexecutive officer and secretary of the commission, and upon the\nrecommendation of such director to employ directors, supervisors and\nteachers and all other persons necessary to carry on such special\neducation projects as it may establish, and to determine the salaries to\nbe paid.\n  7. To purchase, lease, rent, improve or sell land, and build, repair,\nimprove, lease, rent, buy and sell buildings.\n  8. To acquire real property by condemnation for the purposes of such\nspecial education district. Such condemnation proceedings shall be\ninstituted and conducted by such commission in the name of the district,\nunder the provisions of the statutes relating to the condemnation of\nreal property.\n  9. To purchase all necessary furniture, implements, books, materials,\nequipment and supplies.\n  10. To make contracts with cities, villages, school districts or other\nagencies for carrying out the purposes of part two of this article.\n  11. To appoint advisory committees.\n  12. To make and establish, and from time to time alter and amend,\nrules and regulations for the transaction of its business and for the\nadministration of the work under its charge.\n  13. It shall be the duty of the commission to make an itemized\nestimate of the money needed for the ensuing year for the purposes of\npart two of this article and file the same with the clerk of the board\nof supervisors or other governing elective body at least sixty days\nbefore the annual meeting of such board.\n  14. It shall be the duty of the commission to make an annual report in\nwriting to the regents of The University of the State of New York and to\nthe board of supervisors or other governing elective body on or before\nthe first day of October in each year. It shall also be its duty to make\nsuch other reports as may be required by the commissioner of education\nand by such board or body.\n  15. It shall have such other powers and shall perform such other\nduties as may be necessary to carry into effect the purposes of part two\nof this article.\n  16. It shall not incur liabilities against county funds in excess of\nthe amounts appropriated by the board of supervisors or other governing\nelective body.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>