<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1121"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1121"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1121"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1121">
        <num>1121</num>
        <heading>Service centers for independent living; purpose and duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such center shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be a private not-for-profit corporation, pursuant to subdivision\nfive of paragraph a of section one hundred two of the not-for-profit\ncorporation law; provided, however, that persons with disabilities\ncomprise at least fifty-one percent of the membership of the board of\ndirectors;\n  (ii) be staffed by persons experienced in assisting persons with\ndisabilities;\n  (iii) provide services designed to meet the needs of persons with\ndisabilities, including such services as assisting persons with\ndisabilities to obtain housing, employment referral, transportation\nreferral, attendant care, independent living skills, peer counseling,\nadvocacy services, job training, health care, homemaker services, and\nother such services as approved by the commissioner;\n  (iv) train personnel for the purpose of attendant care in assisting\nand serving persons with disabilities; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>serve persons with disabilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such center may also, but need not limit itself to, provide\ndisability awareness programs, peer counseling, role modeling and any\nother appropriate services within elementary and secondary schools.\n  2. Such service centers shall not be established or operated as a\nresidential or housing facility.\n  3. Such service centers shall make maximum use of existing resources\navailable to persons with disabilities and shall not duplicate any\nexisting services or programs, to the extent that such services or\nprograms are available through other state sources to meet the needs of\npersons with disabilities. Such centers shall however provide necessary\ninformation and referral to assist a person with a disability in\nobtaining such services and coordinate where possible the delivery of\nsuch services to persons with disabilities.\n  4. Such service centers shall be in compliance with all applicable\nlocal laws and ordinances.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>