<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-140"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-140"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="140"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-140/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-140/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-140/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-140/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_140">
        <num>140</num>
        <heading>Historical documentary heritage grants and aid</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_140__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>individual historical\nrecords program projects shall be eligible for at least thirty-five\npercent of the amount available;\n  (ii) cooperative projects shall be eligible for up to twenty percent\nof the amount available.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aid.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>regional advisory and assistance agencies shall be\neligible for forty percent of the amount available;\n  (ii) the central administration of the state university of New York\nshall be eligible for two and one-half percent of the total amount\navailable;\n  (iii) the central administration of the city university of New York\nshall be eligible for two and one-half percent of the total amount\navailable.\n  b. Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraphs one and two of\nparagraph a of this subdivision, the commissioner, taking into account\nthe recommendations of the New York state historical records advisory\nboard, may distribute funds designated for one purpose to address the\nneeds of another purpose, provided that the commissioner determines that\nthe significance of the contributions to be realized from the proposals\nin one category outweighs the significance of the contributions to be\nrealized from the proposals in another category.\n  5. Cost-sharing. The commissioner shall determine the amount of\ncost-sharing required from historical records programs, including\ncooperative programs. For individual historical records program projects\ninvolving arrangement, description, and other work relating directly to\nthe administration of historical records held by a program, the amount\nof such cost-sharing shall be at least fifty percent.\n  6. Applications for historical records program projects. a. Filing. By\ndates determined by the commissioner each year, an eligible institution\nmay file an application, in a form prescribed by the commissioner, for a\ngrant to support the approved costs of a proposed historical records\nproject.\n  b. Content. Such application shall include, but need not be limited\nto:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a statement describing the applicant's need for the funding\nrequested;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>collection statements and policies used by the institution to\nguide its acquisition efforts;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a summary description of the records included in the historical\nrecords program of the institution;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the status of finding aids and published guides for the historical\nrecords held by the institution;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the current and/or anticipated level of use and audience for the\nhistorical records;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the importance of the historical records for documenting life in\nNew York;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the expected impact of the grant upon the historical records\nprogram;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the plan of work for the activities for which the funding is\nsought;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the proposed project budget, including cost-sharing which would be\ncommitted to the project; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the staff and other resources devoted to the institution's\nhistorical records program on an ongoing basis.\n  c. Approval. In approving any application pursuant to this\nsubdivision, the commissioner shall consider:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>information in the proposal as set forth in paragraph b of this\nsubdivision;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the capacity of the institution to make the historical records\nknown and accessible for research, education, public programs, improved\npolicy making and other public benefits;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the potential for improving the documentation of the heritage of\nany racial and ethnic group; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the potential for improving the documentation of under documented\nsubjects, institutions, or activities.\n  7. Application for cooperative projects. a. Filing. By dates to be\nestablished by the commissioner each year, a service provider or an\neligible institution acting as fiscal agent on behalf of a group of\neligible institutions, may file an application, in a form prescribed by\nthe commissioner. A group of cooperating institutions may be formed\nbecause of a common purpose, rather than because of geographical\nproximity.\n  b. Content. Such application shall include, but need not be limited\nto:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a statement describing the applicant's need for the funding\nrequested;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a description of the issue, problem, or need that the project will\naddress;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a description of the historical records programs to be served and\nhow the effort to be undertaken in a cooperative project relates to and\nwill strengthen these programs;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>description of the plan of work for the project;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>outcome or product of the project and how it will improve the\nidentification and administration of historical records or contribute to\nthe strengthening of historical records programs; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the proposed budget, including cost-sharing that would be\ncontributed to the project.\n  c. Approval. In approving any application pursuant to this\nsubdivision, the commissioner shall consider:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>information in the proposal as set forth in paragraph b of this\nsubdivision;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the importance of the records involved for the documentation of\nlife in New York state;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the importance of the project and the intended outcome or product\nin terms of strengthening the programs of the cooperating institutions\nand promoting improved historical records management;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the capacities of the cooperating institutions or service\nproviders for carrying out the project, including prior experience with\ncooperative or service projects; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_140__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the potential for cooperating institutions to sustain an ongoing\nproductive cooperative relationship as a result of the project.\n  8. Aid for regional advisory and assistance agencies. a. Coordination.\nThe commissioner shall establish statewide priorities for regional\nadvisory and assistance agencies and shall assist and coordinate their\nefforts.\n  b. Historical records program advice and assistance plans. To be\neligible to receive aid annually, each participating regional advisory\nand assistance agency shall submit an annual workplan acceptable to the\ncommissioner, and, after the first year of receiving aid, a report on\nactivities of the prior year and a five-year plan, by dates designated\nby the commissioner. The five-year plan shall outline goals and\nobjectives to be accomplished in the region during the five-year period.\nThe annual workplan shall describe the activities to be carried out\nduring the year and the program advice and assistance to be provided.\nThe five-y...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>