<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1505-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1505-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1505-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1505-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1505-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1505-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1505-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1505_A">
        <num>1505-A</num>
        <heading>Teachers' rights as a result of the dissolution of a school district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1505-a. Teachers' rights as a result of the dissolution of a school\ndistrict.  1. In any case in which a school district is dissolved and\nportions of such former district are added to more than one school\ndistrict pursuant to the provisions of section fifteen hundred five of\nthis article or section seventeen hundred five of this chapter, each\nteacher employed in such former school district at the time of such\ndissolution shall select the particular school district to which\nterritory is added in which he or she shall be considered an employee,\nwith the same tenure status he or she maintained in such former school\ndistrict. Such selection of the particular school district to which\nterritory is added by such teacher shall be based upon each teacher's\nseniority in such former school district, with the right of selection\npassing from such teachers with the most seniority to such teachers with\nleast seniority.\n  2. Any such teacher who is unable to obtain a teaching position in any\nsuch school district to which territory is added, because the number of\npositions needed are less than the number of teachers eligible to be\nconsidered employees pursuant to subdivision one of this section, shall,\nin all such school districts to which territory is added, be placed on a\npreferred eligible list of candidates for appointment to a vacancy that\nmay thereafter occur in a position similar to the one such teacher\nfilled in such former school district. The teachers on such a preferred\neligible list shall be appointed to such vacancies in such corresponding\nor similar positions under the jurisdiction of the school district to\nwhich territory is added in the order of their length of service in such\nformer school district, within seven years from the date of the\ndissolution of such former school district.\n  3. For any such teacher as set forth in subdivision one of this\nsection, for salary, sick leave and any other purpose, the length of\nservice credited in such former school district shall be credited as\nemployment time with such school district to which territory is added.\n  4. This section shall in no way be construed to limit the rights of\nany such teachers set forth in this section granted by any other\nprovision of law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>