<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1529"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1529"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1529"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1529/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1529/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1529/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1529/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1529">
        <num>1529</num>
        <heading>Times for filing statements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1529. Times for filing statements. 1. The times for filing the\nstatements prescribed by section fifteen hundred twenty-eight of this\narticle shall be as follows:\n  a. A first statement shall be filed on or before the thirtieth day\nnext preceding the election to which it relates.\n  b. A second statement shall be filed on or before the fifth day next\npreceding the election to which it relates.\n  c. A third statement shall be filed within twenty days next succeeding\nthe election to which it relates.\n  2. Unless otherwise provided, each statement shall cover the period up\nto and including the day next preceding the day herein specified for the\nfiling thereof; provided, however, that any contribution or loan in\nexcess of one thousand dollars, if received after the close of the\nperiod to be covered in the last statement filed before the election but\nbefore such election, shall be reported, in the same manner as other\ncontributions, within twenty-four hours after receipt.\n  3. It shall not be necessary to itemize in any statement the data\npreviously reported in any prior statement but each statement shall\ninclude a summary of all expenditures and contributions and other\nparticulars reported in any previous statements.\n  4. A statement shall be deemed properly filed when deposited in an\nestablished post-office within the prescribed time, duly stamped,\nregistered and directed to the clerk of the school district in which he\nis a candidate and to the commissioner of education, but in the event it\nis not received, a duplicate of such statement shall be promptly filed\nupon notice by the school district administrative officer and/or the\ncommissioner of its non-receipt. Each statement shall be preserved for a\nperiod of three years from the date of filing thereof and it shall\nconstitute a part of the public records and shall be open to public\ninspection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>