<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1703"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1703"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1703"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1703">
        <num>1703</num>
        <heading>Change in number of members of board of education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1703. Change in number of members of board of education.  1.  The\nnumber of members of the board of education of a union free school\ndistrict may be increased or decreased at an annual meeting by a\nmajority vote of the qualified voters present and voting to be\nascertained by taking and recording the ayes and noes or by ballot. The\nnumber of members of such board shall not be increased to more than nine\nnor decreased to less than three.\n  2. No vote shall be taken upon the proposition to increase or decrease\nthe number of members of such board of education unless the notice of\nthe annual meeting shall contain a statement to the effect that the\nvoters of such district will vote upon such proposition. The board of\neducation of any such district shall, upon the application of at least\ntwenty-five voters or five percent of the number of voters who voted in\nthe previous annual election of the members of the board of education,\nwhichever is greater, such number to be determined by the number of\npersons recorded on the poll list as having voted at such election,\ninclude in the notice of the annual meeting a statement that the\nproposition to increase or decrease such board will be presented to the\nannual meeting for determination. If the board refuses or fails to give\nsuch notice, the notice may be given in such manner as the commissioner\nof education may direct.\n  3. The additional members first elected shall be elected at a special\nmeeting which shall be called by the board and be held not less than\nthirty nor more than sixty days following the annual meeting at which\nthe number was increased, and pending the first election of such\nadditional members no vacancy shall be deemed to exist in the offices\nthereof except for the purpose of filling the same by election,\nnotwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>