<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1719"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1719"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1719"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1719/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1719/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1719/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1719/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1719">
        <num>1719</num>
        <heading>Deposit, custody and payment of moneys in villages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1719. Deposit, custody and payment of moneys in villages. 1. All\nmoneys raised for the support of schools in any union free school\ndistrict whose boundaries are coterminous with the boundaries of an\nincorporated village or apportioned to the same by the education\ndepartment or otherwise, shall be paid into the treasury of such village\nto the credit of the board of education therein; and the funds so\nreceived into such treasury shall be kept separate and distinct from any\nother funds received into the said treasury. And the officer having the\ncharge thereof shall give such additional security for the safe custody\nthereof as the corporate authorities of such village shall require. The\nboard of education in any such union free school district may, in its\ndiscretion, fix the compensation to be paid to the treasurer of such\nvillage for the services imposed upon him by this section, and such\ncompensation, as so fixed, shall be paid from such moneys.\n  2. No money shall be drawn from such funds, credited to a board of\neducation, unless in pursuance of a resolution of said board, and on\nvoucher-order checks signed by the treasurer, payable to the order of\nthe persons entitled to receive such money, and stating on their face\nthe purpose or service for which such moneys have been authorized to be\npaid by the said board of education. The board of education may in its\ndiscretion require that such checks be countersigned by another officer\nof such district. When authorized by resolution of the board of\neducation such checks may be signed with the facsimile signature of the\ntreasurer and other district officer whose signature is required, as\nreproduced by a machine or device commonly known as a checksigner. No\nresolution of the board of education, however, shall be necessary for\nthe payment of compensation for services of an officer or employee\nengaged at agreed wages by the hour, day, week, month or year when the\nname of such officer or employee appears upon a duly certified payroll,\nor of the principal of or interest on indebtedness of the district. By\nresolution duly adopted, the board may determine to enter into a\ncontract to provide for the deposit of the periodic payroll of the\nschool district in a bank or trust company for disbursal by it in\naccordance with provisions of section ninety-six-b of the banking law.\n  3. When obligations are issued and sold pursuant to the local finance\nlaw by a union free school district whose boundaries are the same as the\nboundaries of an incorporated village, the proceeds of the sale of such\nobligations shall be paid into the treasury of said incorporated\nvillage, to the credit of the board of education.\n  4. So much of this section as relates to the deposit of moneys raised\nfor the support of schools in any union free school district shall not\napply to the Bronxville union free school district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>