<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1720"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1720"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1720"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1720/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1720/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1720/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1720/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1720">
        <num>1720</num>
        <heading>Moneys and accounts in union free school districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1720. Moneys and accounts in union free school districts.  1.  All\nmoneys raised in a union free school district or apportioned thereto by\nthe education department or otherwise, shall be paid to the treasurer of\nthe district entitled to receive the same, and be applied to the uses of\nthe district and the board shall annually render their accounts of all\nmoneys received and expended by them for the use of said schools.\n  2. No money shall be drawn from such funds in possession of such\ntreasurer, unless in pursuance of a resolution of said board, and on\nvoucher-order checks signed by the treasurer, payable to the order of\nthe persons entitled to receive such money and stating on their face the\npurpose or service for which said moneys have been authorized to be paid\nby the said board of education.  The board of education may in its\ndiscretion require that such checks be countersigned by another officer\nof such district.  When authorized by resolution of the board of\neducation such checks may be signed with the facsimile signature of the\ntreasurer and other district officer whose signature is required, as\nreproduced by a machine or device commonly known as a check-signer.\nSuch board may by resolution designate one of its members other than\nsaid other officer whose signature is required or appoint a deputy\ntreasurer who shall serve at the discretion of the board, to sign such\nchecks in lieu of either the treasurer or other officer whose signature\nis required, in case of their absence or inability, provided that any\nboard member or deputy treasurer so authorized shall, before acting in\nthe place and stead of the treasurer, execute and file an official\nundertaking in an amount and in the manner required as to such treasurer\npursuant to the provisions of this chapter.  No resolution of the board,\nhowever, shall be necessary for the payment of compensation for services\nof an officer or employee engaged at agreed wages by the hour, day,\nweek, month or year, where the name of such officer or employee appears\nupon a duly certified payroll, or of the principal of or interest on\nindebtedness of the district.  By resolution duly adopted, the board may\ndetermine to enter into a contract to provide for the deposit of the\nperiodic payroll of the school district in a bank or trust company for\ndisbursal by it in accordance with provisions of section ninety-six-b of\nthe banking law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>