<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-174"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-174"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="174"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-174/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-174/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-174/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-174/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_174">
        <num>174</num>
        <heading>Powers formerly exercised by the state board of geographic names</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 174. Powers formerly exercised by the state board of geographic\nnames.  The regents, or such bureau, division or officers of the\nuniversity or of the education department as may be designated by them\nfor such purpose, shall 1.  Determine and establish the correct\nhistorical and etymological form of the place names in this state and\nrecommend the adoption of such correct forms for public use.\n  2. Determine the form and propriety of new place names proposed for\ngeneral use, and no corporation, individual or community shall introduce\nsuch new place names without the consent and approval of this board.\n  3. Co-operate with the United States board of geographic names and\nwith the United States post-office department in establishing a proper,\ncorrect and historically accurate form for all place names proposed as\ndesignations of new post-offices.\n  4. No petition or recommendation for the naming of any mountain, lake,\nriver or other natural object for or in honor of any living person shall\nbe granted, approved or consented to by the regents of the university or\nby the committee on geographic names appointed by it except by unanimous\nvote.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>