<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1801"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1801"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1801"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1801">
        <num>1801</num>
        <heading>Formation and changes of central school districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1801.  Formation and changes of central school districts.  1. The\ncommissioner of education is hereby authorized and empowered to lay out\ncentral school districts for the establishment of central schools to\ngive instruction in elementary or elementary and high school subjects\nand to fix, determine and define the boundaries of said districts as\nhereinafter provided.\n  2. The commissioner is authorized and empowered to make and enter in\nhis office orders laying out territory in new central school districts\nor annexing to existing central school districts territory not contained\nwithin a city school district in a city having a population of more than\nten thousand inhabitants, and not contained within a city school\ndistrict having a full valuation of taxable real estate per public\nschool pupil residing in the district of more than fifteen thousand\ndollars; provided, however, that no territory contained within a city\nschool district in a city having a population of ten thousand\ninhabitants or less may be included in new central school districts or\nannexed to existing central school districts after July first, nineteen\nhundred fifty-five. The commissioner of education is authorized and\nempowered to make and enter in his office orders dissolving and annexing\na central school district or districts to another central school\ndistrict, pursuant to the provisions of subdivision two of section\neighteen hundred two of this chapter.  The commissioner in laying out\nsuch central school districts and in fixing and defining the boundaries\nthereof shall include only territory of suitable size conveniently\nlocated for the attendance of pupils and having a sufficient number of\npupils for the establishment of a central school. The commissioner shall\ndesignate all central school districts by such simplified name as he\nshall deem proper.\n  3. Within ten days after the making and entry of the order pursuant to\nthis section, the commissioner shall transmit a certified copy thereof\nto the clerk, or in the event there is no clerk, to the trustee or\ntrustees of each school district the territory of which is affected by\nsaid order. The clerk, the trustee or trustees, as the case may be,\nshall, within five days after receipt of such order, post a copy thereof\nin five conspicuous places in such district.\n  4. No central school district laid out by order of the commissioner\nshall operate as a central school district, nor be entitled to receive\nthe benefits of a central school district until it has been organized by\nthe qualified voters of the district in accordance with the provisions\nof this article, provided, however, a central school district which was\norganized prior to April seventh, nineteen hundred forty-four, or\npursuant to the provisions of this section and to which territory may be\nannexed shall not be required to again organize.\n  5. The commissioner of education is hereby authorized and empowered to\nmake and enter in his office an order annexing the territory of common\nschool district number three of the town of Wilmington, Essex county to\ncentral school district number two of the town of North Elba, Essex\ncounty, together with such territory of common school district number\none of the town of Wilmington, Essex county as will provide contiguity\nbetween the aforementioned Wilmington common school district number\nthree and North Elba central school district number two.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>