<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1803"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1803"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1803"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1803/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1803/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1803/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1803/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1803">
        <num>1803</num>
        <heading>Proceedings at meeting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1803. Proceedings at meeting. 1. Any meeting held pursuant to the\nnotice provided in section eighteen hundred two shall be called to order\nby a school official or a qualified voter of the district, designated by\nthe commissioner of education for the purpose. The first order of\nbusiness shall be the election of a chairman and a clerk who shall be\nqualified voters of the district. The meeting may be adjourned from time\nto time by a majority vote of the qualified voters present but no such\nadjournment shall be for a longer period than ten days. The affirmative\nvote of a majority of the qualified voters present and voting shall be\nrequired on the adoption of a resolution.\n  2. At a meeting held pursuant to subdivision one of section eighteen\nhundred two a resolution in substantially the following form shall be\npresented for the action and determination of the meeting, viz.:\n"Resolved that the ........ central school district (add designation) as\ndescribed in the order of the commissioner of education now before this\nmeeting, be organized and a central school for instruction in elementary\nand high school subjects be established."\n  3. At a meeting held in an existing central school district pursuant\nto subdivision two of section eighteen hundred two a resolution in\nsubstantially the following form shall be presented for the action and\ndetermination of the meeting, viz.: "Resolved that the ........ (insert\nsimplified name of district in accordance with section three hundred\nfifteen of this chapter) school district be annexed to the .........\ncentral school district (designate central school district) as provided\nin the order of the commissioner of education now before this meeting."\nSaid resolution may be amended by a majority vote of the qualified\nvoters present to exclude one or more of the districts described in said\norder of the commissioner from annexation to the central school\ndistrict.\n  4. At a meeting held in any common or union free school district\npursuant to subdivision two of section eighteen hundred two a resolution\nin substantially the following form shall be presented for the action\nand determination of the meeting, viz.: "Resolved that the .........\n(insert simplified name of district in accordance with section three\nhundred fifteen of this chapter) school district be annexed to the\n.......... central school district (designate central school district) as\nprovided in the order of the commissioner of education now before this\nmeeting."\n  5. Votes upon the adoption of a resolution shall be cast in the same\nmanner as votes for the election of school district trustees. The\ncommissioner of education may order such modifications in the manner of\nvoting as are customary for school district elections in the community\naffected by such vote. Such modifications may include the use of voting\nmachines and shall include the use of absentee ballots as provided under\nsection two thousand eighteen-a or two thousand eighteen-b of this\ntitle, whichever shall apply, and early mail ballots as provided in\nsection two thousand eighteen-e or two thousand eighteen-f of this\ntitle, whichever shall apply.\n  6. A copy of the minutes of the meeting or meetings duly certified by\nthe clerk shall be filed by him with the commissioner of education, with\neach school superintendent in whose jurisdiction such school district,\nor any part thereof, is or may thereafterward be located and with the\ntown clerk of each town in which any part of said school district is or\nmay thereafterward be located.\n  7. If the resolution described in subdivision two of this section is\nadopted, then the voters shall proceed to organize in accordance with\nthe provisions of this article.\n  8. If at any such meeting the resolution described in subdivision two,\nthree or four of this section shall be presented and shall not be\nadopted, there shall be no further proceedings at such meeting, except a\nmotion to reconsider the question. No such meeting shall again be called\nwithin one year after such original meeting. No new meeting shall be\ncalled unless a petition therefor shall be presented to the commissioner\nin the manner provided in subdivision two of section eighteen hundred\ntwo of this article. If no meeting shall be called to reconsider the\nquestion within two years after such original meeting or if at any such\nmeeting called within two years after such original meeting the\nresolution shall again fail of adoption, the order of the commissioner\nof education to which the resolution relates shall be deemed null and\nvoid and of no further force or effect.\n  9. If the resolution submitted to the voters as provided in either\nsubdivision three or subdivision four of this section shall be adopted\nthe territory described therein shall thereupon be annexed to the\nexisting central school district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>