<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1901"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1901"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1901"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1901">
        <num>1901</num>
        <heading>Central high school districts; number and election of members of board of education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1901. Central high school districts; number and election of members\nof board of education. 1. Existing central high school districts are\ncontinued. Boards of education of such central high school districts\nheretofore established shall continue as constituted under the order of\nthe commissioner. The number of their members shall be not less than\nfive. There shall be at least one member of such a board from each\ncommon school district and at least two from each union free school\ndistrict within the central high school district. The board of education\nof each union free school district in each such central high school\ndistrict shall appoint the number of persons so designated by the\ncommissioner to represent such district as members of the board of\neducation of such central high school district. In each common school\ndistrict having a sole trustee, such trustee shall represent such\ndistrict as a member of the board of education of such central high\nschool district. If a common school district have three trustees, such\nboard of trustees shall designate one of its members to represent such\ndistrict as a member of such board of education. The persons so\ndesignated shall be members of the board of education of the central\nhigh school district during their terms of office as members of the\nboard of education or as trustees of the districts respectively\nrepresented by them. Whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of a\nmember of the board of education of such central high school district,\nit shall be filled as above provided.\n  2. Each central high school district shall establish a process for\ndesignating at least one student as an ex officio member pursuant to\nparagraph c of this subdivision. If, prior to August fifth, two thousand\nthree, a school district had a policy that allowed a student or students\nto be ex officio members of the school board, such policy shall be\ndeemed to meet the requirements of this subdivision and shall be deemed\nto have full legal effect. In any district that contains more than one\nhigh school, such process shall take into consideration the number of\nhigh schools within the district and shall provide for a mechanism which\nallows for fair representation among the schools. Such district shall\nallow such selected student or students to serve as ex officio members\nof such board of education, and provided further that:\n  a. The ex officio student members of the board shall be entitled to\nsit with board members at all public meetings and hearings of the board\nand may participate in other board activities and responsibilities at\nthe discretion of the board.\n  b. The ex officio student members of the board shall not be allowed to\nvote, shall not be allowed to attend executive session or any other\nmeetings or hearings not open to the public, and shall not be entitled\nto receive compensation of any form for participating at board meetings.\n  c. Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, the ex officio\nstudent members of the board may be any of the following: the student\nthat has been duly elected as student president of the high school; a\nstudent duly elected by the student body; a student selected by the high\nschool student government; a student selected by the high school\nprincipal; a student selected by the superintendent of schools; a\nstudent selected by majority vote of the school board.\n  d. The ex officio student members shall have attended such high school\nfor at least one year prior to selection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>