<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1905"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1905"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1905"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1905">
        <num>1905</num>
        <heading>District treasurer and clerk; custody and disbursement of funds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1905. District treasurer and clerk; custody and disbursement of\nfunds.  The board of education of a central high school district shall\nappoint a treasurer, who shall hold office during the pleasure of the\nboard and shall be subject to the provisions of this chapter relative to\nthe treasurer of a union free school district.  The amount raised by tax\nin the several districts included within the central high school\ndistrict for the support and maintenance of such central high school,\nshall be paid to the treasurer of such central high school district and\nshall be paid out by him upon the orders of the board of education\nissued and executed in pursuance of a resolution of said board.  The\nprovisions of this chapter relative to the payment of claims against a\nunion free school district shall apply, so far as practicable, to the\npayment of claims against a central high school district.  The board of\neducation of such district may appoint one of its members or a qualified\nelector of such district as clerk of the district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>