<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1906"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1906"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1906"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1906">
        <num>1906</num>
        <heading>District meetings; vote upon school taxes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1906. District meetings; vote upon school taxes. 1. The annual\nmeeting and election of a central high school district shall be held on\nthe third Tuesday in May, provided, however, that such annual meeting\nand election shall be held on the second Tuesday in May if the\ncommissioner at the request of a local school board certifies no later\nthan March first that such election would conflict with religious\nobservances, and any school budget revote shall be held on the date\nspecified in subdivision three of section two thousand seven of this\ntitle. The board of education of every central high school district\nshall hold a budget hearing prior to each annual meeting and election or\nspecial district meeting at which a school budget vote will occur, and\nshall prepare and present to the voters at such budget hearing a\nproposed school district budget for the ensuing school year. Special\nmeetings may be called in the same manner and for the same purposes as\nspecial meetings in union free school districts. Such meetings shall be\nheld for the same purposes and in the same manner, and be subject to the\nsame provisions of law, except as may be provided otherwise in\nsubdivision two of this section, as like meetings in union free school\ndistricts, and all persons who are qualified electors of the school\ndistricts included in such central high school district may vote at such\nmeetings.\n  2. For any annual or special meeting the board of education may on its\nown motion divide the central high school district into such number of\nelection districts as there shall be union free school districts within\nthe central high school district. The boundaries of such election\ndistricts shall be coterminous with the boundaries of such union free\nschool districts. Such meetings shall be held so far as possible in the\npublic schoolhouse within each such election district designated by the\nboard of education. The schoolhouse or other place so designated for\neach election district shall be stated in the notice of the meeting. The\nlegal voters present in each election district shall elect a chairman\nand secretary and the chairman so elected shall appoint at least three\ninspectors of election who shall canvass the result of the election in\nsuch election district and prepare and sign a statement showing the\nresults of the voting. Each such statement shall be forthwith delivered\nto the district clerk. The district clerk shall forthwith examine and\ntabulate the statements and prepare a certificate of the combined\nresults of the voting, announce the result thereof and record the\ncertificate with the records of the meeting. The proceedings, in the\nevent of such division, in all other respects shall be the same as if\nthe school meeting were held in one place.\n  3. The board of education of such district shall present at the annual\nmeeting a detailed statement in writing of the estimated expenditures\nrequired for the support and maintenance of the central high school\ntherein for the ensuing year. The said meeting shall vote the necessary\ntaxes to meet such expenditures, in the same manner as taxes are voted\nat a district meeting in a union free school district. The provisions of\nsections seventeen hundred twenty-five and seventeen hundred sixteen to\nseventeen hundred nineteen, inclusive, of this chapter, and all other\nprovisions relative to the making of appropriations, the voting of\ntaxes, and the expenditure of moneys for the support, maintenance and\nexpenses of public schools in union free school districts, shall apply\nto the support, maintenance, and expenses of a central high school\ndistrict.\n  4. a. Whenever the board of education of a central high school\ndistrict in the county of Nassau shall have provided for the personal\nregistration of voters at school meetings or elections in such district,\nsuch board of education shall fix the day or days for registration by\nresolution adopted not later than the fortieth day preceding each annual\nor special meeting or election in such district. The last day for such\nregistration shall not be more than eleven nor less than three days\npreceding each annual or special meeting or election. Such board shall\nforthwith notify the clerk of each component union free school district\nproviding for personal registration, of such registration day or days\nfor each annual meeting. Such board shall also notify each such clerk of\nevery special meeting or election in such central high school district\nat least ten days prior thereto. The board of registration of the\ncentral high school district shall meet on the day or days fixed by such\nboard of education for the purpose of preparing a register,\ncomplementary to the register or registers of any component union free\nschool district providing for personal registration, for the personal\nregistration of qualified voters within any component union free school\ndistrict providing for personal registration, which voters have not\nregistered for the annual or any subsequent special meeting or election\nin such union free school district, and for the personal registration of\nqualified voters of any component union free school district not\nproviding for personal registration.\n  b. Whenever personal registration of voters shall have been provided\nfor in any such central high school district, any qualified voter of a\ncomponent union free school district who is duly registered in such\nunion free school district for the annual meeting or a subsequent\nspecial meeting or election therein, shall be deemed duly registered for\nand entitled to vote at the annual meeting or any special meeting or\nelection in such central high school district occurring between the date\nof such registration and the next ensuing annual meeting.\n  c. Whenever the board of education of such central high school\ndistrict shall have so provided for registration of voters, the board of\neducation of any component union free school district in such central\nhigh school district, which board of education shall have provided or\nshall provide for personal registration of voters at school meetings or\nelections of such union free school district, shall designate the day or\ndays for registration so that the last day for such registration shall\nnot be more than eleven nor less than five days preceding each such\nschool meeting. In designating the day or days of registration for the\nannual meeting such board shall include the day or days which shall have\nbeen theretofore designated by the board of education of the central\nhigh school district as the registration day or days for the annual\nmeeting of the central high school district. The register prepared in\nsuch union free school district, in addition to complying with the\nrequirements of subdivision two of section two thousand fourteen of this\nchapter, shall include columns or space to make the proper entries\nrelating to any annual or special central high school district meeting\nor election. Such register shall be delivered by the clerk of such union\nfree school district to the custody of the clerk of the central high\nschool district on the day preceding the meeting or election of the\ncentral high school district at which it is to be used. It shall be\nreturned to the clerk of the union free school district on the day\nfollowing such meeting or election. Such register shall at all\nreasonable times be open to inspection by any qualified voter of the\ncentral high school district, even though in the possession of the clerk\nof such union free school district.\n  d. The provisions of sections two thousand four, two thousand fourteen\nand two thousand fifteen of this chapter shall be applicable in any\ncentral high school district providing for personal registration, except\nas otherwise provided in this subdivision.\n  e. Nothing contained in this subdivision shall be deemed to require\nthe board of education of any component union free school district to\nprovide for personal registration of voters for meetings or elections in\nsuch union free school district.\n  5. a. The board of education of a central high school district in the\ncounty of Nassau, which has provided for the personal registration of\nvoters at school meetings and elections in such central high school\ndistrict, may, by resolution duly adopted and entered upon its minutes,\non its own motion divide the central high school district into election\ndistricts. The boundaries of such election districts shall be\ncoterminous with the boundaries of the union free school districts\nwithin the central high school district, except that where a component\nunion free school district, in turn, shall have been or hereafter is\ndivided into school election districts pursuant to section two thousand\nseventeen of this chapter, such school election districts of such union\nfree school districts shall in such case, without further action of the\nboard of education of the central high school district, become and be\nelection districts of the central high school district.\n  b. Where the board of education shall have so divided the central high\nschool district into election districts pursuant to the provisions of\nthis subdivision, notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions one and\nthree of this section, the vote upon the appropriation of the necessary\nfunds to meet the estimated expenditures of the central high school\ndistrict and upon any propositions involving the expenditure of money by\nthe central high school district or upon any other matter which may\nproperly be brought before the annual meeting or election of the central\nhigh school district, shall be held at the same time as the annual\nmeetings or elections of the component union free school districts. The\nclerk of the central high school district shall give the notices\nrequired by subdivision one of section two thousand four of this\nchapter, in relation to suc</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>