<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1911"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1911"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1911"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1911">
        <num>1911</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of site and erection of building</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1911. Acquisition of site and erection of building.  1. The board of\neducation of a central high school district shall, when the site of the\nsaid high school building shall have been designated as provided herein,\nsubmit to the qualified electors of such district a proposition\nauthorizing the levy and collection of a tax, in one sum or by\ninstallments, sufficient in amount for the purchase or acquisition of\nsuch site.\n  2. The said board of education shall also submit to the qualified\nelectors of the said central high school district a proposition\nauthorizing the levy and collection of a tax, in one sum or in\ninstallments, for the erection on such site of a new building suitable\nfor high school purposes and for the construction of such improvements\nor structures on such site as may be required for the establishment and\nmaintenance of a high school in such district.\n  3. Such propositions shall be voted upon by the qualified electors of\nthe district at a meeting called by the board of education of such\ncentral high school district, and for the purpose of voting upon such\npropositions the said district shall be deemed to be a school district\nand the provisions of this chapter relative to district meetings and the\nadoption of propositions authorizing the levy of school taxes shall\napply to meetings held in such central high school district for the\npurposes herein specified.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>