<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1913"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1913"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1913"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1913/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1913/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1913/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1913/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1913">
        <num>1913</num>
        <heading>Laying out; referendum procedure</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1913. Laying out; referendum procedure.  1. The commissioner is\nauthorized to lay out a central high school district for the\nestablishment and maintenance of instruction for secondary pupils in\ngrades seven through twelve and to fix its boundaries.\n  2. Within ten days after the making and entry of the order pursuant to\nthis section, the commissioner shall transmit a certified copy thereof\nto the clerk, or in the event there is no clerk, to the trustee or\ntrustees of each school district affected by such order. The clerk, the\ntrustee or trustees, as the case may be, shall, within five days after\nreceipt of such order, post a copy thereof in five conspicuous places in\nsuch district.\n  3. No central high school district laid out by order of the\ncommissioner shall operate as such until it has been established by the\nqualified voters of the district in accordance with the provisions of\nthis article.\n  4. Upon the request of the boards of education of two or more school\ndistricts involved, or upon the receipt of petitions representing\nqualified voters equal to ten percent of resident school age pupils from\neach of a majority of the districts to be included, the commissioner\nshall order a referendum to be conducted in each of the districts\nincluded in the proposed reorganization. The conduct of such referenda\nshall be consistent with the provisions of sections eighteen hundred\none, eighteen hundred two, eighteen hundred three and eighteen hundred\nfour of this chapter, except as specifically provided in this article.\nIf the resolution to establish the central high school district is\npassed in all of the districts, the central high school district shall\nbe established as laid out. If the proposition to establish the central\nhigh school district shall fail to receive a majority of the votes cast\nin any district, the order laying out such central high school district\nshall be deemed void. However, nothing herein contained shall prevent\nthe commissioner from issuing a new order and ordering a vote in\ndistricts in which a resolution shall have received a majority of the\nvotes cast. An order defeated at the polls may not be reissued for two\nyears.  Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, upon consent\nof the commissioner and each of the boards of education of the school\ndistricts involved, there may also be offered before the qualified\nvoters of all the districts, at the same time as the referendum to form\na central high school district, a bond referendum for the construction\nof a new high school to serve as the central high school of the new\ncentral high school district, provided, however, that if either\nreferendum shall fail to gain approval, both shall be deemed to have\nfailed and provided, further, that the boards of education of the school\ndistricts involved shall submit the proposition and that such\nproposition shall be deemed to have been submitted by the board of\neducation of the newly formed central high school district. The board of\neducation of the central high school district subsequently formed shall\nbe authorized to carry out all acts necessary to effectuate such\nconstruction, and such board shall be deemed to have assumed full\nauthority to take all action necessary and to proceed with all other\nbusiness to establish the central high school district and to enter into\nany and all contracts, including but not limited to construction\ncontracts, and be eligible for any and all state aid and state aid\nreimbursement pursuant to subdivision six and paragraph c of subdivision\nfourteen of section thirty-six hundred two of this chapter, provided\nthat the percent increase pursuant to such paragraph c shall be thirty,\nand shall be in effect for expenditures incurred on or after the date\nupon which a bond referendum for the construction of a new high school\nto serve as the central high school of the new central high school\ndistrict is offered before the qualified voters of the district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>