<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1914"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1914"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1914"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1914/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1914/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1914/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1914/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1914">
        <num>1914</num>
        <heading>Board of education; number and election</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1914. Board of education; number and election.  For any central high\nschool district formed on or after July first, nineteen hundred\neighty-one, the order of the commissioner establishing such central high\nschool district shall specify the number of members to constitute the\nboard of education of such district and the number of members\nrepresenting each of the districts included in such district. The number\nof members of such board shall be not less than five. There shall be at\nleast one member of such board from each component school district. The\nboard of education of each union free school district or central school\ndistrict in such central high school district shall appoint the number\nof persons so designated by the commissioner to represent such district\nas members of the board of education thereof. In each common school\ndistrict having a sole trustee, such trustee shall represent such\ndistrict as a member of the board of education of such central high\nschool district. If a common school district has three trustees, such\nboard of trustees shall designate one of its members to represent such\ndistrict as a member of such board of education. The persons so\ndesignated shall be members of the board of education of the central\nhigh school district during their terms of office as members of the\nboard of education or as trustees of the districts respectively\nrepresented by them. Whenever a vacancy shall occur in the office of a\nmember of the board of education of such central high school district,\nit shall be filled as above provided; except that each component school\ndistrict may choose to fill vacancies from its district on the central\nhigh school district board by election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>