<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1951"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1951"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1951"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1951/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1951/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1951/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1951/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1951">
        <num>1951</num>
        <heading>Budget of board of cooperative educational services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1951__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>anticipated participation in the\nensuing school year, or (ii) participation in the current year, or (iii)\na two or three year average including participation in the current year,\nwhich unit cost shall be the same for all participating component school\ndistricts and shall be computed in accordance with a uniform methodology\napproved annually by at least three-quarters of the participating\ncomponent school districts after consultation by local school officials\nwith their respective boards; provided, however, such unit cost shall be\nsubject to final adjustment for programs for students with disabilities\nbased on actual participation in accordance with regulations of the\ncommissioner. The school authorities of each school district in the\nboard of cooperative educational services shall add such amount to the\nbudget of such school district and shall pay such amount to the\ntreasurer of the board of cooperative educational services, and shall be\npaid out by the treasurer upon orders of the board issued and executed\npursuant to the resolution of said board.\n  2. a. If the board of cooperative educational services determines to\nsubmit a proposition to authorize the purchase or acquisition of sites\nor additions thereto and real property and to construct buildings\nthereon and to purchase buildings and construct additions thereto, or to\nauthorize the sale of any real property the title to which is vested in\nthe board of cooperative educational services and buildings thereon and\nappurtenances or any part thereof, or to authorize the exchange of real\nproperty held by the board of cooperative educational services for the\npurpose of improving or changing school sites, to the qualified voters\nof the board of cooperative educational services, then the board shall\ncall a meeting and submit to the qualified voters of the board of\ncooperative educational services such a proposition. The board shall\ncause a notice of such meeting to be given by public notice of...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1951__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A citizen of the United States.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1951__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Eighteen years of age.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1951__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A resident within the board of cooperative educational services\nfor a period of thirty days next preceding the meeting at which he\noffers to vote.\n  No person shall be deemed to be ineligible to vote at any such\nmeeting, by reason of sex, who has the other qualifications required by\nthis paragraph.\n  d. If a person offering to vote at any meeting of the voters of the\nboard of cooperative educational services shall be challenged as\nunqualified by any legal voter of such board at such meeting, the\nchairman presiding at such meeting shall require the person so offering\nto make the following declaration: "I do declare and affirm that I am,\nand have been, for the thirty days last past, an actual resident of this\nboard of cooperative educational services and that I am qualified to\nvote at this meeting." Every person making such declaration shall be\npermitted to vote on all questions proposed at such meeting; but if any\nperson shall refuse to make such declaration his vote shal...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1951__subsec_i__subsec_000">
            <num>(000)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and that the ballot labels are properly placed,\nand that the machine is in all respects in proper condition for use. The\nuse of such machine shall be deemed a compliance with any provision of\nlaw requiring the vote to be by ballot. The board of cooperative\neducational services may purchase the necessary voting machine or\nmachines; or if the county board of elections shall consent thereto,\nsuch machines belonging to the county or belonging to the town in which\nany part of said board of cooperative educational services shall be\nlocated may be used at any such meeting, the expense of delivery and\nreturning and setting up, and any other expense connected therewith\nshall be defrayed by the board of cooperative educational services; but\nsuch machines belonging to the county shall not be so used at the time\nor times when they may be required under the election law.\n  h. The board of cooperative educational services shall appoint a\nqualified voter of the board of cooperative educ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>