<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1952"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1952"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1952"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1952/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1952/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1952/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1952/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1952">
        <num>1952</num>
        <heading>Technologies network ties program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1952. Technologies network ties program. 1. There is hereby\nestablished a model technologies network ties program to pilot\ninnovative uses of technology for interactive instruction and\nadministrative purposes, in order to determine the feasibility of\ndeveloping a statewide technologies network ties program.\n  2. The commissioner shall develop a plan, subject to the approval of\nthe director of the budget, for the allocation of such funds as may be\nmade available for this program, including competitive grants to school\ndistricts and boards of cooperative educational services for interactive\ninstruction. Such plan shall include a listing of the school districts,\nboards of cooperative educational services and library network systems\nselected to take part in the pilot program.\n  3. Objectives of the program shall include the development of a\nnetwork consisting of a structure which will electronically link all\nparticipating agencies and allow for the transfer of administrative and\ninstructional data between and among the participating sites. The\ncommissioner, in consultation with appropriate consultants and\nrepresentatives of participating districts and boards of cooperative\neducational services, will be responsible for determining the\nappropriate communication standards and protocols for the selection of\nhardware and software to be used in all facets of the project.\n  4. The commissioner shall adopt regulations to implement the\nprovisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>