<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1981"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1981"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1981"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1981/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1981/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1981/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1981/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1981">
        <num>1981</num>
        <heading>Shared personnel between school districts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1981__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The agreement to share personnel shall allow other participating\ndistricts to be substituted as the principal employing district.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of law, upon substitution of a new\nprincipal employing district, the shared employee shall be considered an\nemployee of the new principal employing district with the same tenure\nstatus he or she maintained in such prior principal employing district.\nFor any such shared employee for salary, sick leave and any other\npurposes, the length of service credited in such prior principal\nemploying district shall be credited as employment time with such new\nprincipal employing district.\n  (ii) Where the principal employing district abolishes the position of\na shared employee and creates a new position for the performance of\nsimilar duties, in determining the right of the employee under\nsubdivision one of section three thousand thirteen or subdivision one of\nsection twenty-five hundred ten to appointment to such new position, the\nnew position shall be deemed similar if more than forty percent of the\nfunctions of the new position were performed by the shared employee in\nthe shared position.\n  (iii) Where a participating district other than the principal\nemploying district determines to discontinue the services of a shared\nemployee pursuant to the terms of the agreement to share personnel, the\nemployee shall retain his or her tenure rights in the principal\nemploying district only.\n  3. School authorities of any school district sharing personnel\npursuant to this section shall retain the right to promulgate\neducational or administrative policies pertaining to their respective\nschool district pursuant to law, rule or regulation.\n  4. All agreements to share personnel pursuant to this section shall be\nsubject to the approval and oversight of the district superintendent, if\nany, or by the commissioner or his designee if there is no local\ndistrict superintendent.\n  5. The commissioner may pro...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>