<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2002"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2002"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-03-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2002"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2002">
        <num>2002</num>
        <heading>Time and place of annual meeting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2002. Time and place of annual meeting. 1. The annual meeting and\nelection of each school district shall be held on the third Tuesday of\nMay in each year, provided, however that such annual meeting and\nelection shall be held on the second Tuesday in May if the commissioner\nat the request of a local school board certifies no later than March\nfirst that such election would conflict with religious observances.\nUnless the hour and place thereof shall have been fixed by a vote of a\nprevious district meeting, the same shall be held in the schoolhouse, or\nany building owned or leased by the district, at seven-thirty p.m. in\nthe case of a school district that is not divided into election\ndistricts and conducts its election or vote by recording the ayes or\nnoes of the qualified voters attending, or, in the case of all other\ndistricts, during at least six consecutive hours after six a.m., two of\nwhich hours shall be after six p.m. as determined by resolution of the\ntrustees or board of education, provided, however, that the trustees or\nboard of education of any school district that conducted its annual\nmeeting at seven-thirty p.m. in nineteen hundred ninety-seven may\nconduct its annual election and budget vote at such time in nineteen\nhundred ninety-eight. If a district possesses more than one schoolhouse\nor building, or leases more than one building, it shall be held in the\none usually employed for that purpose, unless the trustees or board of\neducation designate another, provided that if the school district is\ndivided into election districts such annual meeting and election shall\nbe held at such place in each election district as the board of\neducation may designate. If the district possesses no schoolhouse or\nbuilding, or does not lease a building, or if the schoolhouse or\nbuilding shall not be accessible or adequate, then the annual meeting\nand election shall be held at such place as the trustees or board of\neducation, or the clerk, shall designate in the notice.\n  2. The use of any building owned or leased by a school district, as\ndescribed in subdivision one of this section, shall comply with the\naccessibility provisions set out in subdivisions one-a and one-b of\nsection 4-104 of the election law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>