<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2006"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2006"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2006"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2006">
        <num>2006</num>
        <heading>Special meeting in common school district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2006. Special meeting in common school district. 1. A special\ndistrict meeting of a common school district shall be held whenever\ncalled by the trustees or whenever called for by petition of the voters\npursuant to subdivision three of this section. The notice thereof shall\nstate the purposes for which it is called, and no business shall be\ntransacted at such special meeting, except that which is specified in\nthe notice; and the district clerk, or, if the office be vacant, or the\nclerk be sick or absent, or shall refuse to act, a trustee, or some\ntaxable inhabitant, by order of the trustees, shall serve the notice\nupon each inhabitant of the district qualified to vote at district\nmeetings, at least six days before the day of the meeting, in the manner\nprescribed in section two thousand one of this part or the trustees\nshall give notice of the time and place of such special meeting, and the\nnotice shall be published once in each week within the four weeks next\npreceding the special meeting, the first publication to be at least\ntwenty-two days before said meeting, in two newspapers if there shall be\ntwo, or in one newspaper if there shall be but one, having general\ncirculation within such common school district. But if no newspaper\nshall then have general circulation therein, the said notice shall be\nposted in at least twenty public places in said district twenty-two days\nbut not more than twenty-eight days before the time of such meeting.\n  2. The inhabitants of a district may, at any annual meeting, adopt a\nresolution prescribing some other mode of giving notice of special\nmeetings, which resolution and the mode prescribed thereby shall\ncontinue in force until rescinded or modified at some subsequent annual\nmeeting.\n  3. Whenever the voters shall have defeated the budget of the school\ndistrict at the annual meeting and election, the trustees may call a\nspecial district meeting for a school budget revote to be held on the\nthird Tuesday of June, provided, however that such budget revote shall\nbe held on the second Tuesday in June if the commissioner at the request\nof a local school board certifies no later than March first that such\nvote would conflict with religious observances. The trustees shall give\nthe notices required by subdivision one of section two thousand three of\nthis part and this section by publishing such notices once in each week\nwithin the two weeks next preceding such special meeting, the first\npublication to be at least fourteen days before such meeting, with any\nrequired posting to be fourteen days before the time of such meeting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>