<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2012"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2012"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2012"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2012/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2012/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2012/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2012/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2012">
        <num>2012</num>
        <heading>Qualifications of voters at district meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2012. Qualifications of voters at district meetings.  A person shall\nbe entitled to vote at any school meeting or election for the election\nof school district officers, and upon all other matters which may be\nbrought before such meeting or election, who is: 1.  A citizen of the\nUnited States.\n  2. Eighteen years of age.\n  3. A resident within the district for a period of thirty days next\npreceding the meeting or election at which he offers to vote.\n  4. No person shall have the right to register for or vote at any\nschool meeting or election who would not be qualified to register for or\nvote at an election in accordance with the provisions of section 5-106\nof the election law.\n  No person shall be deemed to be ineligible to vote at any such meeting\nor election, by reason of sex, who has the other qualifications required\nby this section; and notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this\nsection, no Indian eighteen years of age or over who, having been born\nin the United States to a member of an Indian tribe, or having been\nnaturalized or otherwise acquired citizenship, shall have resided on an\nIndian reservation in the state for a period of thirty days next\npreceding the meeting or election at which he offers to vote or the\nspouse of such Indian shall be deemed ineligible to vote at any such\nmeeting or election of the school district where the majority, as\ndetermined by the commissioner, of the Indian children of such\nreservation are being educated under a contract pursuant to subdivision\ntwo of section forty-one hundred one of this chapter, except that the\nparents or guardians of Indian children of such reservation who are\nbeing educated in the schools of a district other than the district\nwhich educates the majority of such children, shall be eligible to vote\nonly in the district where their children are being so educated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>