<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2014"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2014"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2014"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2014/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2014/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2014/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2014/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2014">
        <num>2014</num>
        <heading>Registration of voters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2014. Registration of voters.  1. In any union free school district,\nthe board of education may upon its own motion provide for the personal\nregistration of voters at school meetings or elections in such district\nas provided in this section.\n  In such event, the board of education in such district shall\nimmediately designate four qualified voters of such district to\nconstitute a board of registration for such district to serve until the\nthirtieth day following the next annual meeting or election of such\ndistrict. Thereafter, the board of education of such district shall\nannually designate, not later than the thirtieth day following the\nannual meeting or election of such district, four qualified voters of\nsuch district to constitute a board of registration for such district.\nSuch members of the board of registration so appointed shall serve until\nthe thirtieth day after the annual meeting or election of such district\nin the following year. In the event that a vacancy shall occur on the\nboard of registration, the board of education at any time may designate\na qualified voter of such district as a member of the board of\nregistration for such district to fill the vacancy.\n  Each member of the board of registration shall be entitled to\ncompensation at a rate to be fixed by the board of education for each\nday actually and necessarily spent upon the duties of his office.\n  2. The board of registration of such district shall meet during the\nannual meeting or election of such district at the place where such\nannual meeting or election is held for the purpose of preparing a\nregister for meetings or elections held subsequent to such annual\nmeeting or election. Such board of registration of such district shall,\nin addition, meet on such day or days as shall be fixed by the board of\neducation, the last day of which, however, shall not be more than\nfourteen nor less than five days preceding each school meeting or\nelection in such district at such place in the school district, and at\nsuch hours, as the board of education shall by resolution designate,\nwhich hours shall include at least four consecutive hours between seven\no'clock in the morning and eight o'clock in the evening, for the purpose\nof preparing a register for such meeting or election provided, however,\nthat at any annual meeting the majority of the voters may adopt a\nresolution authorizing the registration of voters during the hours for\nenrollment of children for a school term; provided further, however,\nthat such voters may also authorize registration during certain\nspecified hours of the school day, at the office of the district clerk\nor business office of the school district by the district clerk,\nassistant district clerk or a member of the board of registration. Such\nregistration shall not take place less than five days preceding any\nschool meeting or election. Such registration shall be effective to\ninclude the next annual meeting and shall take place at the school or\nschools within the district designated in the resolution. The register\nshall, so far as practical, be in the same form as the register of\nvoters in an election district for general elections in a city or\nvillage having five thousand inhabitants or more, under the election\nlaw. The register shall be arranged alphabetically by the surnames, and\nthe place of residence by street and number or otherwise of each person\nnamed on the list shall be given, or if none, some description\naccurately locating such place of residence shall be given on such\nregister. In addition, the register shall have a column or columns in\nwhich the inspectors of election may indicate whether each person named\non the list shall have voted in any election or elections or at any\nmeeting or meetings. The district clerk of such district shall attend\nwith the board of registration. The board of registration and the\ndistrict clerk, shall, for the annual meeting or election of the school\ndistrict, prepare a register of the qualified voters of such school\ndistrict who shall present themselves personally for registration. Such\nboard of registration shall in like manner prepare a register for each\nspecial school meeting or election within such school district, except\nthat the register prepared at the last annual meeting or election and\nthe register or registers for any subsequent special meeting, meetings,\nelection, or elections in such school district shall be used by them as\nthe basis therefor.  The register so prepared shall include all persons\nwho shall have presented themselves personally for registration in\naccordance herewith and may include all persons who shall have been\npreviously registered hereunder for any annual or special meeting or\nelection and who shall have voted at any annual or special meeting or\nany election held or conducted during the four calendar years prior to\nthe year in which such register is being prepared; and the board of\nregistration shall remove from the register all persons who are known to\nbe deceased, who have moved out of the school district or who are\notherwise not qualified as school district electors. The district clerk\nshall furnish the necessary blank books and blanks at the expense of\nsuch school district. School meetings and elections in such school\ndistrict shall be thereafter conducted in the manner provided by this\nchapter, except that no person shall be entitled to vote thereat whose\nname does not appear upon the register of the school district in which\nhe claims to be entitled to vote. In all cases, the board of education\nshall cause the district clerk to give the notice required by\nsubdivision four of section two thousand four of this chapter.\n  3. The board of education may, upon its own motion and at least two\nmonths prior to a school district meeting or election at which the same\nis to be effective, revoke the provisions for personal registration\nadopted as provided in this section. However, the board of education may\nnot thereafter provide for personal registration unless authorized by\nthe voters at a district meeting or election.\n  4. Whenever any union free school district in which personal\nregistration of voters at school meetings or elections therein is\nrequired as provided in subdivision one of this section shall have been\ndivided into election districts pursuant to section two thousand\nseventeen of this chapter, the board of education shall appoint a board\nof registration pursuant to the provisions of subdivision one of this\nsection consisting of as many members as shall provide two for each\nelection district, shall designate a place in each such election\ndistrict and shall designate two members of the board of registration to\nattend thereat for the purpose of preparing a register for such election\ndistrict. At the same time, the board of education shall designate the\nregistration place at which the district clerk shall attend. The\nprovisions of subdivisions one, two and three of this section shall\napply with respect to the registration of voters in such union free\nschool districts, except as may be inconsistent with the foregoing\nprovisions of this subdivision, and except that the notice provided to\nbe given by the district clerk in subdivision two of this section and\nsubdivision five and six of section two thousand four of this chapter\nshall describe each of the election districts as required in subdivision\ntwo of section two thousand seventeen and subdivision six of section two\nthousand four of this chapter.\n  5. The provisions of this section shall not apply with respect to any\nperson registered to vote pursuant to the provisions of section three\nhundred fifty-two of the election law.\n  6. In any case where a union free school district has provided for the\nregistration of voters during specified hours of the school day at the\noffice of the district clerk, assistant clerk or a member of the board\nof registration, such school district's board of registration, at the\ndiscretion of the board of education, may not be required to meet prior\nto the annual meeting or election, or prior to a special meeting or\nspecial election pursuant to subdivision two of this section, solely for\nthe purposes of registering voters.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>