<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2015"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2015"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2015"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2015/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2015/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2015/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2015/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2015">
        <num>2015</num>
        <heading>Register to be filed; addition to and correction of register; challenges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2015. Register to be filed; addition to and correction of register;\nchallenges.  1. The register prepared as provided in section two\nthousand fourteen of this chapter shall, immediately upon its completion\nand not less than five days prior to the time set for the school meeting\nor election at which it is to be used, be filed in the office of the\nclerk of the district, and thereafter shall at all reasonable times be\nopen to inspection by any qualified voter of such school district on\neach day up to and including the day set for the meeting or election,\nexcept Sundays.\n  2. The name of no voter may be placed upon a register unless such\nvoter appears before the board of registration except if a qualified\nvoter is a resident of a school district and his name appears on a\nregister as a resident of another district, a written sworn statement\nmay be filed by such voter with the clerk of the district showing his\ncorrect residence and the name of such voter shall thereupon be stricken\nfrom such register and placed upon the proper register.\n  3. A qualified voter may, upon the examination of such list, file a\nwritten challenge of the qualifications as a voter of any person whose\nname appears on such list.\n  4. Statements and challenges shall be received and preserved by the\nclerk of the district or other person designated by the board of\neducation, and immediately upon receiving any such sworn statement of a\nvoter, applying to have his name placed upon the register or any\nchallenge as to a name already thereon, the clerk shall file such\nstatement or challenge or copy thereof, with the register and hold the\nsame open for inspection by any qualified voter of the district. Upon\nthe face of such statement or challenge, the clerk shall write clearly\nwhat action was taken with reference thereto, immediately upon such\naction being taken.\n  5. The clerk of the district shall cause a copy of the register of\nsuch school district to be delivered on the day of the meeting or\nelection before the opening of the polls to the inspectors of election\nat each voting place within the district at the place or places where\nthe meeting or election is to be held. If there be not more than one\nvoting place, the clerk shall produce the register at the place of the\nmeeting or election, at the opening thereof. The inspectors of election\nat each voting place shall indicate on the copy of the register\ndelivered to them, and opposite the name of each person so registered,\nwhether each such person did vote in such election or at such meeting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>