<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2017"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2017"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2017"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2017/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2017/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2017/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2017/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2017">
        <num>2017</num>
        <heading>Division of union free school district into election districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2017. Division of union free school district into election\ndistricts.  1. In any union free school district having personal\nregistration of voters pursuant to section two thousand fourteen of this\nchapter, the board of education may upon its own motion divide the\nschool district into election districts, and shall upon the petition of\ntwenty-five qualified voters of the district, or five percent of the\nvoters who voted in the previous annual election of the members of the\nboard of education, whichever is greater, cause to be submitted at an\nannual or special meeting, a proposition to divide such school district\ninto election districts provided, however, that in each election\ndistrict the number of qualified voters shall at least equal three\nhundred.\n  2. If it is determined to divide the district into election districts,\nthe board of education shall immediately thereafter and not less than\nthirty days prior to an annual or special meeting or election, within\nsuch district, adopt a resolution dividing the school district into such\nnumber of election districts as the board of education may determine.\nThe school district shall be so divided that if circumstances will\npermit, there shall be a schoolhouse in each election district or in as\nmany of such election districts as possible. The election districts so\nformed shall continue in existence until modified by resolution of the\nboard of education. Such resolution shall accurately describe the\nboundaries of each such district by streets, alleys and highways, or\notherwise. School meetings and elections shall thereafter be held so far\nas may be possible in the public schoolhouses within any such school\nelection district. The board of education shall designate the place\nwithin each election district where the meeting or election shall be\nheld.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>