<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2018"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2018">
        <num>2018</num>
        <heading>Nomination of candidates for the office of member of the board of education in all union free school districts or for the office of membe...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2018. Nomination of candidates for the office of member of the board\nof education in all union free school districts or for the office of\nmember of the board of trustees in all common school districts which\nhave elected to vote for trustees at a time or place separate from the\nannual meeting. a. In all union free school districts candidates for the\noffice of member of the board of education shall be nominated by\npetition. Each vacancy upon the board of education to be filled shall be\nconsidered a separate specific office. A separate petition shall be\nrequired to nominate a candidate to each separate office. Each petition\nshall be directed to the clerk of the school district, shall be signed\nby at least twenty-five qualified voters of the district, or two percent\nof the voters who voted in the previous annual election of the members\nof the board of education, whichever is greater, such number to be\ndetermined by the number of persons recorded on the poll list as having\nvoted at such election shall state the residence of each signer, shall\nstate the name and residence of the candidate and shall describe the\nspecific vacancy on the board of education for which the candidate is\nnominated, which description shall include at least the length of the\nterm of office and the name of the last incumbent, if any. In the event\nthat any such nominee shall withdraw his candidacy prior to the\nelection, such person shall not be considered a candidate unless a new\npetition nominating such person in the same manner and within the same\ntime limitations applicable to other candidates is filed with the clerk\nof the district. Each petition shall be filed in the office of the clerk\nof the district between the hours of nine a.m. and five p.m., not later\nthan the thirtieth day preceding the school meeting or election at which\nthe candidates nominated are to be elected. No person shall be nominated\nby petition for more than one separate office.\n  b. At any school election in such district, the electors may adopt a\nproposition providing that, in all subsequent elections, vacancies upon\nthe board of education shall not be considered separate specific offices\nand that the nominating petitions shall not describe any specific\nvacancy upon the board of education for which the candidate is\nnominated. Such procedure shall be followed with respect to all\nnominations and elections in subsequent years until and unless such\nproposition is repealed by the electors of the district at a regular\nelection by the adoption of a proposition to repeal the same.\n  c. In all common school districts, candidates for the office of member\nof the board of trustees shall be nominated by petition. Such petition\nshall not describe any specific vacancy on the board of trustees. Each\npetition shall be directed to the clerk of the school district and shall\nbe signed by at least twenty-five qualified voters of the district or\ntwo percent of the voters who voted in the previous annual election of\nthe members of the board of trustees, whichever is greater. Such a\npetition shall state the residence of each signer, and shall contain the\nname and residence of the candidate.\n  d. If a candidate for whom a nominating petition for the office of\nmember of a board of education has been duly filed withdraws such\npetition, dies or becomes otherwise ineligible to hold such office at a\ntime which is later than fifteen days before the last day for the filing\nof nominating petitions as provided in subdivision a of this section,\nthe time for filing nominating petitions for such office shall be\nextended to five p.m. on the fifteenth day after the day on which such\ncandidate withdrew, died, or otherwise became ineligible to hold such\noffice, provided that no such nominating petition may be filed after\nfive p.m. on the seventh day preceding the date of the election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>