<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2018-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2018_B">
        <num>2018-B</num>
        <heading>Absentee ballots for school district elections by poll registration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a resident or patient in a hospital, including a veteran's\nadministration hospital, or unable to appear personally at the polling\nplace on such day because of illness or physical disability, or duties\nrelated to the primary care of one or more individuals who are ill or\nphysically disabled; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>absent from the county of such applicant's residence; provided,\nhowever, if the applicant expects to be absent from such county for a\nduration covering more than one election and seeks an absentee ballot\nfor each election, such applicant shall state the dates when they expect\nto begin and end such absence; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>detained in jail awaiting action by a grand jury or awaiting trial\nor confined in jail or prison after a conviction for an offense other\nthan a felony and stating the place where such applicant is so detained\nor confined.\n  b. Such application must be received by the district clerk or designee\nof the trustees or school board at least seven days before the election\nif the ballot is to be mailed to the voter, or the day before the\nelection, if the ballot is to be delivered personally to the voter.\n  c. Such application shall include the following statement to be signed\nby the voter.\n  I hereby declare that the foregoing is a true statement to the best of\nmy knowledge and belief, and I understand that if I make any material\nfalse statement in the foregoing statement of application for absentee\nballots, I shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\nDate...................   Signature of Voter ...........................\n  d. The clerk of the school district or a designee of the trustees or\nschool board shall request registration lists from the board of\nelections pursuant to subdivision three of section 5-612 of the election\nlaw for those voters whose registration record has been marked\n"permanently disabled". An applicant whose ability to appear personally\nat the polling place of the school district of which such applicant is a\nqualified voter is substantially impaired by reason of permanent illness\nor physical disability and whose registration record has been marked\n"permanently disabled" as determined by the board of elections pursuant\nto the provisions of this chapter and who has previously applied for an\nabsentee ballot shall be entitled to receive subsequent absentee ballots\npursuant to the provisions of this section without making separate\napplication for such absentee ballot, and the clerk of the school\ndistrict or a designee of the trustees or school board shall send an\nabsentee ballot to such voter at such voter's last known address with a\nr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>