<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2022"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2022"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2022"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2022/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2022/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2022/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2022/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2022">
        <num>2022</num>
        <heading>Vote on school district budgets and on the election of school district trustees and board of education members</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2022__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>through (iv) of paragraph i of subdivision two of\nsection two thousand twenty-three-a of this part, that would result from\nadoption of the proposed budget. Such notice shall be in a form\nprescribed by the commissioner.\n  a. Commencing with the proposed budget for the two thousand one--two\nthousand two school year, such notice shall also include a description\nof how total spending and the tax levy resulting from the proposed\nbudget would compare with a projected contingency budget adopted\npursuant to section two thousand twenty-three of this article, assuming\nthat such contingency budget is adopted on the same day as the vote on\nthe proposed budget. Such comparison shall be in total and by component\n(program, capital and administrative), and shall include a statement of\nthe assumptions made in estimating the projected contingency budget.\n  b. Commencing with the proposed budget for the two thousand eight--two\nthousand nine school year, such notice shall also include, in a format\nprescribed by the commissioner, an estimate of the tax savings that\nwould be available to an eligible homeowner under the basic school tax\nrelief (STAR) exemption authorized by section four hundred twenty-five\nof the real property tax law if the proposed budget were adopted. Such\nestimate shall be made in the manner prescribed by the commissioner, in\nconsultation with the office of real property services.\n  3. In all elections for trustees or members of boards of education or\nvotes involving the expenditure of money, or authorizing the levy of\ntaxes, the vote thereon shall be by ballot, or, in school districts that\nprior to nineteen hundred ninety-eight conducted their vote at the\nannual meeting, may be ascertained by taking and recording the ayes and\nnoes of such qualified voters attending and voting at such district\nmeetings.\n  4. The budget adoption process shall conform to the requirements set\nforth in section two thousand twenty-three-a of this part. In the e...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>