<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2032"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2032"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2032"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2032/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2032/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2032/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2032/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2032">
        <num>2032</num>
        <heading>Ballots for election of school district officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2032. Ballots for election of school district officers. 1. In common\nschool districts the ballots for the election of district officers shall\nbe written or printed, typed or mimeographed, or partly written and\npartly printed, typed or mineographed, containing the name of the person\nvoted for and designating the office for which each is voted.\n  2. a. In union free school districts the board of education shall\ncause ballots containing the names of all candidates nominated for\nelection to the board of education to be printed, typed or mimeographed.\n  b. The names of all candidates for each separate specific office shall\nbe grouped together and at the top of each group shall be placed a\ndescription of the separate specific office for which such candidates\nare nominated, which description shall include at least the length of\nthe term of office and the name of the last incumbent, if any, and in\naddition a direction that only one vote may be cast in each separate\ngroup. The names of the candidates for each separate specific office\nshall be listed in the order as determined by a drawing by lot. Such\ndrawing shall be conducted by the clerk of the board of education and\nshall be held the day after the last possible date for candidates to\nfile a petition. In the event that any candidate is not present in\nperson or by a person designated in a written proxy to accomplish the\ndrawing, the district clerk shall be authorized to act as proxy. In any\ndistrict where a proposition has been adopted pursuant to paragraph b of\nsection two thousand eighteen, the names of all candidates for vacancies\nupon the board of education shall be arranged according to lot as\nprescribed in this section, and a direction shall be made that as many\ncandidates may be voted for as there are vacancies to be filled.\n  c. A voting square shall be provided to the left of the name of each\ncandidate upon the ballot.\n  d. A single cross X mark in pen or pencil, or a single check * mark,\nin pen or pencil, in the voting square shall indicate a vote.\n  * NB There should be a check mark in this space.\n  e. One blank space shall be provided under the name of the last\ncandidate for each separate specific office so that voters may vote for\ncandidates who have not been nominated for the offices to be filled at\nsuch election and the writing in, with a pencil having black lead, by a\nvoter, of a name in the blank space so provided, shall indicate a vote.\n  f. Such ballot shall have placed thereon the name of the district and\ninstructions explaining in substance the provisions of paragraphs d and\ne of subdivision two of this section and subdivisions three and four of\nsection two thousand thirty-four of this chapter.\n  3. All spoiled or defective ballots shall be sealed in an envelope and\nso endorsed by the inspectors of election. Such envelope shall be placed\nin the ballot box as provided in subdivision six of section two thousand\nthirty-three of this chapter.\n  4. The clerk of the district shall cause to be delivered to the\ninspectors of election, on the day of the meeting or election and not\nbefore, a sufficient supply of the ballots for the use of the qualified\nvoters. Such ballots shall be prepared at the expense of the school\ndistrict.\n  5. The ballot shall be folded by the voter so as to conceal his\nmarking or writing thereon before the ballot is deposited in a ballot\nbox.\n  6. If official ballots are not furnished as provided in subdivision\ntwo of this section, an election of members of a board of education in a\nunion free school district shall not be declared invalid or illegal\nbecause of the use of ballots which do not conform to the requirements\nof subdivision two of this section, provided the intent of the voter may\nbe ascertained from the use of such irregular or defective ballots and\nsuch use was not fraudulent and did not substantially affect the result\nof the meeting or election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>