<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2035"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2035"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2035"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2035/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2035/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2035/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2035/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2035">
        <num>2035</num>
        <heading>Use of voting machines at school district meetings or elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2035. Use of voting machines at school district meetings or\nelections.  1. If the trustees or board of education of any school\ndistrict shall so determine, voting machines may be used for recording\nthe vote on elections and questions, or either, at the school district\nmeetings or elections, annual and special, or either, in such district.\nBefore any such machine is used at any such meeting or election, the\ninspectors of election shall examine it and see that all the counters\nare set at zero (000) and that the ballot labels are properly placed,\nand that the machine is in all respects in proper condition for use. The\nuse of such machine shall be deemed a compliance with any provision of\nlaw requiring the vote to be by ballot. Such trustees or board of\neducation, with district funds available, may purchase the necessary\nvoting machine or machines; or, if the county board of elections shall\nconsent thereto, such machines belonging to the county or belonging to\nthe town in which any part of said school district shall be located, may\nbe used at any such meeting, the expense of delivery and returning and\nsetting up, and any other expense connected therewith, to be defrayed by\nthe school district; but such machines belonging to the county shall not\nbe so used at the time or times when they may be required under the\nelection law.\n  2. In common school districts the manner of making nominations or\nsubmitting propositions by anyone other than the trustees and in union\nfree school districts the manner of submitting propositions by anyone\nother than the board of education for the purpose of preparing ballots\nfor the machine shall be prescribed by a rule previously adopted by the\ntrustees or board of education; provided, however, that the petition,\ncertificate, declaration, notice or other paper required by such rule,\nfor the making of any such nomination or submission, except as to a\nquestion or proposition required by law to be stated in the published or\nposted notice of the meeting shall be filed with the trustees or board\nof education not later than thirty days before the meeting or election.\nAny nomination may be rejected by the trustees if the candidate is\nineligible for the office or has declared his unwillingness to serve;\nany proposition may be rejected by the trustees or board of education if\nthe purpose of the proposition is not within the power of the voters, or\nwhere the expenditure of moneys is required by the proposition, if the\nproposition fails to include the necessary specific appropriation. Any\nsuch rule may be amended from time to time and may state that a\nreasonable minimum number of signatures shall be required for\nsubmission. The trustees or board of education shall cause such rule,\nand amendments from time to time, to be printed for general distribution\nin the district. Provided, however, that the provisions of any special\nlaw relating to nominations and elections in any union free school\ndistrict shall continue to remain in force, and the manner of making\nnominations and the conduct of meetings and elections, shall conform to\nsuch special law.\n  3. Any proposition submitted pursuant to this section shall be subject\nto the requirements set forth in subdivision nine of section two\nthousand twenty-three-a of this part.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>