<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="204"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Meetings and absences</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_204__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The regents may provide for\nregular meetings of the board of regents and any committee,\nsubcommittee, task force, or other subgroups thereof. Notice of time and\nplace for all regular public meetings of the board of regents and any\ncommittee, subcommittee, task force, or other subgroups thereof shall be\npublicly provided at least seven days in advance of such meeting. Such\nnotice of time, place and agenda shall be distributed via the board's\nofficial internet website and specifically distributed by United States\npostal service to all regents at their usual addresses and, if a meeting\nof a committee, subcommittee, task force, or other subgroups thereof, by\nsuch means, including but not limited to the United States postal\nservice or electronic means, as determined by the committee,\nsubcommittee, task force, or other subgroups thereof. An agenda for a\nregular public meeting of the board shall be comprised of a list of all\nitems to be considered with a description of the subject matter of each\nsuch item and shall be posted at least three days in advance of the\nmeeting; provided however, that in an instance of a health or public\nsafety emergency, the board may include additional items to the agenda\nwith less than three days notice. In an instance of a health or public\nsafety emergency, the board shall use best efforts to make public any\nchanges to the agenda prior to the regular meeting. The notice and\nagenda shall be considered a public record.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The chancellor or the commissioner, or any five regents, may at\nany time call a special meeting of the board of regents and fix the time\nand place therefor. Notice of time, place and agenda for all special\npublic meetings of the board of regents shall be publicly provided at\nleast three days in advance of such meeting. Such notice of time, place\nand agenda shall be distributed via the board's official internet\nwebsite and specifically circulated according to the rules and\nregulations of the regents to all regents. The board of regents special\npublic meeting agenda shall be comprised of a list of all items to be\nconsidered with a description of the subject matter of each such item;\nprovided however, that in an instance of a health or public safety\nemergency, the board may include additional items to the agenda with\nless than three days notice. In an instance of a health or public safety\nemergency, the board shall use best efforts to make public any changes\nto the agenda prior to the special meeting. The notice and agenda shall\nbe considered a public record.\n  2. Any meeting of the board of regents and any committee,\nsubcommittee, task force, or other subgroups thereof shall be conducted\nin accordance with article seven of the public officers law.\n  3. A summary of committee reports, any other minutes, and attendance\nof the board of regents for either regular or special meetings shall be\nelectronically available on the board of regents website at the close of\neach board meeting and shall be considered a public record. The video\nrecording of any regular full board meeting shall be posted no later\nthan five days following the meeting of the board. Any meeting summaries\nand actions taken shall be posted on the board of regents website within\nfive days of approval by the board. Information posted on the board of\nregents website shall remain on the site as archived data for a minimum\nof ten years.\n  4. If any regent shall fail to attend three c...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>