<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2040"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2040"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2040"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2040/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2040/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2040/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2040/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2040">
        <num>2040</num>
        <heading>District meeting to authorize contract system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2040. District meeting to authorize contract system. 1. Any school\ndistrict may decide by a majority vote of the qualified voters present\nand voting at a district meeting:\n  a. To contract for the education of all the elementary pupils of such\ndistrict in another school district in this state or in any adjoining\nstate, instead of maintaining a home school.\n  b. To contract for the education of part of the elementary pupils of\nsuch district in another school district in this state or in an\nadjoining state and maintain a home school;\n  c. To contract for a period of not less than two and not more than\nfive years for the education of all the high school pupils of grades\nseven to twelve, inclusive, of such district in another school district\nin this state or in an adjoining state, instead of maintaining a home\nhigh school for such grades.\n  d. To contract for a period of not less than two and not more than\nfive years for the education of some of the pupils of grades seven to\ntwelve, inclusive, of such district in another school district in this\nstate or in an adjoining state provided that such district maintains a\nhome high school for such grades. Nothing herein shall require a\ndistrict to enter into a written contract for the education of its high\nschool pupils where the term is for a period of less than two years.\n  2. Such contract may be made with one or more school districts. The\ndesignation of the school districts with which such contracts may be\nmade shall be made pursuant to the commissioner's regulations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>