<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2102-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2102-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2102-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2102-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2102-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2102-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2102-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2102_A">
        <num>2102-A</num>
        <heading>Required training for school district officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2102-a. Required training for school district officers.  1. a. Every\ntrustee or voting member of a board of education of a school district or\na board of cooperative educational services, elected or appointed for a\nterm beginning on or after July first, two thousand five, shall, within\nthe first year of his or her term, complete a minimum of six hours of\ntraining on the financial oversight, accountability and fiduciary\nresponsibilities of a school board member.\n  b. In addition to the training required by paragraph a of this\nsubdivision, every trustee or voting member of a board of education of a\nschool district or a board of cooperative educational services, elected\nor appointed for a first term beginning on or after the first of July\nnext succeeding the effective date of this paragraph, shall, within the\nfirst year of his or her term, complete a training course to acquaint\nhim or her with the powers, functions and duties of boards of education,\nas well as the powers and duties of other governing and administrative\nauthorities affecting public education.\n  c. Upon demonstration of compliance, no trustee or member of a board\nof education or a board of cooperative educational services shall be\nrequired to repeat the training requirements provided for in paragraphs\na and b of this subdivision. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to\nrequire a member of a central high school district board or a member of\na board of cooperative educational services to complete such\nrequirements if such member has already completed such requirements as a\nmember of a board of a component school district. Nothing in this\nsection shall be deemed to require trustees or voting members of a board\nof education of a school district or a board of cooperative educational\nservices to complete the requirements of paragraph b of this subdivision\nif such trustee or member is seated or appointed on or before the\neffective date of the chapter of the laws of two thousand ten that\namended this subdivision.\n  2. The curriculum used for training on financial oversight,\naccountability and fiduciary responsibilities shall be approved by the\ncommissioner in consultation with the comptroller and the curriculum\nused for the general training shall be approved by the commissioner.\nThese curricula may be offered together as a single course or\nseparately. The training required by this section may be offered by\nproviders approved by the commissioner. In approving other providers for\nthese trainings, the commissioner shall consider the potential\nprovider's understanding of the educational environment, the roles of\ntrustees and boards of education and boards of cooperative educational\nservices, and the experience of the provider in delivering such\ntraining.\n  3. Each trustee or member shall demonstrate compliance with these\nrequirements by filing with the district clerk a certificate of\ncompletion of such course or courses issued by the provider. Actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred by a trustee or member in complying with the\nforegoing requirements shall be a charge against the school district.\n  4. As long as the chancellor of a school district in a city having a\npopulation of one million or more inhabitants shall annually certify to\nthe commissioner that such district has a training program that meets or\nexceeds the requirements of this section, the provisions of this section\nshall not apply to such school district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>