<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="212-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_212_B">
        <num>212-B</num>
        <heading>Return of tuition for colleges, universities, professional, proprietary and graduate schools</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 212-b. Return of tuition for colleges, universities, professional,\nproprietary and graduate schools. Any person who pays tuition to a\ncollege, university, professional, proprietary or graduate school and\nwho demands its refund in writing before the thirtieth day before the\ncommencement of the term for which the tuition was paid shall be\nentitled to one hundred percent reimbursement of such tuition within\nsixty days of receipt of such demand by the college, university,\nprofessional, proprietary or graduate school; provided, however, that no\ndeposit on tuition payable upon acceptance shall be governed by the\nprovisions of this section. The provisions of this section shall not\napply if a college, university, professional, proprietary or graduate\nschool enters into a nonrevokable contract for special or extraordinary\ninstructional services after receipt of tuition and in reliance of the\nprospective attendance of the person paying such tuition so long as such\nperson was given notice before paying tuition that such a contract would\nbe entered into.\n  A violator of the provisions of this section shall be liable for a\ncivil penalty not to exceed ten percent of the amount of tuition which\nwas not refunded as herein provided.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>