<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-08-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="212"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_212">
        <num>212</num>
        <heading>Fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 212. Fees. The department shall charge the following fees: 1. For\nthe issuance of a qualifying certificate for admission to a professional\nschool as required by or pursuant to law, five dollars.\n  2. For admission to a special examination in English authorized or\nrequired by or pursuant to law as a pre-requisite to admission to a\nprofessional school or to an examination for a license to engage in or\npractice a profession, ten dollars.\n  3. For other certifications or permits for which fees are not\notherwise provided, fees as fixed by regulations of the department.\n  4. For the issuance of a replacement license, ten dollars.\n  5. For the replacement of a biennial registration certificate which\nhas been lost or destroyed, or for the issuance of each registration\ncertificate for more than one office, five dollars.\n  6. For a detailed certification of licensure record at the request of\nan individual, ten dollars.\n  7. For services and expenses incurred by the department in conducting\nevaluations, processing complaints or performing other administrative\nfunctions related to the review of post-secondary distance education\nconducted by out-of-state institutions seeking approval to offer\ndistance education to students in New York state who do not participate\nin an interstate reciprocity agreement pursuant to section two hundred\nten-c of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>