<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-213"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-213"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="213"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_213">
        <num>213</num>
        <heading>Extension of educational facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 213.  Extension of educational facilities.  1. The regents may\nextend to the people at large increased educational opportunities and\nfacilities, stimulate interest therein, recommend methods, designate\nsuitable teachers and lecturers, conduct examinations and grant\ncredentials, and otherwise organize, aid and conduct such work.  And the\nregents, and with their approval the commissioner of education, may buy,\nsell, exchange and receive by will, or other gift, or on deposit, books,\npictures, statuary or other sculptured work, lantern slides, apparatus,\nmaps, globes, films, sound films, kinescopes, photographic recordings\nand any article or collections pertaining to or useful in and to any of\nthe departments, divisions, schools, institutions, associations or other\nagencies, or work, under their supervision, or control, or\nencouragement, and may lend or deposit any such articles in their\ncustody or control, when or where in their judgement compensating\neducational usefulness will result therefrom; and may also, from time to\ntime, enter into contracts desirable for carrying into effect the\nforegoing provisions.\n  2.  In carrying out the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nthe regents may:  a.  Contract with institutions in the university,\nschool districts, boards of cooperative educational services or other\nnon-profit educational agencies for the acquisition from such\ninstitutions, school districts, boards or agencies of sound films,\nkinescopes, audio recordings and video recordings, scripts, research\nreports or related educational television materials, for the use of the\ndepartment, or for the production of educational television programs:\n  b.  Lease, to school districts, boards of cooperative educational\nservices or television corporations created pursuant to section two\nhundred thirty-six of this chapter, educational television facilities,\nincluding transmitters, micro-wave relay facilities, production centers,\nclosed-circuit systems and any equipment necessary therefor, constructed\nor acquired, and owned by the state, leased by the state, or contract\nwith such districts, boards of cooperative educational services or\ncorporations for the operation of such facilities:\n  c.  Lease and operate a television station in the city of New York.\n  3.  For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of subdivision two\nof this section, the regents may make rules or authorize the\ncommissioner to make regulations providing standards for research and\nexperimentation, operation and programming of educational television by\nthe state and the school districts, boards of cooperative educational\nservices, institutions, corporations and agencies, respectively.\n  4.  In carrying out the provisions of subdivisions one and two of this\nsection and in order to encourage and stimulate the further development\nand use of educational television in the state of New York and for the\npurposes of providing educational services and facilities for pupils in\nthe public schools of the state of New York, the board of regents is\nhereby authorized to make additional apportionments to school districts\nor boards of cooperative educational services in accordance with the\nprovisions of this subdivision to encourage and assist such districts or\nboards to install and operate a broadcast or closed-circuit television\nsystem, or television receiving equipment for the improvement of\nclassroom instruction.\n  a.  Any school district or board of cooperative educational services\nplanning to establish such a program shall submit to the commissioner of\neducation on or before the first day of May of the school year preceding\nthe school year during which the program is to be conducted an\napplication, together with such information as the commissioner of\neducation shall require, including at least a complete statement of\npurposes of the program, the detailed procedures of operation, a\ndetailed estimate of the cost of such program and a complete description\nof the installation and equipment to be installed and the detailed\nprocedures of evaluations to be used in determining the improvement of\nclassroom instruction.\n  b.  The commissioner of education shall establish procedures for\nevaluations of such programs.  One such program for each school district\nor board of cooperative educational services may be approved by the\ncommissioner of education, and any program so approved by the\ncommissioner of education shall be placed on a list in accordance with\nthe educational merit and value of the program, and the date of receipt\nof the application, where several programs are evaluated as having equal\nmerit and value.\n  c.  Apportionment shall then be made in accordance with the formula\ncontained in paragraph d of this subdivision, in the order of such\nprograms on the list established in accordance with paragraph b of this\nsubdivision within the amount of the appropriation therefor.\n  d.  Any district or board which proposes to install and operate a\nbroadcast or closed-circuit television system or television receiving\nequipment for the improvement of classroom instruction, in accordance\nwith a program approved as provided in this subdivision and to the\nextent that funds are available pursuant to this subdivision, shall be\nentitled to an apportionment during the five-year period following the\napproval of the program as follows:\n  Fifty per cent of the approved cost relative to the acquisition and\ninstallation of the equipment, and during the first year fifty per cent\nof the approved operational expenses in connection with the approved\noperation of the program; during the second year forty per cent of the\napproved operational expenses in connection with the approved operation\nof the program; during the third year thirty per cent of the approved\noperational expenses in connection with the approved operation of the\nprogram; during the fourth year twenty per cent of the approved\noperational expenses in connection with the approved operation of the\nprogram; and during the fifth year ten per cent of the approved\noperational expenses in connection with the approved operation of the\nprogram.\n  5.  A school district or a board of cooperative educational services\nis hereby authorized and empowered to do and perform any and all acts\nnecessary or convenient to enable it to carry out the provisions of this\nsection.\n  6.  The regents are authorized to make grants of money, materials and\nequipment for the purpose of promoting the erection and use of\neducational television facilities by educational television corporations\nestablished pursuant to the provisions of section two hundred thirty-six\nof this chapter.  Such grants may be made upon such terms and conditions\nas the regents may prescribe.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>