<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2143"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2143"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2143"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2143/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2143/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2143/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2143/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2143">
        <num>2143</num>
        <heading>County clerks and county treasurers to forward certain reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2143. County clerks and county treasurers to forward certain\nreports.  1. The county clerk of each county shall, upon the requisition\nof the commissioner of education, file with such commissioner any\nreports of trustees of school districts and boards of education or the\nabstract of such reports made by district superintendents which have\nbeen filed in the office of such county clerk pursuant to the provisions\nof this chapter, whenever it is necessary for the commissioner of\neducation to obtain information or data contained in official reports\nwhich have been transmitted to the education department but which have\nbeen destroyed by fire or otherwise.\n  2. The county treasurer of each county shall, upon the requisition of\nthe commissioner of education, forward to said commissioner any original\ncertificates relating to the apportionment of school moneys which the\ncommissioner of education has filed in the office of such treasurer,\nwhenever it is necessary to obtain information on the apportionment of\nschool moneys when the data relating thereto in the office of the\ncommissioner of education have been destroyed by fire or otherwise.\nAfter securing such information as may be necessary from such\ncertificates, the commissioner of education shall return the same to the\ntreasurer of such county.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>