<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-226"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-226"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="226"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_226">
        <num>226</num>
        <heading>Powers of trustees of institutions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 226. Powers of trustees of institutions. The trustees of every\ncorporation created by the regents, unless otherwise provided by law or\nby its charter, may:\n  1. Number and quorum. Fix the term of office and number of trustees,\nwhich shall not exceed twenty-five, nor be less than five. If any\ninstitution has more than five trustees, the body that elects, by a\ntwo-thirds vote after notice of the proposed action in the call for a\nmeeting, may reduce the number to not less than five by abolishing the\noffice of any trustee which is vacant and filing in the regents' office\na certified copy of the action. A majority of the whole number shall be\na quorum.\n  2. Executive committee. Elect an executive committee of not less than\nfive, who, in intervals between meetings of the trustees, may transact\nsuch business of the corporation as the trustees may authorize, except\nto grant degrees or to make removals from office.\n  3. Meetings and seniority. Meet on their own adjournment or when\nrequired by their by-laws, and as often as they shall be summoned by\ntheir chairman, or in his absense by the senior trustee, on written\nrequest of three trustees. Seniority shall be according to the order in\nwhich the trustees are named in the charter or subsequently elected.\nNotice of the time and place of every meeting shall be mailed not less\nthan five nor more than ten days before the meeting to the usual address\nof every trustee.\n  4. Vacancies and elections; removals by board of regents. Fill any\nvacancy occurring in the office of any trustee by electing another for\nthe unexpired term; provided, however, that where trustees are elected\nby the legal voters the person so appointed to fill any such vacancy\nshall hold office until the next annual election of trustees. The office\nof any trustee shall become vacant on his death, resignation, refusal to\nact, removal from office, expiration of his term, or any other cause\nspecified in the charter. If any trustee shall fail to attend three\nconsecutive meetings without excuse accepted as satisfactory by the\ntrustees, he shall be deemed to have resigned, and the vacancy shall be\nfilled. Any vacancy in the office of trustee continuing for more than\none year, or any vacancy reducing the number of trustees to less than\ntwo-thirds of the full number may be filled by the regents. The regents\nmay remove any trustee of a corporation created by them for misconduct,\nincapacity, neglect of duty, or where it appears to the satisfaction of\nthe regents that the corporation has failed or refuses to carry into\neffect its educational purposes. A hearing in the proceeding for the\nremoval of such trustees shall be had before the board of regents or a\ncommittee thereof and the trustees shall be given at least ten days'\nnotice of the time and place of such hearing. In case of removal the\nregents may appoint successors to the trustees so removed. The\nprovisions of this section as to removal and filling of vacancies in\ntrustees shall not apply to corporations now or hereafter established\nand maintained by a religious denomination, order or sect. No person\nshall be ineligible as a trustee by reason of sex.\n  5. Property holding. Take and hold by gift, grant, devise or bequest\nin their own right or in trust for any purpose comprised in the objects\nof the corporation, such additional real and personal property, beyond\nsuch as shall be authorized by their charter or by special or general\nstatute, as the regents shall authorize within one year after the\ndelivery of the instrument or probate of the will, giving, granting,\ndevising or bequeathing such property, and such authority given by the\nregents shall make any such gift, grant, devise or bequest operative and\nvalid in law. Any grant, devise or bequest shall be equally valid\nwhether made in the corporate name or to the trustees of a corporation,\nand powers given to the trustees shall be powers of the corporation.\n  6. Control of property. a. Buy, sell, mortgage, let and otherwise use\nand dispose of its property as they shall deem for the best interests of\nthe institution; and also to lend or deposit, or to receive as a gift,\nor on loan or deposit, literary, scientific or other articles,\ncollections, or property pertaining to their work; and such gifts, loans\nor deposits may be made to or with the university or any of its\ninstitutions by any person, or by legal vote of any board of trustees,\ncorporation, association or school district, and any such transfer of\nproperty, if approved by the regents, shall during its continuance,\ntransfer responsibility therefor to the institution receiving it, which\nshall also be entitled to receive any money, books or other property\nfrom the state or other sources to which said corporation, association\nor district would have been entitled but for such transfer.\n  b. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, prior to the discarding\nof used or surplus books or other such reading materials by trustees of\na chartered public or free association library which receives over ten\nthousand dollars in state aid, such trustees shall offer to donate such\nbooks or materials to a not-for-profit corporation or political\nsubdivision located within the area of the library system or offer to\nsell such books or materials to the general public. The trustees shall\nretain any proceeds received from the sale of such books and materials\nfor the purpose of maintaining and improving library service within the\nsystem.\n  7. Officers and employees. Appoint and fix the salaries of such\nofficers and employees as they shall deem necessary who, unless employed\nunder special contract, shall hold their offices during the pleasure of\nthe trustees; but no trustee shall receive compensation as such. The\npresident or chief executive officer of an association library\ncorporation shall be elected by the trustees from their own number and\nshall be the chairman of the board.\n  8. Removals and suspensions. Remove or suspend from office by vote of\na majority of the entire board any trustee, officer or employee engaged\nunder special contract, on examination and due proof of the truth of a\nwritten complaint by any trustee, of misconduct, incapacity or neglect\nof duty; provided, that at least one week's previous notice of the\nproposed action shall have been given to the accused and to each\ntrustee.\n  9. Degrees and credentials. Grant such degrees and honors as are\nspecifically authorized by their charter, and in testimony thereof give\nsuitable certificates and diplomas under their seal; and every\ncertificate and diploma so granted shall entitle the conferee to all\nprivileges and immunities which by usage or statute are allowed for\nsimilar diplomas of corresponding grade granted by any institution of\nlearning.\n  10. Rules. Make all by-laws and rules necessary and proper for the\npurposes of the institution and not inconsistent with law or any rule of\nthe university; but no rule by which more than a majority vote shall be\nrequired for any specified action by the trustees shall be amended,\nsuspended or repealed by a smaller vote than that required for action\nthereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>