<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-228"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-228"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="228"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-228/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-228/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-228/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-228/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_228">
        <num>228</num>
        <heading>The Hamilton college sewer district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 228. The Hamilton college sewer district. The Hamilton college sewer\ndistrict established in the town of Kirkland, Oneida county, outside the\nvillage of Clinton, is hereby continued and all the provisions of the\ntown law relating to a sewer district in a town shall apply to such\ndistrict, except as herein otherwise provided: The district shall be\ngoverned by a board of sewer district commissioners consisting of three\npersons, who shall serve until a vacancy shall occur by reason of death,\nresignation or removal from office. The town board of the town of\nKirkland may remove a member of the board for inefficiency, neglect of\nduty or misconduct in office after a public hearing on not less than ten\ndays' written notice and an opportunity to be heard in person or by\ncounsel. A vacancy in office of a commissioner shall be filled by\nappointment by the town board from a list of nominations of not less\nthan three persons made by the remaining commissioners. Each\ncommissioner appointed by the town board must be a resident taxpayer of\nthe sewer district or in lieu thereof an officer, trustee or member of\nthe faculty of Hamilton college. Such commissioners shall select one of\ntheir number as chairman and another as secretary. Each commissioner,\nbefore entering upon the duties of his office, shall take the\nconstitutional oath of office and execute to the town of Kirkland and\nfile with the town clerk an official undertaking in such sum and with\nsuch sureties as the town board from time to time may direct. Such\ncommissioners may be paid for their services an annual amount, as\ndetermined by the town board, up to two thousand dollars. Such\ncompensation shall be deemed an expense of the district. The board of\nsewer district commissioners of such district shall have all the powers\nand be subject to the duties and responsibilities of district\ncommissioners elected pursuant to the provisions of article thirteen of\nthe town law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>