<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-229"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-229"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="229"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-229/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-229/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-229/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-229/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_229">
        <num>229</num>
        <heading>County educational institutions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 229. County educational institutions.  The board of supervisors of a\ncounty, having a population of over five hundred thousand and adjacent\nto a city having a population of over two million, may determine, by\nresolution, to make application to the regents for the incorporation,\npursuant to the provisions of part one of this article of one or more of\nthe institutions enumerated in section two hundred sixteen of this\nchapter.  The regents may, by an instrument under their seal and\nrecorded in their office, incorporate any such institution or\ninstitutions under such name with such number of trustees or other\nmanagers, and with such powers, privileges and duties, and subject to\nsuch limitations and restrictions in all respects as the regents may\nprescribe in conformity to law.  The cost and expenses necessary to\nestablish, maintain and support such institution or institutions\npursuant to the provisions of part one of this article, including the\nacquisition of real property, and the construction and equipment of\nbuildings and grounds, shall be a county charge and the board of\nsupervisors shall provide for the payment of such cost and expenses by\nthe levy, assessment and collection of taxes in the same manner that\ntaxes are levied, assessed and collected for other county purposes.  The\nprovisions of part one of this article shall apply to such institution\nor institutions, except the provision of section two hundred eighteen of\nthis chapter, requiring resources of at least five hundred thousand\ndollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>