<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="239-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_239_A">
        <num>239-A</num>
        <heading>Collection and distribution of student's residual consumer goods</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 239-a. Collection and distribution of student's residual consumer\ngoods. 1. For purposes of this section, the following terms shall have\nthe following meanings:\n  a. "consumer goods" shall mean goods that are used or bought for use\nprimarily for personal, family or household purposes including, but not\nlimited to, home furnishings, canned and non-perishable foods,\nfactory-sealed and/or originally-packaged toiletries, clothing,\ncookware, and electronics.\n  b. "university" and "college" shall have the same meaning as set forth\nin section two of this title.\n  c. "city university" shall have the same meaning as set forth in\nsection sixty-two hundred two of this chapter.\n  2. The administration of the individual state and city universities\nand colleges and every public or private college, community college or\nuniversity within the state, are hereby authorized to facilitate a\ncampus-wide charitable donation program for local area not-for-profit\norganizations utilizing students' residual consumer goods. The\nadministration:\n  a. shall designate a collection area for students to drop-off their\nunused or surplus goods two weeks before the end of the school year;\n  b. shall either develop a direct donation program of the residual\nconsumer goods or organize a charitable event to collect residual\nconsumer goods and donate such goods to local not-for-profit\norganizations; and\n  c. may involve student organizations for the implementation of the\nprogram.\n  3. The consumer goods collected:\n  a. shall be from those college students residing in campus-related\nresidential facilities;\n  b. shall be consumer goods that would be discarded at the end of the\nschool year by college students;\n  c. shall be in useable and good working condition.\n  4. In the event that there is no viable local not-for-profit\norganization able to accept the residential consumer goods collected,\nthe administration of the individual state or city university or college\nor public or private college, community college or university within the\nstate may organize a campus-wide sale of such goods. The profits of such\nsale may be dedicated by the student organizations or by the individual\nstate or city university or college or public or private college,\ncommunity college or university facilitating the program to a local\nnot-for-profit organization.\n  5. The administration of any individual state or city university or\ncollege or public or private college, community college or university\nmay grant credit to student members of organizations involved with the\nprogram, pursuant to subdivision two of this section, in the amount and\nform that such administration deems appropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>