<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2503"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2503">
        <num>2503</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of board of education</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2503__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such transportation was\nprovided during the preceding school year and the qualified voters have\nnot passed a special proposition constricting the mileage limitations\nfor the current school year from those in effect in the prior year, or\n(ii) the qualified voters have passed a special proposition expanding\nthe mileage limitations in effect in the prior year.\n  12-a. May lease a motor vehicle or vehicles for the transportation of\nchildren of the district under the same terms and conditions as the\nboard of education of a union free school district.\n  13. Shall provide, outside the territorial limits of the city school\ndistrict but within the state, for the education of children resident\nwithin the city school district whenever in the judgment of the board of\neducation, approved by the commissioner of education, the health or\nwelfare of such children makes such provision necessary or desirable.\nThe average daily attendance of such pupils shall be included in the\naverage daily attendance of such district as certified to the\ncommissioner in the report of the board of education\n  14.  Shall call special district meetings of the qualified voters of\nthe district, whenever it shall deem it necessary and proper, except as\notherwise provided in section twenty-six hundred one-a of this chapter;\nshall give notice of special or annual elections; and shall submit\npropositions to the voters at such special or annual meetings.\n  15. Shall appoint and compensate a school district clerk, who shall\nalso be the clerk of the board of education, and a school district\ntreasurer, who shall hold their respective offices during the pleasure\nof the board. It shall be the duty of the school district treasurer to\nmaintain detailed accounting records showing the status of each\nappropriation, provided however that the board of education may delegate\nsuch duty to an employee designated for such purpose. No city officer\nshall be appointed to any such office, unless the co...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2503__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirty\nof section three hundred five of this chapter and shall obtain the\napplicant's consent to the criminal history records search. Every set of\nfingerprints taken pursuant to this subdivision shall be promptly\nsubmitted to the commissioner for purposes of clearance for employment.\n  b. Upon the recommendation of the superintendent, the board may\nconditionally appoint a prospective employee. A request for conditional\nclearance shall be forwarded to the commissioner along with the\nprospective employee's fingerprints, as required by paragraph a of this\nsubdivision. Such appointment shall not commence until notification by\nthe commissioner that the prospective employee has been conditionally\ncleared for employment and shall terminate forty-five days after such\nnotification of conditional clearance or when the prospective employer\nis notified of a determination by the commissioner to grant or deny\nclearance, whichever occurs earlier, and may not be extended or renewed\nunless the commissioner issues a new conditional clearance after finding\nthat there was good cause for failing to obtain clearance within such\nperiod, provided that if clearance is granted, the appointment shall\ncontinue and the conditional status shall be removed. Prior to\ncommencement of such conditional appointment, the prospective employer\nshall obtain a signed statement for conditional appointment from the\nprospective employee, indicating whether, to the best of his or her\nknowledge, he or she has a pending criminal charge or criminal\nconviction in any jurisdiction outside the state.\n  c. Upon the recommendation of the superintendent, the board may make\nan emergency conditional appointment when an unforeseen emergency\nvacancy has occurred. When such appointment is made, the process for\nconditional appointment pursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision must\nalso be initiated. Emergency conditional appointment may commence prior\nto notification from the com...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2503__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a vacancy that\noccurred less than ten business days before the start of any school\nsession, including summer school, or during any school session,\nincluding summer school, without sufficient notice to allow for\nclearance or conditional clearance; (ii) when no other qualified person\nis available to fill the vacancy temporarily; and (iii) when emergency\nconditional appointment is necessary to maintain services which the\ndistrict is legally required to provide or services necessary to protect\nthe health, education or safety of students or staff. The provisions of\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2503__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall not apply if the board finds\nthat the district has been unable to fill the vacancy despite good faith\nefforts to fill such vacancy in a manner which would have allowed\nsufficient time for clearance or conditional clearance.\n  d. Shall develop a policy for the safety of the children who have\ncontact with an employee holding conditional appointment or emergency\nconditional appointment.\n  19. Shall upon commencement and termination of employment of an\nemployee by the school district, provide the commissioner with the name\nof and position held by such employee.\n  20. Where the district has provided transportation to students\nenrolled in such district to a school sponsored field trip,\nextracurricular activity or any other similar event, it shall provide\ntransportation back to either the point of departure or to the\nappropriate school in the district, unless the parent or legal guardian\nof a student participating in such event has provided the school\ndistrict with written notice, consistent with district policy,\nauthorizing an alternative form of return transportation for such\nstudent or unless intervening circumstances make such transportation\nimpractical. In cases where intervening circumstances make\ntransportation of a student back to the point of departure or to the\nappropriate school in the district impractical, a representative of the\nschool district shall remain with the student until such student's\nparent or legal guardian has been</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2503__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contacted and informed of the\nintervening circumstances which make such transportation impractical and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2503__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such student had been delivered to his or her parent or legal\nguardian.\n  * 21. To pass a resolution, in the discretion of the board of such\ndistrict, authorizing the entering of an agreement with the city within\nsuch district, for the installation and use of school bus photo\nviolation monitoring systems pursuant to section eleven hundred\nseventy-four-a of the vehicle and traffic law, provided that the\npurchase, lease, installation, operation and maintenance, or any other\ncosts associated with such cameras shall not be considered an aidable\nexpense pursuant to section thirty-six hundred twenty-three-a of this\nchapter.\n  * NB Repealed December 1, 2029\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>