<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2508"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2508"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2508"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2508">
        <num>2508</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of superintendent of schools</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2508.  Powers and duties of superintendent of schools. The\nsuperintendent of schools of a city school district shall possess,\nsubject to the bylaws of the board of education, the following powers\nand be charged with the following duties:\n  1. To be the chief executive officer of the school district and the\neducational system, and to have a seat on the board of education and the\nright to speak on all matters before the board, but not to vote.\n  2. To enforce all provisions of law and all rules and regulations\nrelating to the management of the schools and other educational, social\nand recreational activities under the direction of the board of\neducation.\n  3. To prepare the content of each course of study authorized by the\nboard of education. The content of each such course shall be submitted\nto the board of education for its approval and, when thus approved, the\nsuperintendent shall cause such courses of study to be used in the\ngrades, classes and schools for which they are authorized.\n  4. To recommend suitable lists of textbooks to be used in the schools.\n  5. To have supervision and direction of associate, assistant and other\nsuperintendents, directors, supervisors, principals, teachers,\nlecturers, medical inspectors, nurses, claims auditors, deputy claims\nauditors, attendance officers, janitors and other persons employed in\nthe management of the schools or the other educational activities of the\ndistrict authorized by this chapter and under the direction and\nmanagement of the board of education; to transfer teachers from one\nschool to another, or from one grade of the course of study to another\ngrade in such course, and to report immediately such transfers to such\nboard for its consideration and action; to report to such board\nviolations of regulations and cases of insubordination, and to suspend\nan associate, assistant or other superintendent, director, supervisor,\nexpert, principal, teacher or other employee until the next regular\nmeeting of such board, when all facts relating to the case shall be\nsubmitted to such board for its consideration and action.\n  6. To have supervision and direction over the enforcement and\nobservance of the courses of study, the examination and promotion of\npupils, and over all other matters pertaining to playgrounds, medical\ninspection, recreation and social center work, libraries, lectures, and\nall other educational activities under the management, direction and\ncontrol of the board of education.\n  7. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, the provisions\nof subdivision five of this section relating to the transfer of teachers\nmay be modified by an agreement that is collectively negotiated pursuant\nto the provisions of article fourteen of the civil service law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>