<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2509"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2509"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2509"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2509">
        <num>2509</num>
        <heading>Appointment of assistant and other superintendents, teachers and other employees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2509__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>i. Teachers and all other members of the\nteaching staff appointed prior to July first, two thousand fifteen and\nauthorized by section twenty-five hundred three of this article, shall\nbe appointed by the board of education, upon the recommendation of the\nsuperintendent of schools, for a probationary period of three years,\nexcept that in the case of a teacher who has rendered satisfactory\nservice as a regular substitute for a period of two years or as a\nseasonally licensed per session teacher of swimming in day schools who\nhas served in that capacity for a period of two years and has been\nappointed to teach the same subject in day schools on an annual salary,\nthe probationary period shall be limited to one year; provided, however,\nthat in the case of a teacher who has been appointed on tenure in\nanother school district within the state, the school district where\ncurrently employed, or a board of cooperative educational services, and\nwho was not dismissed from such district or board as a result of charges\nbrought pursuant to subdivision one of section three thousand twenty-a\nof this chapter, the probationary period shall not exceed two years. The\nservice of a person appointed to any of such positions may be\ndiscontinued at any time during such probationary period, on the\nrecommendation of the superintendent of schools, by a majority vote of\nthe board of education. Each person who is not to be recommended for\nappointment on tenure shall be so notified by the superintendent of\nschools in writing not later than sixty days immediately preceding the\nexpiration of his probationary period.\n  ii. Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation to the\ncontrary, teachers and all other members of the teaching staff appointed\non or after July first, two thousand fifteen and authorized by section\ntwenty-five hundred three of this article, shall be appointed by the\nboard of education, upon the recommendation of the superintendent of\nschools, for...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2509__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>i. Administrators, directors, supervisors, principals and all\nother members of the supervising staff, except associate, assistant and\nother superintendents appointed prior to July first, two thousand\nfifteen and authorized by section twenty-five hundred three of this\narticle, shall be appointed by the board of education, upon the\nrecommendation of the superintendent of schools for a probationary\nperiod of three years. The service of a person appointed to any of such\npositions may be discontinued at any time during the probationary period\non the recommendation of the superintendent of schools, by a majority\nvote of the board of education.\n  ii. Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation to the\ncontrary, administrators, directors, supervisors, principals and all\nother members of the supervising staff, except associate, assistant and\nother superintendents, appointed on or after July first, two thousand\nfifteen and authorized by section twenty-five hundred three of this\narticle, shall be appointed by the board of education, upon the\nrecommendation of the superintendent of schools for a probationary\nperiod of four years; provided, however, that in the case of a\nprincipal, administrator, supervisor, or other member of the supervising\nstaff who has been appointed on tenure pursuant to this chapter as an\nadministrator within an authorized administrative tenure area in another\nschool district within the state, the school district where currently\nemployed, or a board of cooperative educational services, and who was\nnot dismissed from such district or board as a result of charges brought\npursuant to subdivision one of section three thousand twenty-a or\nsection three thousand twenty-b of this chapter, the principal,\nadministrator, supervisor or other member of the supervising staff shall\nbe appointed for a probationary period of three years. The service of a\nperson appointed to any of such positions may be discontinued at any\ntime duri...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>