<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2554"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2554">
        <num>2554</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of board of education</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to facilitate operation of the school lunch programs\nadministered by the board of education of the city of New York, better\nto serve the public interest, all persons employed in a cafeteria or\nlunchroom in any high school under the jurisdiction of this board for\none year prior to the date this section takes effect, shall, because of\ntheir special training, experience and efficiency, and, notwithstanding\nany provisions to the contrary in any general, special or local law, be\ncontinued in the employment of this board without competitive\nexamination, provided the necessary funds for such continued employment\nare appropriated by the board. The positions so held by such employees\nshall be in the noncompetitive class. The New York city civil service\ncommission, however, after notice to any such employee of the reasons\ntherefore, and after according such employee a hearing, may exclude him\nfrom further employment if found by the commission not to be a person of\nsatisfactorily good character. Not later than one year after this\nsection shall take effect, the commission shall determine for which of\nsuch positions competitive examinations shall have become feasible, and\nshall thereupon reclassify the various positions, with the approval of\nthe mayor and the state civil service commission. The then incumbents of\nsuch positions shall continue to hold their positions without further\nexamination, provided, however, that all subsequent appointments to such\npositions shall be made in accordance with the civil service law and\nrules.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2002 and revived on June 30, 2026\n  16. To compensate, in its discretion, teachers and other employees for\nloss of personal property but shall provide workmen's compensation\ncoverage as provided in the workmen's compensation law for all teachers\nand other employees for injuries incurred in actual performance of duty\nand with respect to teachers and other employees for whom such workmen's\ncompen...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>identified as having fifteen\npercent or more of their students in special education, or (ii) which\nhave fifty percent or more of their students with disabilities in\nspecial education programs or services sixty percent or more of the\nschool day in a general education building, or (iii) which have eight\npercent or more of their students with disabilities in special education\nprograms in public or private separate educational settings shall\nindicate on their school district report card their respective\npercentages as defined in this paragraph and paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of\nthis subdivision as compared to the statewide average.\n  * NB Effective until June 30, 2026\n  * 24. In every city school district in a city having a population of\nless than one million inhabitants, each year, the board of education\nshall prepare a school district report card, pursuant to regulations of\nthe commissioner, and shall make it publicly available by transmitting\nit to local newspapers of general circulation, appending it to copies of\nthe proposed budget made publicly available as required by law, making\nit available for distribution at the annual meeting, and otherwise\ndisseminating it as required by the commissioner. Such report card shall\ninclude measures of the academic performances of the school district, on\na school by school basis, and measures of the fiscal performance of the\ndistrict, as prescribed by the commissioner. Pursuant to regulations of\nthe commissioner the report card shall also compare these measures to\nstatewide averages for all public schools, and statewide averages for\npublic schools of comparable wealth and need, developed by the\ncommissioner. Such report card shall include, at a minimum, any\ninformation on the school district regarding pupil performance and\nexpenditure per pupil required to be included in the annual report by\nthe regents to the governor and the legislature pursuant to section two\nhundred fifteen-a of this chapter; and any other information required by\nthe commissioner. School districts</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>identified as having fifteen\npercent or more of their students in special education, or (ii) which\nhave fifty percent or more of their students with disabilities in\nspecial education programs or services sixty percent or more of the\nschool day in a general education building, or (iii) which have eight\npercent or more of their students with disabilities in special education\nprograms in public or private separate educational settings shall\nindicate on their school district report card their respective\npercentages as defined in this paragraph and paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of\nthis subdivision as compared to the statewide average.\n  * NB Effective June 30, 2026\n  25. a. Shall require, for purposes of a criminal history record check,\nthe fingerprinting of all prospective employees pursuant to section\nthree thousand thirty-five of this chapter, who do not hold valid\nclearance pursuant to such section or pursuant to section three thousand\nfour-b of this chapter or section five hundred nine-cc or twelve hundred\ntwenty-nine-d of the vehicle and traffic law. Prior to initiating the\nfingerprinting process, the prospective employer shall furnish the\napplicant with the form described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirty\nof section three hundred five of this chapter and shall obtain the\napplicant's consent to the criminal history records search. Every set of\nfingerprints taken pursuant to this subdivision shall be promptly\nsubmitted to the commissioner for purposes of clearance for employment.\n  b. Upon the recommendation of the superintendent, the board may\nconditionally appoint a prospective employee. A request for conditional\nclearance shall be forwarded to the commissioner along with the\nprospective employee's fingerprints, as required by paragraph a of this\nsubdivision. Such appointment shall not commence until notification by\nthe commissioner that the prospective employee has been conditionally\ncleared for employment and shall terminate forty-five days after such\nnotification of conditional clearance or when the prospective employer\nis notified of a determination by the commissioner to grant or deny\nclearance, whichever occurs earlier, and may not be extended or renewed\nunless the commissioner issues a new conditional clearance after finding\nthat there was good cause for failing to obtain clearance within such\nperiod, provided that if clearance is granted, the appointment shall\ncontinue and the conditional status shall be removed. Prior to\ncommencement of such conditional appointment, the prospective employer\nshall obtain a signed statement for conditional appointment from the\nprospective employee, indicating whether, to the best of his or her\nknowledge, he or she has a pending criminal charge or criminal\nconviction in any jurisdiction outside the state.\n  c. Upon the recommendation of the superintendent, the board may make\nan emergency conditional appointment when an unforeseen emergency\nvacancy has occurred. When such appointment is made, the process for\nconditional appointment pursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision must\nalso be initiated. Emergency conditional appointment may commence prior\nto notification from the com...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a vacancy that\noccurred less than ten business days before the start of any school\nsession, including summer school, or during any school session,\nincluding summer school, without sufficient notice to allow for\nclearance or conditional clearance; (ii) when no other qualified person\nis available to fill the vacancy temporarily; and (iii) when emergency\nconditional appointment is necessary to maintain services which the\ndistrict is legally required to provide or services necessary to protect\nthe health, education or safety of students or staff. The provisions of\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall not apply if the board finds\nthat the district has been unable to fill the vacancy despite good faith\nefforts to fill such vacancy in a manner which would have allowed\nsufficient time for clearance or conditional clearance.\n  d. Shall develop a policy for the safety of the children who have\ncontact with an employee holding conditional appointment or emergency\nconditional appointment.\n  * NB Effective until June 30, 2026\n  * 25. Shall require, for purposes of a criminal history record check,\nexcept in the city school district of the city of New York, the\nfingerprinting of all prospective employees pursuant to section three\nthousand thirty-five of this chapter, who do not hold valid clearance\npursuant to such section or pursuant to section three thousand four-b of\nthis chapter or section five hundred nine-cc or twelve hundred\ntwenty-nine-d of the vehicle and traffic law. Prior to initiating the\nfingerprinting process, the prospective employer shall furnish the\napplicant with the form described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirty\nof section three hundred five of this chapter and shall obtain the\napplicant's consent to the criminal history records search. Every set of\nfingerprints taken pursuant to this subdivision shall be promptly\nsubmitted to the commissioner for purposes of clearance for employment.\n  * NB Effective June 30, 2026\n  * 26. Shall, upon commencement and termination of employment of an\nemployee by the city school district, provide the commissioner with the\nname of and position held by such employee.\n  * NB Effective until June 30, 2026\n  * 26. Shall, except in the city school district of the city of New\nYork, upon commencement and termination of employment of an employee by\nthe city school district, provide the commissioner with the name of and\nposition held by such employee.\n  * NB Effective June 30, 2026\n  27. Where the district has provided transportation to students\nenrolled in such district to a school sponsored field trip,\nextracurricular activity or any other similar event, it shall provide\ntransportation back to either the point of departure or to the\nappropriate school in the district, unless the parent or legal guardian\nof a student participating in such event has provided the school\ndistrict with written notice, consistent with district policy,\nauthorizing an alternative form of return transportation for such\nstudent or unless intervening circumstances make such transportation\nimpractical. In cases where intervening circumstances make\ntransportation of a student back to the point of departure or to the\nappropriate school in the district impractical, a representative of the\nschool district shall remain with the student until such student's\nparent or legal guardian has been</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contacted and informed of the\nintervening circumstances which make such transportation impractical and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2554__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such student had been delivered to his or her parent or legal\nguardian.\n  * 28. To pass a resolution, in the discretion of the board of such\ndistrict, authorizing the entering of an agreement with the city within\nsuch district, for the installation and use of school bus photo\nviolation monitoring systems pursuant to section eleven hundred\nseventy-four-a of the vehicle and traffic law, provided that the\npurchase, lease, installation, operation and maintenance, or any other\ncosts associated with such cameras shall not be considered an aidable\nexpense pursuant to section thirty-six hundred twenty-three-a of this\nchapter.\n  * NB Repealed December 1, 2029\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>