<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2554-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2554_B">
        <num>2554-B</num>
        <heading>Special provisions relating to the city school district of the city of New York during emergency period</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2554-b. Special provisions relating to the city school district of\nthe city of New York during emergency period. 1. As used in this\nsection, the term "emergency period" shall mean the period from the\neffective date of this section to the first day of July, nineteen\nhundred sixty-two.\n  2. In order to place the educational affairs of the city school\ndistrict of the city of New York under the closer supervision of the\nregents and the commissioner during the emergency period, the board of\neducation of such district shall submit to the regents and the\ncommissioner and to the mayor of the city of New York on the first day\nof January and April, nineteen hundred sixty-two, an interim progress\nreport in such form and detail as the commissioner shall prescribe and\non the first day of July, nineteen hundred sixty-two, a final report in\nsuch form and detail as the commissioner shall prescribe as to:\n  a. the corrective action taken in the emergency period and planned by\nthe board of education with respect to the administration of the program\nfor new school building construction;\n  b. the corrective action taken in the emergency period and planned by\nthe board of education with respect to the repair and maintenance of\nexisting school buildings and other structures under the control of the\nschool district;\n  c. the disciplinary action taken in the emergency period with respect\nto employees guilty of accepting gratuities in relation to the\nperformance of their duties, and the corrective action taken by the\nboard of education to prevent recurrences of such misconduct;\n  d. the corrective action taken in the emergency period and planned by\nthe board of education with respect to administrative reform and the\ndevelopment of a program for the division of responsibility between the\nboard and the superintendent of schools and the administrative staff for\nthe more efficient and effective management of the district;\n  e. the plans developed and action taken in the emergency period by the\nboard of education for the revitalization of local school boards and for\nincreased participation of residents throughout the city of New York in\nthe affairs of their local neighborhood schools;\n  f. the plans developed and action taken in the emergency period by the\nboard of education to establish a long-range program and the necessary\nstaff organization for better informed and coordinated planning of new\nschool construction and the modernization of existing structures; and\n  g. the steps taken in the emergency period by the board of education\nto evaluate and to improve the quality of instruction in the schools.\n  3. During the emergency period, the board of education of the city\nschool district of the city of New York shall have, specifically, the\npower:\n  a. To undertake any studies, inquiries, surveys or analyses it may\ndeem relevant through the personnel of the district or in cooperation\nwith or by agreement with any other public or private agency;\n  b. To employ and at pleasure remove educational, engineering,\narchitectural, legal or management consultants and such other assistants\nas it may deem necessary for the performance of its functions and fix\ntheir compensation within the amounts made available by appropriation\ntherefor;\n  c. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of section\ntwenty-five hundred sixty-five of this chapter, to remove at its\npleasure by a vote of a majority of all its members, the superintendent,\nany deputy superintendent or any associate superintendent of schools of\nthe district irrespective of the date of their appointments, provided,\nhowever, that the board may enter into a contract with the\nsuperintendent of schools for a period of not less than three and not\nmore than five years; and\n  d. To authorize the superintendent of schools and the administrative\nstaff of the district by by-law, rule, regulation or resolution to\nexercise on its behalf such of its administrative and ministerial powers\nand duties with respect to the administration of the city school\ndistrict, the purchase, repair, remodeling, improvement or enlargement\nof school buildings or other buildings or sites and the construction of\nnew buildings as the board deems necessary or desirable for the more\nefficient administration of the district or for the more expeditious\ncompletion of school construction, maintenance or repairs, provided,\nhowever, that the board shall not authorize the superintendent of\nschools and the administrative staff to exercise any powers and duties\nrelating to its investigative or judicial functions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>