<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2556"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2556"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2556"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2556/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2556/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2556/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2556/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2556">
        <num>2556</num>
        <heading>Buildings, sites, et cetera</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding subdivision three-a of section four hundred\neight of this chapter, it shall be unlawful for a new schoolhouse to be\nconstructed in the city of New York within five hundred feet of a\ncontrolled-access highway unless</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the president of the New York city\nschool construction authority determines that there is no other\nappropriate site to erect such schoolhouse; (ii) if such schoolhouse is\nplanned to contain a secondary school, the community district, as such\nterm is defined in section twenty-five hundred ninety-a of this title,\nin which the site of such schoolhouse is to be located has a projected\nenrollment rate for secondary school education greater than seventy\npercent of its capacity, based on the most recent report issued pursuant\nto section 21-988 of the administrative code of the city of New York;\n(iii) if such schoolhouse is planned to contain an elementary school or\na middle school, the subdistrict, as such term is defined in section\n21-989 of the administrative code of the city of New York, in which the\nsite of such schoolhouse is to be located has a projected enrollment\nrate for elementary school education or middle school education, as\napplicable, greater than seventy percent of capacity, based on the most\nrecent report issued pursuant to section 21-988 of the administrative\ncode of the city of New York; (iv) the site of such schoolhouse is\nlocated on a property a portion of which is used or is planned to be\nused for residential or commercial purposes; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>plans for such\nschoolhouse include adequate engineering controls to address air\nquality, based on regulations promulgated by the New York city\ndepartment of environmental protection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this subdivision, neither the construction of a\nnew schoolhouse upon the site of an existing schoolhouse nor an addition\nnor an annex constructed to serve an existing schoolhouse shall be\nconsidered construction of a new schoolhouse.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this subdivision, a "controlled-access highway"\nshall mean:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a controlled-access highway as defined by section one\nhundred nine of the vehicle and traffic law under the jurisdiction of\nthe commissioner of transportation which has been functionally\nclassified by the department of transportation as principal arterial -\ninterstate or principal arterial - other freeway/expressway on official\nfunctional classification maps approved by the federal highway\nadministration pursuant to part 470.105 of title 23 of the code of\nfederal regulations, as amended from time to time; and (ii) a divided\nhighway under the jurisdiction of the New York state thruway authority\nfor mixed traffic with access limited as the authority may determine and\ngenerally with grade separations at intersections.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to create a private\nright of action to enforce the terms of this subdivision.\n  * NB Effective December 21, 2029\n  6. After a site has been selected and plans and specifications for a\nbuilding thereon have been approved as provided herein, a board of\neducation in a city having a population of more than four hundred\nthousand but less than one million may, in its discretion, by regulation\ndeliver such plans and specifications to the common council or other\nlocal legislative body which may thereupon, in its discretion, award a\ncontract for the erection of such building in the same manner and in\naccordance with the provisions of law regulating the awarding of\ncontracts for the construction of municipal buildings of such city.\n  7. a. The board of education of the city of New York, with the\npermission of the department of parks and of the board of estimate, may\nconstruct schoolhouses and school playgrounds upon a portion of the\npublic parks in the district east of the Bowery and Catharine street and\nsouth of Fourth street in such city.\n  b. The board of education of the city of New York, with the permission\nof the department of parks and recreation and of the board of estimate,\nmay construct a temporary schoolhouse upon a portion of a public park in\nthe borough of Queens, commonly referred to as Equity Park.\nNotwithstanding any inconsistent provision of subdivision nine of this\nsection, such park land shall revert to the control and management of\nthe department of parks and recreation seven years after the date of the\ncompletion of the construction of such temporary schoolhouse without\nfurther action of the board of education or of the board of estimate.\n  8. In a city having a population of one hundred twenty-five thousand\nor more and less than two hundred fifty thousand in which the common\ncouncil, the board of estimate and apportionment and the board of\ncontract and supply and the commissioner...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>identify each outdoor schoolyard located at educational\nfacilities, as defined in subdivision nine of section twenty-five\nhundred ninety-a of this title, of the city school district. Each\noutdoor schoolyard shall be identified by the community school district\nin which the outdoor schoolyard is located, its address, approximate\nsize and physical condition;\n  (ii) identify which outdoor schoolyards are used for physical\neducation, activity and/or recreation; for each such outdoor schoolyard,\na description of how often students of the city school district use the\noutdoor schoolyard and any limitations on the uses of the schoolyard;\n  (iii) identify which outdoor schoolyards are not used for physical\neducation, activity or recreation. For each such schoolyard, an\nexplanation of why it is not being used for physical education, physical\nactivity or recreation by students of the city school district;\n  (iv) whether each outdoor schoolyard is used and the frequency of such\nuse during the school day and whether it is available for use by\nstudents or the general public during after school hours;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for each outdoor schoolyard, a description of the capital plans\nfor construction, placement, renovation and/or reconfiguration thereof,\nand any plan to increase or decrease the availability and utilization\nthereof; and\n  (vi) any other facts, information and recommendations which the\nchancellor deems necessary to improve the outdoor schoolyards of the\neducational facilities of the city school district. Such improvements\nshall be those that enhance the physical education, physical and mental\nfitness, and well-being of the students of the city school district.\n  b. On or before December thirty-first, two thousand twelve, the\nchancellor shall submit the inventory and report, compiled pursuant to\nparagraph a of this subdivision, to the governor, the temporary\npresident of the senate, the speaker of the assembly, the chairs of the\nsenate and assembly committees on education, and the department.\n  c. For the purposes of this subdivision, "outdoor schoolyard" means\noutdoor space which is located at educational facilities, and is used or\nintended to be used by students for physical education, physical\nactivity and/or recreation.\n  15. a. The chancellor of a city school district in a city having a\npopulation of one million or more shall compile an inventory of and\nissue a written report and develop recommendations regarding\ntransportable classroom units ("TCU" or also commonly known as a\n"trailer"). Such inventory, report and recommendations shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2556__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>identify each transportable classroom unit located in the city\nschool district. Each transportable classroom unit shall be identified\nby the community school district in which it is located, its address\nwith identification of any school building it is part of or associated\nwith, its approximate size, its age, and a description of its physical\ncondition;\n  (ii) identify the number of students served within each transportable\nclassroom unit, including the grade level of such students, if\napplicable, the average class size within each transportable classroom\nunit, and a description of the amount of the school day the students\nspend within each transportable classroom unit;\n  (iii) provide recommendations to minimize the number of transportable\nclassroom units within the city school district.\n  b. On or before December thirty-first, two thousand seventeen, the\nchancellor shall submit the inventory, report, and the recommendations\nto minimize the number of transportable classroom units within the city\nschool district, compiled and developed pursuant to paragraph a of this\nsubdivision, to the governor, the temporary president of the senate, the\nspeaker of the assembly, the chairs of the senate and assembly\ncommittees on education, and the department. Annually, on or before\nDecember thirty-first, the chancellor shall update such inventory,\nreport and recommendations and provide such updated information and\nrecommendations to the governor, the temporary president of the senate,\nthe speaker of the assembly, the chairs of the senate and assembly\ncommittees on education, and the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>