<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2573"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2573"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2573"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2573/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2573/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2573/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2573/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2573">
        <num>2573</num>
        <heading>Appointment of assistant, district or other superintendents, teachers and other employees; their salaries, et cetera</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>i.\nTeachers and all other members of the teaching staff, appointed prior to\nJuly first, two thousand fifteen and authorized by section twenty-five\nhundred fifty-four of this article, shall be appointed by the board of\neducation, upon the recommendation of the superintendent of schools, for\na probationary period of three years, except that in the case of a\nteacher who has rendered satisfactory service as a regular substitute\nfor a period of two years or as a seasonally licensed per session\nteacher of swimming in day schools who has served in that capacity for a\nperiod of two years and has been appointed to teach the same subject in\nday schools on an annual salary, the probationary period shall be\nlimited to one year; provided, however, that in the case of a teacher\nwho has been appointed on tenure in another school district within the\nstate, the school district where currently employed, or a board of\ncooperative educational services, and who was not dismissed from such\ndistrict or board as a result of charges brought pursuant to subdivision\none of section three thousand twenty-a of this chapter, the probationary\nperiod shall not exceed two years; provided, however, that in cities\nwith a population of one million or more, a teacher appointed under a\nnewly created license, for teachers of reading and of the emotionally\nhandicapped, to a position which the teacher has held for at least two\nyears prior to such appointment while serving on tenure in another\nlicense area who was not dismissed as a result of charges brought\npursuant to subdivision one of section three thousand twenty-a of this\nchapter, the probationary period shall be one year. The service of a\nperson appointed to any of such positions may be discontinued at any\ntime during such probationary period, on the recommendation of the\nsuperintendent of schools, by a majority vote of the board of education.\nEach person who is not to be recommended for appointment on tenure shall\nbe so n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>i. Administrators, directors, supervisors, principals and all\nother members of the supervising staff, except executive directors,\nassociate, assistant, district and community superintendents and\nexaminers, appointed prior to July first, two thousand fifteen and\nauthorized by section twenty-five hundred fifty-four of this article,\nshall be appointed by the board of education, upon the recommendation of\nthe superintendent or chancellor of schools, for a probationary period\nof three years. The service of a person appointed to any of such\npositions may be discontinued at any time during the probationary period\non the recommendation of the superintendent of schools, by a majority\nvote of the board of education.\n  ii. Administrators, directors, supervisors, principals and all other\nmembers of the supervising staff, except executive directors, associate,\nassistant, district and community superintendents and examiners,\nappointed on or after July first, two thousand fifteen and authorized by\nsection twenty-five hundred fifty-four of this article, shall be\nappointed by the board of education, upon the recommendation of the\nsuperintendent or chancellor of schools, for a probationary period of\nfour years provided that such probationary period may be extended in\naccordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of this section;\nprovided, however, that in the case of a principal, administrator,\nsupervisor, or other member of the supervising staff who has been\nappointed on tenure pursuant to this chapter as an administrator within\nan authorized administrative tenure area in another school district\nwithin the state, the school district where currently employed, or a\nboard of cooperative educational services, and who was not dismissed\nfrom such district or board as a result of charges brought pursuant to\nsubdivision one of section three thousand twenty-a or section three\nthousand twenty-b of this chapter, the principal, administrator,\nsupervisor or other member of the supervising staff shall be appointed\nfor a probationary period of three years. The service of a person\nappointed to any of such positions may be discontinued at any time\nduring the probationary period on the recommendation of the\nsuperintendent of schools, by a majority vote of the board of education.\n  2. The chancellor shall require, in anticipation of the reasonable\nneeds of the school system, that interviews and performance tests be\nconducted for teaching service positions, pursuant to section two\nthousand five hundred sixty-nine of this article, so that qualifying\neligible lists may be ready for promulgation as soon as vacancies come\ninto existence.  Where vacancies already exist, and cannot be filled\nbecause eligible lists have been exhausted, the chancellor shall require\ninterviews and performance tests to be conducted forthwith and shall\nhave lists available for promulgation within six months from the date of\nthe administration of the test. Appropriate procedures for filling\nsupervisory positions shall be established pursuant to regulations\npromulgated by the chancellor and qualifying eligible lists shall be\npromulgated and thereafter supplemented annually Supervisory positions\nshall be filled in accordance with regulations promulgated by the\nchancellor; su...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the expiration of the probationary term of any persons\nappointed for such term prior to July first, two thousand fifteen, the\nsuperintendent of schools shall make a written report to the board of\neducation recommending for permanent appointment those persons who have\nbeen found competent, efficient and satisfactory. Such persons and all\nothers employed in the teaching, service of the schools of a city, who\nhave served the full probationary period, shall hold their respective\npositions during good behavior and efficient and competent service, and\nshall not be removable except for cause after a hearing as provided by\nsection three thousand twenty-a of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the expiration of the probationary term of any persons\nappointed for such term on or after July first, two thousand fifteen,\nthe superintendent of schools shall make a written report to the board\nof education recommending for permanent appointment those persons who\nhave been found competent, efficient and satisfactory. Any person who\nhas acquired tenure shall, upon such person's effective tenure date,\nhold their position during good behavior and efficient and competent\nservice, and shall not be removable except for cause after a hearing as\nprovided by section three thousand twenty and section three thousand\ntwenty-a of this chapter. Failure to maintain certification as required\nby this chapter and the regulations of the commissioner shall constitute\ncause for removal.\n  6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a city having a population of four hundred thousand or more,\nat the expiration of the probationary term of any persons appointed for\nsuch term prior to July first, two thousand fifteen, the superintendent\nof schools shall make a written report to the board of education\nrecommending for permanent appointment those persons who have been found\nsatisfactory, and such board of education shall immediately thereafter\nissue to such persons permanent certificates of appointment. Such\npersons and all others employed in the teaching service of the schools\nof such city, who have served the full probationary period shall receive\npermanent certificates to teach issued to them by the certificating\nauthority, except as otherwise provided in subdivision ten-a of this\nsection, and shall hold their respective positions during good behavior\nand satisfactory teaching service, and shall not be removable except for\ncause after a hearing as provided by section three thousand twenty-a of\nthis chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the expiration of the probationary term of any persons\nappointed for such term on or after July first, two thousand fifteen,\nthe superintendent of schools shall make a written report to the board\nof education recommending for permanent appointment those persons who\nhave been found competent, efficient and satisfactory. Any person who\nhas acquired tenure shall, upon such person's effective tenure date,\nhold their position during good behavior and efficient and competent\nservice, and shall not be removable except for cause after a hearing as\nprovided by section three thousand twenty and section three thousand\ntwenty-a of this chapter. Failure to maintain certification as required\nby this chapter and the regulations of the commissioner shall constitute\ncause for removal.\n  8. No charges under this section shall be brought more than three\nyears after the occurrence of the alleged incompetency or misconduct\nexcept where the charge is of misconduct which resulted in conviction\nfor a crime.\n  9. No principal, supervisor, director, or teacher shall be appointed\nto the teaching force of a city who does not possess qualifications\nrequired under this chapter and under the regulations prescribed by the\ncommissioner of education for the persons employed in such positions in\nthe schools of the cities of the state, but a board of education may\nprescribe additional or higher qualifications for the persons employed\nin any of such positions.\n  10.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a city having a population of one million or more,\nrecommendations for appointment to the teaching service shall be from\nthe first three persons chosen by random selection from the qualifying\neligible lists prepared by the chancellor. Competitive eligible lists in\nexistence at the time of enactment of this subdivision shall not be\nmerged and any such lists shall be exhausted or have expired before\nnominations are made from a qualifying list of a subsequent date\npromulgated hereunder. Qualifying eligible lists for supervisory\npositions shall be merged with any subsequently promulgated lists in the\nsame license area so that there shall be one continuing non-expiring\neligible list for each license area. No competitive eligible list shall\nremain in force for a longer period than four years, nor have a life of\nless than three years. No competitive eligible list now in force shall\nterminate any sooner than four years from the date on which it was\npromulgated. The board of education, on the recommendation of the\nchancellor shall designate, subject to the other provisions of this\nchapter, the kind and grades of licenses which shall be required for\nservice as principal, branch principal, director, supervisor or teacher\nof a special branch, head of department, assistant, school psychiatrist,\nschool psychologist, school medical inspector, school social worker,\nschool social caseworker, school secretary, industrial or trade helper\nin vocational schools, school librarian, laboratory assistant, or any\nother position of the teaching staff together with the academic and\nprofessional qualifications required for each kind or grade of license.\nNo person required to have a license under the provisions of this\nchapter in order to be employed in a position who does not have such\nlicense shall have any claim for salary, except that a person who has\nbeen assigned to teach in a subject or field not specifically covered in\nhis license but on the same rank or le...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Qualifying eligible lists for teaching and supervisory positions\nshall consist of the names of all persons who have met the eligibility\nrequirements for appointment as defined by the chancellor pursuant to\nsections two thousand five hundred ninety-j and two thousand five\nhundred sixty-nine of this chapter. Where the regulations of the\ncommissioner do not identify a state certificate that corresponds to a\nlicense utilized by the city school district, the chancellor shall\ndevelop and administer an examination appropriate to the license,\nprovided the development of such examination and the passing score are\nbased upon appropriate validity studies conducted in accordance with\nprofessional standards of measurement. For teaching service positions,\ncompetitive eligible lists in existence on the effective date of this\nparagraph shall not be merged. Subsequently promulgated qualifying\neligible lists in the same license area shall be merged so that there\nshall be one qualifying eligible list for each license area. No\ncandidate shall remain on the qualifying eligible list longer than seven\nyears from the date the candidate is placed on the qualifying eligible\nlist. This paragraph does not affect the examinations for teaching or\nsupervisory service positions announced by the board of examiners prior\nto the effective date of this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2573__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each year, the chancellor shall direct the division of personnel\nto select by random selection from among candidates who are available\nfor assignment and who are on the qualifying eligible lists for teaching\npositions in existence on such date for each license area, a list of\nprospective appointees deemed to be sufficient to meet the needs of the\nschool system for the next school year. The random selection to\nestablish the initial list of prospective appointees shall be held prior\nto April first, nineteen hundred ninety-one. In any instance where the\nlist of prospective appointees is insufficient for the twelve month\nperiod, the chancellor shall direct the division of personnel to select\nby random selection additional candidates who are available for\nassignment and who are on qualifying eligible lists in order to compile\na supplementary list of prospective appointees.\n  (ii) Candidates selected by a random selection system and whose names\nappear on the list of prospective appointees for teaching positions\nshall be assigned to community districts and to divisions under the\njurisdiction of the chancellor in the order in which their names were\nselected by such system provided that each appointment by the chancellor\nor community board as appropriate shall be made from among the first\nthree persons so assigned.\n  (iii) Lists of prospective appointees for teaching positions shall not\nbe merged and a list shall be exhausted or have expired before\nassignments are made from a list of prospective appointees selected by a\nrandom selection procedure of subsequent date. No candidate shall remain\non the list of prospective appointees longer than seven years from the\ndate that the candidate was placed on the qualifying eligible list.\n  10-a. In the city school district of the city of Buffalo, members of\nthe teaching and supervising staff appointed on or after the effective\ndate of this subdivision shall be required to hold a state teaching\ncertificate,...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>