<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2575-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2575_C">
        <num>2575-C</num>
        <heading>Transfer of the director of attendance, assistant director of attendance, chief attendance officer, division supervising attendance offic...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2575-c. Transfer of the director of attendance, assistant director\nof attendance, chief attendance officer, division supervising attendance\nofficers and district supervising attendance officers, supervisors of\nschool social workers to the New York city teachers' retirement system.\nAny director of attendance, assistant director of attendance, chief\nattendance officer, division supervising attendance officers, and\ndistrict supervising attendance officers, supervisors of school social\nworkers who are members of the board of education retirement system of\nthe city of New York shall have the right to transfer his membership to\nthe teachers' retirement system of the city of New York.  In order to\neffect such transfer, such member must give notice to the board of\neducation retirement system of the city of New York, on or before\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy, of his intention to\ntransfer to said teachers' retirement system.  Upon receipt of such\nnotice, the board of education retirement system shall transfer to such\nteachers' retirement system the reserves, including the reserve for\nincreased take home pay, or such member's benefits in the manner\nprovided by section forty-three of the retirement and social security\nlaw.  The former system shall also transfer to the latter system the\nmember's accumulated deductions which shall become such member's\naccumulated deductions in the latter system.  A person so transferring\nshall be deemed to have been a member of the system to which he has\ntransferred during the entire period of membership service credited to\nhim in the system from which he has transferred.  Such transferee shall\nbe entitled to all the rights, privileges and benefits of the system to\nwhich he has transferred.  Upon his retirement, the mortality table in\neffect in the teachers' retirement system of the city of New York on the\ndate when he last became a member of the board of education retirement\nsystem shall apply.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>