<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-259"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-259"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-10-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="259"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-259/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-259/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-259/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-259/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_259">
        <num>259</num>
        <heading>Library taxes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_259__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not include a city with a population of one million or more,\n  (ii) mean only a county when the public libraries located in such\ncounty are members of a federated public library system whose central\nlibrary is located in a city of more than three hundred thousand\ninhabitants.\n  2. In the case of a joint public library authorized to be established\nby two or more municipalities or districts pursuant to section two\nhundred fifty-five of this chapter, the governing bodies of the\nparticipating municipalities and districts shall enter into an agreement\ndesignating the treasurer of one of the participating municipalities or\ndistricts to be the treasurer of the joint public library. The agreement\nshall be for a period of not less than one year nor more than five years\nand the state comptroller and the commissioner of education shall be\nnotified in writing by the board of library trustees of such agreement\nand designation.\n  The municipality or district whose treasurer is designated to serve as\ntreasurer of a joint public library may be compensated for the services\nrendered by such official to the library. The amount to be paid for such\nservices shall be determined by agreement between the governing body of\nthe municipality or district and the board of library trustees, and\nshall be paid at least annually from the public library fund.\n  3. The treasurer of a joint public library shall maintain the separate\nlibrary fund required by subdivision one of this section and shall\ncredit to such fund all moneys received. The state aid apportioned to a\njoint public library, amounts appropriated by participants toward its\nsupport and all amounts received from other sources shall be paid to the\nlibrary treasurer. Appropriations for the library made by the\nparticipating municipalities or districts shall be paid in full to the\nlibrary treasurer within sixty days after the beginning of the library\nfiscal year.\n  Disbursements for purposes of a joint public lib...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>