<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-U"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-U"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2590-U"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2590_U">
        <num>2590-U</num>
        <heading>New York city independent budget office reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_U__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>student graduation and dropout data;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_U__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>student enrollment projections;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_U__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>school utilization, class sizes and pupil-to-teacher ratios;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_U__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>student assessment data;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_U__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the delivery of services to students who are in bilingual or\nEnglish as a second language programs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_U__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the delivery of services to students with disabilities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_U__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the utilization of federal funds including funds pursuant to title\nI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of nineteen hundred\nsixty-five, as amended, directed at parental involvement; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_U__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>matters relating to city district finances.\n  2. In addition to the appropriation available pursuant to section two\nhundred fifty-nine of the New York city charter, the city of New York\nshall appropriate during each fiscal year an amount to the independent\nbudget office of the city of New York not less than two and one-half per\ncentum of the appropriations available to pay for the expenses of the\noffice of management and budget of the city of New York during each\nfiscal year, to carry out the duties and functions assigned in this\nsubdivision.\n  3. The director of the independent budget office of the city of New\nYork shall be authorized to secure such information, data, estimates and\nstatistics from the city board and the chancellor as such director\ndetermines to be necessary for the performance of the functions and\nduties of such office, and the city board and the chancellor shall\nprovide such information, to the extent that it is available, in a\ntimely fashion. The director of the independent budget office of the\ncity of New York shall not be entitled to obtain records which are\nprotected by the privileges for attorney-client communications, attorney\nwork product, and material prepared for litigation.\n  4. The director of the independent budget office of the city of New\nYork shall ensure that such office uses up-to-date appropriate and\nprofessionally accepted methodologies in producing annual data reports\nrelated to the city district and that such methodologies used are\nidentified in such reports.\n  * NB Repealed June 30, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>