<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2590-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2590_O">
        <num>2590-O</num>
        <heading>Educational facilities master plan</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_O__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>set forth the minimum acceptable standards for each type\nof educational facility and the number and identity to the extent\nascertainable of facilities of each such type that the chancellor\nbelieves do not currently meet such minimum standards, (ii) identify\nthose facility defects and shortcomings that most seriously impede\nlearning and teaching, (iii) describe the remedial measures proposed to\nbe taken, (iv) establish priorities for their initiation and completion,\nincluding a list of prioritized projects to the extent ascertainable and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_O__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>list each proposed new educational facility and set forth a\njustification, including demographic data, documenting the longterm need\ntherefor. In addition, the master plan shall include an estimate of its\ncost and such other information as the chancellor shall determine.\n  2. No later than January sixth, nineteen hundred eighty-nine, the\nchancellor shall, in conjunction with the submission of the five-year\neducational facilities capital plan required by section twenty-five\nhundred ninety-p of this chapter, submit the master plan to each\ncommunity school board, which shall conduct a public hearing on both the\neducational facilities master plan and the five-year educational\nfacilities capital plan and shall prepare and submit recommendations to\nthe chancellor on or before February twentieth, nineteen hundred\neighty-nine with respect to matters in the plans that involve that\nschool district. The chancellor shall consider the recommendations\nreceived from the community school boards, and, on or before March\neighth, nineteen hundred eighty-nine, shall submit a final educational\nfacilities master plan to the city board for its approval. On or before\nMarch twenty-second, nineteen hundred eighty-nine, the city board shall\napprove the educational facilities master plan submitted by the\nchancellor or such plan as is determined by the city board.\n  ** 3. No later than January first, nineteen hundred ninety-three, the\nchancellor shall prepare and submit a preliminary proposed revision to\nthe educational facilities master plan to the city board and to each\ncommunity school board. This proposed revision shall reflect the\nprogress achieved during the first three years of the master plan and\nshall incorporate such changes to the master plan as the chancellor\ndeems necessary. Each such community school board shall conduct a public\nhearing and shall prepare and submit recommendations to the chancellor\non or before March first, nineteen hundred ninety-three...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>