<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2607"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2607"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2607"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2607">
        <num>2607</num>
        <heading>Inspectors of election; organization</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2607. Inspectors of election; organization. Not less than ten days\nprior to each special or annual election, the board of education shall\nappoint for each election district three qualified voters residing\ntherein to act as inspectors of election in such election district at\nsuch election. The clerk of the board of education shall give written\nnotice of appointment to the persons so appointed. If a person appointed\nan inspector of election refuses to accept such appointment or fails to\nserve, the board may appoint a qualified voter of the school election\ndistrict to fill the vacancy. Additional inspectors of elections for\neach district may be appointed for one or more of such school election\ndistricts when, in the opinion of the board, special circumstances exist\nrequiring the services of such additional inspectors. Such inspectors\nshall, before opening the polls in the election district for which they\nare appointed, organize by electing one of their number as chairperson\nand one as poll clerk. The chairperson may also appoint one of the\ninspectors as an assistant poll clerk. Each inspector shall receive for\nhis or her services a compensation to be fixed by the board of\neducation, not to exceed the basic compensation paid to inspectors of\nelection at the preceding general elections, as fixed by the governing\nbody of the city in which such school district is wholly or partly\nlocated, to be paid out of the school funds in the same manner as other\nclaims against the city school district. Notwithstanding the foregoing\nprovisions of this section, a person seventeen years of age who is\nenrolled in a school district and fulfilling the requirements of section\nthirty-two hundred seven-a of this chapter shall be eligible to be\nappointed as, and to perform the duties of, an election inspector or\npoll clerk as provided in this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>