<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-272"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-272"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="272"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-272/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-272/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-272/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-272/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_272">
        <num>272</num>
        <heading>Conditions under which library systems are entitled to state aid</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_272__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at least one chartered degree-granting institution of higher\neducation offering graduate programs for a masters degree whose library\nholds not less than two hundred seventy-five thousand volumes and\ncurrently receives not less than three thousand periodical titles, or\n  (ii) a public library which holds not less than four hundred thousand\nadult volumes and currently receives not less than one thousand five\nhundred periodical titles.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The membership may also include approved public and school library\nsystems which are within the region served by the reference and research\nlibrary resources system.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A public library in Suffolk or Nassau county that provides service\nwithin the area served by the system except that no such public library\nwhich is not a member of a public library system shall be eligible for\nmembership in a reference and research library resources system.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A reference and research library resources system may set its own\nminimum standards for membership consistent with regulations of the\ncommissioner, except that;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_272__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any chartered institution of higher education whose library meets\nthe departmental standards shall be eligible for membership, and\n  (ii) any chartered institution of higher education whose library does\nnot meet the departmental standards may not be eligible for membership\nunless it submits to the department a five-year plan for the realization\nof the standards, the plan bearing the signed approval of the head\nlibrarian, the president, and the academic dean of the institution, and\n  (iii) any hospital whose library meets the standards established by\nthe regents in accordance with section two hundred fifty-four of this\narticle shall be eligible for membership, and\n  (iv) any hospital whose library does not meet the standards\nestablished by the regents will not be eligible for membership unless it\nsubmits to the commissioner a five year plan for the realization of the\nstandards, such plan bearing the signed approval of the head of the\ngoverning board of such hospital.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The member institutions of each reference and research library\nresources system shall be broadly representative of the chartered\neducational agencies, nonprofit organizations, hospitals and other\nspecial libraries providing library service within the defined area of\nservices of the system.\n  d. Plan of service.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The reference and research library resources system shall submit a\nplan of service to the commissioner for approval, in a form to be\nprescribed by the commissioner to cover resources, needs, proposed\nprogram, budget, contractual agreements, and any other information which\nthe commissioner may require.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The plan of service must show the manner in which the reference\nand research library resources system will improve the library resources\nand services presently available in the area to the research community,\nincluding improved reader access.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The plan of service shall indicate the manner in which the\nreference and research library resources system strengthens the library\nprograms of its members and the manner in which the system program is\nrelated to appropriate regional programs in higher education.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The plan of service shall identify the resources and needs of each\nhospital library, or library serving hospitals and show the manner in\nwhich the reference and research library resources system will improve\nhospital library services and in which it will assist each hospital\nlibrary which does not meet the regents' standards to attain such\nstandards and will assist each non-member hospital library or library\nserving a hospital to attain membership in the system.\n  e. The commissioner shall by regulation establish the standard of\nservice to be met by such a reference and research library resources\nsystem.\n  f. Each reference and research library resources system receiving\nstate aid pursuant to this section and section two hundred seventy-three\nof this article shall furnish such information regarding its library\nservice as the commissioner may from time to time require to discharge\nhis duties under such sections. The commissioner may at any time revoke\nhis approval of a pl...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The prevention of unreasonable discrimination among the persons\nserved by such library system;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The need for regional resources of sufficient size and varied in\nkind and subject matter;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The need for adequate books, materials (print and non-print) and\nfacilities for research and information;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The need for outlets convenient in time and place for the sharing\nof library materials;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The need for the economic and efficient utilization of public\nfunds;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The need for full utilization of local responsibility, initiative\nand support of library service and the use of state aid in their\nstimulation but not as their substitute.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_272__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The need for adequate books, materials, including both print and\nnon-print materials, and facilities for current medical information\nservices to be provided each hospital.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>