<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-273"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-273"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-10-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="273"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-273/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-273/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-273/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-273/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_273">
        <num>273</num>
        <heading>Apportionment of state aid to libraries and library systems</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, or seventy-six thousand five\nhundred dollars, whichever is more.\n  e. The sum of fifty-two dollars per square mile of area served by the\nlibrary system in the case of library systems serving one county or\nless. Such sum shall be increased by five dollars for each additional\nentire county served, provided, however, that no apportionment pursuant\nto this paragraph shall exceed seventy-two dollars per square mile of\narea served. If an entire county is served by two or more library\nsystems, each of which serves a part thereof, each of such library\nsystems shall be entitled to receive, in addition to the aid computed in\naccordance with the foregoing provisions of this paragraph, a pro rata\nshare of an increase of five dollars to be computed as follows: the sum\nresulting from the computation of five dollars per square mile of area\nserved by the one of such library systems which would receive the\nlargest amount of aid pursuant to this paragraph shall be pro rated\namong the library systems serving such county in accordance with the\nratio which the population of the area served by each of such library\nsystems bears to the population of the county as determined under\nsubdivision one of section two hundred seventy-two of this article.\n  f.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Local library services aid. Except in cities with a population\nin excess of one million inhabitants, each chartered and registered\npublic and free association library meeting standards of service\npromulgated by the commissioner, and each public or free association\nlibrary serving a city with a population of one hundred thousand or more\nwhich merged with the public library system on or before January first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-six and which meets standards of service\npromulgated by the commissioner, shall be eligible to receive annually\nthirty-one cents per capita of the population of the library's chartered\nservice area as on file with the commissioner on January first of the\ncalendar year for which aid is payable, or, thirty-one cents per capita\nof the population of the city with a population of one hundred thousand\nor more whose public or free association library merged with the public\nlibrary system on or before January first, nineteen hundred seventy-six,\nwith a ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Local services support aid. Except in cities with a population in\nexcess of one million inhabitants, each public library system operating\nunder an approved plan of service shall be eligible to receive annually\nlocal services support aid equal to two-thirds of the total dollar\namount paid in local library services aid to the member libraries of the\nsystem plus thirty-one cents per capita of the system's population who\ndo not reside within the chartered service area of a member library.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Local consolidated systems aid. In cities with a population in\nexcess of one million inhabitants, each public library system operating\nunder an approved plan of service shall be eligible to receive annually\nlocal consolidated system aid equal to the sum of</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>thirty-one cents\nper capita of the population served by the system, but not less than the\namount of local library incentive aid received in nineteen hundred\nninety-one as reported on the library's nineteen hundred ninety-one\nannual report; and (ii) an additional amount equal to two-thirds of the\ntotal dollar amount computed for the system pursuant to clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subparagraph.\n  g. In addition to the sums otherwise provided in paragraphs a, b, c,\nd, e, f, h and i of this subdivision, the New York Public Library shall\nreceive six million four hundred sixteen thousand six hundred dollars\nfor the general support of its research libraries. In addition to any\nother sums provided to such library, the sum of two million dollars\nshall be payable annually to the New York Public Library for the general\nsupport of library services provided by the New York Public Library to\nthe students of the City University of New York and the sum of one\nmillion dollars shall be payable annually to the New York Public Library\nfor the general support of its science, industry and business library.\n  h.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Coordinated outreach services. Each public library system which\nprovides coordinated outreach services, as defined by regulations to be\npromulgated by the commissioner, to persons who are educationally\ndisadvantaged or who are members of ethnic or minority groups in need of\nspecial library services, or who are unemployed and in need of job\nplacement assistance, or who live in areas underserved by a library, or\nwho are blind, physically disabled, have developmental or learning\ndisabilities, or who are aged or confined in institutions, or who are\nat-risk youth from birth to age twenty-one, shall be entitled to receive\nannually forty-three thousand dollars and thirteen cents per capita of\nthe total population of the area served.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition, each system serving a population of two million\ninhabitants or more shall receive an additional amount of forty-six\nthousand three hundred thirty-three dollars and each system serving a\npopulation of four hundred thousand inhabitants and less than two\nmillion inhabitants shall receive an additional amount of twenty-three\nthousand dollars and each system serving a population of less than four\nhundred thousand inhabitants shall receive an additional amount of\nfourteen thousand dollars.\n  i. In addition to any other sums provided for such purposes, the New\nYork Public Library shall receive annually the sum of seven hundred\nthirty-four thousand dollars for the program of the Schomburg center for\nresearch in black culture, and the additional sum of nine hundred\neighty-four thousand dollars for the program of the library for the\nblind and physically handicapped.\n  j. In addition to any other sums provided to such library, the sum of\ntwo hundred fifty thousand doll...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any\nreference and research library resources system providing service under\nan approved plan during a calendar year shall be entitled to receive\nannual state aid consisting of an annual grant of:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Two hundred seventy thousand dollars plus the sum of one dollar\nand fifty cents per square mile of area served plus the sum of six cents\nper capita of the population of the area served; and\n  (ii) Two hundred thousand dollars plus the sum of two cents per capita\nof the population of the area served.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each system may annually appropriate funds received under this\nsubdivision to obtain matching funds from the National Endowment for the\nHumanities and other federal programs.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The annual amount payable to each approved system under this\nparagraph shall be payable on or before July first, provided that, upon\nreceipt of annual system activity reports satisfactory to the\ncommissioner, the commissioner shall determine the amount of any under-\nor overpayments and shall apply such adjustment to the next annual\npayment due such system.\n  b. The commissioner is hereby authorized to expend up to five hundred\nsix thousand dollars annually in each state fiscal year to provide\nformula grants to approved reference and research library resources\nsystems for provision of consumer health and medical information\nservices for all types of libraries and library systems. Such grants\nshall assist libraries in providing access to timely and accurate\nmedical and health information for medical personnel and for the general\npublic. In addition to any other sum provided in this subdivision, each\nreference and research library resources system providing service under\nan...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Funds shall be available to each reference and research library\nresources system in such manner as to insure that the ratio of the\namount each system is eligible to receive equals the weighted ratio of\nthe total number of institutions as defined in subparagraph two of this\nparagraph in the region served by the system to the total number of such\ninstitutions in the state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of determining the amount of funds available to\neach system, institutions and their weightings are as follows:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not-for-profit hospitals licensed by the New York state health\ndepartment, with a weighting of two;\n  (ii) for-profit teaching hospitals licensed by the New York state\nhealth department, with an additional weighting of one; and\n  (iii) member institutions of a reference and research library\nresources system, excluding public and hospital libraries, with a\nweighting of one.\n  c.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner is hereby authorized to expend up to one\nmillion three hundred ninety-six thousand dollars in each state fiscal\nyear to provide formula grants to approved reference and research\nlibrary resources systems for provision of services to member hospital\nlibraries in not-for-profit hospitals licensed by the New York state\nhealth department, or to member libraries serving such hospitals. Such\nformula grants shall be determined on the basis of criteria to be\ndeveloped by the commissioner and shall assist member hospital libraries\nor member libraries serving hospitals in meeting the standards\nestablished by the regents in accordance with section two hundred\nfifty-four of this article. Such formula grants shall support\nintegration of member hospital libraries or member libraries serving\nhospitals into existing networks.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall provide grants to the reference and\nresearch library resources systems in the following manner:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an amount equal to seventy-five cents per square mile of area\nserved by the reference and research library resource system in\nfurtherance of the purposes of this paragraph, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the remainder for library services to hospitals in accordance with\nregulations of the commissioner adopted for such purpose.\n  5. Coordinated collection development program for public and nonprofit\nindependent colleges and universities.\n  a. Libraries of public and nonprofit independent colleges and\nuniversities are entitled to receive annual funding for a coordinated\ncollection development grant if they meet the following conditions:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Membership in a reference and research library resources system,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Their resources are made available to the public, through full\nparticipation in the interlibrary loan and other resource sharing\nprograms of the reference and research library resources system of which\nthey are members, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>They meet the requirements set forth in regulations adopted by the\ncommissioner including but not confined to\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>maintenance of effort,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>relationships between reference and research library resources\nsystems' programs and the regional higher education master plan,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>submission of interlibrary loan statistics, and such other reports\nas may be required by the commissioner.\n  b. Public and nonprofit independent colleges and universities with\nlibraries which meet the criteria of paragraph a of this subdivision are\neligible for annual grants as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Four thousand four hundred dollars for each institution, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_273__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>One dollar and four cents for each full-time equivalent student\nenrolled in each qualifying institution, in the academic year completed\nprior to the state fiscal year. For purposes of this section, a\nfull-time equivalent shall be calculated as follows:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one full-time undergraduate student shall be considered one\nfull-time equivalent student;\n  (ii) one part-time undergraduate student shall be considered one-third\nof a full-time equivalent student;\n  (iii) one part-time graduate student shall be considered one full-time\nequivalent student; and\n  (iv) one full-time graduate student shall be considered one and\none-half of a full-time equivalent student.\n  c. Funds for the support of this program shall be appropriated to the\ndepartment, except that funds for the state-operated institutions of the\nstate university of New York and the senior colleges of the city\nuniversity of New York, shall be appropriated to the state university of\nNew York out of any moneys in the state treasury in the general fund to\nthe credit of the state purposes fund not otherwise appropriated, and\nfunds shall be appropriated to the city university of New York out of\nany moneys in the state treasury in the general fund to the credit of\nthe local assistance fund not otherwise appropriated, and shall be\nsubject to the same distribution formula as provided in paragraph b of\nthis subdivision.\n  6. Conservation and preservation of library research materials.  a.\nThe commissioner shall award in any academic year, an annual formula\ngrant of one hundred fifty-eight thousand dollars for a program of\nconservation and/or preservation of library research materials to each\nof the following comprehensive research libraries: Columbia university\nlibraries, Cornell university libraries, New York state library, New\nYork university libraries, university of Rochester libraries, Syracuse\nuniversity libraries, the research libraries of the New York public\nlibrary, state university of New York at Albany library, state\nuniversity of New York at Binghamton library, state university of New\nYork at Buffalo library, and state university of New York at Stony Brook\nlibrary.\n  b. To be eligible for such formula grants, each such comprehensive\nre...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subparagraph one of paragraph a of\nsubdivision four of this section; and\n  c. Each school library system established pursuant to section two\nhundred eighty-two of this part and operating under a plan approved by\nthe commissioner is entitled to receive annually thirty-nine thousand\ndollars and an amount equal to ten and ninety-four hundredths percent of\nthe amount of state aid received for the current year by such system\nunder paragraphs a, b, c, d, e and f of subdivision one of section two\nhundred eighty-four of this part.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>