<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-274"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-274"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="274"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-274/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-274/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-274/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-274/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_274">
        <num>274</num>
        <heading>Use and care of school library</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 274. Use and care of school library.  The school library shall be a\npart of the school equipment and shall be kept in the school building at\nall times. Such library shall be devoted to the exclusive use of the\nschool, except as otherwise provided by the rules of the commissioner of\neducation and except in a district where there is no free library, in\nwhich case such school library shall be a circulating library for the\nuse of the residents of the district.\n  The commissioner of education shall prescribe rules regulating\n  1. The purchase, recording, safekeeping and loaning of books in school\nlibraries, and the use of such books by pupils and teachers in the\npublic schools.\n  2. The conditions under which books in a school library may be used by\nthe public in a district in which a free library is situated.\n  3. The management of school libraries and their use as circulating\nlibraries by the residents of the district in which they are situated.\n  4. The contents and submission of reports of school librarians,\nteachers and other school authorities as to school libraries.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>