<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-275"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-275"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="275"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-275/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-275/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-275/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-275/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_275">
        <num>275</num>
        <heading>Librarians of school libraries</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 275. Librarians of school libraries.  In a school district\nmaintaining an academic department or high school the board of education\nmay employ, and fix the compensation of, a person to act as school\nlibrarian who may be engaged for all or a part of the time in\nperformance of the duties of the position as may be directed by the said\nboard.  The person so employed, who may be the librarian of the free\nlibrary, shall be possessed of the qualifications prescribed by the\ncommissioner of education.  In all other districts the trustees or board\nof education may appoint a competent person to act as librarian.  In\ncase of a failure of a city or union free school district maintaining an\nacademic department or high school to employ a librarian as above\nprovided, the teacher of English in such school shall be the librarian.\nIn case of a failure to appoint a librarian in any other district, the\nteacher, or if there be more than one teacher the principal teacher,\nshall act as librarian.  The trustees or board of education shall report\nto the commissioner of education the name and address of the person\nemployed or appointed as librarian.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>