<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3001"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3001">
        <num>3001</num>
        <heading>Qualifications of teachers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3001. Qualifications of teachers. No person shall be employed or\nauthorized to teach in the public schools of the state who is:\n  1. Under the age of eighteen years.\n  2. Not in possession of a teacher's certificate issued under the\nauthority of this chapter or a diploma issued on the completion of a\ncourse in state college for teachers or state teachers college of this\nstate.\n  The provisions of this subdivision shall not prohibit a certified\nteacher from permitting a practice or cadet teacher enrolled in an\napproved teacher education program from teaching a class without the\npresence of the certified teacher in the classroom provided the\nclassroom certified teacher is available at all times and retains\nsupervision of the practice or cadet teacher. The number of certified\nteachers shall not be diminished by reason of the presence of cadet\nteachers.\n  3. Not a citizen. The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply,\nhowever, to a noncitizen teacher now or hereafter employed, provided\nsuch teacher shall make due application to become a citizen and\nthereafter within the time prescribed by law shall become a citizen. The\nprovisions of this subdivision shall not apply, after July first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-seven, to a noncitizen teacher employed pursuant\nto regulations adopted by the commissioner of education permitting such\nemployment. The citizenship requirements of this subdivision shall not\napply to a noncitizen teacher now or hereafter employed whose\nimmigration status is that of a lawful permanent resident of the United\nStates and who would otherwise be eligible to serve as a teacher, or to\napply for or receive permanent certification as a teacher, but for the\nforegoing requirements of this subdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>