<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3003"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3003"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3003"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3003">
        <num>3003</num>
        <heading>Qualifications of superintendents</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3003. Qualifications of superintendents.  1. No person except one in\npossession of a valid superintendent's certificate prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-one shall hereafter be eligible to the position\nof superintendent of schools, deputy superintendent of schools,\nassociate superintendent of schools, assistant superintendent of schools\nor other superintendent of schools or member of a board of examiners in\na city school district or as a superintendent of schools in a union free\nor central school district having a population of more than forty-five\nhundred, or eligible to appointment to the office of district\nsuperintendent of schools in this state, who is not eligible for a\nsuperintendent's certificate issued by the commissioner in accordance\nwith the following requirements:\n  a. He shall be a graduate of a college or university approved by the\ncommissioner and in addition shall have completed sixty semester hours\nin graduate courses approved by the commissioner; and\n  b. At the time of his appointment each shall have completed three\nyears of teaching experience satisfactory to the commissioner in public\nor non-public schools.\n  2. The commissioner of education shall issue a superintendent's\npermanent certificate to any person who on March twenty-fifth, nineteen\nhundred thirty-seven, held or was appointed to, a position of\nsuperintendent of schools, deputy superintendent of schools, associate\nsuperintendent of schools, assistant superintendent of schools or other\nsuperintendent of schools or member of a board of examiners in a city or\nas a superintendent of schools in a village having a population of more\nthan forty-five hundred, or district superintendent of schools.\n  3. The commissioner, at the request of a board of education or board\nof cooperative educational services, may provide for the issuance of a\ncertificate as superintendent of schools to exceptionally qualified\npersons who do not meet all of the graduate course or teaching\nrequirements of subdivision one of this section, but whose exceptional\ntraining and experience are the substantial equivalent of such\nrequirements and qualify such persons for the duties of a superintendent\nof schools.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the commissioner shall\nrequire that any person applying, on or after January first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-one, for a superintendent's certificate shall, in\naddition to all the other requirements, have completed two hours of\ncoursework or training regarding the identification and reporting of\nchild abuse and maltreatment. The coursework or training shall be\nobtained from an institution or provider which has been approved by the\ndepartment to provide such coursework or training. The coursework or\ntraining shall include information regarding the physical and behavioral\nindicators of child abuse and maltreatment and the statutory reporting\nrequirements set out in sections four hundred thirteen through four\nhundred twenty of the social services law, including but not limited to,\nwhen and how a report must be made, what other actions the reporter is\nmandated or authorized to take, the legal protections afforded\nreporters, and the consequences for failing to report. Each applicant\nshall provide the department with documentation showing that he or she\nhas completed the required training.\n  5. The commissioner may provide for the issuance of a certificate as\ndeputy, associate or assistant superintendent for business to any\nqualified person who meets all of the requirements of subdivision one of\nthis section, except those contained in paragraph b of subdivision one\nof this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>