<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3004-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3004-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3004-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3004-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3004-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3004-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3004-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3004_B">
        <num>3004-B</num>
        <heading>Special procedures for certification</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3004_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirty of section three hundred five of\nthis chapter and shall obtain the applicant's consent to the criminal\nhistory records search. The commissioner shall obtain from each\napplicant two sets of fingerprints and the division of criminal justice\nservices processing fee imposed pursuant to subdivision eight-a of\nsection eight hundred thirty-seven of the executive law and any fee\nimposed by the federal bureau of investigation. The commissioner shall\npromptly transmit such fingerprints and fees to the division of criminal\njustice services for its full search and retain processing. The division\nof criminal justice services is authorized to submit the fingerprints\nand the appropriate fee to the federal bureau of investigation for a\nnational criminal history record check. The division of criminal justice\nservices and the federal bureau of investigation shall forward such\ncriminal history record to the commissioner in a timely manner. For the\npurposes of this section the term "criminal history record" shall mean a\nrecord of all convictions of crimes and any pending criminal charges\nmaintained on an individual by the division of criminal justice services\nand the federal bureau of investigation. In addition, upon request from\nan applicant who has applied for employment with the city school\ndistrict of the city of New York, the commissioner shall have the\nauthority to forward a copy of such criminal history record to the city\nschool district of the city of New York by the most expeditious means\navailable. Furthermore, upon notification that such applicant is\nemployed by the city school district of the city of New York, the\ndivision of criminal justice services shall have the authority to\nprovide subsequent criminal history notifications directly to the city\nschool district of the city of New York. Upon request from an applicant\nwho has already been cleared for licensure and/or employment by the city\nschool district of the city of New...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>