<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3005"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3005"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3005"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3005/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3005/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3005/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3005/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3005">
        <num>3005</num>
        <heading>Leave of absence to teachers for teaching in foreign countries, other states and territories and other school districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3005. Leave of absence to teachers for teaching in foreign\ncountries, other states and territories and other school districts.  The\ntrustee, trustees or board of education of any school district may\npermit any teacher having had at least five years service in the school\nor schools of said district to apply for and receive a leave of absence\nfor a period not to exceed two years for teaching in the schools of a\nforeign country, other states of the United States or any of its\nterritories or in any other school district within this state provided\nsuch foreign country, other state or territory or other school district\nshall have agreed to furnish a teacher of corresponding rank or school\nlevel to fulfill the duties of the said teacher on leave of absence.\nDuring the period of said leave of absence the said teacher shall\nreceive from the school district the same compensation that he would\nhave received had he been present and teaching in a school of the\ndistrict.  Such leave of absence shall not in any way affect the\nretirement rights of said teacher as a member of a retirement system and\nthe period of the aforesaid leave of absence shall be credited to the\ntotal years of service of said member in the same manner and for all\npurposes as if he had not been granted said leave of absence and had\nbeen present within the district engaged in actual teaching service.\nNotwithstanding any of the provisions of this chapter, when the\nqualifications of the teacher from the foreign country, other state or\nterritory or other school district have been approved by the\ncommissioner of education, he shall be legally entitled to render\ninstructional service in any public school in this state and a permit\nfor a period not to exceed two years for such service shall be issued by\nthe commissioner of education without the payment of fee.  Any school\ndistrict employing a teacher under this section may supplement the\nsalary received from the foreign country, other state or territory or\nother school district by said teacher.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>