<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3006"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3006"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3006"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3006">
        <num>3006</num>
        <heading>Commissioner of education to issue certificates</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3006__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For a certificate issued under this section based upon completion\nof a teacher education program registered by the department, fifty\ndollars;\n  (ii) For a certificate issued under this section based upon education\nor experience completed in other than a teacher education program\nregistered by the department, one hundred dollars;\n  (iii) For a temporary license or a temporary coaching license, fifty\ndollars;\n  (iv) For a continuing certificate for a teaching assistant,\nthirty-five dollars;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3006__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For a duplicate certificate, twenty-five dollars.\n  b. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph a of this subdivision,\nin a case where an individual applies for a certificate of\nqualification, provisional and/or permanent certificate within twelve\nmonths of having been issued a temporary license in the same\ncertification area, the fee for such additional certificate or\ncertificates shall be fifty dollars.\n  3. Registration. a. Commencing with the two thousand sixteen--two\nthousand seventeen school year, any holder of a teaching certificate in\nthe classroom teaching service, teaching assistant certificate, or\neducational leadership certificate that is valid for life as prescribed\nby the commissioner in regulations shall be required to register with\nthe department every five years in accordance with regulations of the\ncommissioner. Such regulations shall prescribe the date or dates by\nwhich applications for initial registration must be submitted and may\nprovide for staggered initial registration and/or rolling\nre-registration so that re-registrations are distributed as equally as\npossible throughout the year and across multiple years.\n  b. The department shall post an application for registration on its\nwebsite. An application shall be submitted for a registration\ncertificate. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the\ndepartment shall renew the registration of each certificate holder upon\nreceipt of a proper application on a form prescribed by the department.\nAny certificate holder who fails to register by the beginning of the\nappropriate registration period may be subject to late filing penalties\nas prescribed by the commissioner. No certificate holder resuming\npractice after a lapse of registration shall be permitted to practice\nwithout verification of re-registration.\n  c. Any certificate holder who is not engaging in the practice of his\nor her profession in this state and does not desire to register shall so\nadvise the depa...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>