<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="301"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_301">
        <num>301</num>
        <heading>Commissioner of education continued</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 301. Commissioner of education continued.  The office of\ncommissioner of education is hereby continued. Subject to the general\ndirection and control of the regents of the university, he shall\ncontinue to have, exercise and perform the functions, powers and duties\nconferred or imposed by law upon the commissioner of education. He shall\ncontinue to exercise the judicial functions conferred by law upon the\ncommissioner of education and, subject to rules of the regents, to make,\nexecute and issue in the name of the department such determinations,\ndecisions, orders, notices and certificates as may be required for the\nexercise and performance of the functions, powers and duties conferred\nor imposed upon the department. With the approval of the board of\nregents, he shall continue to prepare the annual estimates and requests\nfor appropriations for operation, maintenance and construction of the\nNew York state school for the blind.  All moneys appropriated for the\nNew York school for the blind, or derived from other sources in the\ncourse of the administration thereof, shall be expended upon vouchers\napproved by the commissioner of education, when and in the manner\nauthorized by the board of regents. The regents may adopt rules\nconferring and imposing upon the commissioner of education such\nadditional powers and duties as may be required for the effective\nadministration of the department and of the state system of education.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>