<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3011"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3011"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3011"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3011/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3011/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3011/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3011/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3011">
        <num>3011</num>
        <heading>Contract with teacher</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3011__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section one thousand ninety-six of\nthe tax law and shall be added to any compensation amounts referred to\nabove that have not been paid when owed.\n  2. No contract for the employment of a teacher in a district having\nthree trustees or a board of education shall be made for more than one\nyear in advance or for a shorter time than ten weeks unless for the\npurpose of filling an unexpired term of school; except that a contract\nmay be made in such a district for not more than five years with any\nteacher who has been employed in such district for at least three\nconsecutive years immediately prior to the execution of the contract.\n  3. No contract for the employment of a teacher in a district having a\nsole trustee shall be made to extend beyond the date of the expiration\nof the term of office of such trustee. A sole trustee of a school\ndistrict shall have full power and authority to contract with teachers\nfor the term for which he has been elected any time after the date of\nthe annual meeting at which such trustee was elected.\n  4. No trustee shall contract with any teacher whose certificate of\nqualifications shall not cover a period at least as long as that covered\nby the contract of service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>