<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3012-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3012_C">
        <num>3012-C</num>
        <heading>Annual professional performance review of classroom teachers and building principals</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a\nstate assessments and other comparable measures subcomponent which shall\ncomprise twenty or twenty-five percent of the evaluation; (ii) a locally\nselected measures of student achievement subcomponent which shall\ncomprise twenty or fifteen percent of the evaluation; and (iii) an other\nmeasures of teacher or principal effectiveness subcomponent which shall\ncomprise the remaining sixty percent of the evaluation, which in sum\nshall constitute the composite teacher or principal effectiveness score.\nSuch annual professional performance reviews shall result in a single\ncomposite teacher or principal effectiveness score, which incorporates\nmultiple measures of effectiveness related to the criteria included in\nthe regulations of the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For annual professional performance reviews conducted in\naccordance with paragraph b of this subdivision for the two thousand\neleven--two thousand twelve school year and for annual professional\nperformance reviews conducted in accordance with paragraphs f and g of\nthis subdivision for the two thousand twelve--two thousand thirteen\nschool year, the overall composite scoring ranges shall be in accordance\nwith this subparagraph. A classroom teacher and building principal shall\nbe deemed to be:\n  (A) Highly Effective if they achieve a composite effectiveness score\nof 91-100.\n  (B) Effective if they achieve a composite effectiveness score of\n75-90.\n  (C) Developing if they achieve a composite effectiveness score of\n65-74.\n  (D) Ineffective if they achieve a composite effectiveness score of\n0-64.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For annual professional performance reviews conducted in\naccordance with paragraph b of this subdivision for the two thousand\neleven--two thousand twelve school year and for annual professional\nperformance reviews conducted in accordance with paragraph f of this\nsubdivision for the two thousand twelve--two thousand thirteen school\nyear for classroom teachers in subjects and grades for which the board\nof regents has not approved a value-added model and for building\nprincipals employed in schools or programs for which there is no\napproved principal value-added model, the scoring ranges for the student\ngrowth on state assessments or other comparable measures subcomponent\nshall be in accordance with this subparagraph. A classroom teacher and\nbuilding principal shall receive:\n  (A) a highly effective rating in this subcomponent if the teacher's or\nprincipal's results are well-above the state average for similar\nstudents and they achieve a subcomponent score of 18-20;\n  (B) an...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For annual professional performance reviews conducted in\naccordance with paragraph g of this subdivision for the two thousand\ntwelve--two thousand thirteen school year for classroom teachers in\nsubjects and grades for which the board of regents has approved a\nvalue-added model and for building principals employed in schools or\nprograms for which there is an approved principal value-added model, the\nscoring ranges for the student growth on state assessments or other\ncomparable measures subcomponent shall be in accordance with this\nsubparagraph. A classroom teacher and building principal shall receive:\n  (A) a highly effective rating in this subcomponent if the teacher's or\nprincipal's results are well-above the state average for similar\nstudents and they achieve a subcomponent score of 22-25;\n  (B) an effective rating in this subcomponent if the teacher's or\nprincipal's results meet the state average for similar students and they\nachieve a subcomponent score of 10-21; or\n...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For annual professional performance reviews conducted in\naccordance with paragraph b of this subdivision for the two thousand\neleven--two thousand twelve school year and for annual professional\nperformance reviews conducted in accordance with paragraph f of this\nsubdivision for the two thousand twelve--two thousand thirteen school\nyear for classroom teachers in subjects and grades for which the board\nof regents has not approved a value-added model and for building\nprincipals employed in schools or programs for which there is no\napproved principal value-added model, the scoring ranges for the locally\nselected measures of student achievement subcomponent shall be in\naccordance with this subparagraph.  A classroom teacher and building\nprincipal shall receive:\n  (A) a highly effective rating in this subcomponent if the results are\nwell-above district-adopted expectations for student growth or\nachievement and they achieve a subcomponent score of 18-20; or\n  (B) an effective r...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For annual professional performance reviews conducted in\naccordance with paragraph b of this subdivision for the two thousand\neleven--two thousand twelve school year and for annual professional\nperformance reviews conducted in accordance with paragraph g of this\nsubdivision for the two thousand twelve--two thousand thirteen school\nyear for classroom teachers in subjects and grades for which the board\nof regents has approved a value-added model and for building principals\nemployed in schools or programs for which there is an approved principal\nvalue-added model, the scoring ranges for the locally selected measures\nof student achievement subcomponent shall be in accordance with this\nsubparagraph.  A classroom teacher and building principal shall receive:\n  (A) a highly effective rating in this subcomponent if the results are\nwell-above district-adopted expectations for student growth or\nachievement and they achieve a subcomponent score of 14-15; or\n  (B) an effective rating...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the two thousand thirteen--two thousand fourteen school year\nand thereafter, the commissioner shall review the specific scoring\nranges for each of the rating categories annually before the start of\neach school year and shall recommend any changes to the board of regents\nfor consideration.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except for the student growth measures on the state assessments or\nother comparable measures of student growth prescribed in paragraphs e,\nf and g of this subdivision, the elements comprising the composite\neffectiveness score and the process by which points are assigned to\nsubcomponents shall be locally developed, consistent with the standards\nprescribed in the regulations of the commissioner and the requirements\nof this section, through negotiations conducted, pursuant to the\nrequirements of article fourteen of the civil service law.\n  b.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Annual professional performance reviews conducted by school\ndistricts or boards of cooperative educational services for the two\nthousand eleven--two thousand twelve school year of classroom teachers\nof common branch subjects or English language arts or mathematics in\ngrades four to eight and all building principals of schools in which\nsuch teachers are employed shall be conducted pursuant to this\nsubdivision and shall use two thousand ten--two thousand eleven school\nyear student data as the baseline for the initial computation of the\ncomposite teacher or principal effectiveness score for such classroom\nteachers and principals.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to paragraph k of this subdivision the entire annual\nprofessional performance review shall be completed and provided to the\nteacher or principal as soon as practicable but in no case later than\nSeptember first, two thousand twelve. The provisions of subparagraphs\ntwo and three of paragraph c of this subdivision shall apply to such\nreviews.\n  c.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Annual professional performance reviews conducted by school\ndistricts or boards of cooperative educational services for the two\nthousand twelve--two thousand thirteen school year and thereafter of all\nclassroom teachers and all building principals shall be conducted\npursuant to this subdivision and shall use two thousand eleven--two\nthousand twelve school year student data as the baseline for the initial\ncomputation of the composite teacher or principal effectiveness score\nfor such classroom teachers and principals. For purposes of this\nsection, an administrator in charge of an instructional program of a\nboard of cooperative educational services shall be deemed to be a\nbuilding principal.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to paragraph k of this subdivision the entire annual\nprofessional performance review shall be completed and provided to the\nteacher or principal as soon as practicable but in no case later than\nSeptember first of the school year next following the school year for\nwhich the classroom teacher or building principal's performance is being\nmeasured. The teacher's and principal's score and rating on the locally\nselected measures subcomponent, if available, and on the other measures\nof teacher and principal effectiveness subcomponent for a teacher's or\nprincipal's annual professional performance review shall be computed and\nprovided to the teacher or principal, in writing, by no later than the\nlast day of the school year for which the teacher or principal is being\nmeasured. Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to authorize a\nteacher or principal to trigger the appeal process prior to receipt of\nhis or her composite effectiveness score and rating.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each such annual professional performance review shall be based on\nthe state assessments or other comparable measures subcomponent, the\nlocally selected measures of student achievement subcomponent and the\nother measures of teacher and principal effectiveness subcomponent,\ndetermined in accordance with the applicable provisions of this section\nand the regulations of the commissioner, for the school year for which\nthe teacher's or principal's performance is measured.\n  d. Prior to any evaluation being conducted in accordance with this\nsection, each individual who is responsible for conducting an evaluation\nof a teacher or building principal shall receive appropriate training in\naccordance with the regulations of the commissioner of education.\n  e.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For annual professional performance reviews conducted in\naccordance with paragraph b of this subdivision for the two thousand\neleven--two thousand twelve school year, forty percent of the composite\nscore of effectiveness shall be based on student achievement measures as\nfollows:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>twenty percent of the evaluation shall be based upon\nstudent growth data on state assessments as prescribed by the\ncommissioner or a comparable measure of student growth if such growth\ndata is not available; and (ii) twenty percent shall be based on other\nlocally selected measures of student achievement that are determined to\nbe rigorous and comparable across classrooms in accordance with the\nregulations of the commissioner and as are developed locally in a manner\nconsistent with procedures negotiated pursuant to the requirements of\narticle fourteen of the civil service law.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such locally selected measures may include measures of student\nachievement or growth on state assessments, regents examinations and/or\ndepartment approved equivalent, provided that such measures are\ndifferent from those prescribed by the commissioner pursuant to clause\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subparagraph one of this paragraph. The regulations of the\ncommissioner shall describe the types of measures of student growth or\nachievement that may be locally selected. The selection of the local\nmeasure</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as described in this paragraph to be used by the school\ndistrict or board of cooperative educational services shall be\ndetermined through collective bargaining.\n  f.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_s__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For annual professional performance reviews conducted in\naccordance with paragraph c of this subdivision for the two thousand\ntwelve--two thousand thirteen school year and thereafter for classroom\nteachers in subjects and grades for which the board of regents has not\napproved a value-added model and for building principals employed in\nschools or programs for which there is no approved principal value-added\nmodel, forty percent of the composite score of effectiveness shall be\nbased on student achievement measures as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>twenty percent of\nthe evaluation shall be based upon student growth data on state\nassessments as prescribed by the commissioner or a comparable measure of\nstudent growth if such growth data is not available; and (ii) twenty\npercent shall be based on other locally selected measures of student\nachievement that are determined to be rigorous and comparable across\nclassrooms in accordance with the regulations of the commissioner and as\nare developed locally in a manner consistent with procedures negotiated\npursuant to the requirements of article fourteen of the civil service\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>One or more of the following types of locally selected measures of\nstudent achievement or growth may be used for the evaluation of\nclassroom teachers:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>student achievement or growth on state assessments, regents\nexaminations and/or department approved alternative examinations as\ndescribed in the regulations of the commissioner including, but not\nlimited to, advanced placement examinations, international baccalaureate\nexaminations, and SAT II, using a measure that is different from the\ngrowth score prescribed by the department for student growth on such\nassessments or examinations for purposes of the state assessment or\nother comparable measures subcomponent that is either:\n  (A) the change in percentage of a teacher's students who achieve a\nspecific level of performance as determined locally, on such\nassessments/examinations compared to those students' level of\nperformance on such assessments/examinations in the previous school year\nsuch as a three percentage point increase in students earning the\nproficient level (three) or better performance level on the seventh\ngrade math state assessment compared to those same students' performance\nlevels on the sixth grade math state assessment, or an increase in the\npercentage of a teacher's students earning the advanced performance\nlevel (four) on the fourth grade English language arts or math state\nassessments compared to those students' performance levels on the third\ngrade English language arts or math state assessments; or\n  (B) a teacher specific growth score computed by the department based\non the percent of the teacher's students earning a department determined\nlevel of growth. The methodology to translate such growth into the\nstate-established subcomponent scoring ranges shall be determined\nlocally; or\n  (C) a teacher-specific achievement or growth score computed in a\nmanner determined locally based on a measure of student performance on\nthe state assessments, regents examinations and/or department approved\nalternative examinations other than the measure described in item (A) or\n(B) of this subparagraph;\n  (ii) student growth or achievem...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>where applicable, for teachers in any grade or subject where there\nis no growth or value-added growth model approved by the board of\nregents at that grade level or in that subject, a structured\ndistrict-wide student growth goal-setting process to be used with any\nstate assessment or an approved student assessment or a district,\nregional or BOCES-developed assessment that is rigorous and comparable\nacross classrooms.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>One or more of the following types of locally selected measures of\nstudent achievement or growth may be used for the evaluation of\nprincipals, provided that each measure is rigorous and comparable across\nclassrooms and that any such measure shall be different from that used\nfor the state assessment or other comparable measures subcomponent:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>student achievement levels on state assessments in English\nlanguage arts and/or mathematics in grades four to eight such as\npercentage of students in the school whose performance levels on state\nassessments are proficient or advanced, as defined in the regulations of\nthe commissioner;\n  (ii) student growth or achievement on state or other assessments in\nEnglish language arts and/or mathematics in grades four to eight for\nstudents in each of the performance levels described in the regulations\nof the commissioner;\n  (iii) student growth or achievement on state assessments in English\nlanguage arts and/or mathematics in grades four to eight for students\nwith disabilities and English language learners in grades four to eight;\n  (iv) student performance on any or all of the district-wide locally\nselected measures approved for use in teacher evaluations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for principals employed in a school with high school grades, four,\nfive and/or six-year high school graduation and/or dropout rates;\n  (vi) percentage of students who earn a regents diploma with advanced\ndesignation and/or honors as defined in the regulations of the\ncommissioner, for principals employed in a school with high school\ngrades;\n  (vii) percentage of a cohort of students that achieve specified scores\non regents examinations and/or department approved alternative\nexaminations including, but not limited to, advanced placement\nexaminations, international baccalaureate examinations and SAT II, for\nprincipals employed in a school with high school grades such as the\npercentage of students in the two thousand nine cohort that scored at\nleast a three on an advanced placement examination since entry into the\nninth grade; and/or\n  (viii) students' progress toward graduation in the school using strong\npredictive indicators, including but not limited to ninth and/or tenth\ngrade credit accumulation and/or the percentage of students that pass\nninth and/or tenth grade subjects most commonly associated with\ngraduation and/or students' progress in passing the number of required\nregents examinations for graduation, for principals employed in a school\nwith high school grades.\n  (ix) For school districts or boards of cooperative educational\nservices that choose to use more than one set of locally selected\nmeasures described in this paragraph for principals in the same or\nsimilar grade configuration or program such as one set of locally\nselected measures is used to evaluate principals in some K-5 schools and\nanother set of locally selected measures is used to evaluate principals\nin the other K-5 schools in the district, the superintendent or district\nsuperintendent shall, in their professional performance review plan,\ncertify that the sets of measures are comparable, in accordance with the\ntesting standards as defined in regulations of the commis...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For building principals employed in schools or programs for which\nthere is no approved principal value-added model, the types of locally\nselected measures of student achievement or growth specified in\nsubparagraph three of paragraph g of this subdivision may be used. In\naddition, a structured district-wide student growth goal-setting process\nto be used with any state assessment or an approved student assessment\nor a district, regional of BOCES-developed assessment that is rigorous\nand comparable across classrooms may be a locally selected measure.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_x__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The selection of the local measure or measures as described in\nsubparagraphs two and three of this paragraph to be used by the school\ndistrict or board of cooperative educational services shall be\ndetermined through collective bargaining.\n  g.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_x__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For annual professional performance reviews conducted in\naccordance with paragraph c of this subdivision for the two thousand\ntwelve--two thousand thirteen school year and thereafter for classroom\nteachers in subjects and grades in which there is a value-added growth\nmodel approved by the board of regents and for building principals\nemployed in schools or programs for which there is an approved principal\nvalue-added model, forty percent of the composite score of effectiveness\nshall be based on student achievement measures as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ntwenty-five percent of the evaluation shall be based upon student growth\ndata on state assessments as prescribed by the commissioner or a\ncomparable measure of student growth if such growth data is not\navailable; and (ii) fifteen percent shall be based on other locally\nselected measures of student achievement that are determined to be\nrigorous and comparable across classrooms in accordance with the\nregulations of the commissioner and as are locally developed in a manner\nconsistent with procedures negotiated pursuant to the requirements of\narticle fourteen of the civil service law. The department shall develop\nthe value-added growth model and shall consult with the advisory\ncommittee established pursuant to subdivision seven of this section\nprior to recommending that the board of regents approve its use in\nevaluations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>One or more of the following types of locally selected measures of\nstudent achievement or growth may be used for the evaluation of\nclassroom teachers:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>student achievement or growth on state assessments, regents\nexaminations and/or department approved alternative examinations as\ndescribed in the regulations of the commissioner including, but not\nlimited to, advanced placement examinations, international baccalaureate\nexaminations and SAT II, using a measure that is different from the\ngrowth score prescribed by the department for student growth on such\nassessments or examinations for purposes of the state assessment or\nother comparable measures subcomponent that is either:\n  (A) the change in percentage of a teacher's students who achieve a\nspecific level of performance as determined locally, on such\nassessments/examinations compared to those students' level of\nperformance on such assessments/examinations in the previous school year\nsuch as a three percentage point increase in students earning the\nproficient level (three) or better performance level on the seventh\ngrade math state assessment compared to those same students' performance\nlevels on the sixth grade math state assessment, or an increase in the\npercentage of a teacher's students earning the advanced performance\nlevel (four) on the fourth grade English language arts or math state\nassessments compared to those students' performance levels on the third\ngrade English language arts or math state assessments; or\n  (B) a teacher specific growth score computed by the state based on the\npercent of the teacher's students earning a state determined level of\ngrowth. The methodology to translate such growth into the\nstate-established subcomponent scoring ranges shall be determined\nlocally; or\n  (C) a teacher-specific achievement or growth score computed in a\nmanner determined locally based on a measure of student performance on\nthe state assessments, regents examinations and/or department approved\nalternative examinations other than the measure described in item (A) or\n(B) of this subparagraph;\n  (ii) student growth or achievement compute...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>One or more of the following types of locally selected measures of\nstudent achievement or growth may be used for the evaluation of\nprincipals, provided that each measure is rigorous and comparable across\nclassrooms and that any such measure shall be different from that used\nfor the state assessment or other comparable measures subcomponent:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>student achievement levels on state assessments in English\nlanguage arts and/or mathematics in grades four to eight such as\npercentage of students in the school whose performance levels on state\nassessments are proficient or advanced, as defined in the regulations of\nthe commissioner;\n  (ii) student growth or achievement on state or other assessments in\nEnglish language arts and/or mathematics in grades four to eight for\nstudents in each of the performance levels described in the regulations\nof the commissioner;\n  (iii) student growth or achievement on state assessments in English\nlanguage arts and/or mathematics in grades four to eight for students\nwith disabilities and English language learners in grades four to eight;\n  (iv) student performance on any or all of the district-wide locally\nselected measures approved for use in teacher evaluations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for principals employed in a school with high school grades, four,\nfive and/or six-year high school graduation and/or dropout rates;\n  (vi) percentage of students who earn a regents diploma with advanced\ndesignation and/or honors as defined in the regulations of the\ncommissioner, for principals employed in a school with high school\ngrades;\n  (vii) percentage of a cohort of students that achieve specified scores\non regents examinations and/or department approved alternative\nexaminations including, but not limited to, advanced placement\nexaminations, international baccalaureate examinations and SAT II, for\nprincipals employed in a school with high school grades such as the\npercentage of students in the two thousand nine cohort that scored at\nleast a three on an advanced placement examination since entry into the\nninth grade; and/or\n  (viii) students' progress toward graduation in the school using strong\npredictive indicators, including but not limited to ninth and/or tenth\ngrade credit accumulation and/or the percentage of students that pass\nninth and/or tenth grade subjects most commonly associated with\ngraduation and/or students' progress in passing the number of required\nregents examinations for graduation, for principals employed in a school\nwith high school grades.\n  (ix) For school districts or boards of cooperative educational\nservices that choose to use more than one set of locally selected\nmeasures described in this paragraph for principals in the same or\nsimilar grade configuration or program, the superintendent or district\nsuperintendent shall, in their professional performance review plan,\ncertify that the sets of measures are comparable, in accordance with the\ntesting standards as defined in regulations of the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The selection of the local measure or measures as described in\nsubparagraphs two and three of this paragraph to be used by the school\ndistrict or board of cooperative educational services shall be\ndetermined through collective bargaining.\n  h. The remaining sixty percent of the evaluations, ratings and\neffectiveness scores shall be locally developed, consistent with the\nstandards prescribed in the regulations of the commissioner, through\nnegotiations conducted pursuant to article fourteen of the civil service\nlaw.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A majority of the sixty points for classroom teachers shall be\nbased on multiple classroom observations conducted by a principal or\nother trained administrator, which may be performed in-person or by\nvideo. For evaluations for the two thousand twelve--two thousand\nthirteen school year and thereafter, at least one such observation shall\nbe an unannounced visit.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the remaining portion of these sixty points for evaluations\nfor the two thousand eleven--two thousand twelve school year, the\ncommissioner's regulation shall prescribe the other forms of evidence of\nteacher and principal effectiveness that may be used.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For evaluations of classroom teachers for the two thousand\ntwelve--two thousand thirteen school year and thereafter, the remaining\nportion of these sixty points shall be based on one or more of the\nfollowing:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one or more classroom observations by independent trained\nevaluators selected by the school district or board of cooperative\neducational services who are teachers or former teachers with a\ndemonstrated record of effectiveness and have no prior affiliation with\nthe school in which they are conducting the evaluation and no other\nrelationship with the teachers being evaluated that would affect their\nimpartiality;\n  (ii) classroom observations by trained in-school peer teachers; and/or\n  (iii) use of a state-approved instrument for parent or student\nfeedback; and/or\n  (iv) evidence of student development and performance through lesson\nplans, student portfolios and other artifacts of teacher practices\nthrough a structured review process.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A majority of these sixty points for building principals shall be\nbased on a broad assessment of the principal's leadership and management\nactions based on the principal practice rubric by the building\nprincipal's supervisor, a trained administrator or a trained independent\nevaluator, with one or more visits conducted by the supervisor, and, for\nevaluations for the two thousand twelve--two thousand thirteen school\nyear and thereafter, that such assessment must incorporate multiple\nschool visits by a supervisor, a trained administrator or other trained\nevaluator, with at least one visit conducted by the supervisor and at\nleast one unannounced visit. For the remaining portion of these sixty\npoints for evaluations for the two thousand eleven--two thousand twelve\nschool year, such regulations shall also prescribe the other forms of\nevidence of principal effectiveness that may be used consistent with the\nstandards prescribed by the commissioner.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For evaluations of building principals for the two thousand\ntwelve--two thousand thirteen school year and thereafter, the remaining\nportion of these sixty points shall include, in addition to the\nrequirements of subparagraph three of this paragraph, at least two other\nsources of evidence from the following options: feedback from teachers,\nstudents, and/or families using state-approved instruments; school\nvisits by other trained evaluators; and/or review of school documents,\nrecords, and/or state accountability processes. Any such remaining\npoints shall be assigned based on the results of one or more ambitious\nand measurable goals set collaboratively with principals and their\nsuperintendents or district superintendents as follows:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at least one goal must address the principal's contribution to\nimproving teacher effectiveness, which shall include one or more of the\nfollowing: improved retention of high performing teachers, the\ncorrelation between student growth scores of teachers granted tenure as\nopposed to those denied tenure; or improvements in the proficiency\nrating of the principal on specific teacher effectiveness standards in\nthe principal practice rubric.\n  (ii) any other goals shall address quantifiable and verifiable\nimprovements in academic results or the school's learning environmental\nsuch as student or teacher attendance.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district or board of cooperative educational services shall\nestablish specific minimum and maximum scoring ranges for each\nperformance level within this subcomponent before the start of each\nschool year and shall assign points to a teacher or principal for this\nsubcomponent based on the standards prescribed in the regulations of the\ncommissioner, all in accordance with, and subject to, the requirements\nof paragraph j of this subdivision.\n  i. For purposes of this section, student growth means the change in\nstudent achievement for an individual student between two or more points\nin time.\n  j.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The process by which points are assigned in subcomponents and\nthe scoring ranges for the subcomponents must be transparent and\navailable to those being rated before the beginning of each school year.\nThe process by which points are assigned in the respective subcomponents\nare to be determined as follows:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the state assessment or other comparable measures\nsubcomponent, that process shall be formulated by the commissioner with\nthe approval of the board of regents.\n  (ii) For the locally selected measures of the student achievement\nsubcomponent, that process shall be established locally through\nnegotiations conducted under article fourteen of the civil service law.\n  (iii) For the other measures of teacher and principal effectiveness\nsubcomponent, that process shall be established locally through\nnegotiations conducted under article fourteen of the civil services law.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such process must ensure that it is possible for a teacher or\nprincipal to obtain each point in the applicable scoring ranges,\nincluding zero, for the state assessment or other comparable measures\nsubcomponent, the locally selected measures of student achievement\nsubcomponent and the overall rating categories. The process must also\nensure that it is possible for a teacher or principal to obtain each\npoint in the scoring ranges prescribed by the district or board of\ncooperative educational services for the other measures of teacher and\nprincipal effectiveness subcomponent.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The superintendent, district superintendent or chancellor and the\npresident of the collective bargaining representative (where one exists)\nshall certify in its plan that the process will use the narrative\ndescriptions of the standards for the scoring ranges provided in the\nregulations of the commissioner to effectively differentiate a teacher\nor principal's performance in each of the subcomponents and in their\noverall ratings to improve student learning and instruction.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The scoring ranges for the other measures of teacher and principal\neffectiveness subcomponent shall be established locally through\nnegotiations conducted under article fourteen of the civil service law.\n  k. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule or regulation to\nthe contrary, by July first, two thousand twelve, the governing body of\neach school district and board of cooperative educational services shall\nadopt a plan, on a form prescribed by the commissioner, for the annual\nprofessional performance review of all of its classroom teachers and\nbuilding principals in accordance with the requirements of this section\nand the regulations of the commissioner, and shall submit such plan to\nthe commissioner for approval. The plan may be an annual or multi-year\nplan, for the annual professional performance review of all of its\nclassroom teachers and building principals. The commissioner shall\napprove or reject the plan by September first, two thousand twelve, or\nas soon ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>professional teaching standards; (ii) standards for\nprofessional contexts; and (iii) standards for a continuum of system\nsupport for teachers and principals developed in consultation with the\nadvisory committee. Regulations promulgated pursuant to this section\nshall be effective no later than July first, two thousand eleven, for\nimplementation in the two thousand eleven--two thousand twelve school\nyear.\n  8. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule or regulation to\nthe contrary, all collective bargaining agreements applicable to\nclassroom teachers or building principals entered into after July first,\ntwo thousand ten shall be consistent with requirements of this section.\nNothing in this section shall be construed to abrogate any conflicting\nprovisions of any collective bargaining agreement in effect on July\nfirst, two thousand ten during the term of such agreement and until the\nentry into a successor collective bargaining agreement, provided that\nnotwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, upon\nexpiration of such term and the entry into a successor collective\nbargaining agreement the provisions of this section shall apply.\nFurthermore, nothing in this section or in any rule or regulation\npromulgated hereunder shall in any way, alter, impair or diminish the\nrights of a local collective bargaining representative to negotiate\nevaluation procedures in accordance with article fourteen of the civil\nservice law with the school district or board of cooperative educational\nservices.\n  9. a. The department shall annually monitor and analyze trends and\npatterns in teacher and principal evaluation results and data to\nidentify school districts, boards of cooperative educational services\nand/or schools where evidence suggests that a more rigorous evaluation\nsystem is needed to improve educator effectiveness and student learning\noutcomes. The criteria for identifying school districts, boards of\ncooperative educational services ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>