<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3012-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3012_E">
        <num>3012-E</num>
        <heading>Teacher and principal performance review plans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A school board or board of cooperative educational services\nshall make its most recently adopted and reviewed plan pursuant to this\nsection available on the school district or board of cooperative\neducational services' website.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On an annual basis, each school district and board of cooperative\neducational services shall submit to the commissioner the ratings for\neach classroom teacher and building principal on each applicable\nteaching or leadership standard, as well as the overall rating for each\nteacher and principal, where available, on a form and in a manner\nprescribed by the commissioner. Such data shall be collected and used to\nthe extent necessary to comply with any applicable state and federal\nstatutory requirements.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner and each school district and board of cooperative\neducational services shall ensure that any release to the public of data\ncollected pursuant to this section, or any other data that is used as a\ncomponent of performance reviews, does not include personally\nidentifying information for any classroom teacher or building principal;\nprovided, however, that each school district or board of cooperative\neducational services shall fully disclose and release to the parents or\nlegal guardians of a student the most recent performance review rating\nreceived for each of the teachers and for the principal of the school\nbuilding to which the student is assigned for the current school year\nconsistent with paragraph b of subdivision ten of section three thousand\ntwelve-c of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Performance reviews of individual classroom teachers and building\nprincipals shall not be subject to disclosure pursuant to article six of\nthe public officers law.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Performance review plans developed pursuant to this section\nshall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>include the criteria by which all classroom teachers and building\nprincipals shall be reviewed and a description of the review procedures;\n  (ii) address each state teaching and educational leadership standard,\nas developed or adopted by the commissioner;\n  (iii) consist of multiple measures; provided, however, that one\nmeasure shall be classroom observations of classroom teachers and school\nvisits of building principals. The plan shall describe the number and\nfrequency of observations; provided that nothing herein shall be\nconstrued to require that all classroom teachers or building principals\nhave the same number or frequency of observations.\n  (iv) provide the classroom teacher or building principal with timely,\nactionable feedback on their practice based on the information collected\nas part of the performance review;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>assign ratings on each applicable teaching or educational\nleadership standard and an overall rating of Level 4, Level 3, Level 2,\nor Level 1 consistent with the following requirements:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Level 1 shall indicate performance significantly below a school\ndistrict's or board of cooperative educational services' expectations\naligned to teaching or educational leadership standards;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Level 2 shall indicate performance that partially meets a school\ndistrict's or board of cooperative educational services' expectations\naligned to teaching or educational leadership standards;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Level 3 shall indicate performance that meets a school district's\nor board of cooperative educational services' expectations aligned to\nteaching or educational leadership standards; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Level 4 shall indicate performance that exceeds a school\ndistrict's or board of cooperative educational services' expectations\naligned to teaching or educational leadership standards;\n  (vi) ensure that it is possible for a classroom teacher or building\nprincipal to obtain each rating on each teaching or educational\nleadership standard and as an overall rating. The process by which\nratings are assigned shall be transparent and available to those being\nrated prior to the start of the school year, to the extent practicable;\nand\n  (vii) include a process for each classroom teacher and building\nprincipal to receive formal support for professional growth each year,\nprovided that teachers and principals who receive an overall rating of\nLevel 1 or 2 shall have a personalized professional development plan,\ndeveloped by the school district or board of cooperative educational\nservices, consistent with a locally determined growth goal setting\nprocess.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>One measure may be used to address more than one teaching or\neducational leadership standard provided that the performance review\nincludes multiple measures.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Performance reviews conducted pursuant to this section may assess\na subset of the teaching and educational leadership standards in a given\nyear; provided, however, that probationary classroom teachers and\nbuilding principals shall be rated on each teaching or educational\nleadership standard annually.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_E__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require all\nclassroom teachers or building principals to be evaluated based on the\nsame measures or to receive an overall rating annually; provided,\nhowever, that at a minimum, probationary teachers and principals shall\nreceive a rating on each teaching or educational leadership standard and\nan overall rating annually, while other teachers and principals may have\na differentiated performance review process that does not culminate in\nan overall rating annually. Provided, further, that nothing herein shall\nbe construed to prohibit or prevent any other teachers and principals\nfrom receiving an overall rating annually.\n  6. The school district or board of cooperative educational services,\nas applicable, shall ensure that all classroom teachers and building\nprincipals as well as any individual who conducts all or part of a\nperformance review receive appropriate training consistent with the\nregulations of the commissioner and shall ensure that each teacher and\nprincipal who is reviewed in accordance with this section has the\nopportunity to provide written comment on their performance review in\naddition to any collectively bargained teacher and principal performance\nreview grievance or appeal procedures.\n  7. Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the unfettered\nstatutory right of a school district or board of cooperative educational\nservices, as applicable, to terminate a probationary classroom teacher\nor principal for any statutorily and constitutionally permissible\nreasons.\n  8. Performance review plans developed pursuant to this section shall\nbe submitted to the commissioner on a form and in a manner prescribed by\nthe commissioner. The commissioner shall review such plan to determine\ncompliance with the requirements of this section. If the commissioner\ndetermines that the submitted plan is not in compliance with this\nsection, the plan shall be returned to the school district or boa...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>