<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3014"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3014">
        <num>3014</num>
        <heading>Tenure: boards of cooperative educational services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3014__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nAdministrative assistants, supervisors, teachers and all other members\nof the teaching and supervising staff of the board of cooperative\neducational services appointed prior to July first, two thousand\nfifteen, shall be appointed by a majority vote of the board of\ncooperative educational services upon the recommendation of the district\nsuperintendent of schools for a probationary period of not to exceed\nthree years; provided, however, that in the case of a teacher who has\nbeen appointed on tenure in a school district within the state, the\nboard of cooperative educational services where currently employed, or\nanother board of cooperative educational services, and who was not\ndismissed from such district or board as a result of charges brought\npursuant to subdivision one of section three thousand twenty-a of this\narticle, the probationary period shall not exceed two years. Services of\na person so appointed to any such positions may be discontinued at any\ntime during such probationary period, upon the recommendation of the\ndistrict superintendent, by a majority vote of the board of cooperative\neducational services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3014__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Administrative assistants, supervisors, teachers and all other\nmembers of the teaching and supervising staff of the board of\ncooperative educational services appointed on or after July first, two\nthousand fifteen, shall be appointed by a majority vote of the board of\ncooperative educational services upon the recommendation of the district\nsuperintendent of schools for a probationary period of not to exceed\nfour years; provided, however, that in the case of a teacher who has\nbeen appointed on tenure in a school district within the state, the\nboard of cooperative educational services where currently employed, or\nanother board of cooperative educational services, and who was not\ndismissed from such district or board as a result of charges brought\npursuant to section three thousand twenty-a of this article, the teacher\nshall be appointed for a probationary period of three years; and\nprovided further that in the case of a principal, administrator,\nsupervisor, or other member of the supervising staff who has been\nappointed on tenure pursuant to this chapter as an administrator within\nan authorized administrative tenure area in another school district\nwithin the state, the school district where currently employed, or a\nboard of cooperative educational services, and who was not dismissed\nfrom such district or board as a result of charges brought pursuant to\nsubdivision one of section three thousand twenty-a of this article, the\nprincipal, administrator, supervisor, or other member of the supervising\nstaff shall be appointed for a probationary period of three years.\nServices of a person so appointed to any such positions to which this\nparagraph applies may be discontinued at any time during the\nprobationary period, upon the recommendation of the district\nsuperintendent, by a majority vote of the board of cooperative\neducational services.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3014__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before the expiration of the probationary term of a\nperson appointed for such term prior to July first, two thousand\nfifteen, the district superintendent of schools shall make a written\nreport to the board of cooperative educational services recommending for\nappointment on tenure persons who have been found competent, efficient\nand satisfactory. Such persons shall hold their respective positions\nduring good behavior and competent and efficient service and shall not\nbe removed except for any of the following causes, after a hearing, as\nprovided by section three thousand twenty-a of this article:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3014__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nInsubordination, immoral character or conduct unbecoming a teacher; (ii)\nInefficiency, incompetency, or neglect of duty; (iii) Failure to\nmaintain certification as required by this chapter and by the\nregulations of the commissioner. Each person who is not to be so\nrecommended for appointment on tenure shall be so notified in writing by\nthe district superintendent not later than sixty days immediately\npreceding the expiration of such person's probationary period.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3014__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before the expiration of the probationary term of a person\nappointed for such term on or after July first, two thousand fifteen,\nthe district superintendent of schools shall make a written report to\nthe board of cooperative educational services recommending for\nappointment on tenure persons who have been found competent, efficient\nand satisfactory. Such persons shall hold their respective positions\nduring good behavior and competent and efficient service and shall not\nbe removed except for any of the following causes, after a hearing, as\nprovided by section three thousand twenty-a of this article:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3014__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nInsubordination, immoral character or conduct unbecoming a teacher; (ii)\nInefficiency, incompetency, or neglect of duty; (iii) Failure to\nmaintain certification as required by this chapter and by the\nregulations of the commissioner. Each person who is not to be so\nrecommended for appointment on tenure shall be so notified in writing by\nthe district superintendent not later than sixty days immediately\npreceding the expiration of such person's probationary period.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>