<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3014-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3014-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3014_D">
        <num>3014-D</num>
        <heading>Teachers' rights as a result of a school district sending students to another district on a tuition basis pursuant to section two thousan...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3014-d. Teachers' rights as a result of a school district sending\nstudents to another district on a tuition basis pursuant to section two\nthousand forty of this chapter.  1. As used in this section, a "sending\ndistrict" shall mean a school district which sends students to another\nschool district on a tuition basis pursuant to section two thousand\nforty of this chapter, and a "receiving district" shall mean a school\ndistrict which receives and provides the educational program for\nstudents from another district on a tuition basis pursuant to section\ntwo thousand forty of this chapter.\n  2. In any case in which a sending district sends such students to a\nreceiving district, each teacher previously employed in the education of\nstudents by such sending district prior to the time that such sending\ndistrict sends its students to a receiving district shall be considered\nan employee of such receiving district, with the same tenure status he\nmaintained in such sending district.\n  3. If the number of teaching positions needed to provide the\neducational services required by such receiving district is less than\nthe number of teachers eligible to be considered employees of such\nreceiving district as provided by subdivision two of this section, the\nservices of the teachers having the least seniority in the sending\ndistrict within the tenure area of the position shall be discontinued.\nSuch teachers shall be placed on a preferred eligible list of candidates\nfor appointment to a vacancy that may thereafter occur in an office or\nposition under the jurisdiction of the sending district and the\nreceiving district similar to the one such teacher filled in such\nsending district. The teachers on such preferred list shall be\nreinstated or appointed to such vacancies in such corresponding or\nsimilar positions under the jurisdiction of the sending district or the\nreceiving district in the order of their length of service in such\nsending district, within seven years from the date of the abolition of\nsuch office or position.\n  4. For any such teacher as described in subdivision two of this\nsection for salary, sick leave and any other purposes, the length of\nservice credited in such sending district shall be credited as\nemployment time with such receiving district.\n  5. This section shall in no way be construed to limit the rights of\nany of such teachers described in this section granted by any other\nprovision of law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>