<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3020-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3020-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3020-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3020-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3020-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3020-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3020-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3020_A">
        <num>3020-A</num>
        <heading>Disciplinary procedures and penalties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3020_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the charges in detail, (ii) the maximum penalty\nwhich will be imposed by the board if the employee does not request a\nhearing or that will be sought by the board if the employee is found\nguilty of the charges after a hearing and (iii) the employee's rights\nunder this section, shall be immediately forwarded to the accused\nemployee by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested or by\npersonal delivery to the employee.\n  b. The employee may be suspended pending a hearing on the charges and\nthe final determination thereof. The suspension shall be with pay,\nexcept the employee may be suspended without pay if the employee has\nentered a guilty plea to or has been convicted of a felony crime\nconcerning the criminal sale or possession of a controlled substance, a\nprecursor of a controlled substance, or drug paraphernalia as defined in\narticle two hundred twenty or two hundred twenty-one of the penal law;\nor a felony crime involving the physical abuse of a minor or student.\n  c. Where charges of misconduct constituting physical or sexual abuse\nof a student are brought on or after July first, two thousand fifteen,\nthe board of education may suspend the employee without pay pending an\nexpedited hearing pursuant to subparagraph (i-a) of paragraph c of\nsubdivision three of this section. Notwithstanding any other law, rule,\nor regulation to the contrary, the commissioner shall establish a\nprocess in regulations for a probable cause hearing before an impartial\nhearing officer within ten days to determine whether the decision to\nsuspend an employee without pay pursuant to this paragraph should be\ncontinued or reversed. The process for selection of an impartial hearing\nofficer shall be as similar as possible to the regulatory framework for\nthe appointment of an impartial hearing officer for due process\ncomplaints pursuant to section forty-four hundred four of this chapter.\nThe hearing officer shall determine whether probable cause supports the\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3020_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For hearings commenced by the filing of charges prior to July\nfirst, two thousand fifteen, within ten days of receipt of the statement\nof charges, the employee shall notify the clerk or secretary of the\nemploying board in writing whether he or she desires a hearing on the\ncharges and when the charges concern pedagogical incompetence or issues\ninvolving pedagogical judgment, his or her choice of either a single\nhearing officer or a three member panel, provided that a three member\npanel shall not be available where the charges concern pedagogical\nincompetence based solely upon a teacher's or principal's pattern of\nineffective teaching or performance as defined in section three thousand\ntwelve-c of this article. All other charges shall be heard by a single\nhearing officer.\n  (ii) All hearings commenced by the filing of charges on or after July\nfirst, two thousand fifteen shall be heard by a single hearing officer.\n  f. The unexcused failure of the employee to notify the clerk or\nsecretary of his or her desire for a hearing within ten days of the\nreceipt of charges shall be deemed a waiver of the right to a hearing.\nWhere an employee requests a hearing in the manner provided for by this\nsection, the clerk or secretary of the board shall, within three working\ndays of receipt of the employee's notice or request for a hearing,\nnotify the commissioner of the need for a hearing. If the employee\nwaives his or her right to a hearing the employing board shall proceed,\nwithin fifteen days, by a vote of a majority of all members of such\nboard, to determine the case and fix the penalty, if any, to be imposed\nin accordance with subdivision four of this section.\n  3. Hearings. a. Notice of hearing. Upon receipt of a request for a\nhearing in accordance with subdivision two of this section, the\ncommissioner shall forthwith notify the American Arbitration Association\n(hereinafter "association") of the need for a hearing and shall request\nthe association to ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3020_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Hearing officers. All hearings pursuant to this section shall\nbe conducted before and by a single hearing officer selected as provided\nfor in this section. A hearing officer shall not be eligible to serve in\nsuch position if he or she is a resident of the school district, other\nthan the city of New York, under the jurisdiction of the employing\nboard, an employee, agent or representative of the employing board or of\nany labor organization representing employees of such employing board,\nhas served as such agent or representative within two years of the date\nof the scheduled hearing, or if he or she is then serving as a mediator\nor fact finder in the same school district.\n  (A) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for hearings commenced\nby the filing of charges prior to April first, two thousand twelve, the\nhearing officer shall be compensated by the department with the\ncustomary fee paid for service as an arbitrator under the auspices of\nthe association for each day of actual service plus necessary travel and\nother reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of his or her\nduties. All other expenses of the disciplinary proceedings commenced by\nthe filing of charges prior to April first, two thousand twelve shall be\npaid in accordance with rules promulgated by the commissioner. Claims\nfor such compensation for days of actual service and reimbursement for\nnecessary travel and other expenses for hearings commenced by the filing\nof charges prior to April first, two thousand twelve shall be paid from\nan appropriation for such purpose in the order in which they have been\napproved by the commissioner for payment, provided payment shall first\nbe made for any other hearing costs payable by the commissioner,\nincluding the costs of transcribing the record, and provided further\nthat no such claim shall be set aside for insufficiency of funds to make\na complete payment, but shall be eligible for a partial payment in one\nyear and shall retain i...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3020_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>(A) The commissioner shall have the power\nto establish necessary rules and procedures for the conduct of hearings\nunder this section.\n  (B) The department shall be authorized to monitor and investigate a\nhearing officer's compliance with statutory timelines pursuant to this\nsection. The commissioner shall annually inform all hearing officers who\nhave heard cases pursuant to this section during the preceding year that\nthe time periods prescribed in this section for conducting such hearings\nare to be strictly followed. A record of continued failure to commence\nand complete hearings within the time periods prescribed in this section\nshall be considered grounds for the commissioner to exclude such\nindividual from the list of potential hearing officers sent to the\nemploying board and the employee for such hearings.\n  (C) Such rules shall not require compliance with technical rules of\nevidence. Hearings shall be conducted by the hearing officer selected\npursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision with full and fair\ndisclosure of the nature of the case and evidence against the employee\nby the employing board and shall be public or private at the discretion\nof the employee and provided further that the hearing officer, at the\npre-hearing conference, shall set a schedule and manner for full and\nfair disclosure of the witnesses and evidence to be offered by the\nemployee. The employee shall have a reasonable opportunity to defend\nhimself or herself and an opportunity to testify in his or her own\nbehalf. The employee shall not be required to testify. Each party shall\nhave the right to be represented by counsel, to subpoena witnesses, and\nto cross-examine witnesses. All testimony taken shall be under oath\nwhich the hearing officer is hereby authorized to administer. A child\nwitness under the age of fourteen may be permitted to testify through\nthe use of live, two-way closed-circuit television, as such term is\ndefined in subdivision four of section 65...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3020_A__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that at the pre-hearing conference the employing\nboard presents evidence that the professional license of the employee\nhas been revoked and all judicial and administrative remedies have been\nexhausted or foreclosed, the hearing officer shall schedule the date,\ntime and place for an expedited hearing, which hearing shall commence\nnot more than seven days after the pre-hearing conference and which\nshall be limited to one day. The expedited hearing shall be held in the\nlocal school district or county seat of the county or any county,\nwherein the said employing board is located. The expedited hearing shall\nnot be postponed except upon the request of a party and then only for\ngood cause as determined by the hearing officer. At such hearing, each\nparty shall have equal time in which to present its case.\n  (vi) During the pre-hearing conference, the hearing officer shall\ndetermine the reasonable amount of time necessary for a final hearing on\nthe charge or charges and shall schedule the location, time</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3020_A__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and\ndate</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3020_A__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the final hearing. The final hearing shall be held in the\nlocal school district or county seat of the county, or any county,\nwherein the said employing school board is located. In the event that\nthe hearing officer determines that the nature of the case requires the\nfinal hearing to last more than one day, the days that are scheduled for\nthe final hearing shall be consecutive. The day or days scheduled for\nthe final hearing shall not be postponed except upon the request of a\nparty and then only for good cause shown as determined by the hearing\nofficer. In all cases, the final hearing shall be completed no later\nthan sixty days after the pre-hearing conference unless the hearing\nofficer determines that extraordinary circumstances warrant a limited\nextension.\n  (vii) All evidence shall be submitted by all parties within one\nhundred twenty-five days of the filing of charges and no additional\nevidence shall be accepted after such time, absent extraordinary\ncircumstances beyond the control of the parties.\n  d. Limitation on claims. Notwithstanding any other provision of law,\nrule or regulation to the contrary, no payments shall be made by the\ndepartment pursuant to this subdivision on or after April first, two\nthousand twelve for:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3020_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>compensation of a hearing officer or hearing\npanel member, (ii) reimbursement of such hearing officers or panel\nmembers for necessary travel or other expenses incurred by them, or\n(iii) for other hearing expenses on a claim submitted later than one\nyear after the final disposition of the hearing by any means, including\nsettlement, or within ninety days after the effective date of this\nparagraph, whichever is later; provided that no payment shall be barred\nor reduced where such payment is required as a result of a court order\nor judgment or a final audit.\n  4. Post hearing procedures. a. The hearing officer shall render a\nwritten decision within thirty days of the last day of the final\nhearing, or in the case of an expedited hearing within ten days of such\nexpedited hearing, and shall forward a copy thereof to the commissioner\nwho shall immediately forward copies of the decision to the employee and\nto the clerk or secretary of the employing board. The written decision\nshall include the hearing officer's findings of fact on each charge, his\nor her conclusions with regard to each charge based on said findings and\nshall state what penalty or other action, if any, shall be taken by the\nemploying board. At the request of the employee, in determining what, if\nany, penalty or other action shall be imposed, the hearing officer may\nconsider the extent to which the employing board made efforts towards\ncorrecting the behavior of the employee which resulted in charges being\nbrought under this section through means including but not limited to:\nremediation, peer intervention or an employee assistance plan. In those\ncases where a penalty is imposed, such penalty may be a written\nreprimand, a fine, suspension for a fixed time without pay, or\ndismissal. In addition to or in lieu of the aforementioned penalties,\nthe hearing officer, where he or she deems appropriate, may impose upon\nthe employee remedial action including but not limited to leaves of\nabsen...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>