<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3036"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3036"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3036"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3036/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3036/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3036/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3036/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3036">
        <num>3036</num>
        <heading>Coursework for reporting child abuse and maltreatment for those with coaching licenses or coaching certificates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3036. Coursework for reporting child abuse and maltreatment for\nthose with coaching licenses or coaching certificates. 1.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the commissioner shall\nprescribe regulations requiring that all persons currently holding a\ntemporary coaching license or a professional coaching certificate and\npersons applying for such license or certificate shall, in addition to\nall the other licensure or certification requirements, have completed\ntwo hours of coursework or training regarding the identification and\nreporting of child abuse and maltreatment. The coursework or training\nshall be obtained from an institution or provider which has been\napproved by the department to provide such coursework or training. The\ncoursework or training shall include information regarding the physical\nand behavioral indicators of child abuse and maltreatment and the\nstatutory reporting requirements set out in sections four hundred\nthirteen through four hundred twenty of the social services law,\nincluding but not limited to, when and how a report must be made, what\nother actions the reporter is mandated or authorized to take, the legal\nprotections afforded reporters, and the consequences for failing to\nreport. Each applicant shall provide the department with documentation\nshowing that he or she has completed the required training.\n  2. Persons currently holding a temporary coaching license or a\nprofessional coaching certificate shall meet the coursework or training\nrequirements prescribed in subdivision one of this section no later than\nJuly first, two thousand fifteen.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>