<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3037"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3037"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3037"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3037/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3037/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3037/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3037/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3037">
        <num>3037</num>
        <heading>Grants for hiring teachers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3037__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is certified to teach in New York\nstate pursuant to section three thousand four of this article; or holds\na Master's degree or Ph.D. in Mathematics, Science, Technology or\nEducation; or holds a Bachelor's degree in Mathematics, Science,\nTechnology or Education and is currently enrolled in a Master's or Ph.D.\nprogram in Mathematics, Science, Technology or Education within five\nyears from the later of the effective date of this section or the\nemployment start date with the nonpublic school,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3037__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>teaches\nMathematics, Science or Technology in any grades from three through\ntwelve, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3037__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is employed by a nonpublic school.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3037__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within amounts appropriated therefor, nonpublic schools shall,\nupon application, be reimbursed by the department for the salaries of\neligible teachers. Each school which seeks a reimbursement pursuant to\nthis section shall submit to the office of religious and independent\nschools an application therefor, together with such additional documents\nas the commissioner may reasonably require, at such times, in such form\nand containing such information as the commissioner may prescribe by\nregulation. Applications for reimbursement pursuant to this section must\nbe received by August first of each year for schools to be reimbursed\nfor the salaries of eligible teachers in the prior year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3037__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3037__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, reimbursement for\neligible teachers shall be the average comparable teacher salary and\npersonal service, per subject area, of public school teachers in the\nschool district in which such nonpublic schools are located, multiplied\nby the percentage of full time equivalent secular instructional hours\ncompleted in the school day per subject area. Reimbursements shall not\nbe provided for eligible teachers who provide instruction in\nmathematics, science or technology if such teachers also provide\nnon-secular instruction in any capacity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3037__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that the applications for reimbursement under this\nsection exceed the appropriation available for this program, then each\napplicant shall only be reimbursed an amount equal to the percentage\nthat each such applicant represents to the total of all applications\nsubmitted.\n  3. The commissioner may promulgate any rules or regulations necessary\nto carry out the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>