<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-10-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="305"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_305">
        <num>305</num>
        <heading>General powers and duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The termination of employment was based solely on the conviction\nof a sex offense, or conviction of a violent felony offense or offenses\ncommitted against a child when such child was the intended victim of\nsuch offense or the revocation or annulment of a certificate based on\nsuch conviction, and such conviction has been set aside on appeal or\notherwise reversed, vacated or annulled and the commissioner has\nreinstated the teacher's certification pursuant to paragraph e of this\nsubdivision; or\n  (ii) The termination of employment was based solely on the conviction\nof a sex offense or violent felony offense or offenses committed against\na child when such child was the intended victim of such offense and it\nhas been determined that the teacher is not the same person as the\nconvicted offender.\n  g. If a teacher's employment was terminated as a result of a\ndisciplinary proceeding conducted pursuant to section three thousand\ntwenty-a of this chapter or other disciplinary hearing conducted\npursuant to any collective bargaining or contractual agreement on one or\nmore grounds other than conviction of a sex offense, or the revocation\nor annulment of a certificate based on such conviction, then nothing in\nparagraph f of this subdivision shall require a school district to\nreinstate employment of such teacher or be liable for back pay or\nbenefits.\n  h. No provision of this article shall be deemed to preclude the\nfollowing:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the commissioner from conducting a due process hearing\npursuant to subdivision seven of this section and part eighty-three of\ntitle eight of the New York codes, rules and regulations; or (ii) a\nschool district or employing board from bringing a disciplinary\nproceeding pursuant to section three thousand twenty-a or three thousand\ntwenty-b of this chapter; or (iii) a school district or employing board\nfrom bringing an alternative disciplinary proceeding conducted pursuant\nto a collective bargaining or contractual agreement.\n  i. The commissioner shall be authorized to promulgate any regulations\nnecessary to implement the provisions of this subdivision.\n  7-b. a. In addition to the authority to revoke and annul a certificate\nof qualification of a teacher in a proceeding brought pursuant to\nsubdivisions seven and seven-a of this section, the commissioner shall\nbe authorized, and it shall be his or her duty, to revoke and annul in\naccordance with this subdivision the certificate of a school\nadministrator or supervisor convicted of an offense listed under\nsubparagraph two of paragraph b of this subdivision.\n  b. As used in this subdivision, the following terms shall have the\nfollowing meanings:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"conviction" means any conviction whether by plea of guilty or\nnolo contendere or from a verdict after trial or otherwise;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"offense" means defrauding the government as defined in section\n195.20 of the penal law, and any such offense in any other jurisdiction\nwhich includes all of the elements of such felony and for which a\nsentence to a term of imprisonment in excess of one year was authorized\nand is authorized in such state, irrespective of whether such sentence\nwas imposed;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"school administrator or supervisor" means any professional school\ndistrict administrator, school administrator or supervisor, or school\nbusiness administrator holding a certificate as defined in subparagraph\nfour of this paragraph; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"certificate" means the certificate or license or other\ncertificate of qualification granted to qualify an individual to serve\nas a school administrator or supervisor by any authority whatsoever.\n  c. Upon receipt of a certified copy of a criminal history record\nshowing that a school administrator or supervisor has been convicted of\nan offense as defined in subparagraph two of paragraph b of this\nsubdivision or upon receipt of notice of such a conviction as provided\nin paragraph d of this subdivision, the commissioner shall automatically\nrevoke and annul the certificate of such school administrator or\nsupervisor without the right to a hearing. The commissioner shall mail\nnotice of the revocation pursuant to this subdivision by certified mail,\nreturn receipt requested, and by first-class mail directed to the school\nadministrator's or supervisor's last known address and, if different,\nthe last address filed by the certificate holder with the commissioner\nand to the school a...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The termination of employment was based solely on the conviction\nof an offense defined in subparagraph two of paragraph b of this\nsubdivision, or the revocation or annulment of a certificate based on\nsuch conviction, and such conviction has been set aside on appeal or\notherwise reversed, vacated or annulled and the commissioner has\nreinstated the school administrator's or supervisor's certification\npursuant to paragraph e of this subdivision; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The termination of employment was based solely on the conviction\nof an offense defined in subparagraph two of paragraph b of this\nsubdivision and it has been determined that the school administrator or\nsupervisor is not the same person as the convicted offender.\n  g. If a school administrator's or supervisor's employment was\nterminated as a result of a disciplinary proceeding conducted pursuant\nto section three thousand twenty-a of this chapter or other disciplinary\nhearing conducted pursuant to any collective bargaining or contractual\nagreement on one or more grounds other than conviction of an offense\ndefined in subparagraph two of paragraph b of this subdivision, or the\nrevocation or annulment of a certificate based on such conviction, then\nnothing in paragraph f of this subdivision shall require a school\ndistrict to reinstate the employment of such school administrator or\nsupervisor or be liable for back pay or benefits.\n  h. No provision of this article shall be deem...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the commissioner from conducting a due process hearing\npursuant to subdivision seven of this section and part eighty-three of\ntitle eight of the New York codes, rules and regulations; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a\nschool district or employing board from bringing a disciplinary\nproceeding pursuant to section three thousand twenty-a of this chapter;\nor</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a school district or employing board from bringing an alternative\ndisciplinary proceeding conducted pursuant to a collective bargaining or\ncontractual agreement.\n  i. The commissioner shall be authorized to promulgate any regulations\nnecessary to implement the provisions of this subdivision.\n  8. He shall cause to be prepared and keep in his office records of all\npersons who have received, or shall receive, certificates of\nqualification to teach or diplomas of the state teachers colleges, and\nstate colleges for teachers, with the dates thereof, and shall note\nthereon all annulments of such certificates and diplomas, and reversals\nthereof, with the dates and causes thereof, together with such other\nparticulars as he may deem expedient.\n  9. The commissioner shall procure with the consent of the federal\nauthorities complete lists giving the names, ages and destination within\nthe state of all noncitizen children of school age and such other facts\nas will tend to identify th...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>are made by the board of education or the trustee of a\ndistrict, under rules and regulations prescribed by the commissioner,\nand,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>do not extend the original contract period beyond five years\nfrom the date cafeteria and restaurant service commenced thereunder and\nin the case of contracts for the transportation of pupils, for the\nmaintenance of school buses or for mobile instructional units, that such\ncontracts may be extended, except that power is hereby vested in the\ncommissioner, in addition to his existing statutory authority to approve\nor disapprove transportation or maintenance contracts,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to reject any\nextension of a contract beyond the initial term thereof if he finds that\namount to be paid by the district to the contractor in any year of such\nproposed extension fails to reflect any decrease in the regional\nconsumer price index for the N.Y., N.Y.-Northeastern, N.J. area, based\nupon the index for all urban consumers (CPI-U) during the preceding\ntwelve month period; and (ii) to reject any extension of a contract\nafter ten years from the date transportation or maintenance service\ncommenced thereunder, or mobile instructional units were first provided,\nif in his opinion, the best interests of the district will be promoted\nthereby. Upon such rejection of any proposed extension, the commissioner\nmay order the board of education or trustee of the district to seek,\nobtain and consider bids pursuant to the provisions of this section. The\nboard of education or the trustee of a school district electing to\nextend a contract as provided herein, may, in its discretion, increase\nthe amount to be paid in each year of the contract extension by an\namount not to exceed the regional consumer price index increase for the\nN.Y., N.Y.-Northeastern, N.J. area, based upon the index for all urban\nconsumers (CPI-U), during the preceding twelve month period, provided it\nhas been satisfactorily established by the contractor that there has\nbeen at least an equivalent increase in the amount of his cost of\noperation, during the period of the contract.\n  b. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph a of this subdivision,\nin the case of any emergency arising out of an accident or other\nunforeseen occurrence or condition affecting pupil transportation\nservices within a district, and requiring immediate action which cannot\nawait competitive bidding, interim contracts for pupil transportation\nservices may be let by the board of education or the trustee of such\ndistrict for a period not to exceed one month, pending the award of a\ncontract for such services ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the sum of the actual cost of qualifying criminal\nhistory and driver licensing testing fees attributable to special\nrequirements for drivers of school buses pursuant to articles nineteen\nand nineteen-A of the vehicle and traffic law plus the actual cost of\nany diagnostic tests and physical performance tests that are deemed to\nbe necessary by an examining physician or the chief school officer to\ndetermine whether an applicant to drive a school bus under the terms of\nthe contract has the physical and mental ability to operate a school\ntransportation conveyance and to satisfactorily perform the other\nresponsibilities of a school bus driver pursuant to regulations of the\ncommissioner; (ii) in a school district located in a city with at least\none million inhabitants, the actual cost of clean air technology filters\nand Global Positioning System (GPS) technology; (iii) in a school\ndistrict located in a city with at least one million inhabitants, with\nrespects only to any extension beginning in fiscal year two thousand\nfive--two thousand six, the sum of the actual cost of providing school\nbus attendants including the actual cost of criminal history record\nchecks for school bus attendant applicants and training and instruction\nfor school bus attendants pursuant to section twelve hundred\ntwenty-nine-d of the vehicle and traffic law plus up to five percent of\nsuch cost for necessary administrative services; and (iv) the actual\ncost of equipment or vehicle modification, or training required, by any\nstate or local legislation or regulation promulgated or effective on or\nafter June first, two thousand five. Such costs shall be approved by the\ncommissioner upon documentation provided by the school district and\ncontractor as required by the commissioner.\n  * d. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs a, b and c of this\nsubdivision, the board of education or the trustee of a district and a\ncontractor providing pupil transportation services to such di...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the contractor is not the most responsive\nto the request for proposals, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the best interests of the\ndistrict will be promoted thereby.\n  f. When a board of education or a trustee of a school district elects\nto receive proposals submitted in response to a request for proposals,\nsuch board of education or trustee shall evaluate each proposal from a\nresponding contractor according to criteria established by the\ncommissioner. For evaluation of proposals related to contracts for pupil\ntransportation services, such criteria shall include at a minimum</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe previous experience of the contractor in transporting pupils, (ii)\nthe name of each transportation company the contractor has been an owner\nor a manager and previous experience, (iii) a description of any safety\nprograms implemented by the contractor, (iv) a record of accidents in\nmotor vehicles under the control of the contractor,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>driving history\nof employees of the contractor, (vi) inspection records and model year\nof the motor vehicles under the control of the contractor, (vii)\nmaintenance schedule of the motor vehicles under the control of the\ncontractor, (viii) financial analysis of the contractor, and (ix)\ncompliance with insurance requirements. For evaluation of proposals\nrelated to contracts for mobile instructional units, such criteria shall\ninclude at a minimum</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the previous experience of the contractor in\nproviding mobile instructional units for use by public school districts,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name of each transportation company or manufacturer in which the\ncontractor or any of the contractor's officers has been an owner or a\nmanager or has had a controlling interest,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a description of any\nvehicle safety standards included in the design standards for the mobile\ninstructional units under the control of the contractor that exceed\napplicable standards defined in statute or regulations,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inspection\nrecords and model year of the mobile instructional units under the\ncontrol of the contractor,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>maintenance schedule of the mobile\ninstructional units under the control of the contractor,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>financial\nanalysis of the contractor and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>compliance with insurance\nrequirements.\n  g. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subdivision, section one\nhundred three of the general municipal law, or any other provision of\nlaw to the contrary, the board of education shall be authorized to enter\ninto a piggyback contract with another school district that transports\nstudents pursuant to a contract with a private transportation\ncontractor, provided that the board finds that the contract cost is\nappropriate and entry into a piggyback contract will result in a cost\nsavings to the school district. For purposes of this paragraph, a\n"piggyback contract" means a contract for the transportation of students\nthat:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>provides transportation to a location outside the students'\nschool district of residence to which another school district is already\nproviding transportation to its own students through an existing\ncontract with a private transportation contractor, other than a\ncooperatively bid contract;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is entered into by the private\ntransportation contractor and each school district involved; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nprovides for transportation in accordance with the terms and conditions\nof such existing transportation contract.\n  15. The extension industrial teacher training courses heretofore\nestablished are continued under the jurisdiction and control of the\neducation department. Members of the faculty to teach such courses shall\nbe appointed by the commissioner of education and, subject to the\napproval of the director of the budget, shall be classified, allocated\nand paid in accordance with the schedules contained in section three\nhundred fifty-five-a of this chapter.\n  16. The commissioner shall cooperate with the commissioner of health\nto facilitate the timely establishment and maintenance of current\nrecords of courses in advanced emergency medical technology.\n  17. Whenever a mistake has been made, or an honest dispute exists, as\nto the location of the division line between land owned by the state,\nwhich is under the jurisdiction, care, custody or control of the\ndepartment o...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>determining the base year level of general\nsupport for public schools pursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision\nfor the two thousand seventeen--two thousand eighteen school year and\nthereafter, the commissioner is directed to include the state-funded\ngrant amounts allocated pursuant to subdivision ten of section\nthirty-six hundred two-e of this chapter where such state-funded grants\nhad previously been allocated to districts by means other than general\nsupport for public schools, and (ii) for the purposes of determining\nboth the base year and current year levels of general support for public\nschools pursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision for the two thousand\nnineteen--two thousand twenty school year and thereafter, the\ncommissioner is also directed to include grant amounts pursuant to\nsection thirty-six hundred two-ee of this chapter, provided that,\nnotwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, such base year\ngrant amounts shall not be included in:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the allowable growth amount\ncomputed pursuant to paragraph dd of subdivision one of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this chapter,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the preliminary growth\namount computed pursuant to paragraph ff of subdivision one of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this chapter, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the allocable growth\namount computed pursuant to paragraph gg of subdivision one of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this chapter, and shall not be considered, and\nshall not be available for interchange with, general support for public\nschools.\n  e. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law to the contrary,\nin preparing an electronic data file pursuant to paragraph b of this\nsubdivision, for the purposes of using estimated data for projections of\napportionments for the following school year, the commissioner shall</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ncalculate the negative difference, if any, of the allowable growth\namount computed pursuant to subdivision one of section thirty-six\nhundred two of this chapter less the preliminary growth amount pursuant\nto such subdivision, and (ii) include such negative difference as the\n"growth cap adjustment" in any file that aggregates apportionments of\ngeneral support for public schools for the purpose of determining the\namounts necessary in the state fiscal years associated with the school\nyear estimates, provided that the commissioner shall not allocate any\namount of such growth cap adjustment to any school district.\n  22. The commissioner shall establish the procedures for a statewide\nsystem of assigning unique student identification numbers for all\nstudents in public and nonpublic schools within the state for purposes\nof student tracking and for state reporting purposes. Students shall\nretain their numbers until they attain the age of twenty-one. As new\nstudents enter schools in New York, they shall be assigned a unique\nnumber. The commissioner shall include in such system appropriate\nprocedures for insuring security and confidentiality of student\ninformation. The commissioner shall adopt regulations to provide for the\nimplementation of such statewide system by school districts and\nnonpublic schools.\n  23. The commissioner shall have primary responsibility for the\ndevelopment and implementation of integrated employment opportunities\nincluding short-term and intensive supported employment services and, as\nappropriate, long-term extended support services and shall coordinate\nwith the commissioner of social services, the commissioner of the office\nof mental health and the commissioner of the office for people with\ndevelopmental disabilities under an integrated employment implementation\nplan, pursuant to article twenty-one of this chapter.\n  24. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this chapter, the\ncommissioner may, by regulation, prov...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, in cooperation with the division of criminal\njustice services and in accordance with all applicable provisions of\nlaw, shall promulgate rules and regulations to require the\nfingerprinting of prospective employees, as defined in section eleven\nhundred twenty-five of this chapter, of school districts, charter\nschools and boards of cooperative educational services and authorizing\nthe fingerprinting of prospective employees of nonpublic and private\nelementary and secondary schools, and for the use of information derived\nfrom searches of the records of the division of criminal justice\nservices and the federal bureau of investigation based on the use of\nsuch fingerprints. The commissioner shall also develop a form for use by\nschool districts, charter schools, boards of cooperative educational\nservices, and nonpublic and private elementary and secondary schools in\nconnection with the submission of fingerprints that contains the\nspecific job title sought and any other information that may be relevant\nto consideration of the applicant. The commissioner shall also establish\na form for the recordation of allegations of child abuse in an\neducational setting, as required pursuant to section eleven hundred\ntwenty-six of this chapter. No person who has been fingerprinted\npursuant to section three thousand four-b of this chapter or pursuant to\nsection five hundred nine-cc or twelve hundred twenty-nine-d of the\nvehicle and traffic law and whose fingerprints remain on file with the\ndivision of criminal justice services shall be required to undergo\nfingerprinting for purposes of a new criminal history record check. This\nsubdivision and the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto\nshall not apply to a school district within a city with a population of\none million or more.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, in cooperation with the division of criminal\njustice services, shall promulgate a form to be provided to all such\nprospective employees of school districts, charter schools, boards of\ncooperative educational services, and nonpublic and private elementary\nand secondary schools that elect to fingerprint and seek clearance for\nprospective employees that shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>inform the prospective employee that the commissioner is required\nor authorized to request his or her criminal history information from\nthe division of criminal justice services and the federal bureau of\ninvestigation and review such information pursuant to this section, and\nprovide a description of the manner in which his or her fingerprint\ncards will be used upon submission to the division of criminal justice\nservices;\n  (ii) inform the prospective employee that he or she has the right to\nobtain, review and seek correction of his or her criminal history\ninformation pursuant to regulations and procedures established by the\ndivision of criminal justice services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The prospective employer shall obtain the signed, informed consent\nof the prospective employee on such form supplied by the commissioner\nwhich indicates that such person has:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>been informed of the right and procedures necessary to obtain,\nreview and seek correction of his or her criminal history information;\n  (ii) been informed of the reason for the request for his or her\ncriminal history information;\n  (iii) consented to such request for a report;\n  (iv) supplied on the form a current mailing or home address for the\nprospective employee;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>been informed that he or she may withdraw his or her application\nfor employment pursuant to this section, without prejudice, at any time\nbefore employment is offered or declined, regardless of whether the\nprospective employee or employer has reviewed such prospective\nemployee's criminal history information;\n  (vi) where the applicant is to be fingerprinted pursuant to section\nthree thousand thirty-five of this chapter, the process for seeking a\nwaiver of the fees associated with conducting a criminal history records\ncheck, pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of section three\nthousand thirty-five of this chapter,\n  (vii) been informed that in the event his or her employment is\nterminated and such person has not become employed in the same or\nanother school district, charter school, board of cooperative\neducational services, or nonpublic or private elementary or secondary\nschool within twelve-months of such termination, the commissioner shall\nnotify the division of criminal justice services of such termination,\nand the division of criminal justice services shall destroy the\nfingerprints of such person. Such person may request that the\ncommissioner notify the division of criminal justice services that his\nor her fingerprints shall be destroyed prior to the expiration of such\ntwelve month period in which case the commissioner shall notify the\ndivision of criminal justice services and the division shall destroy the\nfingerprints of such person promptly upon receipt of the request; and\n  (viii) been informed of the manner in which he or she may submit to\nthe commissioner any information that may be relevant to the\nconsideration of his or her application for clearance including, where\napplicable, information in regard to his or her good conduct and\nrehabilitation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall develop forms to be provided to all school\ndistricts, charter schools, boards of cooperative educational services,\nand to all nonpublic and private elementary and secondary schools that\nelect to fingerprint their prospective employees, to be completed and\nsigned by prospective employees when conditional appointment or\nemergency conditional appointment is offered.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may promulgate rules and regulations regarding\nthe conditional appointment and emergency conditional appointment of a\nprospective employee.\n  * 31. The commissioner shall direct that each school district, charter\nschool, and private elementary and secondary school appoint a designated\neducational official for the purposes set forth in section 380.90 of the\ncriminal procedure law, subdivision seventeen of section 301.2 and\nsubdivision three of section 380.1 of the family court act. In addition,\nthe commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations, in consultation\nwith the office of court administration, to facilitate electronic access\nby the courts to the names and addresses of such designated educational\nofficials.\n  * NB There are 2 sub 31's\n  * 31. The commissioner shall cooperate with the commissioner of\nagriculture and markets in establishing a farm-to-school program and\ncoordinating New York Harvest For New York Kids Week as described in\nsubdivision five-b of section sixteen of the agriculture and markets\nlaw. The commissioner's responsibilities shall include, but not be\nlimited to, compiling information for the department of agriculture and\nmarkets from school districts and other educational institutions under\nthe department's jurisdiction interested in purchasing New York farm\nproducts and disseminating to those districts and institutions\ninformation from the department of agriculture and markets about the\navailability of New York farm products, and contact information for\nfarmers and other businesses marketing such products. The commissioner\nshall report to the legislature about the need for changes in law to\nfacilitate the purchase of such products by schools and other\ninstitutions.\n  * NB There are 2 sub 31's\n  34. The commissioner is hereby authorized and directed to apply school\nbus safety practices instruction and retraining requirements prescribed\npursuant to the provisions of section thirty-six hundre...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section three of the children's\nmental health act of 2006.\n  * NB There are 2 sb 35's\n  36. The commissioner shall ensure that by July first, two thousand\neight, a student progress report, written in plain English and in a form\nprescribed by the commissioner, is prepared for all students. Such\nprogress report shall provide parents or persons in parental relation\nwith information on their child's performance on state assessments over\nmultiple years of testing and shall also explain the process by which\nparents or persons in parental relation may inquire further about their\nchild's progress. All school districts and charter schools shall prepare\nand disseminate the student progress report to parents or persons in\nparental relation in a timely manner.\n  37. The commissioner shall develop methods to support educators in the\nuse of performance data to assist in student learning, which shall be\nperiodically improved based on feedback from educators.\n  38. The commissioner shall develop informational materials to assist\nparents or persons in parental relation and teachers in understanding\nthe regents learning standards and the results of state assessments.\n  39. The commissioner shall develop a school leadership report card and\na separate school progress report card to assist boards of education,\nthe state and the public in assessing the performance of school leaders,\nincluding superintendents of schools and building principals, and the\nschools that they lead. The report cards shall include an assessment of\nthe school's progress in achieving standards of excellence. By January\nfirst, two thousand nine, the commissioner shall develop such standards\nof excellence which shall include, but not be limited to, parent\ninvolvement, curriculum, teacher quality, and accountability measures as\nset forth in section two hundred eleven-a of this title. The\ncommissioner shall promulgate regulations requiring the trustees or\nboards of ed...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring a course of instruction relating to recognizing the\nsymptoms of mild traumatic brain injuries and monitoring and seeking\nproper medical treatment for pupils who suffer mild traumatic brain\ninjuries. Such course of instruction shall be required to be completed\non a biennial basis by all school coaches, physical education teachers,\nnurses and athletic trainers. The course of instruction required by this\nsubparagraph shall include, but not be limited to, the definition of a\n"concussion," signs and symptoms of mild traumatic brain injuries, how\nsuch injuries may occur, practices regarding prevention, and the\nguidelines for the return to school and to certain school activities\nafter a pupil has suffered a mild traumatic brain injury regardless of\nwhether such injury occurred outside of school. Such training may be\ncompleted by means of courses of instruction, including but not limited\nto, courses provided online and by teleconference approved by the\ndepartment;\n  (ii) providing that the department and the department of health shall\npost on their internet websites information relating to mild traumatic\nbrain injuries, which shall include but not be limited to, the\ndefinition of a "concussion," signs and symptoms of mild traumatic brain\ninjuries, how such injuries may occur, and the guidelines for the return\nto school and to certain school activities after a pupil has suffered a\nmild traumatic brain injury regardless of whether such injury occurred\noutside of school. Schools shall be required to include such information\nin any permission form or parent or person in parental relation consent\nform or similar document that may be required for a pupil's\nparticipation in interscholastic sports and shall also include such\ninformation, or reference how to obtain such information from the\ndepartment and the department of health internet websites, on the\nschool's internet website, if one exists;\n  (iii) requiring the immediate removal from ath...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\n19.07 of the mental hygiene law.\n  44. The commissioner shall prohibit the administration of traditional\nstandardized tests, as defined in regulations issued by the\ncommissioner, in pre-kindergarten programs and in grades kindergarten\nthrough second grade; provided, however, that nothing herein shall\nprohibit assessments in which students perform real-world tasks that\ndemonstrate application of knowledge and skills or assessments that are\notherwise required to be administered by federal law.\n  45. The commissioner shall provide that no school district or board of\ncooperative educational services may place or include on a student's\nofficial transcript or maintain in a student's permanent record any\nindividual student score on a state administered standardized English\nlanguage arts or mathematics assessment for grades three through eight,\nprovided that nothing herein shall be construed to interfere with\nrequired state or federal reporting or to excuse a school district from\nmaintaining or transferring records of such test scores separately from\na student's permanent record, including for purposes of required state\nor federal reporting.\n  46. The commissioner shall provide that any test results on a state\nadministered standardized English language arts or mathematics\nassessment for grades three through eight sent to parents or persons in\nparental relation to a student include a clear and conspicuous notice\nthat such results will not be included on the student's official\ntranscript or in the student's permanent record and are being provided\nto the student and parents for diagnostic purposes.\n  47. The commissioner shall provide that no school district shall make\nany student promotion or placement decisions based solely or primarily\non student performance on the state administered standardized English\nlanguage arts and mathematics assessments for grades three through\neight. However, a school district may consider student performan...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>seek the recommendations of teachers, school administrators,\nteacher educators and others with educational expertise in the proposed\ncurriculum;\n  (ii) seek comment from parents, students and other interested parties;\n  (iii) consider the amount of instructional time such curriculum will\nrequire and whether such time would detract from other mandated courses\nof study;\n  (iv) consider the fiscal impact, if any, on the state and school\ndistricts; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>consider any additional factors the commissioner deems relevant.\n  c. No later than one hundred eighty days after the effective date of\nthis subdivision, the commissioner shall provide a recommendation to the\nboard of regents to either adopt and promulgate appropriate rules and\nregulations implementing such curriculum or reject the implementation of\nsuch curriculum. Upon receiving a recommendation from the commissioner,\npursuant to this subdivision, the board of regents shall vote to either\naccept or reject the commissioner's recommendation no later than sixty\ndays after receiving such recommendation.\n  d. If the board of regents adopts such curriculum, the curriculum\nrequirement shall take effect no later than the next school year after\nsuch curriculum has been adopted.\n  e. If the board of regents rejects such curriculum, the commissioner\nshall provide a report as to the determination of the board to the\ngovernor, the temporary president of the senate, the speaker of the\nassembly and the chairs of the senate and assembly committees on\neducation providing the reasons for such rejection not later than thirty\ndays after the board of regents rejects such curriculum.\n  53. The commissioner is authorized and directed to establish a content\nreview committee for the purposes of reviewing all standardized test\nitems and/or selected passages used on English language arts and\nmathematics state assessments for grades three through eight to ensure:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>they are grade level appropriate, in general;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>they are presented\nat a readability level that is grade-level appropriate;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>they are\nwithin grade-level expectations; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>they appropriately measure the\nlearning standards approved by the board of regents applicable to such\nsubject and/or grade level. The review of such items and passages shall\nbe conducted prior to their use in such assessments provided however,\nfor the two thousand fifteen--two thousand sixteen school year only, if\nsuch requirement would prevent the ability of such assessments to be\nadministered, then items or passages that have not been reviewed may be\nused. Provided further, the content review committee shall review any\nnew standardized test items and/or selected passages prior to their use\nin such assessments. Such committee shall also ensure that any new test\nitems and/or selected passages are fair and appropriately measure the\nlearning standards approved by the board of regents applicable to such\nsubject and/or grade level. Such committee shall also ensure that\nadequate and appropriate time is given to students for the\nadministration of such assessments, provided however that subdivision\nforty-nine of this section must be complied with. The content review\ncommittee shall include classroom teachers and experienced educators in\nthe content area and/or grade level of the items/passages being\nreviewed, including teachers of students with disabilities and English\nlanguage learners.\n  54. Notwithstanding any law, rule or regulation to the contrary, no\nteacher, principal, or superintendent shall be required to sign a\nconfidentiality agreement with their respective school district, board\nof cooperative educational services, or the department that prevents\nsuch teacher, principal, or superintendent from discussing the contents\nof any items on the English language arts and mathematics assessments in\ngrades three through eight after such items have been released by the\ndepartment pursuant to subdivision fifty-one-a of this section or after\nsuch items have been publicly disclosed by the department or other\nappropriate entity. The commissioner sh...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>age-appropriate model curriculum, exemplar lesson plans, and best\npractice instructional resources for students, parents and school\npersonnel designed to promote awareness and prevention methods against\nsepsis. Such model curriculum, lesson plans and instructional resources\nshall include but not be limited to guidelines and methods of\nprevention, including recommendations for the reduction of exposure to\nsepsis and an appropriate course of action for sepsis treatment;\n  (ii) instructional tools and materials for students, parents and\nschool personnel developed in collaboration with the commissioner of\nhealth, which shall include updated data and information on sepsis\nawareness and prevention, with a review of such data and information to\noccur periodically, at intervals deemed appropriate by the commissioner\nand the commissioner of health; and\n  (iii) public availability of all materials related to the sepsis\nawareness, prevention and education program on a dedicated webpage on\nthe department's internet website, and provided at no cost to every\nschool district, board of cooperative educational services, charter\nschool and nonpublic school upon request.\n  b. The commissioner shall issue a guidance memorandum to every school\ndistrict, board of cooperative educational services, charter school and\nnonpublic school, to inform them of the availability of the sepsis\nawareness, prevention and education program and to encourage them to\ndevelop policies and procedures, in consultation with their director of\nschool health services, or the substantial equivalent as determined by\nthe commissioner in regulations, regarding when parents and persons in\nparental relations are to be notified of illness or injuries occurring\nin school which affects their child, in accordance with article nineteen\nof this chapter. The commissioner shall annually remind school\ndistricts, boards of cooperative educational services, charter schools\nand nonpublic schools, of th...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>study the potential barriers to: achieving diversity within\nteacher preparation programs; obtaining an initial certificate in the\nclassroom teaching service; and obtaining teacher certification as a\nteacher aide or teaching assistant;\n  (ii) include available data on race, ethnicity, gender, and age; the\nefforts higher education institutions with teacher preparation programs\nare taking to recruit and retain a diverse student population into such\nprograms; and the efforts that the state and schools are taking to\nattract, hire, and retain certified teachers who reflect the diversity\nwithin New York state's schools; and\n  (iii) make recommendations on programs, practices and policies that\nmay be implemented by schools and teacher preparation programs to\nimprove teacher diversity throughout the state.\n  b. The commissioner shall consult with stakeholders and other\ninterested parties when preparing such report. The state university of\nNew York, the city university of New York, the commission on independent\ncolleges and universities, and the proprietary college sector with\nregistered teacher education programs in this state shall, to the extent\npracticable, identify and provide representatives to the department, at\nthe request of the commissioner, in order to participate in the\ndevelopment and drafting of such report.\n  59. The commissioner shall make available educational materials\ndeveloped pursuant to subdivision two of section three hundred seventy-c\nof the social services law to every school district, charter school,\nnonpublic school, approved preschool, approved preschool special\neducation program, approved private residential or non-residential\nschool for the education of students with disabilities, state-supported\nschool in accordance with article eighty-five of this chapter, and board\nof cooperative educational services for the purpose of educating\nparents, guardians and other authorized individuals responsible for the\nchild's care a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ways to recruit underrepresented candidates, including those who\nare current teaching assistants and current students in teacher\npreparation programs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>initiatives aimed at creating an early recruitment pipeline\nbeginning in secondary school;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>how to establish partnerships between school districts,\ncommunity-based organizations, and institutions of higher education to\nencourage and support underrepresented candidates to enter and remain in\nthe teaching profession; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ways to identify existing funding sources available to school\ndistricts to attract and retain underrepresented candidates into the\nteaching profession.\n  * NB There are 2 sb 60's\n  * 60. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations\nprohibiting a teacher, administrator, officer, employee or agent of any\nschool within the state from using corporal punishment.\n  * NB There are 2 sb 60's\n  61. a. The commissioner shall require each school district to ensure\nverification of one of the following from the parent or guardian of each\nstudent or from the student if the student is eighteen years of age or\nolder or legally emancipated, during the school year in which the\nstudent is a senior enrolled in such school district:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>completion of\neither the free application for federal student aid for such student or,\nif applicable, the Jose Peralta New York State DREAM Act application; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>completion of a waiver form promulgated by the department indicating\nthat the parent or guardian or, if the student is eighteen years of age\nor older or legally emancipated, the student understands what the free\napplication for federal student aid or, if applicable, the Jose Peralta\nNew York State DREAM Act application are and has chosen not to file an\napplication pursuant to the provisions of subparagraph one of this\nparagraph. For purposes of this subdivision, verification of completion\nof either the free application for federal student aid or the Jose\nPeralta New York State DREAM Act application shall not require a parent,\nguardian, or student to identify which type of application was\ncompleted.\n  b. On and after July first, two thousand twenty-five, each school\ndistrict shall annually report to the department the following data for\nall seniors enrolled in such school district, aggregated by high school:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the total number of students that have completed either the free\napplication for federal student aid or, if applicable, the Jose Peralta\nNew York State DREAM Act application;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the number of students who\ncompleted a waiver pursuant to paragraph a of this subdivision; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nthe total number of seniors enrolled.\n  c. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations necessary\nto implement this subdivision, including requiring each school district\nto notify each high school senior, no less than two times during each\nschool year, of the state-sponsored scholarships, financial aid and\nassistance available to students attending college or post-secondary\neducation, and to provide referrals for support or assistance to\ncomplete the free application for federal student aid or, if applicable,\nthe Jose Peralta New York State DREAM Act application.\n  d. A student shall not be penalized or punished if the student's\nparent or guardian or the student, if the student is eighteen years of\nage or older or legally emancipated, does not fulfill the requirements\nof this subdivision and this subdivision shall not affect a student's\nability to graduate.\n  * 62. a. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations to\nestablish uniform statewide prot...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>