<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3202"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3202">
        <num>3202</num>
        <heading>Public schools free to resident pupils; tuition from nonresident pupils</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall have been discharged therefrom\nunder conditions other than dishonorable, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has a qualifying\ncondition, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law, and\nhas received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from\nsuch service, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is a discharged LGBT veteran, as defined in section\none of the veterans' services law, and has received a discharge other\nthan bad conduct or dishonorable from such service, may attend any of\nthe public schools of the state upon conditions prescribed by the board\nof education, and such veterans shall be included in the pupil count for\nstate aid purposes. A nonveteran under twenty-one years of age who has\nreceived a high school diploma shall be permitted to attend classes in\nthe schools of the district in which such person resides or in a school\nof a board of cooperative educational services upon payment of tuition\nunder such terms and conditions as shall be established in regulations\npromulgated by the commissioner; provided, however, that a school\ndistrict may waive the payment of tuition for such nonveteran, but in\nany case such a nonveteran who has received a high school diploma shall\nnot be counted for any state aid purposes. Nothing herein contained\nshall, however, require a board of education to admit a child who\nbecomes five years of age after the school year has commenced unless his\nor her birthday occurs on or before the first of December.\n  1-a. No pupil over the compulsory attendance age in his or her school\ndistrict shall be dropped from enrollment unless he or she has been\nabsent twenty consecutive school days and the following procedure is\ncomplied with: The principal or superintendent shall schedule and\nnotify, in writing and at the last known address, both the student and\nthe person in parental relation to the student of an informal\nconference. At the conference the principal or superintendent shall\ndetermine both the reasons for the pupil's absence and whether\nreasonable changes in the pupil's educational program would encourage\nand facilitate his or her re-entry or continuance of study. The pupil\nand the person in parental relation shall be informed orally and in\nwriting of the pupil's right to re-enroll at any time in t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "school district of origin" shall mean the school\ndistrict within the state of New York in which the child or youth in\nfoster care was attending a public school or preschool on a tuition-free\nbasis or was entitled to attend when the social services district or\noffice of children and family services assumed responsibility for the\nplacement, support and maintenance of such child or youth, which is\ndifferent from the school district of residence.\n  (ii) School district of residence. The term "school district of\nresidence" shall mean the public school district within the state of New\nYork in which the foster care placement is located, which is different\nfrom the school district of origin.\n  b. Except as provided in subdivision five of this section, the cost of\ninstruction of children in foster care shall be borne by the school\ndistrict of origin. Where a school district other than the school\ndistrict of origin is designated in accordance with paragraph e of\nsubdivision two of section thirty-two hundred forty-four of this\narticle, the cost of instruction shall be borne by the school district\nof origin and the tuition paid to the designated school district of\nattendance shall be computed as provided in paragraph d of this\nsubdivision, except that, where the foster care placement receives\nprogram support from a child care institution affiliated with a special\nact school district as defined in subdivision eight of section four\nthousand one of this chapter, and the designated school district of\nattendance, upon the recommendation of its committee on special\neducation, contracts for such pupil's education pursuant to paragraph c,\nd, e, or f of subdivision two of section forty-four hundred one of this\nchapter or for a nonresidential placement pursuant to paragraph l of\nsuch subdivision, costs incurred shall be reimbursed in accordance with\nparagraph e of this subdivision. Notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovision of law, where the permane...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within ten days of the placement of such pupil, the public agency\nor its designee shall give written notice of such placement to the board\nof education of the school district believed to be the school district\nof origin. Such notification shall include the name of the pupil and any\nparticulars about the pupil that pertain to the identification of the\nschool district as the school district of origin as defined in paragraph\na of this subdivision.\n  (ii) A board of education of a school district which receives\nnotification pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph may submit\nto the public agency, within ten days of its receipt of such notice,\nadditional evidence to establish that it is not the pupil's district of\norigin as defined in paragraph a of this subdivision. Any evidence so\nsubmitted shall be considered by the agency prior to making its final\ndetermination, which shall be made no later than five days after the\nagency's receipt of such additional evidence. In the event such school\ndistrict fails to submit additional evidence within such ten day period,\nthe determination of the public agency shall be final and the\nnotification provided pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph\nshall be deemed final notification of such determination.\n  (iii) If, upon its review, the public agency determines that the\nschool district notified pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph\nwas not the pupil's district of origin, the public agency shall send\nnotification to the correct school district, in the form prescribed by\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph. Alternatively, if, upon its review,\nthe public agency determines that the school district originally\ndesignated pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph is the pupil's\ndistrict of origin, the public agency shall notify such district in\nwriting of its final determination.\n  (iv) The board of education of the school district finally determined\nby the public agency to be the pupil's school district of origin may\nappeal such determination to the commissioner within thirty days of its\nreceipt of final notification pursuant to this paragraph. Such an appeal\nshall be conducted in the same manner as an appeal from the actions of\nlocal school officials pursuant to section three hundred ten of this\nchapter, except that the factual allegations of the petitioner shall not\nbe deemed true in the event the public agency elects not to appear in\nthe appeal. The petitioner shall join as a party to the appeal any other\nschool district suspected to be the pupil's actual school district of\norigin.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the commissioner finds that the school district notified\npursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or (iii) of this paragraph was not the\npupil's school district of origin as defined in paragraph a of this\nsubdivision and that the correct school district was not joined as a\nparty to the appeal, the commissioner shall direct the public agency to\nnotify the correct school district pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nparagraph.\n  (vi) Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of law, during the\npendency of all proceedings to review a denial of financial\nresponsibility, the commissioner shall issue an interim order assigning\nsuch financial responsibility to the school district or, alternatively,\nupon a determination that the public agency failed to make reasonable\nefforts to identify the school district of origin of such child, to the\npublic agency. In the event the public agency fails to provide timely\nnotice pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph, or fails to\nrender its final determination in a timely manner, the public agency\nresponsible for such pupil's residential placement shall reimburse the\ncommissioner for the payments made to the district furnishing\ninstruction pursuant to this paragraph during the pendency of all\nproceedings or for the duration of the current school year, whichever is\nlonger, and the state comptroller shall withhold such amount from any\nmoneys due the county or the city of New York, on vouchers certified or\napproved by the commissioner, in the manner prescribed by law or shall\ntransfer such amount from the account of such state department or agency\nupon certification of the commissioner, and such funds shall be credited\nto the general support for public schools local assistance account of\nthe department.\n  (vii) Any final determination or order of the commissioner concerning\nthe school district of origin of any pupil under this section may only\nbe reviewed in a proceeding brought in the supreme court pursuant to\narticle seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules. In any such\nproceeding under such article seventy-eight, the court may grant any\nrelief authorized by the provisions of section seventy-eight hundred six\nof such law and rules and may also, in its discretion, remand the\nproceedings to the commissioner. A local social services commissioner or\nany state department or agency placing pupils pursuant to this\nsubdivision is a proper party in any such appeal or proceeding.\n  (viii) Upon completion of all proceedings to review the denial of\nfinancial responsibility for the costs of instruction pursuant to this\nparagraph, the commissioner shall refund any payments made by a party\ncleared of such responsibility and shall collect any payments owed by a\nparty found to have such responsibility. Where such transactions involve\na school district liable for reimbursement pursuant to paragraph e of\nthis subdivision, the commissioner shal...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department is authorized to reimburse each school district\nfurnishing educational services to children residing in schools for\nindividuals with developmental disabilities operated by the office for\npeople with developmental disabilities for the direct cost of such\nservices in accordance with regulations promulgated by the commissioner\nand approved by the director of the budget.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The school district in which each such child resided at the time\nthe office for people with developmental disabilities assumed\nresponsibility for the support and maintenance of such child shall\nreimburse the department for its expenditures on behalf of such child,\nin an amount equal to the school district basic contribution as such\nterm is defined in subdivision eight of section forty-four hundred one\nof this chapter, for any such child admitted to a state school for\nindividuals with developmental disabilities on or after July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-eight. The comptroller may deduct from any\nstate funds which become due to a school district an amount equal to the\nreimbursement required to be made by such school district in accordance\nwith this paragraph and the amount so deducted shall not be included in\nthe approved operating expense of such district for the purpose of\ncomputing the approved operating expenses pursuant to paragraph t of\nsubdivision one of sectio...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Children who reside in an intermediate care facility for\nindividuals with developmental disabilities, other than a state operated\nschool for individuals with developmental disabilities, as defined in\nregulations of the office for people with developmental disabilities,\nshall be admitted to the public schools, except as otherwise provided in\nsubparagraph fourteen of this paragraph. The trustees or board of\neducation of the school district in which such facility is located shall\nreceive such children in the school or schools of the district for\ninstruction and for the provision of necessary related services for a\ncompensation to be fixed by the trustees or board of education, unless\nsuch trustees or board of education shall establish to the satisfaction\nof the commissioner that there are valid and sufficient reasons for\nrefusal to receive such children. Evaluation of the educational needs of\nsuch children and placement in appropriate educational programs shall be\nmade in ac...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A child who resides in an individualized residential alternative\nas defined in regulations of the office for people with developmental\ndisabilities which is located in a school district other than the school\ndistrict in which such child's parent or person in parental relation\nresided at the time such child was placed in an institution under the\nauspices of such office shall be deemed to reside in an intermediate\ncare facility for purposes of this subdivision to the extent such child\nis enrolled in a home and community based waiver program approved by the\nHealth Care Financing Administration.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such intermediate care facility is authorized to contract with the\ntrustees or board of education of such school district for the provision\nof services, including transportation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The education department shall reimburse the school district in\nwhich such intermediate care facility is located for the full cost of\nall services, which shall, notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of\nlaw, include transportation services provided pursuant to a contract\nauthorized by this paragraph. Provided, however, that notwithstanding\nany other law, rule or regulation to the contrary, that no reimbursement\nshall be payable pursuant to this subparagraph for due process costs\nincurred on or after July first, two thousand nine. Such reimbursement\nshall be for the period from September first through June thirtieth, and\nstate reimbursement for July and August programs shall be in accordance\nwith subdivision one of section forty-four hundred eight of this\nchapter. The provisions of subdivision two of such section forty-four\nhundred eight shall apply to all July and August programs provided\npursuant to this section.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The school district in which the child resided at the time of\nplacement in such intermediate care facility shall reimburse the\neducation department for its expenditure on behalf of such child in an\namount equal to the school district's basic contribution, as such term\nis defined in subdivision eight of section forty-four hundred one of\nthis article for any child first admitted to such intermediate care\nfacility, on or after July first, nineteen hundred seventy-nine.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon certification by the commissioner of education, the\ncomptroller may deduct from any state funds which become due to the\nschool district an amount equal to the reimbursement required to be made\nby such school district in accordance with this paragraph, and the\namount so deducted shall not be included in the operating expense of\nsuch district for the purpose of computing the approved operating\nexpenses pursuant to paragraph t of subdivision one of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within forty-five days of the placement of a child in a school\ndistrict, the intermediate care facility shall notify the school\ndistrict in which the child resided at time of entrance to the\nintermediate care facility and the school district in which the facility\nis located. Such notice shall include the name of the child, the\nlocation of the intermediate care facility, and the name of the school\ndistrict in which such child resided at the time of placement.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A board of education of a school district which receives\nnotification that a child has been placed in an intermediate care\nfacility for individuals with developmental disabilities may deny\nfinancial responsibility for any child by written notice within twenty\ndays of such notification to the school district furnishing instruction\nand the intermediate care facility.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An intermediate care facility responsible for placing the child,\nthe school district furnishing instruction or the parent or guardian of\nthe child involved may appeal a denial of responsibility to the\ncommissioner of education. If the commissioner finds that the child was\nnot a resident of the school district that was notified that the child\nwas a resident therein, the commissioner shall request the intermediate\ncare facility to ascertain the correct school district and notify such\nschool district pursuant to subparagraph six of this paragraph. The\ncommissioner shall review and determine responsibility for the child in\nquestion. If the commissioner finds that a child has no residence in\nthis state, he shall determine that there is no local contribution for\nsuch child.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the intermediate care facility fails to make a reasonable\neffort to identify the residence of such a child, such agency shall be\nresponsible for the local contribution and, upon notification by the\ncommissioner of education, shall pay such amount to the commissioner of\neducation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the intermediate care facility rejects the finding of the\ncommittee on special education of the school district of attendance, or\na finding affirmed or revised on appeal, such facility shall retain\nresponsibility for payment of the cost of instruction of such child.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any final determination or order of the commissioner concerning\nresidence or placement of any child under this paragraph may only be\nreviewed in a proceeding brought in the supreme court pursuant to\narticle seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules. In any such\nproceeding, the court may grant any relief authorized by the provisions\nof section seventy-eight hundred six of such law and rules or may, in\nits discretion, remand the proceedings to the commissioner. An\nintermediate care facility attempting to place a child pursuant to this\nparagraph shall be considered a proper party to any such proceeding.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The school district providing educational services to children\nplaced pursuant to this paragraph shall provide a report on the status\nof each such child with a handicapping condition annually to the\ncommittee on special education of the school district in which the child\nresided at the time of admission to the intermediate care facility for\nindividuals with developmental disabilities. Such report shall also be\nsent to the parent or guardian of the child and the office for people\nwith developmental disabilities.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3202__subsec_i__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of education responsible for providing appropriate\neducational services for a child receiving care in an intermediate care\nfacility developed pursuant to the residential school bed development\nprogram, as authorized by chapter fifty-four of the laws of nineteen\nhundred eighty-five or any subsequent enactment extending such program,\nshall be the board of education of the school district in which such\nchild would be deemed to reside but for such child's placement in such\nan intermediate care facility. The department shall reimburse such\nschool district of residence for all nonfederally reimbursable costs of\nsuch educational services in accordance with subparagraph four of this\nparagraph as if such district were the school district in which the\nintermediate care facility is located, and such school district of\nresidence shall be responsible for reimbursement of the department for\nits expenditure on behalf of the child in an amount equal to the school\ndistrict basic...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3202__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of section nineteen hundred fifty of\nthis chapter. A youth attending a local public school while in residence\nat such facility shall be deemed a resident of the school district where\nhis parent or guardian resides at the commencement of each school year\nfor the purpose of determining which school district shall be\nresponsible for the youth's tuition pursuant to section five hundred\nfour of the executive law.\n  7. Youth incarcerated in county correctional facilities or youth\nshelters. a. A person under twenty-one years of age who has not received\na high school diploma and who is incarcerated in a correctional facility\nmaintained by a county or by the city of New York or in a youth shelter\nis eligible for educational services pursuant to this subdivision and in\naccordance with the regulations of the commissioner. Such services shall\nbe provided by the school district in which the facility or youth\nshelter is located, within the limits of the funds allocated by the\ncommissioner for such purposes pursuant to section thirty-six hundred\ntwo of this chapter and pursuant to a plan approved by the commissioner.\nSchool districts shall submit such plan by July fifteenth of each school\nyear. Boards of education are authorized to contract for the provision\nof such educational services by a board of cooperative educational\nservices or by another public school district.\n  b. Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the school district\nin which the child resided at the time of the child's commitment to the\ncustody of the sheriff or local commissioner of corrections or youth\nshelter shall reimburse the education department for its expenditure for\nthe full time equivalent attendance of such child pursuant to\nsubdivision thirteen of section thirty-six hundred two of this chapter\non behalf of such child, in an amount equal to the product of such full\ntime equivalent attendance and the school district basic contribution,\nas such te...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>