<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3210"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3210">
        <num>3210</num>
        <heading>Amount and character of required attendance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3210__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Absence for religious observance and education shall be\npermitted under rules that the commissioner shall establish.\n  (ii) In addition, the board of education or trustees shall determine\nwhether school session should not be held at an individual public\nschool, or district-wide, on a day where, if school were in session,\nabsenteeism may result in the waste of educational resources because a\nconsiderable proportion of the student population is unlikely to attend\nbecause of a religious or cultural day of observance.\n  c. In the event that a person requests the release of a minor required\nby the provisions of part one of this article to attend upon\ninstruction, the identity of such person shall be verified against a\nlist of names provided by the person or persons in parental relation to\nthe minor, as defined in section two of this chapter, at the time of\nsuch minor's enrollment. The school district may adopt appropriate\nprocedures for the purpose of submitting a list of names at a later date\nor updating the list of names provided by the person or persons in\nparental relation. If such person is identified as one of those persons\nincluded on such list, such minor may be released from attendance. If\nsuch person is identified as a person not included on such list, such\nminor may not be released except in the event of an emergency as\ndetermined in the sole discretion of the principal of the school, or his\ndesignee, provided that the person or persons in parental relation to\nthe minor have been contacted and have agreed to such release. A school\ndistrict may presume that either parent of the student has authority to\nobtain the release of said minor unless the school district has been\nprovided with a certified copy of the legally binding instrument such as\nthe court order or decree of divorce, separation or custody which\nprovides evidence to the contrary. No situation shall be deemed an\nemergency until the facts of such situation have been verified...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>