<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3216"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3216"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3216"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3216">
        <num>3216</num>
        <heading>Employment certificates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3216. Employment certificates.  1. A student non-factory\nemployment certificate may be issued to a minor fourteen or fifteen\nyears of age who is attending day school. The certificate shall be valid\nfor work in a trade, business or service, but shall not be valid for\nwork in or in connection with a factory except as provided in\nsubdivision four of section one hundred thirty-one of the labor law.\n  2. A student general employment certificate may be issued to a minor\nsixteen or seventeen years of age who is attending day school. It shall\nbe valid for work in or in connection with a factory or any other trade,\nbusiness or service.\n  3. A full-time employment certificate may be issued to a minor sixteen\nor seventeen years of age who is not attending day school or who\ndeclares his intention to leave day school for full-time employment. It\nshall be valid for work in or in connection with a factory or any other\ntrade, business or service. A full-time employment certificate also may\nbe issued to a minor who is a graduate of a four-year high school, but\nif such minor is under sixteen years of age the certificate shall not be\nvalid for work in or in connection with a factory except as provided in\nsubdivision four of section one hundred and thirty-one of the labor law.\n  4. A limited employment certificate may be issued as provided in\nsubdivision two of section thirty-two hundred twenty of this article.\n  5. A special employment certificate may be issued as provided in\nsection thirty-two hundred twenty-five of this article.\n  6. An employment certificate shall be valid not only for the initial\nemployment but also for subsequent employments in work permitted by the\nparticular type of certificate.\n  7. An employment certificate shall expire two years from the date of\nits issuance, except as otherwise provided in this article. No\nemployment certificate shall be valid for employment in violation of any\nprovision of the labor law or rules issued thereunder.\n  8. An employment certificate shall be kept on file at the place of the\nminor's employment and shall be returned to the minor when the\nemployment terminates.\n  * NB Effective until May 9, 2027\n  * ยง 3216. Employment certificates. 1. A student non-factory employment\ncertificate may be issued to a minor fourteen or fifteen years of age\nwho is attending day school. The certificate shall be valid for work in\na trade, business or service, but shall not be valid for work in or in\nconnection with a factory except as provided in subdivision four of\nsection one hundred thirty-one of the labor law.\n  2. A student general employment certificate may be issued to a minor\nsixteen or seventeen years of age who is attending day school. It shall\nbe valid for work in or in connection with a factory or any other trade,\nbusiness or service.\n  3. A full-time employment certificate may be issued to a minor sixteen\nor seventeen years of age who is not attending day school or who\ndeclares their intention to leave day school for full-time employment.\nIt shall be valid for work in or in connection with a factory or any\nother trade, business or service. A full-time employment certificate\nalso may be issued to a minor who is a graduate of a four-year high\nschool, but if such minor is under sixteen years of age the certificate\nshall not be valid for work in or in connection with a factory except as\nprovided in subdivision four of section one hundred and thirty-one of\nthe labor law.\n  4. An employment certificate shall be valid not only for the initial\nemployment but also for subsequent employments in work permitted by the\nparticular type of certificate, provided that the minor has updated\ntheir electronic registration to reflect the subsequent employer as\nrequired by section one hundred thirty-five of the labor law.\n  5. An employment certificate shall expire two years from the date of\nits issuance, except as otherwise provided in this article. No\nemployment certificate shall be valid for employment in violation of any\nprovision of the labor law or rules issued thereunder.\n  6. An employment certificate shall be kept on file at the place of the\nminor's employment or be readily accessible to any person authorized by\nlaw to examine such document in accordance with the recordkeeping\nrequirements set forth in section one hundred thirty-five of the labor\nlaw.\n  * NB Effective May 9, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>