<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3220"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3220">
        <num>3220</num>
        <heading>Certificate of physical fitness</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3220. Certificate of physical fitness. 1. A certificate of\nphysical fitness shall be issued to a minor if a thorough physical\nexamination made within twelve months of his or her application for an\nemployment certificate shows that such minor is of sound health, and if\nthere are no known health problems at the time of issuance of the\ncertificate, and if the applicant is physically qualified for lawful\nemployment. If a known health problem exists at the time of the\napplication for such certificate, another examination may be required by\nthe issuing authority. Such certificate shall be issued and such\nphysical examination shall be made, in a city of over three hundred\nthousand population, by a physician designated by the board of health,\nand elsewhere by the director of school health services charged with the\nduty of making physical examinations of all school children or by any\nphysician duly licensed to practice medicine in this state. A new\ncertificate of physical fitness shall not be required if one had been\nissued to the minor within twelve months.\n  2. If the physician authorized to issue certificates of physical\nfitness shall find that a minor from fourteen to eighteen years of age\nis not physically sound but that in the physician's opinion the minor\nmay safely engage in certain occupations as specified by the regulations\nof the commissioner of education, the physician shall require a pledge\nof employment and may issue to the minor a certificate of limited\nphysical fitness, and shall describe therein the physical disability of\nthe minor and shall indicate the particular employer and the occupation\nin which the minor may engage. A limited employment certificate issued\nto a minor from fourteen to eighteen years of age who has presented a\ncertificate of limited physical fitness shall be valid for not more than\nsix months from the date of its issuance and shall bear on the face of\nthe certificate the date of its expiration and the particular employer\nand occupation to which the employment of the minor is limited;\nprovided, however, that the examining physician may indicate upon the\ncertificate of limited physical fitness that the physical disability of\nthe minor is of a permanent nature, in which case such certificate shall\nnot expire at the end of six months but shall remain valid for so long\nas the nature and type of work set forth in the pledge of employment\nremain substantially the same.\n  3. A record made of the physical examination shall show whether a\ncertificate of physical fitness has been issued or withheld. Such record\nshall be sent to the certificating official.\n  4. A certificate of physical fitness issued in another state to a\nminor seeking employment in this state may be accepted in lieu of the\ncertificate of physical fitness required by subdivision one of this\nsection, provided the standards for issuing such certificates in the\nother state are deemed substantially equivalent to those of this state\nin accordance with regulations adopted by the commissioner of education.\n  * NB Repealed May 9, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>