<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3222"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3222"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3222"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3222/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3222/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3222/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3222/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3222">
        <num>3222</num>
        <heading>Schooling record</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3222. Schooling record.  1. By whom issued.  The schooling record\nshall be issued by the principal of the school the minor attends or last\nattended, or by a teacher deputized by the principal or by a supervising\nofficial, and during the months of July and August, and at other times\nin extraordinary circumstances and emergencies, by one or more public\nschool officials deputized in writing by the chancellor in New York city\nand elsewhere by the superintendent of schools or by the district\nsuperintendent of schools.\n  2. Procedure.  On application of the person in parental relation, a\nschooling record shall be issued promptly to a minor who complies with\nthe following conditions:\n  a. Presents a certificate of physical fitness.  Upon receipt of an\napplication for a schooling record the person authorized to issue such\nrecord shall request that an examination be made of the minor for a\ncertificate of physical fitness in accordance with the requirements\nherein prescribed.\n  b. Meets the specified age requirement.\n  3. Such schooling record shall show, when practicable, the name of the\nschool and grade or class which the minor is then attending or last\nattended.\n  4. Upon notification by the division of criminal justice services that\na child has been listed as a missing child, a school in which the child\nis currently or was previously enrolled shall flag the schooling record\nof the child in such a manner that whenever a copy of or information\nconcerning the schooling record is requested, the person authorized to\nissue such record shall be alerted to the fact that the child has been\nreported as a missing child. The school shall immediately report to the\nlocal law enforcement authority and the division of criminal justice\nservices any request concerning flagged schooling records or knowledge\nas to the whereabouts of any missing child. Upon notification by the\ndivision of criminal justice services that a reported missing child has\nbeen recovered, the school shall remove the flag from the person's\nschooling record.\n  5. Upon notification by the division of criminal justice services that\na child who may be listed as a missing child is currently enrolled in\nand believed to be attending a New York school, such school shall\nimmediately notify the division of criminal justice services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>