<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3227"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3227"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3227"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3227">
        <num>3227</num>
        <heading>Street trades</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3227. Street trades. 1. Definition. A street trade for the\npurposes of part one of this article shall include the carrying,\nselling, exposing or offering for sale of newspapers or periodicals, and\nwork as a bootblack, but shall not include the occupation engaged in by\na newspaper carrier as defined in subdivision one of section thirty-two\nhundred twenty-eight of this chapter.\n  2. Application.  The provisions of this section shall apply to all\nschool districts.\n  3. No minor under fourteen years of age shall be engaged in a street\ntrade; and no minor from fourteen to eighteen years of age shall be so\nengaged unless a street trades permit has been lawfully issued to the\nminor.\n  4. A street trades permit shall be issued in the same manner and with\nthe same requirements as in the case of an employment certificate.  Such\na permit shall expire two years from the date of its issuance.\n  5. A minor to whom a street trades permit has been issued shall carry\nit on his or her person while engaged in a street trade.  Such a permit\nshall not be transferred to another minor or used by another if\ntransferred.\n  6. No minor shall be engaged in a street trade before six o'clock in\nthe morning nor after seven o'clock in the evening, nor during the time\nthe minor is required to attend upon instruction, nor more than four\nhours in any one day when school is in session, nor more than five hours\nin any one day when school is not in session.\n  7. The police shall enforce the provisions of this section except with\nrespect to the issuance and revocation of street trades permits. The\nindustrial commissioner shall have concurrent power to enforce this\nsection except with respect to the issuance and revocation of street\ntrades permits.\n  8. The school authorities may revoke the permit for cause after due\nnotice.\n  * NB Repealed May 9, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>