<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3241"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3241"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3241"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3241/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3241/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3241/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3241/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3241">
        <num>3241</num>
        <heading>School census in cities, except in cities having a population of one hundred twenty-five thousand or more</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3241. School census in cities, except in cities having a population\nof one hundred twenty-five thousand or more. 1. The board of education\nof each city, except in cities having a population of one hundred\ntwenty-five thousand or more, shall constitute a permanent census board\nin such city. Such board shall, under its regulations, cause a census of\nthe children in its city to be taken and to be amended from day to day,\nas changes of residence shall occur among persons in such cities within\nthe ages prescribed in subdivision two of this section and as other\npersons shall come within the ages prescribed therein and as other\npersons within such ages shall become residents of such cities, so that\nthere shall always be on file with such board a complete census giving\nthe facts and information required in subdivision two of this section;\nprovided, however, that for pre-school students from birth to five years\nof age, such census may be prepared and filed biennially on or before\nthe fifteenth day of October.\n  2. Such census shall include all persons between birth and eighteen\nyears of age and in the case of physically or mentally handicapped\nchildren between birth and twenty-one years of age, their names, their\nrespective residences by street and number, the day of the month and the\nyear of their birth, the names of the persons in parental relation to\nthem, such information relating to physical or mental defects, to\nilliteracy, to employment and to the enforcement of the law relating to\nchild labor and compulsory education as the education department and the\nboard of education of each such city shall require and also such further\ninformation as such board of education shall require.\n  3. Such board shall provide to the commissioner of education upon\nwritten request therefor and in such form as shall be prescribed by him,\na report containing the names, ages and addresses of those children who\nare blind or deaf and those having serious physical or mental defects.\nIn addition such report shall indicate whether such children are being\neducated within the public schools of the district or, if they are not,\nwhere such education is being furnished them.\n  4. It shall be the duty of persons in parental relation to any person\nbetween such ages residing within the limits of any such city to make\nsuch reports as the board of education of such city shall require. Such\nreports shall contain the following information:\n  a. Two weeks before any child shall become of the compulsory school\nage, the name of such child, its residence, the name of the person or\npersons in parental relation thereto, and the name and location of the\nschool to which such child shall have been or shall be sent as a pupil.\n  b. In case a child of compulsory school age shall, for any cause, be\nremoved from one school and sent to another school, or sent to work in\naccordance with the labor law, all the facts in relation thereto.\n  c. In case the residence of a child shall be removed from one police\nprecinct to another police precinct, the new residence and the other\nfacts required in paragraphs a and b of this subdivision.\n  d. In case a child between birth and eighteen years of age shall\nbecome a resident of such city for the first time, the name, residence\nand such other facts as the board of education shall require.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>