<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3310"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3310"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3310"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3310/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3310/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3310/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3310/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3310">
        <num>3310</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the interstate commission</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3310. Powers and duties of the interstate commission. The interstate\ncommission shall have the following powers:\n  1. To provide for dispute resolution among member states.\n  2. To promulgate rules and take all necessary actions to effect the\ngoals, purposes and obligations as enumerated in this compact.\n  3. To issue, upon request of a member state, advisory opinions\nconcerning the meaning or interpretation of the interstate compact, its\nbylaws, rules and actions.\n  4. To enforce compliance with the compact provisions, the rules\npromulgated by the interstate commission, and the bylaws, using all\nnecessary and proper means, including but not limited to the use of\njudicial process.\n  5. To establish and maintain offices which shall be located within one\nor more of the member states.\n  6. To purchase and maintain insurance and bonds.\n  7. To borrow, accept, hire or contract for services of personnel.\n  8. To establish and appoint committees including, but not limited to,\nan executive committee as required by subdivision five of section\nthirty-three hundred nine of this article which shall have the power to\nact on behalf of the interstate commission in carrying out its powers\nand duties hereunder.\n  9. To elect or appoint such officers, attorneys, employees, agents, or\nconsultants, and to fix their compensation, define their duties and\ndetermine their qualifications; and to establish the interstate\ncommission's personnel policies and programs relating to conflicts of\ninterest, rates of compensation, and qualifications of personnel.\n  10. To accept any and all donations and grants of money, equipment,\nsupplies, materials, and services, and to receive, utilize, and dispose\nof it.\n  11. To lease, purchase, accept contributions or donations of, or\notherwise to own, hold, improve or use any property, real, personal, or\nmixed.\n  12. To sell, convey, mortgage, pledge, lease, exchange, abandon, or\notherwise dispose of any property, real, personal or mixed.\n  13. To establish a budget and make expenditures.\n  14. To adopt a seal and bylaws governing the management and operation\nof the interstate commission.\n  15. To report annually to the legislatures, governors, judiciary, and\nstate councils of the member states concerning the activities of the\ninterstate commission during the preceding year. Such reports shall also\ninclude any recommendations that may have been adopted by the interstate\ncommission.\n  16. To coordinate education, training and public awareness regarding\nthe compact, its implementation and operation for officials and parents\ninvolved in such activity.\n  17. To establish uniform standards for the reporting, collecting and\nexchanging of data.\n  18. To maintain corporate books and records in accordance with the\nbylaws.\n  19. To perform such functions as may be necessary or appropriate to\nachieve the purposes of this compact.\n  20. To provide for the uniform collection and sharing of information\nbetween and among member states, schools and military families under\nthis compact consistent with all applicable privacy laws.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>