<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-352"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-352"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-06-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="352"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-352/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-352/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-352/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-352/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_352">
        <num>352</num>
        <heading>State university of New York established</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 352. State university of New York established. 1. There is hereby\ncreated in the state education department and within the university of\nthe state of New York as established under the board of regents a\ncorporation to be known as the state university of New York which shall\nbe responsible for the planning, supervision and administration of\nfacilities and programs in accordance with the plan proposed by the\nstate university trustees as approved by the regents pursuant to section\ntwo hundred thirty-seven of this chapter. The state university shall\nprovide for higher education supported in whole or in part with state\nmoneys in accordance with the provisions of section three hundred\nfifty-eight hereof, and shall perform such other duties as may be\nentrusted to it by the provisions of this article and any other law.\nSubject to the terms of any agreement to which it is a party, such\ncorporation shall have the care, custody, control and management of the\nlands, grounds, buildings, facilities and equipment used for the\npurposes of the state-operated institutions of the state university, and\nit shall have power to protect, preserve and improve the same.\n  2. Whenever such corporation acquires, absorbs, merges or consolidates\nwith or becomes the successor to any higher educational institution, all\nthe right, title and interest in real property held by such predecessor\ninstitution shall vest in and be held and enjoyed by the people of the\nstate of New York and state university of New York shall thereupon be\ndeemed to be vested with and become the successor to all right, title\nand interest in any personal property, or any beneficial interest\ntherein, or any other rights and powers possessed by such institution,\nwhether derived by gift, grant, devise or bequest, in trust or\notherwise.\n  3. The state university shall consist of the four university centers\nat Albany, Binghamton, Buffalo and Stony Brook, the designated colleges\nof arts and sciences at Brockport, Buffalo, Cortland, Fredonia, Geneseo,\nNew Paltz, Old Westbury, Oneonta, Oswego, Plattsburgh, Potsdam and\nPurchase, empire state college, the agricultural and technical colleges\nat Alfred, Canton, Cobleskill, Delhi, Farmingdale and Morrisville,\ndownstate medical center, upstate medical center, the college of\noptometry, the college of environmental science and forestry, maritime\ncollege, the college of technology at Utica/Rome, the statutory or\ncontract colleges at Cornell university and Alfred university, and such\nadditional universities, colleges and other institutions, facilities and\nresearch centers as have been or hereafter may be acquired, established,\noperated or contracted to be operated for the state by the state\nuniversity trustees.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>