<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="355-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_355_A">
        <num>355-A</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of trustees--personnel functions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_355_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nThe state university trustees are authorized and empowered to classify\nand reclassify all positions in the state university determined pursuant\nto section thirty-five of the civil service law to be in the\nprofessional service as defined in subdivision three of this section,\nexcept those of the New York state colleges, schools and experiment\nstations administered by Cornell university and Alfred university.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To the fullest extent possible consistent with its authority under\nthe civil service law, and after consultation with the state university\ntrustees, the state civil service commission shall consider the unique\neducational mission and operating requirements of the state university\nwhen making any determination relating to the jurisdictional\nclassification of positions in the state university in the classified\nservice. The director of the classification and compensation division of\nthe department of civil service shall similarly consider the unique\neducational mission and operating requirements of the state university\nwhen making determinations concerning the classification and\nreclassification and the allocation and reallocation of the positions in\nthe state university in the classified service.\n  2. Subject to the approval of the state university trustees, Cornell\nuniversity and Alfred university are authorized and empowered to\nallocate and reallocate positions in the non-professional services of\nthe New York state statutory or contract colleges, schools and\nexperiment stations administered by such universities, as classified and\nreclassified by the respective universities, in accordance with a\nschedule of positions and salaries filed by the state university\ntrustees pursuant to subdivision four of section three hundred\nfifty-five of this chapter.\n  3. a. The professional service shall include positions requiring the\nperformance of educational functions in teacher education, agriculture,\nhome economics, forestry, ceramics, liberal and applied arts and\nsciences, engineering, technical skills, crafts, business education,\nlabor and industrial relations, medicine, dentistry, veterinary\nmedicine, pharmacy, nursing, law, public affairs, maritime officer\ntraining, academic administration, library service, student activities,\nstudent personnel service and other professions required to carry on the\nwork of the state university and of the colleges...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355_A__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection thirty-five of the civil service law having, as of the effective\ndate of such change, an accrued balance of annual leave or sick leave\nunder the attendance rules for the classified service, shall retain such\nbalances to such employee's credit upon appointment to the professional\nservice, but shall accrue no further annual or sick leave under the\nattendance rules for the classified service. Thereafter any such\nemployees shall be eligible for annual leave and sick leave as provided\nfor by the state university trustees. Upon resignation or retirement\nfrom state service such employee shall be paid in cash for any balance\nof annual leave in accordance with the regulations applicable to persons\nin the professional service; provided however, that in the case of death\nwhile in service, such payment, if any, shall be made to the beneficiary\nto whom a survivor's death benefit pursuant to section one hundred\nfifty-four of the civil service law, if any, would be payable.\n  Any such employee having accrued overtime or personal leave balance\nshall forfeit such credit, except that such employee shall be paid in\ncash for an accrued balance of overtime on the basis of the annual\nsalary in that employee's classified service position at the time of\nsuch employee's appointment to the unclassified service. Hereafter, any\nsuch employee shall be subject to the provisions made by the state\nuniversity trustees with respect to vacation and other leave except as\nherein provided.\n  d. Any employee in the unclassified service pursuant to subdivision\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355_A__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section thirty-five of the civil service law who accepts\nappointment to a classified service position having, as of the effective\ndate of such change, eligibility for vacation or sick leave under the\nprovisions made by the state university trustees shall be credited with\nsuch balance under the attendance rules for the classified service;\nprovided however, that not more than thirty days of annual leave and two\nhundred days of sick leave shall be so credited. Thereafter such\nemployee shall accrue annual leave and sick leave credits in accordance\nwith the attendance rules for the classified service, except that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthat employee's previous state service shall be considered in\ndetermining the rate at which the employee shall accumulate annual leave\nunder such rules and (ii) such service shall be considered in allowing\nany sick leave at one-half salary for which the employee may be\notherwise eligible under such rules. For the purpose of establishing an\nanniversary date for computing personal leave credit, such employee\nshall be deemed to have been appointed on the effective date of that\nemployee's appointment to the classified service from the unclassified\nservice. Thereafter such employee shall be subject to the attendance\nrules for the classified service except as herein provided.\n  11. Whenever a salary for a position in the professional service\nresults in an annual salary rate in an amount other than a whole dollar\namount, said rate shall be increased to the next higher whole dollar.\n  12. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the powers\nheretofore conferred on Cornell university or Alfred university except\nas expressly provided for herein.\n  13. The expenditure of moneys appropriated to support a group\ndisability insurance program for employees in the professional service\nshall not exceed sixty percent of salary plus contributions for annuity\ncontracts not to exceed the rates of employer contributions pursuant to\narticle eight-B of this chapter plus adjustment for cost of living\nincreases reduced by any amount for which the employee is eligible\npursuant to compensation or benefit paid for, by or on behalf of the\nstate or state university and any normal contribution to a retirement\nprogram made by the state or the state university on the employee's\nbehalf while eligible for benefits under such program in accordance with\nregulations of the state university trustees relating to eligibility and\nother terms, conditions and limitations of coverage and benefits and\nadministration of program.\n  13. Notwithstanding subdivisions one throug...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>