<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3602-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3602_B">
        <num>3602-B</num>
        <heading>Apportionment of moneys to school districts employing fewer than eight teachers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3602-b. Apportionment of moneys to school districts employing fewer\nthan eight teachers. 1. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, each\nschool district of the state employing fewer than eight teachers shall\nreceive its apportionment of public money payable during the school year\ncommencing July first, nineteen hundred sixty-three and during\nsubsequent school years pursuant to the provisions of this section. Such\napportionment shall be computed by applying the state sharing ratio of\nthe district computed in the same manner as provided in section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article to the approved operating expense\nof the school district for operating purposes and for transportation.\n  a. Approved operating expense shall be for the year prior to the base\nyear as defined in section thirty-six hundred two of this article and\nshall be determined in the same manner provided in such section,\nprovided, however, that the amount so approved shall not exceed the sum\nof (1) four thousand five hundred dollars multiplied by the lesser of\nthe number of full-time teachers employed during such year prior to the\nbase year or seven and (2) weighted average daily attendance as defined\nin section thirty-six hundred two of this article for the base year\nmultiplied by the sum of sixty dollars plus an amount computed by\nmultiplying ninety cents by such weighted average daily attendance. Any\nsuch district employing three or more teachers shall be permitted to use\nthe weighted average daily attendance averaged over the three year\nperiod immediately preceding the current year as defined in section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article.\n  b. Approved transportation expense shall be for the base year and\nshall be determined in the same manner as provided in subdivision seven\nof section thirty-six hundred two of this chapter.\n  2. If the local revenue provided by any such school district in the\ncurrent year, as defined in section thirty-six hundred two of this\narticle, inclusive of its local nonproperty tax receipts, is less than\nthe amount which could be raised by a tax at the rate specified in this\nsection on its actual valuation as defined in such section, the\napportionment for such current year shall be reduced by the amount which\nsuch local revenue is less than the amount which could be raised at such\nrate. The rate for the school year two thousand seven--two thousand\neight and thereafter shall be the local tax factor established pursuant\nto subdivision four of section thirty-six hundred two of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>