<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3609-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3609_G">
        <num>3609-G</num>
        <heading>Moneys apportioned to school districts for reimbursement of article twenty-three of the tax law payments commencing in the 2009-2010 scho...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3609_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Moneys paid pursuant to this section shall be payable to the\ntreasurer of each city school district, and the treasurer of each union\nfree school district and of each central school district and of each\nother school district, if there be a treasurer, otherwise to the\ncollector or other disbursing officer of such district, who shall apply\nfor and receive the same as soon as payable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3609_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the case of city school districts of the cities with one\nhundred twenty-five thousand inhabitants or more, any payment which\npursuant to this section is required to be made to the treasurer of the\ncity school district, shall be made to the city treasurer or\nchamberlain.\n  4. Any payment to a school district pursuant to this section shall be\ngeneral receipts of the district and may be used for any lawful purpose\nof the district.\n  5. It is the intent of the governor to submit and the legislature to\nenact for each fiscal year after the two thousand nine--two thousand ten\nfiscal year in an annual budget bill an appropriation in the amount to\nbe paid to school districts pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>