<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3609-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3609_D">
        <num>3609-D</num>
        <heading>Moneys apportioned for board of cooperative educational services aidable expenditures when and how payable commencing July first, two tho...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3609_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one hundred percent of the respective amount set\nforth for each school district as payable pursuant to this section in\nthe school aid computer listing produced by the commissioner in support\nof the budget including the appropriation for support of boards of\ncooperative educational services for payments due prior to April first\nfor the current year, or (ii) the apportionment calculated by the\ncommissioner based on data on file at the time the payment is processed;\nprovided however, that for the purposes of any payment to be made in the\nmonth of June of two thousand six such calculation shall be based on the\nschool aid computer listing for the current year using updated data at\nthe time of each payment. For districts subject to chapter five hundred\nsixty-three of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty, thirty-six hundred\ntwo-b, or two thousand forty of this chapter, for aid payable in the two\nthousand four--two thousand five school year and thereafter, "moneys\napportioned" shall mean the apportionment calculated by the commissioner\nbased on data on file at the time the payment is processed. The "school\naid computer listing for the current year" shall be as defined in the\nopening paragraph of section thirty-six hundred nine-a of this article.\nThe definitions "base year" and "current year" as set forth in\nsubdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this article shall\napply to this section.\n  1. Prescribed payments. Of the moneys to be apportioned by the\ncommissioner to school districts during the school year, that portion\npayable pursuant to section nineteen hundred fifty of this chapter shall\nbe used in the first instance to make payments on behalf of boards of\ncooperative educational services to the teachers' retirement system in\nthe same manner as payments made on behalf of school districts pursuant\nto subparagraph one of paragraph a of subdivision one of section\nthirty-six hundred nine-a of this article, and additional payments shal...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>