<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3610"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3610"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3610"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3610">
        <num>3610</num>
        <heading>Apportionment for apprenticeship training</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3610. Apportionment for apprenticeship training.  1. Apprenticeship\ntraining programs. Local education agencies which provide related or\nsupplemental instruction to apprentices registered by the state\ndepartment of labor pursuant to article twenty-three of the labor law\nshall be eligible for an apportionment pursuant to the provisions of\nthis section for the operation of apprenticeship training programs as\napproved by the commissioner. Priority shall be given to local education\nagencies which provide for an increased number of participants in the\nrelated or supplemental instructional component of apprentice training\nprograms. Designated local education agencies may provide such programs\ndirectly, or by contracting with school districts, boards of cooperative\neducational services and other providers of apprentice training\nservices, including postsecondary institutions and other providers\nauthorized to confer degrees in this state or in which the course of\ninstruction is licensed, registered or approved pursuant to any\nprovision of this chapter.\n  2. Apprenticeship training hours. For the purpose of computing an\napportionment under this section, apprenticeship training hours shall be\nthe total number of hours of related or supplemental instruction given\nall apprentices in approved apprenticeship training programs in the area\nserved by the designated local education agency between July first and\nJune thirtieth of the base year as reported to the commissioner by\nSeptember first of the current year.\n  3. Maximum apportionment per hour.  For aid payable for school year\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine--ninety the  maximum apportionment per\napprenticeship training hour shall be computed by dividing the state\nappropriation for related and supplemental instruction for apprentices\nby the total number of apprenticeship training hours of all designated\nlocal education agencies in the state, computed in accordance with the\nregulations of the commissioner. For aid payable for school year\nnineteen hundred ninety--ninety-one and thereafter, this apportionment\nshall be at the rate of one dollar per training hour.\n  4. Apprenticeship training program apportionment. The apportionment\npursuant to this section shall be the product obtained when the\napportionment per hour is multiplied by the number of apprenticeship\ntraining hours of the designated local education agency. Notwithstanding\nthe provisions of section thirty-six hundred nine of this article,\npayment of such apportionment shall be made by November first of the\ncurrent year.\n  5. State aid. No designated local education agency may receive under\nthe provisions of this section an amount which when added to all other\nstate aid received by such designated local education agency for the\npurpose of this section, exceeds one-half the cost of such program in\nthat year. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, if the\ntotal aid received exceeds one-half the cost of the program, any state\naid payable to the designated local education agency shall be reduced in\nthe amount of such excess.\n  6. Apprentices. Apprentices in apprenticeship training programs shall\nnot be included in any attendance count of this article and shall not\ngenerate aid under any other provisions of this chapter.\n  7. Apportionment for administrative costs. In addition to the\napportionment under subdivision four of this section, any designated\nlocal education agency which has reported by September first the\nprocessing of more than one hundred fifty apprentices shall receive an\namount equal to three dollars per apprentice served.\n  8. Regulations. The commissioner may adopt regulations to implement\nany of the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>