<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3612"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3612"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3612"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3612/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3612/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3612/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3612/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3612">
        <num>3612</num>
        <heading>Teachers of tomorrow teacher recruitment and retention program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>tuition charged for test preparation workshops intended to prepare\nrecipients to pass teacher certification exams required for initial or\nprovisional teacher certification, which shall be provided by the board\nof education either through a contract for such services or by providing\nsuch services through employees of the board of education; and\n  (ii) tuition charged for any additional coursework at an accredited\ninstitution of higher education required of the recipient to receive\ninitial or provisional teacher certification, as determined by the\ncommissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Certification stipends of two thousand dollars each may be\nprovided pursuant to this subdivision to award recipients. Fifty percent\nof each award amount shall be payable from state funds provided to the\nschool district pursuant to this section and the remaining fifty percent\nshall be payable by the board of education from other sources of\nrevenue, provided that if the board of education elects to provide the\nservices described in clause</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subparagraph two of this paragraph\nthen such remaining fifty percent share may be paid by the board through\nin-kind direct services to the award recipient.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Awards shall be paid to award recipients upon proof of the\nrecipient's expenditure for allowable expenses as provided for in\nclauses</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of subparagraph two of this paragraph.\n  (ii) Such awards shall be in an amount of two thousand dollars per\naward or the actual expenses incurred by the recipient, whichever is\nless.\n  (iii) No person shall be eligible for more than one award pursuant to\nthis subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of education shall develop and secure from the award\nrecipient a written agreement outlining the service obligation. Such\nagreement shall include provisions for the recipient to repay the amount\nof the award to the school district if the recipient fails to complete\ntheir service obligation in any year where an award is granted, and such\nrepaid amounts shall be deducted from any grant amounts due to the\ndistrict from the state pursuant to this section. Upon a written appeal\nby an award recipient, the board of education, in its discretion, may\nprovide a waiver of repayment provisions for an award recipient who\nfails to complete his or her service requirement for documented reasons\nof health or other severe hardship, as determined by the commissioner.\n  d. Notification. The board of education shall notify both successful\nand unsuccessful applicants by September first of any school year for\nwhich an initial or renewed award is provided to teachers pursuant to\nthis s...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>have completed sixty or more hours of credit bearing college\ncourses, be in good academic standing as determined by the higher\neducation institution of attendance, have attended an accredited New\nYork state college or university full-time in the base year, be enrolled\nin a registered program for the preparation of teachers at an accredited\nNew York state institution of higher education or have indicated a\ndesire to enter the teaching profession, and are recommended by their\ncollege or university to participate in the program.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>agree to a service obligation of the full duration of the\ninternship program, as determined by the board of education.\n  b. Application and selection.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Boards of education in school\ndistricts that are eligible for funding pursuant to this section shall\ndevelop and distribute an application to the accredited colleges and\nuniversities of the state which have approved teacher education\nprograms. Such application shall include at a minimum a description of\nthe program including:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the duration of the program which shall operate for at least five\nor more weeks during the months of June through August generally;\n  (ii) the amount of any stipend for the program;\n  (iii) available housing for the program;\n  (iv) the training and professional development opportunities afforded\nto the student; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3612__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of time the student will spend in direct contact with\nchildren participating in educational activities.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of education shall determine the application process for\nstudents deemed eligible for the award, and shall in its discretion\nselect the number of eligible applicants who will receive an award\npursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the number of eligible applicants exceeds the number of awards\ndetermined by the board pursuant to this subdivision then the board\nshall use an objective competitive process based on educational\nqualifications to determine which eligible applicants shall receive\nawards.\n  c. Payment of awards.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Annual awards from state funds provided for\nthis purpose shall be paid by the board of education to the award\nrecipient. No award shall be made for less than the duration of the\nprogram, as determined by the board of education. Nothing shall prohibit\na board of education from allowing an eligible applicant from\nparticipating in the program more than once, provided the eligible\napplicant provided satisfactory service in any prior year as determined\nby the board of education.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Allowable expenses. Districts may expend funds pursuant to this\nsubdivision for:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>stipends of up to two thousand dollars per student;\n  (ii) housing for a portion of the students participating in the\nprogram, which shall include provisions for the students to pay a\nportion of the housing costs and to pay a refundable security deposit on\nsuch housing;\n  (iii) orientation, training and professional development of the\nstudents participating in the program; and\n  (iv) other expenses appropriate to the operation of the program, as\napproved by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of education shall develop and secure from the award\nrecipient a written agreement outlining the service obligation. Such\nagreement shall include provisions for the recipient to repay the amount\nof any stipend provided pursuant to this subdivision to the school\ndistrict if the recipient fails to complete their service obligation for\nany year where an award is granted, and such repaid amounts shall be\ndeducted from any grant amounts due to the district from the state\npursuant to this section. Upon a written appeal by an award recipient,\nthe board of education, in its discretion, may provide a waiver of\nrepayment provisions for an award recipient who fails to complete his or\nher service requirement for documented reasons of health or other severe\nhardship, as determined by the commissioner.\n  d. Colleges and universities may provide credit for the summer in the\ncity program and may charge a fee for such credit or provide the credit\nfree of charge. Participation in...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>he or she has received national board certification from the\nNational Board for Professional Teaching Standards.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>he or she is to be employed full-time for the school year by a\npublic school designated as a low performing school.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>he or she agrees to a service obligation of three years of service\nin a low performing school as a condition of receiving awards pursuant\nto this subdivision.\n  f. Application and selection.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of education shall\ndetermine the form of the application and the application process for\nteachers deemed eligible for the award, and shall in its discretion\nselect the number of eligible applicants who will receive an award\npursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the number of eligible applicants exceeds the number of awards\ndetermined by the board pursuant to this subdivision then the board\nshall use an objective competitive process based on educational\nqualifications to determine which eligible applicants shall receive\nawards.\n  g. Payment of awards.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Annual awards from state funds provided for\nthis purpose shall be paid by the board of education to the award\nrecipient.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The initial annual award shall be ten thousand dollars, and such\ninitial annual award may be renewable each year, for two additional\nyears, provided that the recipient has provided satisfactory service in\nany prior year in which an initial or renewed annual award was granted\nto the recipient and the recipient continues to fulfill his or her\nservice obligation. No annual awards shall be made for less than one\nyear of service and provided further that the sum of any initial and\nrenewed annual awards shall not exceed thirty thousand dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of education shall develop and secure from the award\nrecipient a written agreement outlining the service obligation. Such\nagreement shall include provisions for the recipient to repay the amount\nof the annual award to the school district if the recipient fails to\ncomplete a year of service in any year where an initial or renewed award\nis granted, and such repaid amounts shall be deducted from any grant\namounts due to the district from the state pursuant to this section.\nUpon a written appeal by an award recipient, the board of education, in\nits discretion, may provide a waiver of repayment provisions for an\naward recipient who fails to complete his or her service requirement for\ndocumented reasons of health or other severe hardship, as determined by\nthe commissioner.\n  h. Each board of education and particular master teacher shall agree\nto a three-year term in an eligible school building for each master\nteacher appointment and each master teacher shall be assign...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>has received initial or provisional certification to teach in the\npublic schools of the state and does not hold any permanent or\nprofessional certification to teach in the public schools of the state;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>he or she is employed full-time for the school year by a public\nschool designated as a teacher shortage area; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>he or she agrees to a service obligation of one year of service in\na teacher shortage area as a condition of receiving the award.\n  c. Application and selection.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of education shall\ndetermine the form of the application and the application process for\nteachers deemed eligible for the award, and shall in its discretion\nselect the number of eligible applicants who will receive an award\npursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the number of eligible applicants exceeds the number of awards\ndetermined by the board pursuant to this subdivision then the board\nshall use an objective competitive process based on educational\nqualifications to determine which eligible applicants shall receive\nawards.\n  d. Payment of awards.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Annual awards from state funds provided for\nthis purpose shall be paid by the board of education to the award\nrecipient.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The initial reimbursement award shall be seven hundred dollars or\nthe actual cost of one approved course, whichever is less, provided that\na recipient shall be eligible to receive three initial reimbursement\nawards in the school year. Such initial award shall be renewable for up\nto one additional year and such renewed reimbursement award shall be\nseven hundred dollars or the actual cost of one approved course,\nwhichever is less, provided that a recipient shall be eligible to\nreceive three renewed reimbursement awards in the school year, and\nprovided further that such eligible teacher has provided satisfactory\nservice in the prior year as determined by the board of education to be\neligible for any initial or renewed reimbursement awards. In no case\nshall the sum of any initial and renewed reimbursement awards exceed\nfour thousand two hundred dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of education shall develop and secure from the award\nrecipient a written agreement outlining the service obligation. Such\nagreement shall include provisions for the recipient to repay the amount\nof any reimbursement awards received to the school district if the\nrecipient fails to complete a year of service in any year where any\ninitial or renewed awards are granted, and such repaid amounts shall be\ndeducted from any grant amounts due to the district from the state\npursuant to this section. Upon a written appeal by an award recipient,\nthe board of education, in its discretion, may provide a waiver of\nrepayment provisions for an award recipient who fails to complete his or\nher service requirement for documented reasons of health or other severe\nhardship, as determined by the commissioner.\n  e. After February first, two thousand four, any course for which\ntuition reimbursement is made shall not be counted toward any continuing\neducation required of persons certifie...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>proof that the applicant has received, or is eligible to receive,\ninitial, provisional, permanent or professional certification to teach\nin the public schools of the state; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>proof that the applicant will be employed for the first time in\nthe city school district as a certified teacher in a teacher shortage\narea.\n  b. Allowable expenses. Funds provided for summer teacher training may\nbe used for the payment of expenses incurred by the district for\ntraining and orientation of certified teachers employed by the district\nfor the first time including team teaching with cooperating teachers,\nobserving summer school classes, and training on meeting new standards\nand assessments provided such expenditures from state funds for this\npurpose shall not exceed one thousand dollars per eligible participant.\nNothing in this subdivision shall limit the expenditure of local funds\nfor the purposes of this subdivision.\n  9. Science, mathematics and bilingual education tuition reimbursement\nprogram. Of the amount appropriated for purposes of this section for\ngrants to school districts for the two thousand seven--two thousand\neight school year and thereafter, fi...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>