<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3641-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3641_B">
        <num>3641-B</num>
        <heading>Grants for summer institutes for mathematics and science teachers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3641-b. Grants for summer institutes for mathematics and science\nteachers. The commissioner shall establish a program of competitively\nawarded grants within the amount appropriated for such purpose, to\npublic and independent colleges and universities offering teacher\neducation programs, in partnership with school districts, to conduct\nsummer institutes for teachers of science and mathematics in grades five\nthrough eight in middle schools, junior high schools, intermediate\nschools or junior/senior high schools with priority given as practicable\nto teachers in schools identified as schools in need of improvement or\nin corrective action or restructuring status, schools under registration\nreview or schools requiring academic progress. Such summer institutes\nshall be designed to advance the content knowledge and pedagogy of\nparticipating science and mathematics teachers and shall, to the extent\npracticable, be aligned and integrated with programs offered to\nexcelsior scholars pursuant to section thirty-six hundred forty-one-a of\nthis article. Teachers shall be selected for participation by their\nbuilding principal.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>