<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3650-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3650_B">
        <num>3650-B</num>
        <heading>Drivers and instructors; training and safety</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3650-b. Drivers and instructors; training and safety. 1.  The\ncommissioner shall establish training and safety technique requirements\nfor school bus drivers and school bus safety training instructors and\nshall make rules and regulations implementing such requirements on a\nstatewide basis.\n  2. The commissioner shall prepare and distribute school bus driver\nsafety training manuals to each school district. Such manual shall be\nperiodically updated and shall provide the framework for continuing\nschool bus safety education programs for school districts.\n  3.  Every school district shall certify to the commissioner that its\nschool bus drivers have successfully completed the school bus driver\nsafety training program established pursuant to the provisions of this\narticle and shall make an annual report to the commissioner on the\nimplementation and effectiveness of the program. Each school district\nshall have the option of having its employees certified as school bus\ndriver safety training instructors or contracting with certified\ninstructors to provide such training to the district.\n  4. The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of motor\nvehicles, shall establish a certification program for school bus driver\nsafety training instructors.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>