<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3651"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3651"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3651"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3651/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3651/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3651/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3651/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3651">
        <num>3651</num>
        <heading>Reserve fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3651__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>until approved by a majority vote of\nthe qualified voters of the district voting on a proposition therefor\nsubmitted at a regular or special school district meeting, or in school\ndistricts which do not have such meetings, at an election called for\nsuch purpose, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3651__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>unless the notice of such meeting or election\nshall have stated that a proposition to establish a reserve fund would\nbe so submitted, the purpose of the fund, the ultimate amount thereof,\nits probable term and the source from which the funds would be obtained.\nSuch reserve fund may be established for financing, in whole or in part,\nthe cost of any object or purpose for which bonds may be issued by, or\nfor the objects or purposes of, the school district pursuant to the\nlocal finance law. The proposition shall specify the purpose for which\nthe fund is established, the ultimate amount, the probable term and the\nsource from which the funds are to be obtained. There shall be paid into\nany such fund an annual amount sufficient to meet the requirements of\nthe proposition. In addition, the voters may from time to time direct\nthe school authorities to pay into such fund moneys derived from any\nother source.\n  1-a. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this\nsection, any school district may establish a reserve fund for the\npayment of judgments and claims in tax certiorari proceedings in\naccordance with article seven of the real property tax law, without\napproval by the qualified voters of the district, provided, however,\nthat the total of the monies held in such reserve fund shall not exceed\nthat amount which might reasonably be deemed necessary to meet\nanticipated judgments and claims arising out of such tax certiorari\nproceedings. Any monies deposited to such reserve fund which are not\nexpended for the payment of judgments or claims arising out of such tax\ncertiorari proceedings for the tax roll in the year such monies are\ndeposited to the said fund and/or which will not reasonably be required\nto pay any such judgment or claim shall be returned to the general fund\non or before the first day of the fourth fiscal year following the\ndeposit of such monies to said reserve fund. For purposes of this\nsubdivision, such monies shall be dee...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>