<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-374"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-374"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="374"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-374/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-374/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-374/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-374/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_374">
        <num>374</num>
        <heading>Relationship with state university</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 374. Relationship with state university.  In order the most\neffectively to carry out its corporate purposes, the fund shall assist\nand cooperate with and shall make its personnel and services fully\navailable to the state university in matters relating to the discharge\nof the capital planning responsibilities and land acquisition program of\nthe state university.  During the course of construction, acquisition,\nreconstruction, rehabilitation and improvement of facilities for the\nstate university, the fund shall consult with the state university as\nthe work progresses in matters relating to changes in space\nrequirements, site plans, architectural concept, and detailed plans and\nspecifications and in matters relating to the materials, equipment and\nsupplies needed to furnish and equip completed facilities.  The state\nuniversity for its part shall assist and cooperate with the fund in\nmatters relating to such construction, acquisition, reconstruction,\nrehabilitation and improvement, including the financing thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>