<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-399"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-399"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-399/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-399/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-399/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-399/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399">
        <num>399</num>
        <heading>Special annuity and custodial account programs authorized</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>received by the employer, in the\nevent such termination is initiated by the employee, or (ii) sent to the\nemployee in the event such termination is initiated by the employer.\n  4. The board of trustees of state university with respect to the state\nuniversity and the community colleges, and the board of trustees of the\ncity university with respect to employees of the city university of New\nYork, shall designate the insurer or insurers from which such annuity\ncontracts or in the case of custodial accounts, the company or companies\nfrom whom regulated investment company shares shall be purchased. In\nmaking such designation, due consideration shall be given to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nnature and extent of the rights and benefits to be provided by contracts\nfor such special annuity or custodial account for employees and their\nbeneficiaries,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the relation of such rights and benefits to the\namount of contributions to be made for such contracts,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nsuitability of such rights and benefits to the needs and interests of\nemployees, and to the interests of employers in the employment and\nretention of employees, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the authority and ability of the\ndesignated insurer or insurers or designated company or companies to\nprovide rights and benefits under such contracts or custodial accounts.\n  5. The board of trustees of state university, with respect to the\nstate university and the community colleges, and the board of trustees\nof the city of New York with respect to the city university, are hereby\nauthorized to provide for the administration of a program for the\npurchase of such special annuities or establishment of custodial\naccounts, and to perform or authorize the performance of such functions\nas may be necessary for such purpose in accordance with this section.\n  6. No agreement for reduction of salary as authorized by this section\nor any termination thereof shall become effective until approved by and\nfiled with the comptroller. Upon such approval and filing the\ncomptroller shall reduce an employee's salary pursuant to said agreement\nand pay an amount equal to the amount agreed upon for such salary\nreduction as an employer contribution to the designated insurer or\ninsurers or designated custodian or custodians.  Notwithstanding the\nreductions of salary authorized by this article,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of\nemployer and employee contributions otherwise required on behalf of an\nemployee electing the optional retirement program pursuant to articles\neight-B or one hundred twenty-five-A of this chapter, as the case may\nbe, shall continue to be made on the basis of the salary of such\nemployee without regard to such reduction, or (ii) in the event a member\nof a public retirement system in this state agrees to a reduction of his\nsalary in accordance with this subdivision, such agreement shall not\ncause him to lose any benefits under such public retirement system to\nwhich he would be otherwise entitled had he not agreed to reduce his\nsalary for the purpose of having a special annuity purchased or\ncontributions to a custodial account made on his behalf, and any\nrequired employer and employee contributions shall continue to be made\non the basis of the salary of such employee without regard to such\nreduction.  Any survivor's benefit payable pursuant to the civil service\nlaw shall be based upon the salary of such employee without regard to\nthe reduction authorized by this article.\n  7. Any payroll deduction, other than income tax withholdings as\nrequired by law, which may be required or authorized pursuant to law,\ncontract, agreement, or any other instrument, the amount of which is\ndetermined in relation to an employee's earnings, shall be based on the\nsalary of such employee without regard to reduction thereof pursuant to\nany agreement authorized by this article.\n  8. An employee agreeing to have his salary reduced in accordance with\nthis article shall be paid an amount equal to his salary less the amount\nof the reduction pursuant to such agreement and any deductions\nauthorized by law, such amount to be paid in equal installments in\naccordance with the payroll procedure otherwise appropriate.\n  9. Payments for contracts providing for a special annuity or custodial\naccount shall be made by the comptroller to the designated insurer or\nins...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>