<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-408-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-408-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="408-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-408-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-408-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-408-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-408-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_408_B">
        <num>408-B</num>
        <heading>Submitting plans and specifications of school buildings with local fire and law enforcement officials</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 408-b. Submitting plans and specifications of school buildings with\nlocal fire and law enforcement officials. The appropriate authorities\nfor each public and private school building in the state shall submit\nthe most current plans and specifications for each school building under\ntheir responsibility to the fire and law enforcement officials in the\ncity, towns or village where the school building is located. The\ncommissioner may adopt such rules and regulations as are necessary and\nappropriate to implement the provisions of this section to facilitate\nits purpose of providing quick and easy access to and passage through\nschool buildings should it be necessary for fire or law enforcement\nreasons. Such regulations shall authorize submittal of simplified plans\nshowing access and passage ways for older schools where original plans\nor blueprints may not exist or where the school authorities can justify\na claim of hardship in meeting the requirements of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>