<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409_J">
        <num>409-J</num>
        <heading>Emergency alert notification system in public schools; cities with a population of one million or more</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 409-j. Emergency alert notification system in public schools; cities\nwith a population of one million or more. On or before January first,\ntwo thousand ten, a city school district located in a city of one\nmillion or more inhabitants shall, pursuant to rules and regulations\npromulgated by the chancellor of such city school district and\nconsistent with section twenty-eight hundred one-a of this chapter,\nimplement an emergency alert notification system to convey timely\ninformation concerning emergency incidents or occurrences, as defined by\nsuch chancellor, that pose an imminent threat to the health or safety of\na substantial number of students, faculty and staff at a particular\neducational facility or program. Such emergency alert notification\nsystem shall employ a variety of communication methods including the\nautomated delivery of text messages, phone calls and/or electronic mail\nand shall notify and advise parents or persons in parental relation,\nfaculty, staff, and elected representatives, who volunteer to receive\nemergency alert notifications.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>