<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409_F">
        <num>409-F</num>
        <heading>Electrically operated partition and door safety</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 409-f. Electrically operated partition and door safety. The board of\neducation, trustees, principal or other person in charge of every public\nor private school or educational institution within the state, wherein\nclassrooms or other facilities used by students are found to have\nelectrically operated partitions, doors or room dividers, shall arrange\nfor, and require, that:\n  1. Appropriate and conspicuous notice regarding the safe and proper\noperation and supervision of the electrical device operating such\npartition, door or room divider is posted in the immediate vicinity of\nthe operating mechanism;\n  2. There is established a procedure for the notification of all school\nemployees and all other persons who regularly make use of the area where\nsuch device is located of the safe and proper procedure for the\noperation of the mechanism and of the applicable penalties for disabling\nsafety equipment required pursuant to this section; and\n  3. Every electrically operated partition or room divider shall be\nequipped with safety devices which, subject to standards established in\nrules and regulations promulgated by the commissioner, stop the forward\nmotion of the partition or room divider and stop the stacking motion of\nthe partition or room divider when a body passes between the leading\npanel of such partition or divider and a wall, or when a body is present\nin the stacking area of such partition or divider.\n  Any person who disables or directs another person to disable any\nsafety equipment required pursuant to this section shall be guilty of a\nviolation punishable by not more than fifteen days imprisonment, or a\nfine not to exceed one hundred dollars, or both such fine and\nimprisonment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>