<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409_A">
        <num>409-A</num>
        <heading>Eye safety devices for certain students and teachers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 409-a. Eye safety devices for certain students and teachers.  1. The\nboard of education, trustees, principal or other person in charge of\nevery public or private school or educational institution within the\nstate, wherein shops or laboratories are conducted providing\ninstructional or experimental programs involving:\n  a. Hot solids, liquids or molten metals; or\n  b. Milling, sawing, turning, shaping, cutting, or stamping of any\nsolid materials; or\n  c. Heat treatment, tempering, or kiln firing of any metal or other\nmaterials; or\n  d. Gas or electric arc welding; or\n  e. Repair or servicing of any vehicle; or\n  f. Caustic or explosive chemicals or materials, shall arrange for and\nrequire, in accordance with regulations of the commissioner, that every\nstudent and teacher participating in any such program wear eye safety\ndevices at the times and under the conditions prescribed in such\nregulations.\n  2. The commissioner shall by regulation prescribe the safety standards\nto be met before the use of any eye safety device may be required and\nshall include in such regulations requirements relating to the times and\nconditions when and under which such eye safety devices shall be worn.\n  3. Visitors to such shops or laboratories shall be furnished with and\nrequired to wear such eye safety devices at the times and under the\nconditions prescribed in such regulations while in such shops or\nlaboratories.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>