<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-09-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409_D">
        <num>409-D</num>
        <heading>Comprehensive public school building safety program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at least once between\nthe period commencing with the first day of January, two thousand twenty\nand ending with the thirty-first day of December, two thousand twenty\nand (ii) at least once between the period commencing with the first day\nof January, two thousand twenty-two and ending with the thirty-first day\nof December, two thousand twenty-two, provided that such inspections\nshall exclude public school buildings in a school district required to\nconduct building condition surveys between January first, two thousand\ntwenty and the end of such period in accordance with regulations of the\ncommissioner adopted pursuant to subparagraph one-a of paragraph c of\nsubdivision four of section thirty-six hundred forty-one of this\nchapter, and provided further that such exclusion shall not apply in the\ncase of a school district which has not completed the building condition\nsurveys so required and submitted the same to the department. Under such\nprogram, the commissioner may require inspections of public school\nbuildings as deemed necessary to maintain the safety of school buildings\nand the welfare of the occupants, and such program shall establish a\nsafety rating system for such school buildings to assess the need for\nmaintenance, repairs, rehabilitation, reconstruction, construction and\nother improvements related to the structural integrity and overall\nsafety of public school buildings including but not limited to building\nsystems related to electrical, plumbing, heating, ventilation, and air\nconditioning, sanitation and health, fire and accident protection; and\nrequire that such ratings be used for the purpose of developing a\nbuildings condition survey as required pursuant to subdivision four of\nsection thirty-six hundred forty-one of this chapter and a five year\nfacilities plan as required pursuant to clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subparagraph two\nof paragraph b of subdivision six of section thirty-six hundred two of\nthis chapter.\n  2. Commissioner's authorization. In implementing the program, the\ncommissioner is authorized to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require the inspection of every public school building and\nprescribe qualifications of persons who may perform or supervise such\ninspections in accordance with the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish a safety rating system keyed to the structural integrity\nand overall safety of the building. Such system shall rate every major\nbuilding system contained within a building and where practicable\nidentify critical maintenance and include such information in the plan\nrequired in subdivision ten of section thirty-six hundred forty-one of\nthis chapter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require each school district to develop a buildings condition\nsurvey;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require each school district to develop a five year capital\nfacilities plan;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish a process for monitoring all school buildings; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_D__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide for waivers of the requirements of this section and/or\nsection four hundred nine-e of this article for districts whose school\nbuilding safety inspection procedures in existence on the effective date\nof this section are in substantial compliance with such requirements.\n  3. Notification. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the\ncontrary, the commissioner shall be authorized to notify in writing any\nschool district or board of cooperative educational services the\nexistence of a hazardous condition found in any school building within\nthe school district that is in violation of applicable building, health,\nor safety codes or regulations that may threaten the health and/or\nsafety of students or staffs. Such notice must be acknowledged and\nresponded to within five business days or less. Such notice shall be\ndelivered to the superintendent of the school district or the district\nsuperintendent of the board of cooperative educational services. In the\ncase of a city school district in a city having a population of one\nmillion or more inhabitants such notice shall be delivered to the\nchancellor of the city district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>