<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4108"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4108">
        <num>4108</num>
        <heading>Persons employing Indian children unlawfully to be fined</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4108. Persons employing Indian children unlawfully to be fined.  A\nperson, firm, association or corporation shall not employ any Indian\nchild residing on any Indian reservation between six and fourteen years\nof age, in any business or service whatever during any part of the term\nduring which the school in the community or district in which such child\nresides or the school where such child should attend is in session, nor\nshall employ any Indian child residing on any reservation between\nfourteen and sixteen years of age, who does not, at the time of such\nemployment present a consent in writing signed by the principal teacher\nof the reservation or the principal of the district which educates the\nchildren in the community in which such child resides to the effect that\nsuch child may be employed, and specifying the nature of the service and\nthe duration of such service or employment.  Any person, firm,\nassociation or corporation who shall employ any Indian child contrary to\nthe provisions of this section shall for each offense forfeit and pay to\nthe principal teacher of the reservation or to the commissioner of\neducation the sum of twenty-five dollars to be sued for in the name of\nthe people of the state of New York by the attorney general.  Such\npenalty, when paid, shall be used for the support and maintenance of the\nschools on said reservation or for said reservation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>