<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4110"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4110">
        <num>4110</num>
        <heading>Attendance officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4110. Attendance officers.  1. The principal teacher of the Indian\nschools on each reservation shall supervise the enforcement of this\narticle within said reservation and shall appoint, subject to the\napproval of the commissioner of education, and remove at pleasure such\nnumber of attendance officers as the commissioner of education shall\ndeem necessary, whose jurisdictions shall extend over all school\ndistricts on the reservation for which they shall be appointed.  Such\nprincipal teachers are also vested with the same power and authority as\nthe attendance officers appointed by them.\n  2. If the education of Indian children of the reservation shall be\nprovided pursuant to the provisions of subdivision two of section\nforty-one hundred one of this chapter, the attendance officer or\nofficers of the school district providing such education shall have\njurisdiction over all Indian children on the reservation.  Such\nattendance officers shall not, however, be entitled to receive from the\ncommissioner of education the payment for services provided in section\nforty-one hundred fourteen of this chapter.\n  3. The commissioner of education may appoint and remove at pleasure\nsuch attendance officers as he shall deem necessary, who shall have\njurisdiction over all children other than Indian children on the\nreservation for which they shall be appointed.  Such attendance officers\nshall receive such sum per day or part thereof as shall be fixed by the\ncommissioner of education for each day or part thereof necessarily\nemployed as such attendance officers.  Compensation of attendance\nofficers herein provided for shall be audited by the commissioner of\neducation and paid in the same manner as other expenses incurred\npursuant to this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>