<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-412"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-412"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="412"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_412">
        <num>412</num>
        <heading>Condemnation of schoolhouse and erection of new schoolhouse in place thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 412. Condemnation of schoolhouse and erection of new schoolhouse in\nplace thereof. 1. A district superintendent, upon the direction of the\ncommissioner, may make an order condemning a school house, if he or she\nfinds upon examination that such schoolhouse is wholly unfit for use and\nnot worth repairing. He or she shall deliver such order to a trustee of\nthe district and transmit a copy thereof to the commissioner. He or she\nshall also state in such order the date on which it shall take effect\nand the sum which in his or her opinion will be necessary to erect a\nschool building available to the needs of the district.\n  2. Immediately upon the receipt of said order, the trustees of such\ndistrict shall call a special meeting of the voters of said district, to\nconsider the question of building a new schoolhouse therein.  Such\nmeeting shall have power to determine the size of said schoolhouse, the\nmaterial to be used in its erection, and to vote a tax to build the\nsame. But such meeting shall have no power to reduce the estimate made\nby the district superintendent aforesaid by more than twenty-five per\ncentum of such estimate.\n  3. And where no tax for building such schoolhouse shall have been\nvoted by such district within thirty days from the time of holding the\nfirst meeting to consider the question, it shall be the duty of the\ntrustees of such district to contract for the building of a schoolhouse\ncapable of accommodating the children of the district, and to levy a tax\nto pay for the same, which tax shall not exceed the sum estimated as\nnecessary by the district superintendent aforesaid, and which shall not\nbe less than such estimated sum by more than twenty-five per centum\nthereof. But such estimated sum may be increased at any subsequent\nschool meeting legally held in the district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>