<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4201"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4201">
        <num>4201</num>
        <heading>Duties of commissioner of education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4201. Duties of commissioner of education. 1. The following\ninstitutions for the instruction of the deaf and of the blind shall be\nsubject to the visitation of the commissioner of education: a. The New\nYork school for the deaf;\n  b. The Lexington school for the deaf;\n  c. St. Mary's school for the deaf in the city of Buffalo;\n  e. St. Joseph's school for the deaf in the city of New York;\n  f. Rochester school for the deaf in the city of Rochester;\n  h. The New York Institute for Special Education in the city of New\nYork;\n  i. Lavelle School for the Blind in the city of New York;\n  j. Mill Neck Manor school for the deaf in Nassau county;\n  k. St. Francis DeSales school for the deaf and hard of hearing in the\ncounty of Kings.\n  l. Cleary Deaf Child Center, Inc., in the counties of Suffolk and\nNassau.\n  2. It shall be the duty of the commissioner:\n  a. To inquire into the organization of the several schools and the\nmethods of instruction employed therein.\n  b. To prescribe courses of study and methods of instruction that will\nmeet the requirements of the state for the education of state pupils.\n  c. To make appointments of pupils to the several schools, to transfer\nsuch pupils from one school to another as circumstances may require; to\ncancel appointments for sufficient reason.\n  d. To ascertain by a comparison with other similar institutions\nwhether any improvements in instruction and discipline can be made; and\nfor that purpose to appoint from time to time, suitable persons to visit\nthe schools.\n  e. To suggest to the directors of such institutions and to the\nlegislature such improvements as he shall judge expedient.\n  f. To make an annual report to the legislature on all of the matters\nenumerated in this subdivision and particularly as to the condition of\nthe schools, the improvement of the pupils, and their treatment in\nrespect to board and lodging.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>