<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4206"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4206">
        <num>4206</num>
        <heading>Persons eligible for appointment as pupils to institutions for instruction of the blind</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4206. Persons eligible for appointment as pupils to institutions for\ninstruction of the blind.  1. All blind persons of suitable age and\ncapacity and who shall have been residents in this state for one year\nimmediately preceding the application or, if a minor, whose parent or\nparents, or, if an orphan, whose nearest friend, shall have been a\nresident in this state for one year immediately preceding the\napplication, shall be eligible for appointment as state pupils to the\nNew York Institute for Special Education in the city of New York or the\nLavelle School for the Blind in the city of New York.\n  2. Blind babies and children of the age of fifteen years and under and\npossessing the other qualifications prescribed in this article and\nrequiring kindergarten training or other special care and instruction,\nshall be eligible for appointment as state pupils by the commissioner of\neducation at his discretion in any incorporated institution furnishing\napproved care, training and instruction for blind babies and children,\nand any such child may be transferred to the New York Institute for\nSpecial Education in the city of New York or the Lavelle School for the\nBlind in the city of New York, to which he or she would otherwise be\neligible for appointment, upon arriving at suitable age, in the\ndiscretion of the commissioner of education.\n  3. All such appointments shall be made by the commissioner of\neducation. The requirement of this section as to length of residence in\nthis state may be waived in the discretion of the commissioner of\neducation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>