<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4207"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4207">
        <num>4207</num>
        <heading>Support and term of instruction of blind state pupils</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4207. Support and term of instruction of blind state pupils. 1. Each\nblind pupil so received into any of the institutions specified in this\narticle shall be provided with board, lodging and tuition; and the\ndirectors of the institution shall receive an appropriation for each\npupil so provided for, in quarterly payments, to be paid by the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance, on the warrant of the comptroller,\nto the treasurer of said institution; provided, however, that an\nestimated one-half of each such quarterly payment shall be due on the\nfirst day of each quarter, the estimate to be based on the affidavit of\nthe chief executive officer of the institution stating the number of\npupils for whom board, lodging and tuition was so provided by the\ninstitution during the preceding quarter and during the comparable\nquarter of the preceding year, and the remaining part of each such\nquarterly payment shall be due thereafter on the first day of the\nquarter next ensuing, upon the presentation by the treasurer of the\ninstitution of a bill showing the actual time and number of pupils\nattending the institution, which bill shall be signed by the chief\nexecutive officer of the institution, and verified by his oath. The\nprovisions of this subdivision shall apply to board, lodging and tuition\nfor the two thousand ten--two thousand eleven and prior school years.\n  2. For expenses incurred in the two thousand eleven--two thousand\ntwelve school year and thereafter, each blind pupil so received into any\nof the institutions subject to this article shall be provided with\nboard, lodging and tuition, and such institutions shall be reimbursed\nfor such expenses in accordance with this subdivision.\n  a. For the two thousand eleven--two thousand twelve and two thousand\ntwelve--two thousand thirteen school years, costs of tuition, as defined\nin section forty-two hundred eleven of this article, shall be a charge\nupon the school district of which any such child is resident at the time\nof admission or readmission to any of the institutions subject to this\narticle and the directors of the institution shall bill such school\ndistrict for such tuition costs on a quarterly basis. The first such\nquarterly payment may be based on projected enrollment, provided that\nsubsequent payments shall be adjusted to reflect actual enrollment. The\namount of tuition paid by such school district shall be eligible for\nreimbursement by the state to the extent provided in section forty-two\nhundred four-b of this article.\n  b. For the two thousand thirteen--two thousand fourteen school year\nand thereafter, the costs of tuition as defined in section forty-two\nhundred eleven of this article, shall be a charge upon the current\nschool district of residence of any such child subject to this article\nand the directors of the institution shall bill such school district for\nsuch tuition costs on a quarterly basis. The first such quarterly\npayment may be based on projected enrollment, provided that subsequent\npayments shall be adjusted to reflect actual enrollment. The amount of\ntuition paid by such school district shall be eligible for reimbursement\nby the state to the extent provided in section forty-two hundred four-b\nof this article.\n  c. The costs of board and lodging shall be a charge upon the state and\nthe directors of the institution shall receive an appropriation for each\npupil so provided for, in quarterly payments, to be paid by the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance, on the warrant of the comptroller,\nto the treasurer of said institution; provided, however, that an\nestimated one-half of each such quarterly payment shall be due on the\nfirst day of each quarter, the estimate to be based on the affidavit of\nthe chief executive officer of the institution stating the number of\npupils for whom board and lodging was so provided by the institution\nduring the preceding quarter and during the comparable quarter of the\npreceding year, and the remaining part of each such quarterly payment\nshall be due thereafter on the first day of the quarter next ensuing,\nupon the presentation by the treasurer of the institution of a bill\nshowing the actual time and number of pupils attending the institution\nwho received board and lodging, which bill shall be signed by the chief\nexecutive officer of the institution, and verified by his oath.\n  3. The regular term of instruction of any such blind pupil in the New\nYork Institute for Special Education shall be eight years. The\ncommissioner may in his discretion extend the term of any pupil for a\nperiod not exceeding three years. It shall also be lawful for the\ncommissioner to continue such pupils as state pupils for an additional\nperiod of three years for the purpose of pursuing or completing a course\nof high school study; such pupils must be recommended by the trustees of\nthe New York Institute for Special Education before such extension is\ngranted.\n  4. The term of appointment for blind babies and children of the age of\nfifteen years and under received into any institution in accordance with\nthis article shall be at the discretion of the commissioner.\n  5. Children placed in any such institutions for the blind pursuant to\nsection forty-two hundred six shall be maintained therein for the period\nof time the school is in session.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>