<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4307"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4307">
        <num>4307</num>
        <heading>Superintendent, personnel of the faculty, and salaries</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4307. Superintendent, personnel of the faculty, and salaries. 1.\nThere shall continue to be a superintendent of such school, who shall be\nthe chief executive officer of the school, under the jurisdiction and\ncontrol of the education department. He shall be appointed by the board\nof regents, upon the recommendation of the board of visitors submitted\nto and approved by the commissioner of education. A superintendent may\nbe removed by the board of regents, subject to the approval of the board\nof visitors and the commissioner of education. Subject to the rules of\nthe board of regents, such superintendent shall have the supervision and\nmanagement of the school, appoint and remove all subordinate officers,\nteachers and employees thereof, prescribe their duties, fix their\ncompensation, except as provided for hereinafter, within the amount of\nthe appropriations made therefor and have and perform all the powers and\nduties prescribed by law for the superintendent of such school.\n  2. The commissioner of education shall have power, in conformity with\nregulations approved by the regents, to appoint all other needed\nofficers and employees and determine their duties. The commissioner\nshall by regulations approved as aforesaid, establish for positions in\nthe unclassified service in such department as certified by him pursuant\nto section thirty-five of the civil service law, suitable personnel\nprocedures and conditions of employment including:\n  a. A classification plan which shall include titles, duties and\nminimum qualifications.\n  b. A salary plan which shall include minimum and maximum salaries and\nincrements and procedures for adjustment of salaries on appointment,\npromotion and reassignment.\n  c. Regulations for appointments, promotions, probation, permanent\ntenure, disciplinary action and attendance.\n  d. Such other rules and regulations as may be necessary for carrying\nout the provisions of this section.\n  The regulations establishing such salary plan shall be subject to the\napproval of the director of the budget.\n  3. With the approval of the commissioner of education and the\nsuperintendent an instructor may be granted a leave of absence for\ntravel or for study, on part pay as determined by the regents, provided\nsuch instructor agrees to remain in the service of the state not less\nthan two years immediately following the expiration of such leave. The\nbalance of the salaries appropriated for such instructors, or so much\nthereof as may be necessary, may be applied by the commissioner of\neducation during the period of such absence for the payment of the\nsalaries of substitute instructors employed in such school to take the\nplaces of the instructors to whom leaves of absence have been granted as\nprovided herein.\n  4. The commissioner of education shall, subject to the approval of the\ndirector of the budget, determine the amount to be deducted from the\nsalaries provided above for the maintenance of personnel at the school.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>