<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4313"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4313"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4313"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4313/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4313/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4313/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4313/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4313">
        <num>4313</num>
        <heading>School district and social services district financial responsibility</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4313. School district and social services district financial\nresponsibility. 1. Financial responsibilities. School districts and\nsocial services districts shall be responsible for the cost of tuition\nand maintenance, respectively, for children in attendance at the New\nYork state school for the blind during the September first through June\nthirtieth session. Such costs shall be established pursuant to section\nforty-four hundred five of this chapter.  a. The school district of\nwhich any such child is resident at the time of admission or readmission\nto the New York State school for the blind pursuant to this article\nshall be required to reimburse the state in an amount equal to the\ntuition payments made to the state school by the state on behalf of the\nschool district. The comptroller shall deduct the appropriate tuition\namounts from any state funds which become due to a school district for\neach year in which such child is in attendance at such school, and shall\ndeposit such funds to the special revenue accounts established for such\npurpose. Any tuition amounts deducted pursuant to this subdivision shall\nbe included in the approved operating expense of the school district\npursuant to paragraph t of subdivision one of section thirty-six hundred\ntwo of this chapter.\n  b. The social services district in which any such child is resident at\nthe time of admission or readmission to the New York state school for\nthe blind pursuant to this article shall be required to reimburse the\nstate in an amount equal to the maintenance payments made to the state\nschool by the state on behalf of the social services district. The\ncomptroller may deduct the appropriate maintenance amounts from any\nstate funds which become due to a social services district for each year\nin which such child is in attendance at such school only upon\nnotification by the commissioner of social services after receiving\nnotice by the commissioner of education that such social services\ndistrict has failed to remit the required maintenance payments to the\nstate within ninety days of the date on which such social services\ndistrict was billed by the state for services rendered, and shall\ndeposit such funds to the special revenue accounts established for such\npurpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>