<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4354"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4354"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4354"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4354">
        <num>4354</num>
        <heading>Superintendent and other personnel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4354. Superintendent and other personnel.  1. The chief executive\nofficer of such school shall be a superintendent who shall be in the\nunclassified service and who shall be appointed by the board of regents\nupon the recommendation of commissioner of education. Such\nsuperintendent shall serve at the pleasure of the board of regents.\nExcept as hereinafter provided, such superintendent shall have the\nsupervision and management of the school, shall recommend the\nappointment and removal of subordinate officers, teachers and employees\nthereof, prescribe their duties and perform all of the duties and\nexercise the powers and duties prescribed for such superintendent of\nschools by law or by the rules of the board of regents.\n  2. The commissioner shall, subject to the approval of the director of\nthe budget, determine the amount to be deducted from the salaries of\nemployees for the maintenance provided for such personnel in the school.\n  3. The commissioner of education shall have power, in conformity with\nregulations approved by the regents, to appoint all other needed\nofficers and employees and determine their duties. The commissioner\nshall by regulations approved as aforesaid, establish for positions in\nthe unclassified service in such department as certified by him pursuant\nto section thirty-five of the civil service law, suitable personnel\nprocedures and conditions of employment including:\n  a. A classification plan which shall include titles, duties and\nminimum qualifications.\n  b. A salary plan which shall include minimum and maximum salaries and\nincrements and procedures for adjustment of salaries on appointment,\npromotion and reassignment.\n  c. Regulations for appointments, promotions, probation, permanent\ntenure, disciplinary action and attendance.\n  d. Such other rules and regulations as may be necessary for carrying\nout the provisions of this section.\n  The regulations establishing such salary plan shall be subject to the\napproval of the director of the budget.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>