<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4357"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4357"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4357"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4357/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4357/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4357/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4357/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4357">
        <num>4357</num>
        <heading>School district and social services district financial responsibility</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4357. School district and social services district financial\nresponsibility. 1. Financial responsibilities. School districts and\nsocial services districts shall be responsible for the costs of tuition\nand maintenance, respectively, for children attending the New York state\nschool for the deaf during the September first through June thirtieth\nsession. Such costs shall be established pursuant to section forty-four\nhundred five of this chapter.  a. The school district of which any such\nchild is resident at the time of admission or readmission to the New\nYork State school for the deaf pursuant to this article shall be\nrequired to reimburse the state in an amount equal to the tuition\npayments made to the state school by the state on behalf of the school\ndistrict. The comptroller shall deduct the appropriate tuition amounts\nfrom any state funds which become due to a school district for each year\nin which such child is in attendance at such school, and shall deposit\nsuch funds to the special revenue accounts established for such purpose.\nAny tuition amounts deducted pursuant to this subdivision shall be\nincluded in the approved operating expense of the school district\npursuant to paragraph t of subdivision one of section thirty-six hundred\ntwo of this chapter.\n  b. The social services district in which any such child is resident at\nthe time of admission or readmission to the New York state school for\nthe deaf pursuant to this article shall be required to reimburse the\nstate in an amount equal to the maintenance payments made to the state\nschool by the state on behalf of the social services district. The\ncomptroller may deduct the appropriate maintenance amounts from any\nstate funds which become due to a social services district for each year\nin which such child is in attendance at such school only upon\nnotification by the commissioner of social services after receiving\nnotice by the commissioner of education that such social services\ndistrict has failed to remit the required maintenance payments within\nninety days of the date on which such social services district is billed\nby the state for services rendered, and shall deposit such amount to the\nspecial revenue accounts established for such purpose.\n  2. Payment for preschool children with handicapping conditions. The\nstate share of the costs of tuition, maintenance and transportation for\npreschool children attending the New York state school for the deaf\nduring the July and August summer session and the September through June\nsession shall be paid from the state moneys appropriated in support of\nthe provisions of section forty-four hundred ten of this chapter. The\nremaining share shall be a charge on the county, or the city of New\nYork, of which any such child is resident at the time of admission or\nreadmission to such school. The state share shall be as set forth in\nparagraph b of subdivision eleven of section forty-four hundred ten of\nthis chapter. For the purposes of this subdivision "preschool child"\nshall mean a child not eligible, by reason of age, for the deaf-infant\nprogram pursuant to section forty-two hundred four-a of this chapter and\nnot eligible, by reason of age, to attend the public schools pursuant to\nsection thirty-two hundred two of this chapter, provided that a child\nshall be deemed a preschool child through the month of August of the\nschool year in which the child first becomes eligible to attend the\npublic schools. Preschool education charges on a county, or the city of\nNew York, pursuant to this subdivision shall be deducted by the\ncomptroller within thirty days of the issuance of a warrant by the\ncommissioner from any state funds which become due to a county, or the\ncity of New York, and be credited to the special revenue account\nestablished for such purpose. Such tuition, maintenance and\ntransportation costs shall be determined pursuant to section forty-four\nhundred five of this chapter.\n  3. Deaf infants. The full costs of a deaf-infant program, as\ndetermined by the commissioner of education and approved by the director\nof the budget, for children below the age of three served by the New\nYork state school for the deaf pursuant to section forty-two hundred\nfour-a of this chapter shall be paid from the state moneys appropriated\nin support of such section forty-two hundred four-a.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>