<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4404-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4404-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4404-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4404-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4404-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4404-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4404-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4404_A">
        <num>4404-A</num>
        <heading>Mediation program for students with disabilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4404_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>states that all\ndiscussions that occurred during the mediation process shall be\nconfidential and may not be used as evidence in any subsequent due\nprocess hearing or civil action or proceeding; (ii) is signed by both\nthe parent or person in parental relation and a representative of the\nschool district or agency who has the authority to bind such school\ndistrict or agency; and (iii) is enforceable in any state court of\ncompetent jurisdiction or in a United States district court. The\ncommittee on special education or committee on preschool special\neducation shall immediately amend the student's individualized education\nprogram to be consistent with such mediation agreement. Discussions that\noccur in the mediation process shall be confidential, and may not be\nused as evidence in any subsequent proceedings pursuant to section\nforty-four hundred four of this article or in any subsequent civil\nactions or proceedings.\n  * NB Effective until June 30, 2027\n  * 5. Each session in the mediation process shall be scheduled in a\ntimely manner, and shall be held in a location that is convenient to the\nparties to the dispute. An agreement reached by the parties to the\ndispute in the mediation process shall be set forth in a written\nmediation agreement. The committee on special education or committee on\npreschool special education shall immediately amend the student's\nindividualized education program to be consistent with such mediation\nagreement. Discussions that occur in the mediation process shall be\nconfidential, and may not be used as evidence in any subsequent\nproceedings pursuant to section forty-four hundred four of this article\nor in any subsequent civil actions or proceedings. The parties to the\nmediation process may be required to sign a confidentiality pledge prior\nto the commencement of the process.\n  * NB Effective June 30, 2027\n  6. The provisions of this section shall not operate to diminish, deny,\ndelay, or limit any rights provided fo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>