<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4453"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4453"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4453"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4453">
        <num>4453</num>
        <heading>Advisory council on the education of gifted pupils</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4453. Advisory council on the education of gifted pupils.  1.\nSubject to the availability of funds, the commissioner may establish\nwithin the department an advisory council on the education of gifted\npupils.  Such council shall assist and advise the commissioner and his\ndesignees with respect to policies and procedures relating to the\neducation of gifted pupils and programs associated therewith.\n  2. Such advisory council appointed by the commissioner shall consist\nof at least ten members, who are directly concerned with gifted pupils\nor who have specialized in the education of such pupils, provided,\nhowever, that such advisory council shall include at least one parent of\nsuch a pupil. The members shall be residents of this state and shall be\nselected on the basis of their competence, concern, and professional\nactivity in the education of gifted pupils.\n  3. The advisory council shall meet at least twice each year at a\nlocation to be determined by the commissioner.  The advisory council\nshall report at least annually to the commissioner.\n  4. Five years or sooner after the effective date of this section, the\ncommissioner shall review the necessity of such advisory council, and\nshall make a determination whether to continue or disband such council.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>