<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4502"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4502"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4502"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4502">
        <num>4502</num>
        <heading>Establishment of camps by city school districts and appropriations authorized</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4502. Establishment of camps by city school districts and\nappropriations authorized.  1. A city school district, acting through\nits board of education, is hereby authorized to establish camps on land\nprovided therefor in parks adjacent to such city school district under\nthe jurisdiction and control of the state office of parks and recreation\nor department of environmental conservation, or elsewhere. Such camps\nshall be used to furnish instruction, recreation and maintenance to\nchildren of school age. The board of education shall provide opportunity\nfor children to receive instruction in such subjects as it may deem\nproper. Such board shall prescribe the activities to be carried on and\nshall set up rules and regulations for admission to such camps and the\nconduct and discipline thereof. Such camps shall be operated between\nJuly first and August thirty-first of each year and at such other times\nas such board of education may prescribe. No child shall be entitled to\nfree instruction and maintenance in any such camp for a period in excess\nof two weeks during any one year, unless the board of education\nprescribe and direct that physically handicapped or other children be\nmaintained for a longer period.\n  2. The board of education of a city school district may establish a\ncamp for children to be located in state parks on Long Island, which\nhave been or shall be selected by the state office of parks and\nrecreation on account of accessibility and availability, as a model camp\nfor the establishment of future camps.\n  3. The board of education of a city school district is hereby\nauthorized to appropriate such sums as may be necessary for the purpose\nof carrying out the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>