<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-452"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-452"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="452"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-452/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-452/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-452/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-452/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_452">
        <num>452</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 452. Definitions.  As used or referred to in this article, unless a\ndifferent meaning clearly appears from the context:\n  1. "Board" or "board of education" shall mean the chancellor or deputy\nchancellor of the city school district of the city of New York, except\nfor the purposes of section four hundred fifty-three of this chapter.\n  2. "Bonds" and "notes" shall mean bonds and notes respectively, issued\nby the fund pursuant to this article.\n  3. "City" shall mean the city of New York.\n  4. "City agency" shall mean any officer, administration, department,\nboard, commission, bureau, division, agency or instrumentality of the\ncity of New York.\n  5. "Combined occupancy structure" shall mean any improvement on real\nproperty or any interests therein or thereto, including fee interest,\neasements, space rights or air rights, containing school accommodations\nor other facilities of the board of education of the city of New York in\ncombination with other compatible and lawful non-school uses designed\nand intended to increase, from both a planning and an economic\nviewpoint, the efficient utilization of available land areas. A combined\noccupancy structure shall also include a structure in a project or\ndevelopment under the auspices of the fund wherein non-school portions\nof structures placed upon the overall site are not built in space rights\nover the school portion, so long as some part of the non-school portion\nis constructed over or under any part of the school portion of the\ndevelopment.\n  6. "Commissioner of education" shall mean the commissioner of\neducation of the state of New York.\n  7. "Comptroller" or "city comptroller" shall mean the comptroller of\nthe city of New York.\n  8. "Corporation counsel" shall mean the corporation counsel of the\ncity of New York.\n  9. "Developer" shall mean and include any private individual,\npartnership, trust or private or public corporation approved by the\nboard of education as being qualified and eligible to enter into one or\nmore leases, subleases or other agreements with the fund providing for\nthe construction, acquisition, reconstruction, rehabilitation or\nimprovement of one or more combined occupancy structures; which\nagreements shall be subject to approval by the board of education.\n  10. "Director of management and budget" or "city director of\nmanagement and budget" shall mean the director of management and budget\nof the city of New York.\n  11. "Finance commissioner" or "city finance commissioner" shall mean\nthe commissioner of finance of the city of New York.\n  12. "Fund" shall mean the corporate governmental agency created by\nsection four hundred fifty-three of this article.\n  13. "Governor" shall mean the governor of the state of New York.\n  14. "Letting agency" shall mean and include the board of education or\nany other city agency which by agreement with the fund is to award the\ncontracts for a particular construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation\nor improvement; or the fund itself, if it is to award such contracts.\n  14-a. "Maximum debt service reserve fund requirement" shall mean the\namount of money required to be deposited in a debt service reserve fund\nauthorized by section four hundred sixty-two hereof established pursuant\nto a resolution of the fund.\n  15. "Mayor" shall mean the mayor of the city of New York.\n  15-a. "Owner" shall mean and include any private individual,\npartnership, trust or private or public corporation, taking possession\nof the non-school portion of a combined occupancy structure pursuant to\na lease, sub-lease, conveyance or other agreement, or acquiring fee\ntitle to or a leasehold or other interest in such non-school portion.\n  16. "Planning commission" shall mean the planning commission of the\ncity of New York.\n  17. "Real property" shall mean lands, waters, rights in lands or\nwaters, structures, franchises and interests in land, including air or\nspace rights, and any and all other things and rights usually included\nwithin the same term and includes also any and all interests in such\nproperty less than full title, such as easements permanent or temporary,\nrights-of-way, uses, leases, licenses and all other incorporeal\nhereditaments in every estate, interest or right, legal or equitable.\n  18. "School building" shall mean a separate structure entirely devoted\nto use and occupancy for public school purposes; including incidental\nand appurtenant recreational and other facilities.\n  19. "School portion" or "school portion of combined occupancy\nstructure" shall mean that portion of a combined occupancy structure\ndesigned, constructed, reconstructed, rehabilitated or improved for use\nand occupancy for public school purposes; including the real property to\nbe used in connection therewith together with incidental and appurtenant\nrecreational and other facilities.\n  20. "State" shall mean the state of New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>