<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-455"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-455"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="455"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-455/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-455/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-455/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-455/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_455">
        <num>455</num>
        <heading>Relationship with the board of education and the city of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 455. Relationship with the board of education and the city of New\nYork.  In order most effectively to carry out its corporate purposes,\nthe fund shall cooperate with the director of management and budget and\nthe board of education of the city of New York in matters relating to\nland acquisition and capital planning for school buildings and\nfacilities.  During the course of construction, reconstruction,\nrehabilitation and improvement of combined occupancy structures the fund\nshall consult with personnel of such board as the work progresses in\nmatters relating to space requirements, site plans, architectural\nconcept, and substantial changes in the plans and specifications\ntherefor, and in matters relating to the original furnishings,\nequipment, machinery and apparatus needed to furnish and equip the\nschool portion of such buildings and structures, upon the completion of\nwork.  The board, on its part, shall perform such functions and services\nfor the fund as may be requested and the fund shall pay to the board,\nfrom any monies of the fund available for such purpose, the reasonable\ncost of such functions and services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>