<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4605"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4605"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4605"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4605/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4605/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4605/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4605/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4605">
        <num>4605</num>
        <heading>Vocational and educational guidance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4605. Vocational and educational guidance.  1. The board of\neducation of each school district or board of cooperative educational\nservices may employ qualified persons for the purpose of providing\nvocational and educational guidance for minors.  Such vocational and\neducational guidance service and the qualifications of the counselors\nemployed for such work shall be approved by the commissioner.\n  2. The board of education of each school district or board of\ncooperative educational services may establish, conduct and maintain as\na part of the public school system a guidance bureau which shall perform\nsuch of the following duties as may be determined by such board:\n  a. Providing information and counsel for pupils regarding educational\nand occupational opportunities.\n  b. Providing employment and follow-up services for minors in\ncooperation with existing public agencies.\n  c. Conducting research studies of pupils and the local educational and\noccupational opportunities in cooperation with existing public agencies.\n  d. Assisting in the organization of courses of study dealing with\neducational and occupational opportunities for use in the schools and in\nteaching and supervising such courses.\n  e. Organizing and conducting a counseling service in the schools to\nassist pupils in the formation of their educational and vocational\nplans.\n  f. Cooperating with other staff members to advance the educational and\noccupational progress of pupils.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>