<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4703"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4703"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4703"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4703">
        <num>4703</num>
        <heading>Board of managers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4703. Board of managers.  The board of managers of such school shall\nconsist of not less than five members and shall be composed of all the\ncity, village and district superintendents of schools of the county in\nwhich it is located, in addition to such other members as may be\nnecessary to make a total membership of such board of not less than\nfive.  Such additional members of the board shall be appointed by the\nboard of supervisors or other governing elective body from the resident\ntaxpayers of the county, who shall serve for terms of four years\ncommencing on the first day of January succeeding their appointment.\nSuch terms shall be so arranged that the terms of no two of the members\nso appointed shall expire in the same year, and for this purpose the\nterms of the members first appointed hereunder shall be as follows:  In\ncase one member shall be appointed, the term shall be four years, in\ncase two members shall be appointed, the terms shall be four and two\nyears, respectively, in case three members shall be appointed, the terms\nshall be four, three and two years, and in case four members shall be\nappointed, the terms shall be four, three, two and one year,\nrespectively, which terms shall commence on the first day of January\nsucceeding their appointment, and their successors shall be appointed\nfor full terms of four years as above provided.  Appointments to fill\nvacancies shall be for the unexpired portion of the terms.  The members\nof the board shall serve without compensation.  They shall receive their\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.  The\namount of such expenses shall be charged against the county and shall be\npaid in the same manner as other county charges.  The board shall\norganize by the election of one of its members as chairman and another\nas secretary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>