<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-479"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-479"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="479"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-479/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-479/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-479/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-479/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_479">
        <num>479</num>
        <heading>Relationship with the board of education of the city of Yonkers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 479. Relationship with the board of education of the city of\nYonkers.  In  order most effectively to carry out its corporate\npurposes, the fund shall cooperate with the commissioner of finance and\nthe board of education of the city of Yonkers in matters relating to\nland acquisition and capital planning for school buildings and\nfacilities.  During the course of construction, reconstruction,\nrehabilitation and improvement of combined occupancy structures the fund\nshall consult with personnel of such board as the work progresses in\nmatters relating to space requirements, site plans, architectural\nconcept, and substantial changes in the plans and specifications there-\nfor, and in matters relating to the original furnishings, equipment,\nmachinery and apparatus needed to furnish and equip the school portion\nof such buildings and structures, upon the completion of work.  The\nboard, on its part, shall perform such functions and services for the\nfund as may be requested and the fund shall pay to the board, from any\nmonies of the fund available for such purpose, the reasonable cost of\nsuch functions and services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>