<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4803"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4803"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4803"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4803/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4803/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4803/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4803/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4803">
        <num>4803</num>
        <heading>Board of managers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4803. Board of managers.  The board of managers of such school shall\nconsist of not less than five members to be appointed by the mayor of\nsuch city and of which board the superintendent of schools in any such\ncity shall be one member ex-officio.  Members of the board other than\nthe said superintendent shall be appointed from resident taxpayers of\nthe city who shall serve for terms of four years commencing upon the\nfirst day of January succeeding the appointment.  Such terms shall be so\narranged that the terms of no two of the members so appointed shall\nexpire in the same year, and for this purpose the terms of members first\nappointed hereunder shall be as follows:  In case one member shall be\nappointed the term shall be four years; in case two members are\nappointed the term shall be four and two years respectively; in case\nthree members are appointed the term shall be four, three and two years;\nin case four members shall be appointed the terms shall be four, three,\ntwo and one year respectively.  Such terms shall commence on the first\nday of January succeeding the appointment and their successors shall be\nappointed for a full term of four years as above provided.  Appointments\nto fill vacancies shall be for the unexpired portion of the terms.  The\nmembers of the board shall serve without compensation.  They shall\nreceive their necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their\nduties.  The amount of such expenses shall be charged against the city\nand paid in the same manner as other city charges.  The board shall\norganize by the election of one of its members as chairman and another\nas secretary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>