<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4806"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4806"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4806"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4806/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4806/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4806/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4806/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4806">
        <num>4806</num>
        <heading>Powers of superintendent and discipline of school</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4806. Powers of superintendent and discipline of school.  The\nsuperintendent of the school shall, subject to the regulations of the\nboard of managers:\n  1. Have the general management of the school, land, buildings and\nequipment thereof, and devote his entire time to its affairs.\n  2. Supervise and direct the methods of instruction and the performance\nof duties by the teachers, assistants and employees of such school.\n  3. Be responsible for the welfare of the pupils of the school, see\nthat the regulations and directions of the board of managers are carried\ninto effect.\n  4. Prescribe rules for the government and discipline of the pupils of\nthe school and cause such rules to be enforced. Discipline shall be\nmaintained by the honor system so far as practicable. Close or solitary\nconfinement shall not be used excepting when necessary for the\nmaintenance of proper discipline.\n  5. Protect and care for the property of the school.\n  6. Give special attention to the proper instruction, detention,\nrestraint, discipline, comfort, physical and moral welfare of the pupils\nof the school and perform such other duties as may be required of him by\nthe board of managers with a view of carrying out the provisions of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>