<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4807"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4807"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-05-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4807"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4807">
        <num>4807</num>
        <heading>Children admitted to such school</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4807. Children admitted to such school. Children not more than\neighteen nor less than eight years of age may be admitted to or received\nin such school as follows:\n  1. Upon the application of the parents or guardians having the legal\ncustody and control of such children accompanied by the written consent\nof such parents or guardians.\n  2. Truants or children coming within any of the descriptions mentioned\nin section thirty-two hundred fourteen of this chapter upon commitment\nthereto either by the school authorities or by a court having\njurisdiction thereof.\n  3. Children coming within any of the descriptions mentioned in\nsections four hundred eighty-five and four hundred eighty-six of the\npenal law upon commitment thereto by a court.\n  4. Children under twelve years found guilty of juvenile delinquency.\n  5. Children over twelve and under sixteen years of age found guilty of\njuvenile delinquency for the first time and for an offense of a grade\nnot higher than misdemeanor.\n  Children resident in the city establishing such school duly committed\nthereto shall be received therein. The board of managers may in their\ndiscretion and upon such terms as to payment of expenses as they see\nfit, admit children resident in the county in which said city is\nsituated or resident in any adjoining county not having a city to which\nthis article applies.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>