<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-482"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-482"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="482"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-482/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-482/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-482/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-482/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_482">
        <num>482</num>
        <heading>Letting of construction contracts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_482__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision two of section two hundred twenty-two of the labor law,\nor the subcontractor has become otherwise unwilling, unable or\nunavailable to perform the subcontract. The sealed lists of\nsubcontractors submitted by all other bidders shall be returned to them\nunopened after the contract award.\n  3. a. In addition to other bond or bonds, if any, required by law for\nthe completion of the school portion of a combined occupancy structure,\nor in the absence of any such requirement, the fund shall nevertheless\nrequire, prior to the approval of any lease or other agreement providing\nfor the construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation or improvement of\nany combined occupancy structure, that the developer, if other than the\nYonkers city housing authority, or general contractor, furnish a bond\nguaranteeing prompt payment of moneys due to all persons furnishing\nlabor or materials to or for the person furnishing said bond or to his\nor her subcontractors in the prosecution of the entire work provided for\nin such lease or other agreement. Whenever the developer is the Yonkers\ncity housing authority, it shall require each of its contractors to\nfurnish such bond to said authority and fund with respect to the work to\nbe performed and materials supplied by such contractor, and no separate\nor other payment bond shall be required to be furnished to the fund.\n  b. A copy of such payment bond shall be kept in the office of the\nchairman of the fund and a copy shall also be kept in the office of the\nboard of education; such copies shall be open to public inspection.\n  c. Every person who has furnished labor or material, to or for the\ndeveloper or general contractor or contractor furnishing such payment\nbond or to his or her subcontractors in the prosecution of the work\nprovided for in the lease or other agreement for which the bond is\nfurnished and who has not been paid in full therefor before the\nexpiration of a period of ninety days after the day on w...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>