<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-499"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-499"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="499"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-499/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-499/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-499/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-499/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_499">
        <num>499</num>
        <heading>Additional members of a regional college cooperative services board; withdrawal</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 499. Additional members of a regional college cooperative services\nboard; withdrawal.  1. The governing board of any non-public institution\nof higher education which is not a member institution in a regional\ncollege cooperative services board may adopt a resolution requesting\nthat such institution become such a member institution in an existing\nboard. Duplicate copies of such resolution certified by the clerk of\nsuch governing board shall be filed with the board of trustees of the\nregional board. If such board approves such resolution such approval\nshall be endorsed thereon and a copy thereof shall be filed with the\ncommissioner. Upon application, the regents may amend the charter of\nsuch regional board by including such proposed member institution in\nsuch board and thereupon such member institution shall have the same\nrights and duties and privileges as other member institutions therein.\n  2. The refusal of the board of trustees of such regional board to\napprove an application for membership in such board by any higher\neducational institution shall be subject to review by the commissioner\nupon application of such applying institution and, if so directed by the\ncommissioner, such board of trustees shall approve such application and\nrequest the regents to amend the charter of the regional board to\ninclude such institution as a member institution thereof.\n  3. A board of trustees of a member institution may file with the board\nof trustees of a regional board and with the commissioner not less than\nninety days before the first day of July in any year, a resolution\nrequesting the withdrawal of such member institution from such board.\nThereafter, upon application of such member institution or such board,\nthe regents may amend the charter of such board so that such institution\nshall cease to be a member thereof on such July first or such later date\nas shall be fixed by the regents.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>