<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5001"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5001">
        <num>5001</num>
        <heading>Licensed private career schools</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the location and time period in which the program\nwill be offered;\n  (ii) a statement that the students enrolled in the program shall not\nbe subject to any tuition liability for the program, even if such\nstudents do not complete the program;\n  (iii) a statement that the program being provided to the employer has\nnot been approved by the department and is not under the department's\njurisdiction and that the students in the program have been advised of\nthe fact; and\n  (iv) the signatures of the school director or owner of the school and\nthe representative of the employer for which the program is being\noffered certifying the accuracy of the statements on the form.\n  d. Any additional student openings in a program deemed exempt by the\ndepartment may be made available to students not affiliated with the\nemployer on the condition that such students execute a disclosure form\nas prescribed in paragraph c of this subdivision. Such admitted students\nshall only constitute up to ten percent of the exempt program's total\ncapacity.\n  4. Application, renewal application and application fees. a.\nApplication and renewal application for a license as a private career\nschool required by the commissioner shall be filed on forms prescribed\nand provided by the department. Except as provided in subparagraph (iii)\nof paragraph e of this subdivision, each renewal application for a\nprivate career school licensed pursuant to this section shall include an\naudited financial statement audited according to generally accepted\nauditing standards by an independent certified public accountant or an\nindependent public accountant and statistical reports certified by the\nowner or operator of the school, as required by the commissioner;\nprovided, however, that the commissioner shall accept a copy of a\ncurrent financial statement previously filed by a school with any other\ngovernmental agency in compliance with the provisions of any federal or\nstate laws, or ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An initial license issued pursuant to the provisions of this\narticle shall be valid for a period of two years. A renewal of license\nissued pursuant to the provisions of this article shall be valid for a\nperiod of four years.\n  (ii) Every applicant and renewal applicant shall pay to the department\na nonrefundable, nontransferable application fee. The initial\napplication fee for new schools shall be five thousand dollars, of which\nthree thousand dollars shall accrue to the credit of the proprietary\nvocational school supervision account and two thousand dollars shall\naccrue to the tuition reimbursement account. For additional licensed\nlocations of currently operating schools, the application fee shall be\ntwo thousand five hundred dollars, which shall accrue to the credit of\nthe proprietary vocational school supervision account. For renewal\napplications, the fee shall be based on gross annual tuition income as\ndetermined by the annual financial statements required in paragraph a of\nthis subdivision for the most recent school fiscal year, according to\nthe following schedule:\n     GROSS ANNUAL TUITION INCOME           FEE\n     0-$199,999                            $   750.00\n     $200,000-$499,999                     $ 1,500.00\n     $500,000-$999,999                     $ 2,225.00\n     $1,000,000-$4,999,999                 $ 4,500.00\n     $5,000,000-$9,999,999                 $ 9,000.00\n     $10,000,000 or above                  $18,000.00\n  Such  renewal  fees  shall  accrue  to  the  credit of the proprietary\nvocational school supervision account. If the evaluation of a particular\ncourse or facility requires the services of an expert  not  employed  by\nthe  department,  the department shall retain such expert and the school\nshall reimburse the department for the reasonable cost of such services.\n  (iii) Each school shall display, near the entrance to the school, the\nlicense which has been issued to it. Such authorization shall be\ndisplayed...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Licensed private\ncareer schools and candidate schools shall submit such certified\nstatistical reports and annual financial statements as required by the\ncommissioner. The commissioner may require audited statistical reports\nupon a determination that a school has provided false or inaccurate\ncertified statistical reports. The financial statements shall be based\non the fiscal year of the school and shall also include an itemized\naccount of tuition refunds due and owing to past or presently enrolled\nstudents. Statistical reports shall include, but not be limited to,\nenrollment, completion and placement data. The commissioner shall use\nsuch financial statements and statistical reports submitted for the\npurposes of licensure of schools, establishing fees or assessments\npursuant to this article and determining standards pursuant to paragraph\nb of subdivision five of section five thousand two of this article. The\nattorney general, the comptroller and the president of the higher\neducation services corporation shall have access to this information\nwhen it is necessary to perform their duties as required by state law.\n  (ii) Any school which received five hundred thousand dollars or more\nin gross tuition in a school fiscal year shall be required to submit to\nthe commissioner an annual audited financial statement prepared in\naccordance with generally accepted accounting principles for that fiscal\nyear. In addition, any school which has a gross tuition of less than\nfive hundred thousand dollars in a school fiscal year but whose combined\nstate and federal student financial aid in such year equals one hundred\nthousand dollars or more shall also submit an annual audited financial\nstatement to the commissioner for that fiscal year.\n  (iii) Schools whose gross tuition is less than five hundred thousand\ndollars in a school fiscal year and which receive less than one hundred\nthousand dollars in state and federal student financial aid in a school\nfiscal yea...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>correspondence schools in which all approved programs and courses\nare under three hundred hours;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>schools which are eligible for exemption under this section but\nwhich elect to be licensed;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>non-profit schools exempt from taxation under section 501</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5001__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of\nthe internal revenue code whose programs are funded entirely through\ndonations from individuals or philanthropic organizations, or\nendowments, and interest accrued thereon; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>language schools conducted for-profit which provide instruction in\nEnglish as a second language and which accept no public funds.\n  5. Required disclosure for licensure. a. The commissioner shall\nrequire that each applicant for a license for the operation of a private\ncareer school disclose the following information:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether the applicant, or any corporation, partnership,\nassociation or organization or person holding an ownership or control\ninterest in such school, or any employee responsible in a supervisory\ncapacity for the administration of student funds or governmental funds,\nhas been convicted of a crime defined in this article, or any other\ncrime involving the operation of any educational or training program,\nor, in connection with the operation of any such program, a crime\ninvolving the unlawful acquisition, use, payment or expenditure of\neducational or training program funds; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether the applicant, or any corporation, partnership,\nassociation or organization or person holding an ownership or control\ninterest in such school, or any employee responsible in a supervisory\ncapacity for the administration of student funds or governmental funds\nhas been convicted:\n  (A) in this state of any of the following felonies defined in the\npenal law: bribery involving public servants; commercial bribery;\nperjury in the second degree; rewarding official misconduct; larceny, in\nconnection with the provision of services or involving the theft of\ngovernmental funds; offering a false instrument for filing, falsifying\nbusiness records; tampering with public records; criminal usury; scheme\nto defraud; or defrauding the government; or\n  (B) in any other jurisdiction of an offense which is substantially\nsimilar to any of the felonies defined in clause (A) of this\nsubparagraph and for which a sentence to a term of imprisonment in\nexcess of one year was authorized and ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether the applicant, or any corporation, partnership,\nassociation or organization or person holding an ownership or control\ninterest in such school, or any employee responsible in a supervisory\ncapacity for the administration of student funds or governmental funds,\nhas been finally determined in any administrative or civil proceeding to\nhave committed a violation of any provision of this article or any rules\nand regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, or any related order or\ndetermination of the commissioner, or of any similar statute, rule,\nregulation, order or determination of another jurisdiction pertaining to\nthe licensure and operation of any educational or training program; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether any school owned or operated by the applicant closed or\nceased operation and, if so, whether at the time of the closing the\napplicant was subject to a pending disciplinary action, disallowance,\nfine or other penalty and whether it owed refunds to any government\nagency or students.\n  b. No application for any license pursuant to this article shall be\ndenied by reason of disclosure pursuant to this subdivision of the\napplicant, or any corporation, partnership, association or organization\nor person holding an ownership or control interest in such school, or\nany employee responsible in a supervisory capacity for the\nadministration of student funds or governmental funds unless the\ncommissioner makes a written determination that there is a direct\nrelationship between one or more of such previous offenses and the\nlicense sought, or that issuance of the license would create an\nunreasonable risk to property or to the safety, education or welfare of\nspecific individuals or...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if the significance of the convictions or administrative\nviolations warrant such action;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if the commissioner determines that\na school did not make any disclosure required by this subdivision; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5001__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if the commissioner determines that a school's financial condition\nmay result in the interruption or cessation of instruction or jeopardize\nstudent tuition funds.\n  6. If, during the period for which a license is granted, the\ncommissioner determines that a school's financial condition may result\nin the interruption or cessation of instruction or jeopardize student\ntuition funds, the commissioner may, upon notice to the school, place\nthe school on probation for a period of no more than one year, during\nwhich time the school and the department must make efforts to resolve\nthe problems at the school.  The school shall submit a report on its\nfinancial condition to the commissioner within the time prescribed by\nthe commissioner. Such report shall be in the form and shall include\ncontent prescribed by the commissioner and shall be reviewed by the\ncommissioner to determine the school's financial viability. The\ncommissioner may suspend or revoke the school's license, as well as\n...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such annualized assessment shall be one percent for schools\nwhich have paid less than sixteen quarters of assessments, but such\nannual assessment shall not fall below five hundred dollars.\n  (ii) Such annualized assessment shall be eight-tenths of one percent\nfor schools which have paid sixteen or more quarters of assessments, but\nsuch annual assessment shall not fall below five hundred dollars.\n  c.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Of the total assessment provided for herein, five-tenths of one\npercent shall accrue to the credit of the tuition reimbursement account\npursuant to section five thousand seven of this article for those\nschools which have paid less than sixteen quarters of assessments. Of\nthe total assessment provided for schools which have paid sixteen or\nmore quarters of assessments, three-tenths of one percent shall accrue\nto the credit of the tuition reimbursement account pursuant to section\nfive thousand seven of this article.  For schools paying the minimum\nfive hundred dollars annual assessment, none shall accrue to the tuition\nreimbursement account.\n  (ii) The balance of the total assessment provided for herein shall be\ndedicated to fund the department's supervision and regulation of\nlicensed private schools pursuant to an annual appropriation and an\nannual plan of expenditure prepared by the commissioner and approved by\nthe director of the budget.\n  d. Payments made within thirty days following the due date shall be\nsubject to interest at one percent above the prevailing prime rate.\nThereafter, late payments may result in suspension of licensure by the\ncommissioner. Payments required by this subdivision shall be considered\na condition of licensure.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>