<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-511"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-511"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="511"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-511/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-511/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-511/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-511/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_511">
        <num>511</num>
        <heading>Disability retirement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_511__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\none-sixtieth of the member's final average salary multiplied by the\nnumber of years of total service, which formula is to be used if the\npension so computed exceeds one-third of the member's final average\nsalary, or (ii) one-sixtieth of the member's final average salary\nmultiplied by the number of years of total service, not to exceed\ntwenty, which would have been credited to the member had he remained in\nservice until age sixty; or\n  b. in the case of a member age sixty or over, one-sixtieth of the\nmember's final average salary multiplied by the number of years of total\nservice.\n  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this article, any member\nwho shall receive a disability retirement allowance pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be required once each year or at such other interval\nas the retirement board may determine to undergo a medical examination\nby a physician or physicians designated by the retirement board. Should\nany disability beneficiary refuse to submit to a medical examination,\nhis retirement allowance shall be discontinued until his withdrawal of\nsuch refusal, and should refusal continue for one year all rights in and\nto his pension shall be forfeited.\n  In the case of persons who last became members on or after July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-three, the provisions of this subdivision shall\napply only until July first, nineteen hundred seventy-four.\n  4. Once each year or at such other interval as the retirement board\nmay determine, following the retirement of a teacher who joined the New\nYork state teachers retirement system on or after July first, nineteen\nhundred sixty-one, on a disability allowance, or once each year during\nthe first five years following the retirement of the teacher who joined\nthe New York state teachers retirement system prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-one, on a disability allowance the retirement\nboard may, and upon his application shall, require any disability\nbeneficiary to...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_511__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a terminal illness resulting in a life expectancy of no more than\ntwelve months, or (ii) a medical condition of a long continued and\nindefinite duration requiring extraordinary care or treatment regardless\nof life expectancy.\n  c. The benefit provided in paragraph a of this subdivision shall be in\nlieu of any disability benefit to which the member may otherwise be\nentitled. A member who is otherwise eligible to retire for disability\nmust elect the benefit provided in paragraph a of this subdivision no\nlater than the thirtieth day following the day on which</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_511__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the system\nnotifies the member that the member has been retired for disability, or\n(ii) the member is first eligible to commence receiving a disability\nretirement benefit, whichever is later. Such election, when made, shall\nbe irrevocable.\n  d. Except as provided in this paragraph, a member electing the benefit\nprovided in paragraph a of this subdivision shall for all purposes be\ndeemed to have been retired for disability. Notwithstanding the\nforegoing, should a member who has elected the benefit provided in\nparagraph a of this subdivision thereafter be restored to active service\nand again become a member of the system,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_511__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no death benefit shall be payable pursuant to section five hundred\ntwelve of this article or section four hundred forty-eight, five hundred\neight or six hundred six of the retirement and social security law, as\napplicable in the event of the member's subsequent death, and\n  (ii) unless such member shall have rendered five years of credited\nservice since last becoming a member of the system, any retirement\nbenefit to which such member may thereafter become entitled shall be\nreduced by the actuarial value of the benefit paid pursuant to paragraph\na of this subdivision (less the actuarial value of any applicable\npost-retirement death benefit which would have been available, but for\nthis paragraph).\n  e. The retirement board is authorized to adopt such rules and\nregulations as it may deem necessary to implement the provisions of this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>