<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-521"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-521"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="521"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-521/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-521/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-521/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-521/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_521">
        <num>521</num>
        <heading>Collection of contributions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 521. Collection of contributions. 1. The collection of members'\ncontributions shall be as follows:\n  a. Each employer shall cause to be deducted on each and every payroll\nof a contributor for each and every payroll period, the contribution\npayable by such contributor as provided in this article. Each employer\nshall certify to the treasurer of said employer on each and every\npayroll a statement as voucher for the amounts so deducted.\n  b. The treasurer of each employer on receipt from the employer of the\nvoucher for deductions from the salaries of teachers as provided in this\narticle shall transmit monthly or at such times as the retirement board\nshall designate, the amount specified in such voucher to the secretary\nof the retirement board. The secretary of the retirement board after\nmaking record of all such receipts shall transmit them to the head of\nthe division of the treasury in the department of taxation and finance\nfor use according to the provisions of this article.\n  But nothing in this section shall prevent the retirement board from\nmodifying the method of collecting the contribution of members so that\nemployers may retain the amounts so deducted and have a corresponding\namount deducted from the appropriation for the support of common schools\notherwise payable to them.\n  2. The collection of employers' contributions shall be made as\nfollows:\n  a. Upon the basis of each actuarial determination and appraisal\nprovided herein, the retirement board shall annually prepare and certify\nto the commissioner of education a statement of the total amount\nnecessary to be paid by all employers for the ensuing fiscal year to the\npension accumulation and expense funds as provided under subdivision two\nof section five hundred seventeen and under section five hundred\nnineteen of this article. Upon the basis of the rate of contribution for\nsupplemental retirement allowances, determined in accordance with\nsection five hundred thirty-two of this article, the retirement board\nshall certify to the commissioner of education a statement of the total\namount necessary to be paid by all employers for the ensuing fiscal year\nto the supplemental retirement allowance fund. Said certification shall\ninclude interest on amounts necessary to repay advances made to the\nsupplemental retirement allowance fund pursuant to subdivision f of\nsection five hundred thirty-two of this article computed from the date\nof such advances at the rate determined in accordance with paragraph f\nof this subdivision.\n  b. The commissioner of education shall include in the certificate\nwhich he files with the state comptroller showing the amount of state\nfunds apportioned to the school districts within each county for the\nsupport of common schools, a statement showing the amount to be\ncontributed by each employer in each of such counties as required under\nthis article.\n  The amount to be contributed by each employer except those who operate\nlocal district pension systems, shall be such percentage of the total\ncompensation or salaries of all teachers in his employ who are members\nof the retirement system as the aggregate amount of the normal and\ndeficiency contributions for the year shall bear to the total\ncompensation or salaries paid by all employers, except those who operate\nlocal district pension systems, to all teachers who are members of the\nretirement system.\n  c. The comptroller shall issue his warrant to the custodian of such\nfund directing such custodian to credit to the pension accumulation fund\nand expense fund respectively, from the appropriation for the support of\ncommon schools the amounts required to be made as contributions to such\nfunds by the employers as shown by the certificate of the commissioner\nof education filed with him as directed in paragraph b of this\nsubdivision.\n  d. The comptroller, in issuing his warrant to the custodian for\npayment to each county treasurer of that portion of the moneys\napportioned for the support of common schools, shall deduct therefrom an\namount equal to the amount required to be contributed by employers of\nsuch county, as shown by the certificate of the commissioner of\neducation of this state filed with the comptroller as required by\nparagraph b of this subdivision.\n  e. In order to meet the financial requirements of this article,\nemployers who obtain funds directly by taxation are hereby authorized\nand directed to levy annually such additional taxes as are required to\nprovide the funds deducted from the amounts apportioned to such\nemployers from the appropriation of the state for the support of the\ncommon schools.\n  f. Employers whose payments from the moneys apportioned from the state\nfor the support of common schools are insufficient to pay the amount due\nand owing the system, or who do not receive such payments, shall pay the\nsystem each year the amount of contributions due and owing from the\nemployer pursuant to this article within thirty days from the date a\nbill is mailed by the system. Interest, at a rate equal to the average\nyield payable on fifty-two week United States treasury bills on June\nthirtieth immediately preceding the day the bill is mailed by the\nsystem, shall accrue on the outstanding amount due and owing commencing\nwith the thirty-first day after the bill is mailed.\n  g. Whenever the system determines the contributions made by an\nemployer are less than the percentage of total compensation or salaries\nof members of the system in the employ of such employer, as required by\nthis article, such employer shall pay the system such deficiency within\nthirty days from the date a bill is mailed by the system. Interest, at a\nrate equal to the average yield payable on fifty-two week United States\ntreasury bills on June thirtieth immediately preceding the day before\nthe bill is mailed by the system, shall accrue on the outstanding amount\ndue and owing commencing with the thirty-first day after the bill is\nmailed.\n  h. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, commencing\nwith the payments made in the fiscal year beginning July first, nineteen\nhundred ninety, and each fiscal year thereafter, the employer\ncontributions due and payable as determined pursuant to the provisions\nof this article and the employee contributions due and payable pursuant\nto this article and articles fourteen and fifteen of the retirement and\nsocial security law, on account of compensation paid in the fiscal year\nimmediately preceding, and those employer contributions due and payable\nin each fiscal year pursuant to chapter six hundred sixty-five of the\nlaws of nineteen hundred eighty-four shall be made to the retirement\nsystem and collected in the manner set forth in this section each fiscal\nyear in three payments, each equal to thirty-three and one-third percent\nof the total amount due for such fiscal year. Such payments shall be\npaid on September fifteenth, October fifteenth, and November fifteenth\nof each fiscal year. If a participating employer underpaid its\nobligation to the retirement system, such underpayment as determined by\nthe retirement system shall be deducted from the amounts apportioned to\nsuch employer from the appropriation of the state for the support of the\ncommon schools due and payable the next April fifteenth. Employers whose\npayments from such appropriation are insufficient to pay the amount due\nand owing the system, or who do not receive such payments, shall be\nbilled by the system for such underpayment and shall pay the system the\namount due within thirty days from the date a bill is mailed by the\nsystem. The amount of any employer overpayment of its obligation to the\nretirement system, as determined by such system shall be a credit to the\nemployer and shall reduce by an equal amount thereof the initial payment\nto be made by such employer to such system on the next succeeding\nSeptember fifteenth.\n  i. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the employer\nand employee contributions due and payable in the nineteen hundred\neighty-nine--ninety fiscal year on account of compensation paid in the\nnineteen hundred eighty-eight--eighty-nine fiscal year which were paid\nprior to April first, nineteen hundred ninety shall be deemed (to the\nextent such amount is sufficient) to have consisted of all the employee\ncontributions due and payable pursuant to this article and articles\nfourteen and fifteen of the retirement and social security law in the\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine--ninety fiscal year and those employer\ncontributions due and payable in such fiscal year pursuant to chapter\nsix hundred sixty-five of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-four; and\nthe remaining employer contributions so paid shall be applied evenly to\nthe payments due and payable on September fifteenth, nineteen hundred\nninety, October fifteenth, nineteen hundred ninety and November\nfifteenth, nineteen hundred ninety and the employer contributions\namounting to eight hundred seventy-three million seven hundred eleven\nthousand six hundred fifteen dollars ($873,711,615), due and payable\npursuant to the provisions of this section in the nineteen hundred\neighty-nine--ninety fiscal year on account of compensation paid in\nnineteen hundred eighty-eight--eighty-nine fiscal year, except those\nemployer contributions due and payable in such fiscal year pursuant to\nchapter six hundred sixty-five of the laws of nineteen hundred\neighty-four, shall be deferred and payment shall be made to the\nretirement system in fifteen equal annual payments of ninety-eight\nmillion five hundred thirty-seven thousand five hundred seven dollars\n($98,537,507) on October fifteenth, commencing on October fifteenth,\nnineteen hundred ninety. Such payments are calculated at an interest\nrate of eight percent per annum. Provided, however, the retirement board\nis directed to permit the pre-payment of the amounts ou</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>