<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-532-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-532-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="532-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-532-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-532-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-532-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-532-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_532_A">
        <num>532-A</num>
        <heading>Cost-of-living adjustment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_532_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all\npensioners who have attained age sixty-two and have been retired for\nfive years; (ii) all pensioners who have attained age fifty-five and\nhave been retired for ten years; (iii) all disability pensioners\nregardless of age who have been retired for five years; and (iv) all\nrecipients of an accidental death benefit regardless of age who have\nbeen receiving such benefit for five years.\n  b. Said cost-of-living adjustment shall be a percentage of the annual\nretirement allowance otherwise payable, computed without optional\nmodification, excluding any annuity derived from voluntary contributions\nmade by members, except those made pursuant to elections under\nsubdivision one of section five hundred eleven-a or paragraph c of\nsubdivision three of section five hundred sixteen of this article, but\nincluding any benefit derived from subdivision f of this section and any\nprior year's cost-of-living adjustment derived from this section. Said\npercentage is set forth in subdivision d of this section.\n  c. Said cost-of-living adjustment shall be computed on a base benefit\namount not to exceed eighteen thousand dollars of the annual retirement\nallowance defined in subdivision b of this section.\n  d. The percentage referred to in this section shall be determined\nannually by reference to the consumer price index (all urban consumers,\nCPI-U, U.S. city average, all items, 1982-84=100), published by the\nUnited States bureau of labor statistics, for each applicable calendar\nyear. Said percentage shall equal fifty percent of the annual inflation,\nas determined from the increase in the consumer price index in the one\nyear period ending on the March thirty-first prior to the cost-of-living\nadjustment effective on the ensuing September first. Said percentage\nshall then be rounded up to the next higher one-tenth of one percent and\nshall not exceed three percent nor be less than one percent.\n  e. Said cost-of-living adjustment shall be payable in monthly\ninstallm...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_532_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>with a payment for the month\nof September, two thousand, or (ii) the month following the death of the\ndeceased retired member, whichever is later.\n  h. The benefits provided pursuant to this section shall be in lieu of\nthe benefits presently provided by section five hundred ten or article\nfour or six of the retirement and social security law unless such\nbenefits are in excess of those provided by this section, in which case\nsuch benefits shall be paid by the retirement system pursuant to such\nprovision.\n  i. The liability created by this section shall be funded through the\nnormal rate of contribution in accordance with subparagraph two of\nparagraph f of subdivision two of section five hundred seventeen of this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>