<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5704"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5704"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5704"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5704">
        <num>5704</num>
        <heading>Trustees shall make reports; university subject to visitation of regents; services for state agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5704. Trustees shall make reports; university subject to visitation\nof regents; services for state agencies. 1. The trustees of said\nuniversity shall make all the reports and perform such other acts as may\nbe necessary to conform to the act of congress, entitled "An act\ndonating public lands to the several states and territories which may\nprovide colleges for the benefit of agriculture and the mechanic arts,"\napproved July second, eighteen hundred sixty-two. The said university\nshall be subject to visitation of the regents of the university.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, and\nsubject to the review and approval of the state comptroller, the state\nmay enter into an agreement with the university prescribing the general\nterms and conditions for providing services or technical assistance\npursuant to article eleven of the state finance law or program\nactivities pursuant to article eleven-B of the state finance law.\nSubject to such terms and conditions, state agencies may enter into\nagreements with said university for the provision of such services,\nassistance or activities related to the university's land grant mission,\nwhich agreements shall not be subject to the requirements of the state\nfinance law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>