<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5708"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5708"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5708"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5708/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5708/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5708/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5708/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5708">
        <num>5708</num>
        <heading>Powers to police grounds and regulate traffic thereon</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5708. Powers to police grounds and regulate traffic thereon.  1. For\nthe purpose of providing for the safety of its students, faculty,\nemployees and visitors, Cornell university is hereby authorized and\nempowered through its board of trustees: a. To adopt, make applicable\nand enforce, upon the streets, roads and highways owned, controlled or\nmaintained by said university within the grounds of said university and\nconstituting a part of the educational and research plant or plants\nowned or under the supervision, administration, and control of said\nuniversity, such provisions of the vehicle and traffic law, and such\nrules of the state department of transportation as control or regulate\nvehicular or pedestrian traffic, and parking.\n  b. To adopt and enforce such additional rules and regulations for the\ncontrol of the use of the streets and roads described in the foregoing\nsubdivision as local authorities are empowered to adopt and enforce\npursuant to said vehicle and traffic law.\n  c. To adopt and enforce rules and regulations not inconsistent with\nlaw, controlling parking of vehicles and pedestrian traffic over, along\nand upon the lands and premises of said university or the streets and\nhighways therein, and to control or prohibit thereon or therein vending,\nhawking, loitering and trespassing.\n  d. To erect, operate and maintain at the entrance or entrances to any\nsuch grounds and at other appropriate points thereon or therein control\nlights, signs and signals.\n  2. A violation of any section of the vehicle and traffic law or of any\nrule of the state department of transportation made applicable as\nprovided in paragraph a of subdivision one hereof, shall be a\nmisdemeanor or traffic infraction as designated in such law or rules as\nthe case may be, and punishable as therein provided, and any violation\nof a rule or regulation adopted under paragraph b of subdivision one\nhereof shall be a traffic infraction and punishable as provided in the\nstate vehicle and traffic law.\n  3. A violation of any rules or regulations of the university adopted\npursuant to paragraph c of subdivision one of this section, shall\nconstitute a misdemeanor punishable by fine not exceeding fifty dollars\nor by imprisonment not exceeding six months, or both.\n  4. Notice of any such laws or rules and regulations made applicable or\nadopted as hereinbefore provided shall be given either personally or by\nreasonable notice conspicuously posted on the said lands and premises,\nor by traffic sign, signal or device, and by filing a copy of all such\nlaws, rules and regulations, and amendments thereof from time to time,\nin the office of the clerk of the city, town, or village where they are\nto be enforced. Such laws, rules and regulations shall be enforced, and\nviolations thereof shall be punishable in any court having jurisdiction\nin the territory in which such violations shall occur.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>