<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5711"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5711"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5711"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5711/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5711/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5711/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5711/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5711">
        <num>5711</num>
        <heading>New York state college of veterinary medicine</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5711. New York state college of veterinary medicine. 1. The state\nveterinary college, established by chapter one hundred fifty-three of\nthe laws of eighteen hundred ninety-four, shall hereafter be known as\nthe New York state college of veterinary medicine at Cornell university,\nand shall continue to be under the supervision of the state university\ntrustees. The object of said college of veterinary medicine shall be: To\ngive instruction in the normal structure and function of the animal\nbody, in the pathology, prevention and treatment of animal diseases, and\nin all matters pertaining to biomedical science as applied to animals\nand correlatively to the human family; and to conduct investigations as\nto the nature, prevention and cure of all diseases of animals, including\nsuch as are communicable to man and such as cause epizootics among\nanimals; and to investigate the economic questions which will contribute\nto the more profitable breeding, rearing and utilization of animals.\n  2. All buildings, furniture, apparatus and other property heretofore\nor hereafter erected or furnished by the state for such college of\nveterinary medicine shall be and remain the property of the state. The\nCornell university shall have the custody and control of said property,\nand, as the representative of the state university trustees, shall, with\nwhatever state moneys may be received for the purpose, administer the\nsaid college of veterinary medicine as to the establishment of courses\nof study, the creation of departments and positions, the determination\nof the number and salaries of members of the faculty and other employees\nthereof, the appointment and employment thereof, the maintenance of\ndiscipline and as to all matters, pertaining to its educational\npolicies, activities and operations, including research work.\n  3. The state university trustees shall maintain general supervision\nover the requests for appropriations, budgets, estimates and\nexpenditures of such college. Cornell university shall receive no\nincome, profit or compensation for the exercise and performance of the\npowers and duties conferred and imposed by this section, but all moneys\nreceived from state appropriations for the said college of veterinary\nmedicine or derived from other sources in the course of the\nadministration thereof, shall be kept by said university in a separate\nfund from the moneys of the university, and shall be used exclusively\nfor said New York state college of veterinary medicine. Such moneys as\nmay be appropriated to be paid to the Cornell university by the state in\nany year, to be expended by said university in the administration of\nsaid college of veterinary medicine, shall be payable to the treasurer\nof Cornell university in three equal payments to be made on the first\nday of October, the first day of January, and the first day of April in\nsuch year, and shall be expended upon vouchers approved by the\nchancellor of the state university, as the chief administrative officer\nof the state university, or by such authority or authorities in the\nstate university as shall be designated by the chancellor by a rule or\nwritten direction filed with the comptroller, when and in the manner\nauthorized by the state university trustees.\n  4. The said university shall expend such moneys and use such property\nof the state in administering said college of veterinary medicine, and\nshall submit to the state university trustees during the month of\nSeptember in each year, a detailed statement of such expenditures and of\nthe general operations of the said college of veterinary medicine.\n  5. The tuition fees charged to students shall be regulated by Cornell\nuniversity after consultation with the state university trustees and all\nother fees and charges in said college of veterinary medicine shall be\nfixed by Cornell university, and the moneys so received shall be\nexpended for the current expenses of the said college of veterinary\nmedicine.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>