<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5713"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5713"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5713"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5713/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5713/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5713/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5713/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5713">
        <num>5713</num>
        <heading>New York state agricultural experiment station</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5713. New York state agricultural experiment station. 1. The\ninstitution known as the New York agricultural experiment station,\nlocated in the city of Geneva, for the purposes of promoting agriculture\nin its various branches by scientific investigation and experiment,\nestablished by chapter five hundred ninety-two of the laws of eighteen\nhundred eighty, shall continue to be controlled and managed by Cornell\nuniversity under the supervision of the state university trustees. Said\nstation shall be managed, controlled and administered by Cornell\nuniversity, as the representative of the state university trustees, in\nthe manner and with the powers provided by section fifty-seven hundred\ntwelve of this chapter. Cornell university shall have the power to\nappoint a director and such other scientific and expert workers and\nemployees deemed necessary to accomplish the objects of such experiment\nstation. In such station, said university shall, besides conducting\nexperiments for the promotion of agricultural science, perform and\nreport to the commissioner of agriculture and markets such analyses and\nother scientific work as such commissioner may request and consider to\nbe necessary for the administration of the provisions of the agriculture\nand markets law. The salaries and other expenses incurred by reason of\nsuch analyses and other scientific service shall be paid from funds\nappropriated for such purposes.\n  2. Cornell university is hereby authorized and empowered to publish\nfrom time to time bulletins giving information of the results of\nanalyses made at such station of any commodity or substance analyzed\nthereat and may in like manner publish bulletins containing the results\nof such analyses heretofore made and unpublished.\n  3. In addition to the number of copies otherwise required by law, the\ncommissioner of agriculture and markets may, with the approval of the\ngovernor, cause to be printed by the state printer such number of copies\nof any report of such station heretofore or hereafter made as he deems\nsufficient to meet the public demand therefor. The expense of printing\nsuch copies shall be paid out of the appropriation for legislative\nprinting, as provided by law. Such copies shall be delivered to such\ncommissioner and sold by him to the public at the actual cost thereof as\ndetermined by the comptroller.\n  4. The Cornell university is hereby designated as the institution\nwithin this state entitled to receive the benefits of the act of\ncongress of the United States, approved March second, eighteen hundred\neighty-seven, entitled "An act to establish agricultural experiment\nstations in connection with colleges established in the several states,\nunder the provision of an act approved July second eighteen hundred and\nsixty-two, and of the acts supplementary thereto." Such benefits of such\nact which this state is authorized thereby to apply to any college,\ninstitution or agricultural experiment station within this state are\napplied to Cornell university and this state consents that such\nappropriation, money, or benefits to or for the use of this state, or of\nany institution within this state, payable under or in pursuance of such\nact of congress, shall be paid to the treasurer of Cornell university\nwho is the officer designated to receive the same, to be used by Cornell\nuniversity in such proportion that nine-tenths thereof shall be applied\nto the use of the New York state college of agriculture and life\nsciences and one-tenth thereof to the New York state agricultural\nexperiment station at Geneva.  Such moneys shall be expended as provided\nin such act of congress. The department of taxation and finance shall\nkeep an account of all moneys received by it in pursuance of such act of\ncongress in a separate fund to the credit of the Cornell university and\nshall pay all moneys immediately upon receipt thereof by it to the\ntreasurer of such university, upon the warrant of the comptroller issued\nupon the order of the said university.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>