<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5714"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5714"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5714"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5714">
        <num>5714</num>
        <heading>New York state college of human ecology</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5714. New York state college of human ecology.  1. The school of\nhome economics heretofore administered and maintained in the New York\nstate college of agriculture at Cornell university shall hereafter be\nknown as the New York state college of human ecology at Cornell\nuniversity and shall continue to be under the management and control of\nsaid university, subject to the supervision of the state university\ntrustees.\n  2. The object of said college of human ecology shall be the\nimprovement of family well-being and human welfare by means of\neducation, research, extension teaching, and related public service in\nthe fields of human development and the use of human and environmental\nresources, including consumer economics, family relationships, human\nnutrition, household design, and allied subjects.\n  3. All buildings, furniture, apparatus, and other property heretofore\nerected or furnished by the state for the said college of human ecology,\nand all buildings, furniture, apparatus, and other property hereafter\nerected or furnished by the state for said college of human ecology\nshall be and remain the property of the state. The Cornell university\nshall have the custody and control of said property, and shall, as the\nrepresentative of the state university trustees, with whatever state\nmoneys may be received for the purpose, administer the said college of\nhuman ecology as to the establishment of courses of study, the creation\nof departments and positions, the determination of the number and\nsalaries of members of the faculty and other employees thereof, the\nemployment and appointment thereof, the maintenance of discipline and as\nto all matters pertaining to its educational policies, activities and\noperations, including research work.\n  4. The state university trustees shall maintain general supervision\nover the requests for appropriations, budgets, estimates and\nexpenditures of such college. Cornell university shall receive no\nincome, profit, or compensation for the exercise and performance of the\npowers and duties conferred and imposed by this section, but all moneys\nreceived from state appropriations for said college of human ecology or\nderived from other sources in the course of the administration thereof\nshall be credited by said university to a separate fund and shall be\nused exclusively for said New York state college of human ecology. Such\nmoneys as may be appropriated to be paid to the Cornell university by\nthe state in any year to be expended by said university in the\nadministration of said college of human ecology shall be payable to the\ncomptroller of Cornell university in three equal payments to be made on\nthe first day of July, the first day of November, and the first day of\nMarch, and shall be expended upon vouchers approved by the chancellor of\nthe state university, as the chief administrative officer of the state\nuniversity, or by such authority or authorities in the state university\nas shall be designated by the chancellor by a rule or written direction\nfiled with the comptroller, when and in the manner authorized by the\nstate university trustees.\n  5. The said university shall expend such moneys and use such property\nof the state in administering said college of human ecology as above\nprovided, and shall report to the state university trustees during the\nmonth of September in each year.\n  6. The tuition fees charged to students shall be regulated by Cornell\nuniversity after prior consultation with the state university trustees\nand all other fees and charges in said college of human ecology shall be\nfixed by Cornell university, and the moneys received from these sources\nand from the sales of products shall be credited to a separate fund and\nshall be used for the expenses of said college of human ecology in such\nways as the trustees of said university may determine.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>