<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6003"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6003"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6003"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6003">
        <num>6003</num>
        <heading>College board of trustees; organization</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6003. College board of trustees; organization. There shall continue\nto be a board of trustees of the college consisting of fifteen members\nof which the lieutenant-governor, state commissioner of education,\nchancellor of the state university, the state commissioner of\nenvironmental conservation, and the chancellor of Syracuse university\nshall be ex officio members. Any ex officio member may act through a\nrepresentative appointed in a writing filed with the secretary of the\nboard. One member shall be elected by and from among the students of the\ncollege. The election of the student member shall be conducted in\naccordance with rules and regulations promulgated by the college student\nassociation in accordance with guidelines established by the state\nuniversity. Such student member shall be subject to every provision of\nany general, special, or local law, ordinance, charter, code, rule, or\nregulation applying to the voting members of such board with respect to\nthe discharge of their duties including, but not limited to, those\nprovisions setting forth codes of ethics, disclosure requirements, and\nprohibiting business and professional activities. The one member of such\nboard elected by and from among the students of the college may be\nremoved by such students in accordance with rules and regulations\npromulgated by the college student association in accordance with\nguidelines promulgated by state university trustees.\n  The board shall provide for the calling of regular and special\nmeetings, designate a chairman, other than the student member, fix the\nnumber of voting members required to constitute a quorum for the\ntransaction of business and the number of voting members required to\nexercise the powers vested in the board and otherwise make and amend\nrules for the conduct of its affairs.\n  The members of the board, other than ex officio and student members,\nshall continue to be appointed by the governor, by and with the advice\nand consent of the senate. The members appointed by the governor shall\ncontinue to be divided into three classes, so that the terms of\none-third thereof shall expire every two years. The term of office of\nmembers shall be six years. A vacancy in the office of an appointive\ntrustee, other than by expiration of term, shall be filled by\nappointment for the unexpired term. The term of office for the student\nmember shall be one year commencing July first of the calendar year in\nwhich the election is conducted. In the event that the student member\nceases to be a student at the institution, such member shall be required\nto resign. The members of the board of trustees shall serve without\ncompensation, but shall be entitled to their actual necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of their duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>