<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-608-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-608-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="608-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-608-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-608-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-608-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-608-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_608_A">
        <num>608-A</num>
        <heading>Military enhanced recognition, incentive and tribute ("MERIT") scholarships</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_608_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>while a legal\nresident of New York state, died, became severely and permanently\ndisabled or was classified as missing in action in a combat theater or\ncombat zone of operations as part of military operations related to such\nmilitary service or died as a result of injury or illness suffered or\nincurred during such military service; or (ii) while a legal resident of\nNew York state, died or became severely and permanently disabled as a\nresult of injury or illness suffered or incurred during military\ntraining operations in preparation for duty in a combat theater or\ncombat zone of operations.\n  b. A member of the armed forces of the United States who:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_608_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>became\nseverely and permanently disabled as a result of service in the armed\nforces of the United States, as defined by subdivision eight of section\none of the military law, in a combat theater or combat zone of\noperations as part of military operations at any time on or after the\nsecond day of August, nineteen hundred ninety; and (ii) was a legal\nresident of New York state at the time of military service.\n  c. A member of the armed forces of the United States who:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_608_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>became\nseverely and permanently disabled as a result of injury or illness\nsuffered or incurred during military training operations in preparation\nfor duty in a combat theater or combat zone of operations; and (ii) was\na legal resident of New York state at the time of military service.\n  d. A member of the state organized militia who:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_608_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>became severely\nand permanently disabled as a result of injury or illness suffered or\nincurred during active military service, as defined in subdivision six\nof section one of the military law; and (ii) was a legal resident of New\nYork state at the time of military service.\n  2. Awards under this section shall be payable for each of not more\nthan four academic years of undergraduate study or five years if a\nprogram normally requires five years, as defined by the commissioner\npursuant to this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>