<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6102"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6102">
        <num>6102</num>
        <heading>Administration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6102. Administration.  Such college shall continue to be\nadministered, as to the establishment of courses of study, the creation\nof departments and positions, the determination of the number and\nsalaries of members of the faculty and other employees, the\napportionment and employment thereof, the maintenance of discipline and\nas to all matters pertaining to its educational policies, activities and\noperations, including research work, by Alfred university, as the\nrepresentative of the state university trustees.  All property and\nequipment acquired for the use of such college shall be the property of\nthe state.  Alfred university shall regulate tuition fees at such\ncollege after prior consultation with the state university trustees.  As\nthe representative of the state university trustees, Alfred university\nshall also fix the other fees and charges to be paid by the students of\nthe college.\n  All moneys received for tuition from students, those derived from the\nsale of products of property belonging to the state administered by the\ncollege, and from fees and charges, or any other sources in the course\nof the administration of the college, notwithstanding the provisions of\nsection one hundred twenty-one of the state finance law, shall be\ncredited to a separate fund and shall be expended for the current\nexpenses of such college and for its benefits in such way as Alfred\nuniversity, as the representative of the state university trustees, may\ndetermine.  The amounts so received and expended shall be reported\nannually to the state comptroller.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>