<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6208"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6208"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6208"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6208">
        <num>6208</num>
        <heading>Collective negotiation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6208. Collective negotiation.  For the purposes of article fourteen\nof the civil service law, the city university of New York shall be\ndeemed to be the public employer and as such shall negotiate with and\nenter into written agreements with employee organizations representing\nthe instructional staff and non-instructional staff of the senior\ncolleges and community colleges of such university that have been\ncertified or recognized under such article.  For purposes of such\narticle, the chancellor of the city university shall be deemed to be the\nchief executive officer, the chief legal officer of the city university\nshall be chief legal officer, and the legislature of the state of New\nYork shall be deemed to be the legislative body of the government.  In\ncarrying on such negotiations, the city university of New York shall\nconsult with and seek assistance from the state office of employee\nrelations and the New York city office of municipal labor relations.\nThe state public employment relations board shall have exclusive\njurisdiction for the purpose of administering the provisions of such\narticle and the provisions of section two hundred twelve of such article\nshall not be applicable to any such negotiations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>