<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6213"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6213"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6213"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6213">
        <num>6213</num>
        <heading>Establishment of collegiate centers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6213. Establishment of collegiate centers. 1. The board of trustees\nshall have the same powers to acquire sites, buildings, apparatus, and\nequipment for its community colleges' as the board of education has for\nschool purposes, and it shall follow the procedure prescribed by law for\nthe board of education in the acquisition of such sites, buildings,\napparatus and equipment. When, in its discretion, the city university of\nNew York resolves to establish new centers of instruction for community\ncolleges, it shall follow the procedure of the board of education in\nestablishing new schools.\n  2. The city university of New York shall have the power to acquire\nreal property, as defined by the eminent domain procedure law, in the\nname of the people of the state of New York by purchase, lease or\nappropriation for senior college purposes in accordance with the\nprovisions of section three hundred seven of this chapter, except that\nthe powers and duties in said section mentioned to be performed by the\ncommissioner of education, shall be performed by the board of trustees.\n  3. On the request of the city university construction fund, either the\ncommissioner of general services of the state of New York, with respect\nto any property held by the city university in the name of the people of\nthe state of New York, or the city university, with respect to any\nproperty held by it in its own name, may sell, convey, lease or exchange\nor otherwise make available to the dormitory authority, for nominal\nconsideration, any such property for the purposes of dormitory authority\nfinancing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>