<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6220"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6220">
        <num>6220</num>
        <heading>Salary schedules in certain public institutions of higher learning</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6220. Salary schedules in certain public institutions of higher\nlearning. For the purposes of this section, "college" shall mean a\nsenior college as defined in subdivision five of section sixty-two\nhundred two of this article. Any reference in this section to a\n"community college of the board of trustees" or to a "community college\nsponsored or administered by the board of higher education of the city\nof New York" shall be deemed a reference to a community college as\ndefined in subdivision four of section sixty-two hundred two of this\narticle and to a locally sponsored community college administered by the\nboard pursuant to subdivision three of section sixty-three hundred six\nof this chapter.\n  In any public institution of higher learning under the jurisdiction of\nthe board of trustees, including community colleges sponsored or\nadministered by the board of trustees, the salaries, increments and\nannual salary schedules of the following positions shall continue to be\nno lower than those established by the board of higher education and\napproved by the mayor and in full force and effect the first day of\nJanuary, nineteen hundred sixty-five:\n  1. President;\n  2. Dean;\n  3. Professor;\n  4. Registrar;\n  5. Lecturers;\n  6. Associate professors and librarians;\n  7. Assistant professors and associate librarians;\n  8. Instructors, assistant registrars and assistant librarians;\n  9. Library assistants;\n  10. Tutors;\n  11. Research assistants and clinical assistants;\n  12. Fellows and laboratory teaching assistants;\n  13. Services on an hourly basis of compensation: persons appointed to\nteaching positions in the evening and summer session with compensation\non an hourly basis;\n  14. Temporary employees in teaching and supervising positions; and\n  15. College physician--doctor and/or dentist: on session service.\n  The annual increments provided through the operation of this\nsubdivision shall be added on January first of each year.\n  16. Administrative employees of the non-instructional staff.\n  A. Group I. College office assistant A, college secretarial assistant\nA;\n  Group II. College office assistant B, college secretarial assistant B;\n  Group III. College administrative assistant;\n  Group IV. Such other administrative positions of the non-instructional\nstaff now existing and such other administrative positions of the\nnon-instructional staff as the board of trustees may establish from time\nto time and at such salary and salary schedules as the said board of\ntrustees may establish with the approval of the mayor of the city of New\nYork.\n  B. The annual increments provided through the operation of this\nsection in the foregoing salary schedules for groups I, II, and III\nhereof shall become effective on the first day of July or the first day\nof January in each year following the completion of a year of service.\n  C. Effective July first, nineteen hundred sixty-six, titles of\nadministrative employees of the non-instructional staff of community\ncolleges sponsored or administered by the board of trustees shall be\nchanged as follows:\n  1. Group I. College office assistant A, college secretarial assistant\nA.\n  2. Group II. College office assistant B, college secretarial assistant\nB.\n  3. Group III. College administrative assistant.\n  4. Group IV. Such other administrative positions of the\nnon-instructional staff now existing and such other administrative\npositions of the non-instructional staff as the board of trustees may\nestablish from time to time and at such salary and salary schedules as\nsaid board of trustees may establish with the approval of the mayor of\nthe city of New York.\n  5. The qualification requirements for these positions and the\nconditions of employment shall be as established by the board of\ntrustees, and shall be the same as those established for comparable\ntitles for four-year colleges of the board of trustees of the city\nuniversity of New York.\n  6. Salaries and salary conditions for these positions shall be as\nestablished by the board of trustees, and shall be the same as those\nestablished for comparable titles for four-year colleges of the board of\ntrustees.\n  7. All permanent administrative employees of the non-instructional\nstaff of the community colleges sponsored or administered by the board\nof trustees, who are high school graduates and who on June thirtieth,\nnineteen hundred sixty-six had permanent or probationary status in the\ntitles listed in column one below shall without examination (except as\notherwise specified) have their titles changed to the equated titles in\ncolumn two:\n     Column 1                                              Column 2\nTitle as of June 30, 1966                            Equated Title as of\n                                                            July 1, 1966\nAccount Clerk                                             College office\n                                                             assistant A\nAdministrative assistant                          College administrative\n                                                               assistant\nClerk                                                     College office\n                                                             assistant A\nDepartment library aide                                   College office\n                                                             assistant A\nSenior Clerk                                                     College\n                                                      office assistant B\nSenior stenographer                                  College secretarial\n                                                             assistant B\nStenographer                                         College secretarial\n                                                             assistant A\nSupervising clerk                                 College administrative\n                                                               assistant\n  (if incumbent passes a noncompetitive qualifying examination conducted\nby the New York city department of personnel; a probationary period of\none year shall begin on appointment as a college administrative\nassistant)\n                                   or\n  College office assistant B (if incumbent fails to pass the above\nqualifying examination; in which case incumbent's salary shall continue\nto increase by increments until the maximum of supervising clerk\nschedule has been reached).  Supervising stenographer College\nadministrative assistant\n  (if incumbent passes a non-competitive qualifying examination\nconducted by the New York city department of personnel; a probationary\nperiod of one year shall begin on appointment as college administrative\nassistant)\n                                   or\n  College secretarial assistant B (if incumbent fails to pass the above\nqualifying examination; in which case incumbent's salary shall continue\nto increase by increments until the maximum of supervising stenographer\nschedule has been reached).\nTypist                                        College office assistant A\n  An employee who on July first, nineteen hundred sixty-six has not yet\ncompleted his probationary period shall, if he subsequently completes\nhis probationary period, be reclassified to the appropriate equivalent\ntitle at the time of his permanent appointment. An employee who is not a\nhigh school graduate shall be reclassified within a year after July\nfirst, nineteen hundred sixty-six to the appropriate equivalent title on\npresentation of a high school diploma or its equivalent, failing to do\nwhich such employee shall remain in his career and salary plan title.\n  8. No person employed in the community colleges sponsored or\nadministered by the board of trustees at the time this article goes into\neffect shall suffer any diminution of salary, status, tenure, and\nretirement rights, nor shall he receive in his new title a salary less\nthan he would have received had he continued in his former title. Any\nsuch person shall retain his right to promotion on a city-wide basis\nfrom any civil service list in existence on July first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-six or established as the result of any examination for which the\nfiling period began prior to that date.\n  9. All persons appointed on or after the date this article takes\neffect to serve in administrative positions of the non-instructional\nstaff in the community colleges of the board of trustees shall be\nappointed for the probationary period of one year, during which the\nservice of a person appointed to any such position may be discontinued\nby the board of trustees at any time. All persons employed in the\nadministrative service of the non-instructional staff of the community\ncolleges sponsored or administered by the board of trustees who have\nserved the full probationary period shall hold their respective\npositions during good behavior and efficient and competent service, and\nshall not be removed except for cause after a hearing by the affirmative\nvote of a majority of the board of trustees.\n  The board of trustees shall provide by appropriate by-laws, for the\npresentation of charges, the reference thereof to a committee of the\nboard of trustees or to others for hearings, the conduct of such\nhearings and the report thereof on the basis of which the board of\ntrustees shall take such action as it deems necessary or advisable.\n  10. Laboratory staff.\n  Group I. College science assistant A; college science technician A;\ncollege engineering technician A;\n  Group II. College science assistant B; college science technician B;\ncollege engineering technician B;\n  Group III. College science assistant C; college science technician C;\ncollege engineering technician C;\n  11. Professor;\n  12. Associate professor;\n  13. Assistant professor;\n  14. Instructor;\n  15. Lecturer (nursi</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>