<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6226"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6226"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6226"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6226">
        <num>6226</num>
        <heading>Community college severence provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6226. Community college severence provisions.  a. On July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-five:\n  1. Any funds and copies of all books, papers and records of the\ntrustees of the state university, pertaining to or connected with the\ncommunity colleges, shall become the property of the board of trustees.\n  2. Any business or other matter undertaken or commenced by the\ntrustees of the state university of New York pertaining to or connected\nwith the community colleges may be conducted and completed by the board\nof trustees under the same terms and conditions and with the same effect\nas if conducted and completed by such board of trustees.\n  3. Inclusion in the master plan of the state university of New York of\na facility or of a plan or recommendation with respect to a community\ncollege shall constitute inclusion of such facility, plan or\nrecommendation in the master plan of the city university, and any\napproval by the board of regents of any facility, plan or recommendation\nincluded in the master plan of the state university with respect to a\ncommunity college and the incorporation thereof in the regents plan for\nhigher education, and any approval by the governor of the regents plan\ninsofar as it relates to such facility, plan or recommendation, shall\nconstitute the requisite approvals of the inclusion of such facility,\nplan or recommendation in the master plan of the city university for\npurposes of section two hundred thirty-seven of this article and article\none hundred twenty-five-B of this chapter, and any other law.\n  4. Any person who, immediately prior to July first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-five, was appointed to a position on the instructional staff of\na community college pursuant to former section sixty-two hundred six-b\nof this article shall be considered as of the effective date of this\narticle to have been appointed to a comparable position under section\nsixty-two hundred ten of this chapter. Any person who, immediately prior\nto July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five, had achieved tenure under\nformer section sixty-two hundred six-b of this chapter shall be\nconsidered as of July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five as having\nachieved tenure and/or attained such other right under section sixty-two\nhundred ten of this chapter.  The period of creditable service of any\nperson who, prior to July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five, had at\nany time served in a position on the instructional staff of a community\ncollege pursuant to former section sixty-two hundred six-b of this\nchapter shall be counted in computing the years of service of such\nperson required under section sixty-two hundred ten of this chapter in\nthe achievement of tenure.\n  b. The board of trustees is hereby authorized to enter into any\nagreement to effectuate the purposes of chapter three hundred thirty-two\nof the laws of nineteen hundred seventy-five.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>