<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6228"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6228"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6228"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6228/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6228/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6228/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6228/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6228">
        <num>6228</num>
        <heading>Transitory provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6228. Transitory provisions.  1. Whenever the term "board of higher\neducation of the city of New York" or "board of higher education of a\ncity having a population of one million or more" is referred to or\ndesignated in any law, general, special or local, contract, lease,\njudgment, decision or document pertaining to the functions, powers and\nduties hereby continued in, transferred and assigned to, or devolved\nupon, the corporate body of the city university of New York continued by\nthis article, such reference or designation shall be deemed to refer to\nand include the corporate body of the city university of New York\ncontinued by this article, so far as such law, contract, lease,\njudgment, decision or document pertains to matters which are within its\njurisdiction by reason of the redesignation, continuation, transfer,\nassignment and devolution of functions, powers and duties made by this\narticle.\n  2. All contracts, leases and other agreements entered into by the\nboard of higher education of the city of New York on behalf of the city\nuniversity of New York before the effective date of this article shall\nbe conducted and completed by the body corporate of the city university\nof New York continued by this article in the same manner and under the\nsame terms and conditions and with the same effect as if the same had\nbeen conducted and completed by the board of higher education of the\ncity of New York. In addition, any contracts, leases and other\nagreements entered into by the city university of New York prior to the\neffective date of this article shall remain in full force and effect and\nshall be conducted and completed by the body corporate of the city\nuniversity of New York continued by this article.\n  3. All rights, title and interest in personal property used for\neducational or administrative purposes of the senior colleges of the\ncity university of New York vested in the city of New York on the\neffective date of this article are hereby transferred, assigned and\ndevolved upon the city university of New York.\n  4. No existing right or remedy of any character shall be lost,\nimpaired or affected, nor shall any new right or remedy of any character\naccrue to or for the benefit of any person by reason of the continuation\nof the corporate body of the city university of New York pursuant to the\nprovisions of this article.\n  5. Any lease entered into by the city of New York for the purposes of\nthe senior colleges of the city university of New York before the\neffective date of this article is hereby transferred, assigned and\ndevolved upon the city university of New York, notwithstanding any\nprovision that may be contained therein providing for the\nnonassignability of such lease and any such provision shall be deemed to\nbe void as against the public policy of the state and of no force and\neffect; provided however, that the city of New York shall guarantee the\nperformance by the city university of the obligation of the lessee under\nsuch lease.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>