<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6301"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6301">
        <num>6301</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 1101 of title 8 of the United States\nCode, if such student:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6301__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>attended an approved New York high school for two or more years,\ngraduated from an approved New York high school and applied for\nattendance at an institution or educational unit of the state university\nwithin five years of receiving a New York state high school diploma; or\n  (ii) attended an approved New York state program for general\nequivalency diploma exam preparation, received a general equivalency\ndiploma issued within New York state and applied for attendance at an\ninstitution or educational unit of the state university within five\nyears of receiving a general equivalency diploma issued within New York\nstate; or\n  (iii) was enrolled in an institution or educational unit of the state\nuniversity in the fall semester or quarter of the two thousand one--two\nthousand two academic year and was authorized by such institution or\neducational unit to pay tuition at the rate or charge imposed for\nstudents who are residents of the state.\n  Provided, further, that a student without lawful immigration status\nshall also be required to file an affidavit with such institution or\neducational unit stating that the student has filed an application to\nlegalize his or her immigration status, or will file such an application\nas soon as he or she is eligible to do so.\n  In the event that a person qualified as above for state residence, but\nhas been a resident of two or more counties in the state during the six\nmonths immediately preceding his application for a certificate of\nresidence pursuant to section sixty-three hundred five of this chapter,\nthe charges to the counties of residence shall be allocated among the\nseveral counties proportional to the number of months, or major fraction\nthereof, of residence in each county.\n  6. "Certificate of residence form". A standard form as developed by\nthe chancellor of the state university of New York, in conjunction with\nthe chancellor of the city university of New York.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>