<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6302"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6302"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6302"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6302">
        <num>6302</num>
        <heading>Authorization to establish community colleges</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6302__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Determine that the bidder on a contract for the purchase of\napparel or sports equipment is not an acceptable bidder based on either\nof the following considerations:\n  (A) the labor standards applicable to the manufacture of the apparel\nor sports equipment, including but not limited to employee compensation,\nworking conditions, employee rights to form unions, and the use of child\nlabor, or\n  (B) the bidder's failure to provide information sufficient for the\nstate agency or corporation to determine the labor conditions applicable\nto the manufacture of the apparel or sports equipment.\n  (ii) Include in the internal policies and procedures governing\nprocurement of apparel a prohibition against the purchase of apparel or\nsports equipment from any vendor based upon either or both of the\nfollowing considerations:\n  (A) the labor standards applicable to the manufacture of the apparel\nor sports equipment, including but not limited to employee compensation,\nworking conditions, employee rights to form unions, and the use of child\nlabor; or\n  (B) the bidder's failure to provide sufficient information for said\nstate agencies to determine the labor standards applicable to the\nmanufacture of the apparel or sports equipment.\n  b. For the purposes of this subdivision the term:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6302__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"apparel" shall mean goods, such as, but not limited to, sports\nuniforms, including gym uniforms, required school uniforms, shoes,\nincluding, but not limited to, athletic shoes or sneakers, sweatshirts,\ncaps, hats, and other clothing, whether or not imprinted with a school's\nname or logo, academic regalia, lab coats and staff uniforms; and\n  (ii) "sports equipment" shall mean equipment, such as, but not limited\nto, balls, bats and other goods intended for use by those participating\nin sports and games.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>