<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6303-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6303-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6303-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6303-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6303-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6303-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6303-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6303_A">
        <num>6303-A</num>
        <heading>Graduation, achievement and placement program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Plan" shall mean the graduation, achievement and placement (GAP)\nprogram plan to be developed by the state university trustees pursuant\nto subdivision two of this section, after consultation with the\ncommunity college presidents, councils and faculty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Program" shall mean the GAP program to be developed by the state\nuniversity trustees pursuant to subdivision two of this section.\n  2. By no later than July first, two thousand fourteen, the state\nuniversity trustees shall develop, as part of the master plan to be\nsubmitted pursuant to section three hundred fifty-four of this chapter,\na comprehensive plan to be incorporated into its two thousand sixteen\nmaster plan and fully implemented no later than July first, two thousand\neighteen at each of the state university of New York community colleges.\nSuch plan shall seek to develop a remedial education program to\naccomplish the following goals:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Improve community college outcomes by reducing the time to degree\ncompletion or transfer to a four year college;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Reduce state and local sponsor expenditures on remedial\ncoursework;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Improve overall community college graduation rates and employment\nprospects.\n  3. Each community college shall utilize features in its program\nidentified in the SUNY task force on remediation report, issued pursuant\nto chapter fifty-seven of the laws of two thousand twelve, and shall\nconsider other features of successful existing programs, including, but\nnot limited to the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adoption of a consistent definition of "college readiness" for\nstudent placement into remedial programs using multiple measures of\nstudent achievement;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Accelerated developmental education program offerings;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Incorporating remedial instruction into the beginning of\ncollege-level programs, either as introductory courses or integrated\ninto initial college-level courses;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Utilize supplemental academic support for developmental students\nenrolled in college level courses as well as other contextualization\nmodels;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A consolidated course schedule that permits students to take\nclasses in a morning, afternoon or evening schedule so as to enable\nstudents to balance school, work and other personal responsibilities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An advisement model that directs counselors with assigned\ncaseloads to meet with students monthly from program entry until\ngraduation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Career and employment services that provide students with\ninterview training, job skills and career planning;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Academic support services that provide tutoring from qualified\nundergraduate or graduate students or faculty; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Comprehensive evaluation and the use of data to assess the\neffectiveness of the program.\n  4. Each community college shall be required to implement, on a partial\nbasis, its program by the two thousand fourteen--two thousand fifteen\nacademic year.\n  5. Each community college shall report on the implementation of the\nprogram and shall report on measures of student success for each student\nenrolled in such program. Such report shall include but not be limited\nto:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Annual number and percentage of entering first-time students\nenrolled in remedial (developmental) education courses in math,\nenglish/reading or both and complete a college-level course in the same\nsubject.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Annual number and percentage of entering first-time degree or\ncertificate seeking students who complete entry college-level math,\nenglish and reading courses within the first two consecutive academic\nyears.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6303_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Number and percentage of entering degree or certificate seeking\nstudents enrolling from fall to spring and fall to fall at an\ninstitution of higher education.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>