<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6304"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6304">
        <num>6304</num>
        <heading>Financing of community colleges</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish a policy of offering acceptance in an appropriate\nprogram of the college to all applicants residing in the sponsorship\narea who graduated from high school within the prior year and to\napplicants who are high school graduates and who were released from\nactive duty with the armed forces of the United States within the prior\nyear;\n  (ii) provide for full implementation of such policy by the fall\nsemester of nineteen hundred seventy or, if the college demonstrates to\nthe state university trustees that full implementation by such time\nwould not be feasible and in the best interests of the college, provide\nfor a timetable to achieve such full implementation within five years\nwhich provides for substantial growth in registration each year;\n  (iii) make provision for and contain adequate assurances of the\nexpenditure of funds by the sponsor or sponsors at a level pursuant to\nstate university regulations, at least that necessary to implement the\nplan;\n  (iv) provide for adequate programs of remediation, instruction and\ncounselling to meet the needs of all students to be served by the\ncollege. The trustees may require periodic reports or certifications\nfrom colleges which have submitted plans which have been approved and\nmay, in appropriate cases, revoke such approval in case a college is in\ndefault of implementing its plan.\n  b.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Operating costs shall not include any payment of debt service\nor rentals or other payments by a local sponsor to the dormitory\nauthority pursuant to any lease, sublease or other agreement entered\ninto between the dormitory authority and a local sponsor. Such operating\ncosts shall be subject to such maximum limitations and joint regulations\nas shall be prescribed by both the city university trustees and the\nstate university trustees with the approval of the director of the\nbudget. Such limitations shall be based upon maximum allowances per\nstudent for each student in attendance in the case of operating costs,\nor in accordance with such other factors as may be deemed appropriate.\nOperating costs shall include courses offered for the purpose of\nproviding occupational training or assistance to business for the\ncreation and retention of job opportunities and for the improvement of\nproductivity, through contracts or arrangements between a community\ncollege and a business, labor organization, or not-for-profit\ncorporations or other nongovernmental organizations, including\nlabor-management committees composed of labor, business and community\nleaders organized to promote labor-management relations, productivity,\nthe quality of working life, industrial development, and retention of\nbusiness in the community.\n  (ii) By December thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-three, the\nstate university trustees shall develop a new formula for the financing\nof the operating costs of community colleges. Such formula may include\nmaximum limitations, regulations, and incentives to achieve compliance\nwith the code of standards and procedures for community colleges.\n  The state university trustees shall present to the governor proposed\nlegislation incorporating such formula into law for consideration during\nthe nineteen hundred seventy-four regular session of the legislature.\nThe state university trustees shall also present a detailed analysis of\nthe fiscal impac...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, for the\ncommunity college fiscal year two thousand thirteen--two thousand\nfourteen and thereafter, each program that confers a credit-bearing\ncertificate, an associate of occupational studies degree, or an\nassociate of applied science degree, shall demonstrate that it is\npreparing students for current and future job opportunities by\npartnering with employers as follows:\n  (A) The program is a partnership between the community college and one\nor more employers to train and employ students in a specific occupation;\n  (B) The program has an advisory committee made up of members of whom\nthe majority are employers in the occupation or sector, or a related\nsector, or is otherwise advised by one or more employers in the\noccupation or sector, that employ or will employ workers in the region\nwhere the community college is located, and such committee serves to\nadvise the community college on the program's curriculum, recruitment,\nplacement and evaluation so that it remains up-to-date with employer\nneeds; or\n  (C) The program is in a high-tech sector and is in demand for current\nor projected job growth, including those sectors identified by the\nregional economic development council, and is advised by current or\npotential future employers in the occupation or sector.\n  (ii) On or before January first, two thousand fourteen for the\ncommunity college fiscal year two thousand thirteen--two thousand\nfourteen, November first, two thousand fourteen for the community\ncollege fiscal year two thousand fourteen--two thousand fifteen and\nNovember first of each community college fiscal year thereafter, the\nstate university trustees and the city university trustees shall each\nsubmit a job linkage report to the director of the budget, the chairs of\nthe senate and assembly higher education committees and the chair of the\nsenate finance committee and the chair of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee, including...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph.\n  b-2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, within\namounts appropriated for incentive funding, the state university of New\nYork and city university of New York shall make awards to community\ncolleges from the next generation NY job linkage program incentive fund\nbased on measures of student success for all students enrolled in\nprograms that confer a credit-bearing certificate, an associate of\noccupational studies degree, or an associate of applied science degree,\nincluding, but not limited to:\n  (A) The number of students who are employed following degree or\ncertificate completion and their wage gains, if any, as determined by\nthe department of labor, which shall be given the greatest weighting\namong all measures of student success;\n  (B) The number of degree completions, certificate completions and\nstudent transfers to other institutions of higher education;\n  (C) The number of degree and certificate completions under clause (B)\nof this paragraph by students considered academically at-risk due to\neconomic disadvantage or other factor of under-representation within the\nfield of study; veterans; and the disabled;\n  (D) The number of students who make adequate progress towards\ncompletion of a degree or certificate, which may include accelerated\ncompletion of a developmental education program;\n  (E) The number of degree completions in innovative programs designed\nto enable students to balance school, work and other personal\nresponsibilities; and\n  (F) The number of students engaged in career and employment\nopportunities including apprenticeships, cooperative education programs\nor other paid work experience that is an integral part of their academic\nprogram.\n  (ii) Awards shall be made on a pro-rata basis in accordance with a\nmethodology and in a form and manner developed by the director of the\nbudget, in consultation with the state university and city university.\n  (iii) On or before December first of each year, or an alternativ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the local sponsor of each community college, except a community\ncollege where the local sponsor has entered into an agreement with the\ndormitory authority to finance and construct a community college\nfacility, an amount equal to the aggregate of all rentals and all\npayments due and payable to the dormitory authority pursuant to any\nlease, sublease, or other agreement entered into between the dormitory\nauthority and such local sponsor, whether or not such local sponsor\nshall be liable therefor, for each twelve-month period beginning on the\nnext succeeding July first, and\n  (ii) to the local sponsor of each community college where the local\nsponsor has entered into an agreement with the dormitory authority to\nfinance and construct a community college facility, an amount equal to\none-half of all rentals and all payments due and payable to the\ndormitory authority pursuant to any lease, sublease, or other agreement\nentered into between the dormitory authority and such local sponsor,\nwhether or not such local sponsor shall be liable therefor, for each\ntwelve-month period beginning on the next succeeding July first,\nprovided, however, if such a local sponsor shall thereafter agree to\nfinance the costs of providing all or part of a community college\nfacility the state shall, instead, annually appropriate and pay to such\nlocal sponsor an amount equal to that portion of all rentals and all\npayments due and payable to the dormitory authority during the\ntwelve-month period beginning on the next succeeding July first pursuant\nto any lease, sublease or other agreement providing for such financing\nwhich portion represents the state's share (one-half) of the cost of\neach facility being financed, whether or not the local sponsor shall be\nliable to pay such rentals and payments, and\n  (iii) to the local sponsor of each community college which has\nfinanced the entire capital cost of constructing a community college\nfacility, an amount equal to one-half ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\na first instance appropriation has been enacted into state law prior to\nthe commencement of construction; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state comptroller has\napproved the interest rate of any and all obligations issued by such\nlocal sponsor after July twenty-fourth, nineteen hundred seventy-six to\nfinance the cost of such facility prior to the issuance of such\nobligations; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all contracts for the construction of such facility\nentered into by such local sponsor after July twenty-fourth, nineteen\nhundred seventy-six have been approved by the director of the budget\nprior to the awarding of such contracts.\n  (iv) notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph to the\ncontrary, if the dormitory authority and the state university of New\nYork shall have entered into an agreement pursuant to subdivision\ntwenty-one of section sixteen hundred seventy-eight of the public\nauthorities law and paragraph x of subdivision two of section three\nhundred fifty-five of this chapter, the amounts otherwise payable to the\nlocal sponsors of the community colleges pursuant to this subparagraph\non account of the state's share of the cost of each facility being\nfinanced shall be payable to the dormitory authority in accordance with\nsubdivision five of section ninety-seven-p of the state finance law.\n  b. For the purposes of this subdivision, all references to the local\nsponsor of a community college shall be deemed, in the case of community\ncollege regions, to refer to those counties, cities or school districts\nwhich have appointed members to a community college regional board of\ntrustees.\n  c. For purposes of this subdivision, the reference to the local\nsponsor of a community college may be deemed, in the case of a community\ncollege region, to alternatively refer to the community college regional\nboard of trustees thereof.\n  9. a. Where construction of a community college facility has commenced\npursuant to the provisions of a lease, sublease or other agreement with\nthe dormitory authority or prior to July twenty-fourth, nineteen hundred\nseventy-six, the local sponsor of such community college may elect to\nfinance the entire capital cost of constructing such facility pursuant\nto the provisions of subdivision ten of this section, provided, however,\nthat the proceeds of obligations issued by such local sponsor to finance\nthe capit...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Credit card" means any credit card, credit plate, charge card,\ncharge plate, courtesy card, debit card, other identification card,\nvalue transfer device as defined by the state comptroller or device\nissued by a person to another person which may be used to obtain a cash\nadvance or a loan or credit, or to purchase or lease property or\nservices on the credit of the person issuing the credit card or a person\nwho has agreed with the issuer to pay obligations arising from the use\nof a credit card issued to another person.\n  (ii) "Card issuer" means an issuer of a credit card, charge card or\nother value transfer device.\n  (iii) "Financing agency" means any agency defined as such in\nsubdivision eighteen of section four hundred one of the personal\nproperty law.\n  (iv) "Person" means an individual, partnership, corporation or any\nother legal or commercial entity.\n  b. The board of trustees of any community college may determine, by\nresolution, that it is in the public interest to authorize such\ncommunity college to enter into agreements with one or more financing\nagencies or card issuers to provide for the acceptance, by such officers\nof the community college as may be designated pursuant to this\nsubdivision, of credit cards as a means of payment of tuition, expenses,\nfees, charges, revenue, financial obligations or other amounts owed by\nstudents to the community college. Any such agreement shall govern the\nterms and conditions upon which a credit card proffered as a means of\npayment of tuition, expenses, fees, charges, revenue, financial\nobligations or other amounts shall be accepted or declined and the\nmanner in and conditions upon which the financing agency or card issuer\nshall pay to such community college the amount of tuition, expenses,\nfees, charges, revenue, financial obligations or other amounts paid by\nmeans of a credit card pursuant to such agreement. Any such agreement\nmay provide for the payment by such community college to such fi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the board of trustees of the community college has entered into a\nwritten agreement with the bank or trust company in which such funds\nhave been deposited, prescribing the manner in which electronic or wire\ntransfer of such funds shall be accomplished, identifying by number and\nname those accounts from which electronic or wire transfers may be made,\nidentifying which officer or officers are authorized to order the\nelectronic or wire transfer of funds from those accounts, and\nimplementing a security procedure as defined in section 4-A-201 of the\nuniform commercial code; and\n  (ii) the bank or trust company processing the transfer shall provide\nto the officer ordering the electronic or wire transfer of funds written\nconfirmation of each such transaction no later than the business day\nfollowing the day on which the funds are transmitted.\n  b. It shall be the duty of the board of trustees of the community\ncollege to adopt a system of internal controls for the documentation and\nreporting of all transfers or disbursements of funds accomplished by\nelectronic or wire transfer.\n  13. a. The board of trustees of any community college may determine,\nby resolution, that it is in the public interest and authorize such\ncommunity college to provide for the acceptance of tuition, expenses,\nfees, charges, revenue, financial obligations or other amounts via a\ncommunity college internet website. However, submission via the internet\nmay not be required as the sole method for the collection of tuition,\nexpenses, fees, charges and other amounts. Such payments shall be\naccepted via the internet in a manner and condition defined by such\ncommunity college. Any method used to receive internet payments shall\ncomply with article one of the state technology law and any rules and\nregulations promulgated and guidelines developed thereunder and, at a\nminimum must:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6304__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>authenticate the identity of the sender; and\n  (ii) ensure the security of the information transmitted.\n  b. Payments received via the internet shall be considered received by\nthe appropriate officer and paid by the payor at the time the internet\ntransaction is completed and sent by the payor.\n  c. The underlying debt, lien, obligation, bill, account or other\namount owed by the student to the community college for which payment by\ninternet is accepted by the community college shall not be expunged,\ncancelled, released, discharged or satisfied, and any receipt or other\nevidence of payment shall be deemed conditional, until the community\ncollege has received final and unconditional payment of the full amount\ndue.\n  d. The board of trustees, in enacting a resolution pursuant to this\nsubdivision, shall designate which of its officers, charged with the\nduty of collecting or receiving moneys on behalf of the community\ncollege, shall be authorized to accept such payments via the internet.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>