<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6305"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6305">
        <num>6305</num>
        <heading>Non-resident and out-of-state students</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6305. Non-resident and out-of-state students. 1. In addition to\nadmitting residents of its own local sponsor or sponsors, each community\ncollege shall, within the quota and under the conditions prescribed by\nthe state university trustees, admit non-resident students and\nout-of-state students.\n  2. Any community college may, with the approval of the state\nuniversity trustees, charge non-resident students sufficient tuition and\nfees to cover an allocable portion of the local sponsor's share of the\noperating costs of such community college in addition to regular tuition\nand fees.  Such community college may elect to charge to and collect\nfrom each county within the state which has issued a certificate or\ncertificates of residence pursuant to subdivision three of this section\non the basis of which such non-resident students are attending such\ncommunity college, an allocable portion of the local sponsor's share of\nthe operating costs of such community college attributable to such\nnon-resident students, computed on a per student basis, together with a\nfurther sum of not to exceed three hundred dollars each year to be\ndetermined and approved by the state university trustees for each such\nnon-resident student on account of the local sponsor's share of the\ncapital costs incurred to provide facilities in which such non-resident\nstudents can be accommodated; or, where such non-resident students come\nfrom communities which have elected to participate in and pay an\nappropriate share of the expenses involved in the local sponsor's\ncommunity college program, such allocable portion of operating expenses\nand such further sum not to exceed three hundred dollars per student for\ncapital costs on account of their residents attending such community\ncollege shall be determined and approved by the state university\ntrustees, and be charged to and collected from such communities.\n  3. The chief fiscal officer of each county, as defined in section 2.00\nof the local finance law, shall, upon application and submission to such\nchief fiscal officer of satisfactory evidence in-person or\nelectronically, issue to any person desiring to enroll in a community\ncollege as a non-resident student, a certificate of residence form\nshowing that said person is a resident of said county. No such chief\nfiscal officer shall require a person desiring to enroll in a community\ncollege as a non-resident student to disclose or furnish his or her\nsocial security number. If the chief fiscal officer of a county refuses\nto issue such a certificate on the ground that the person applying\ntherefor is not a resident of such county, the person applying may\nappeal, in writing, electronically or by mail, to the chancellor of the\nstate university. The chancellor of the state university, or such\nofficers or employees thereof as shall be designated by the chancellor\nin a manner authorized by the state university trustees, shall make a\ndetermination after a hearing, upon ten days' notice to such chief\nfiscal officer of the county, and such determination shall be final and\nbinding on the county. Such person shall, upon registration for each\ncollege year, file with the college such a certificate of residence form\nissued not earlier than two months prior thereto, and such certificate\nof residence form shall be valid for a period of one year from the date\nof issuance. The state university trustees shall be authorized to\npromulgate regulations to effectuate the provisions of this subdivision.\n  4. If, pursuant to subdivision two of this section, a community\ncollege elects to charge to and collect an allocable portion of the\noperating costs and a further sum on account of capital costs of such\ncollege from each county which has issued a certificate form or\ncertificates of residence forms pursuant to subdivision three of this\nsection, on the basis of which non-resident students are attending such\ncommunity college, the president of such community college shall, within\nforty-five days after the commencement of each college term or program,\nsubmit to the chief fiscal officer of each county a list of non-resident\nstudents attending such college on the basis of such certificates of\nresidence form and a voucher for the amount payable by each county for\nthese students. Such list and voucher shall be determined on the basis\nof non-resident students enrolled in the program as of the end (or last\nday) of the third week of the commencement for a program scheduled for\none semester, the end of the second for a program scheduled for an\nacademic quarter and the end of the first week for any program scheduled\nto be completed in thirty days or less. The chancellor of the state\nuniversity, or such officers or employees thereof as shall be designated\nby the chancellor in the manner authorized by the state university\ntrustees, shall notify the chief fiscal officers of each county of the\napproved annual operating and capital charge-back rate for each\ncommunity college. The amount billed to the chief fiscal officer of each\ncounty by the president of such community college as a charge for the\nallocable portion of the operating costs and a further sum on account of\ncapital costs of such college for non-resident students shall be paid to\nthe chief fiscal officer of such college by the billed county no later\nthan sixty days after the county receives said billing.\n  5. Amounts payable to such colleges by a county pursuant to this\nsection shall be a general county charge; provided, however, that with\nrespect to the amounts allocable to each community college a county may\ncharge back such amounts in whole or in part to the cities and towns in\nthe county in proportion to the number of students who, on the basis of\ncertificates of residence issued by such county, were attending each\nsuch college as non-residents of the local sponsors thereof during the\nterms for which the county has been charged, and who were residents of\neach such city or town at the beginning of such terms.\n  7. In the case of counties comprising the city of New York, references\nin this section to a county shall mean the city of New York and\nreferences in this section to the chief fiscal officer of a county shall\nmean the comptroller of the city of New York.\n  8. Part-time and out-of-state students shall be charged such tuition\nand fees as may be approved by the state university trustees. Any\nstudent attending a community college who is a member or the spouse or\nthe dependent of a member of the armed forces of the United States on\nfull-time active duty and stationed in this state, whether or not a\nresident of this state, shall be charged the tuition rate for residents\nas approved by the state university trustees. Any student attending a\ncommunity college in accordance with the federal GI bills and in\ncompliance with all applicable eligibility requirements thereof, whether\nor not a resident of this state, shall be charged the tuition rate for\nresidents as approved by the state university trustees. Any student\nattending a community college who is the spouse or the dependent of a\nmember of the armed forces of the United States on full-time active duty\nand not stationed in this state immediately following being stationed\ntherein, whether or not a resident of this state, shall be charged the\ntuition rate for residents as approved by the state university trustees.\n  8-a. The payment of tuition and other fees and charges of a student\nwho is attending a community college and who is not a legal resident of\nNew York state but is a United States citizen, a permanent lawful\nresident, an individual who is granted U or T non-immigrant status\npursuant to the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of\n2000, a person granted temporary protected status pursuant to the\nFederal Immigration Act of 1990, an individual of a class of refugees\nparoled by the attorney general of the United States under his or her\nparole authority pertaining to the admission of noncitizens to the\nUnited States, or an applicant without lawful immigration status may be\nreduced by state-aided programs, scholarships and other financial\nassistance awarded under the provisions of articles thirteen,\nthirteen-A, fourteen and fourteen-A of this chapter, provided that the\nstudent meets the requirements set forth in subparagraph (ii) of\nparagraph a or subparagraph (ii) of paragraph b of subdivision five of\nsection six hundred sixty-one of this chapter, as applicable.\n  9. A community college may expend moneys collected as capital charges\nreceived from counties of nonresident students for up to one-half the\npurchase price of equipment. A community college may include up to\none-half the purchase price of equipment in calculating capital charges\ncollected from counties of nonresident students. Such expenditures shall\nbe made pursuant to guidelines promulgated in rules and regulations of\nthe board of trustees of the state university. In no event shall such\nexpenditures qualify for state aid as capital costs.\n  10. On or before March thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-five and\nevery year thereafter, the state shall reimburse each county which has\nissued a certificate of residence for any non-resident student in\nattendance at the fashion institute of technology during the nineteen\nhundred ninety-three--ninety-four academic year and every year\nthereafter in an amount equal to fifty percent of the actual amount paid\nby such county on behalf of such students and on or before June first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-five and every year thereafter, the state shall\nreimburse each county for the remaining fifty percent of the actual\namount paid by each such county on behalf of such students.\n  12. Such calculated chargeback rates shall be set on an academic year\nbasis and shall not vary by semester within each academic year, and no\nretroactive charge shall</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>