<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6306"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6306">
        <num>6306</num>
        <heading>Administration of community colleges--boards of trustees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6306__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions one and three\nof this section, effective July first, two thousand eight, the fashion\ninstitute of technology shall be administered by a board of trustees of\ntwelve members. Six members shall be appointed by the local sponsor, one\nof whom may be a member of such sponsor; five members shall be appointed\nby the governor from among persons who reside in the city of New York;\nand one member shall be elected by and from among the students of the\nfashion institute of technology.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6306__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of subdivisions one and three of this section\nnotwithstanding, effective July first, two thousand nine, the fashion\ninstitute of technology shall be administered by a board of trustees of\nfourteen members. Seven members shall be appointed by the local sponsor,\none of whom may be a member of such sponsor; six members shall be\nappointed by the governor from among persons who reside in the city of\nNew York; and one member shall be elected by and from among the students\nof the fashion institute of technology.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6306__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of subdivisions one and three of this section\nnotwithstanding, effective July first, two thousand ten, the fashion\ninstitute of technology shall be administered by a board of trustees of\nsixteen members. Eight members shall be appointed by the local sponsor,\none of whom may be a member of such sponsor; seven members shall be\nappointed by the governor from among persons who reside in the city of\nNew York; and one member shall be elected by and from among the students\nof the fashion institute of technology.\n  * 3-b. The board of trustees of each community college, and those\nprovided for in the city of New York by subdivision three of this\nsection, shall adopt a policy for admission of students who have\ncompleted an online high school program located within the United States\nconsistent with the provisions of subparagraph eleven of paragraph h of\nsubdivision two of section three hundred fifty-five of this chapter.\n  * NB Effective March 5, 2026\n  4. The board of trustees of each community college may acquire by\ndeed, gift, devise, bequest or lease, real or personal property suitable\nfor carrying out the program and purposes of the college, and pursuant\nto regulations prescribed by the state university trustees may apply any\nincome that may be derived therefrom to the maintenance thereof; but no\nlands, grounds, buildings, facilities or equipment shall be purchased or\nleased unless an appropriation has been made, therefor, or unless\notherwise authorized by law. Title to personal property so acquired\nshall vest in such board of trustees in its own name and such property\nshall be held and used by such board for college purposes. Title to real\nproperty so acquired shall vest in and be held by the local sponsor in\ntrust for the uses and purposes of the community college. Where a\ncommunity college region is the local sponsor of a community college,\ntitle to real and personal property shall vest in the community college\nregional board...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6306__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>alter\nany existing collective bargaining agreement; (ii) diminish the rights\nof employees pursuant to an existing collective bargaining agreement;\n(iii) affect existing law with respect to an application to the public\nemployment relations board seeking designation by the board that certain\npersons are managerial or confidential; or (iv) alter or restrict the\npower of a county or community college sponsor or employee organization\nto negotiate with respect to an alternate method of appointment or\npromotion of security officers.\n  5-b. Subject to the approval of the board of regents, the board of\ntrustees shall have the authority to grant honorary associate degrees.\n  6. The board of trustees shall have such other powers and perform such\nother duties as may be provided by law or prescribed by the state\nuniversity trustees.\n  7. Subject to the approval of the local sponsor acting through its\nlocal legislative body or board, or other appropriate governing agency,\nand pursuant to such regulations and limitations as may be established\nand prescribed by the state university trustees, the board of trustees\nof each community college may enter into any contract or agreement\ndeemed necessary or appropriate for the effective operation of the\ncollege,</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6306__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>including contracts or agreements entered into with the\nfederal government to enable participation in federal student loan\nprograms, including any and all instruments required thereunder;\nprovided, however, that the sponsor shall not be liable for any portion\nof any defaults which it has agreed to assume pursuant to any such\nagreement in an amount in excess of money appropriated or otherwise\nlawfully available therefor at the time the liability for payment\narises, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6306__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>including contracts with non-profit corporations\norganized by officers, employees, alumni or students of the college for\nthe furtherance of its objects and purposes. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of any other law, general, special or local, such contracts\nentered into with such non-profit corporation shall not be subject to\nany requirement that contracts be let to the lowest responsible bidder\nafter advertisement for bids. Nothing contained in this subdivision\nshall be deemed to diminish or impair any powers or authority otherwise\nvested in the board of trustees of any community college. The provisions\nof this subdivision shall not apply to community college regional boards\nof trustees.\n  8. Subject to the approval of the local sponsor acting through its\nlocal legislative body or board, or other appropriate governing agency,\nand pursuant to such regulations and limitations as may be established\nand prescribed by the state university trustees with the approval of the\ndir...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6306__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inform each victim of a sexual offense of their\noptions to notify proper law enforcement authorities, including\non-campus and local police;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6306__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inform the victim of a sexual offense of\nthe right to report or not to report such offense to the local law\nenforcement agencies; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6306__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>offer the option to be assisted by campus\nauthorities in notifying such authorities, if the victim of sexual\nassault so chooses, all in compliance with applicable federal law,\nincluding, but not limited to, the federal Campus Sexual Assault\nVictims' Bill of Rights under Title 20 U.S. Code Section 1092</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6306__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n  b. As used in this subdivision, the following terms shall have the\nfollowing meanings:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6306__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Local law enforcement agencies" means any agency or agencies\nemploying peace officers or police officers for the enforcement of the\nlaws of the state, and which has or have jurisdiction under provisions\nof the criminal procedure law over offenses occurring at or on the\ngrounds of any institution subject to the provisions of this\nsubdivision.\n  (ii) "Missing student" means any student of an institution subject to\nthe provisions of this subdivision, who resides in a facility owned or\noperated by such institution and who is reported to such institution as\nmissing from his or her residence.\n  (iii) "Violent felony offense" means a violent felony offense as\ndefined in subdivision one of section 70.02 of the penal law.\n  9. In the case of colleges sponsored by community college regions,\nreferences in subdivisions two, four, five, six and eight-a of this\nsection to the board of trustees of a community college shall mean the\ncommunity college regional board of trustees.\n  10. The boards of trustees of the state university of New York\ncommunity colleges shall consult with boards of cooperative educational\nservices (BOCES) to identify new or existing programs offered to\nstudents that would allow a student to pursue an associate of\noccupational studies (AOS) degree from a community college upon high\nschool graduation. Once identified, BOCES in collaboration with the\ncommunity college boards of trustees shall make such path, identified\nprograms, and AOS degree options known to ensure that students are aware\nthat such options exist.  Such notification shall begin in the eighth\ngrade, and include the provision of materials on AOS degree options to\nschool counselors in each school district in such region. Provided\nhowever, that such boards and BOCES shall not take any action to direct\nor suggest that a student should pursue a particular degree or pathway.\n  11. The board of trustees of each community college shall adopt\nwritten policies requiring tha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6306__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section one hundred forty-five of\nthe public buildings law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>