<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6310"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6310"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6310"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6310/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6310/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6310/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6310/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6310">
        <num>6310</num>
        <heading>Community college regions - administration and finance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two individuals\nshall be appointed for terms of two and four years respectively;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two\nindividuals for terms of six years and two individuals for terms of\neight years. Appointments by local authorities shall be as follows:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthree individuals for terms of one, three and five years, respectively;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two individuals for terms of seven years, and two individuals for\nterms of nine years. Vacancies shall be filled for unexpired terms in\nthe same manner as original selections by the authority responsible for\nthe original selection. The board shall select its own chairman from\namong its voting membership. Trustees shall receive no compensation for\ntheir services but shall be reimbursed for their expenses actually and\nnecessarily incurred by them in the performance of their duties under\nthis article. Members initially appointed or elected under this\nsubdivision to any community college regional board of trustees\nhereafter established shall take office immediately upon their selection\nand qualification, but for purposes of determining the expiration of\ntheir respective terms and the commencement of the terms of their\nsuccessors, the term of office of each such initial member shall be\ndeemed to have commenced on the first day of July of the year in which\nsuch college was established. The terms of office of all members of\ncommunity college regional boards of trustees heretofore established,\nappointed or elected as provided in this subdivision, shall terminate on\nthe thirtieth day of June of the calendar year within which such terms\nexpire under the provisions of this subdivision as hereby amended. For\nthe purpose of determining such year all initial terms of office of\nappointed members of the community college regional board of trustees\nheretofore established shall be deemed to have commenced on the first\nday of July of the year in which such community college regions were\nestablished and the terms of their successors for full terms, if any,\nshall be deemed to have commenced upon the expiration of the number of\nyears from such date for which such initial appointments were made.\n  The one member elected by and from among the students of the college\nmay be removed by such students in accordance with rules and regulations\npromulgated by the respe...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>without any charge back to any city or town within such county; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>with a charge back of all or any portion of such operating costs\nto the cities (including the city of Jamestown) and towns in such\ncounty, in proportion to the number of students attending such community\ncollege each term who were residents of each such city or town at the\nbeginning of such term.\n  2. Pursuant to such regulations and limitations as may be established\nand prescribed by the state university trustees, the community college\nregional board of trustees may enter into any contract or agreement\ndeemed necessary or appropriate for the effective operation of the\ncollege, including:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contracts or agreements entered into with the\nfederal government to enable participation in federal student loan\nprograms, including any and all instruments required thereunder; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ncontracts with non-profit corporations organized by officers, employees,\nalumni or students of the college for the furtherance of its objects and\npurposes. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, general,\nspecial or local, such contracts entered into with such non-profit\ncorporation shall not be subject to any requirement that contracts be\nlet to the lowest responsible bidder after advertisement for bids.\nNothing contained in this subdivision shall be deemed to diminish or\nimpair any powers or authority otherwise vested in the community college\nregional board of trustees.\n  3. Pursuant to such regulations and limitations as may be established\nand prescribed by the state university trustees with the approval of the\ndirector of the budget, the community college regional board of trustees\nmay participate in cooperative educational programs, services and\narrangements with colleges, universities, school districts, boards of\ncooperative educational services, libraries, museums and join any\ncooperative association of such educational institutions formed as a\ncorporation pursuant to section two hundred sixteen of this chapter.\n  4. The community college regional board of trustees is hereby created\na body corporate. All property which is now vested in, or shall\nhereafter be conveyed or transferred to the community college regional\nboard of trustees, shall be held by them as a corporation.\n  4-a.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A community college regional board of trustees shall have the\nauthority to appoint security officers for the community college and, in\nits discretion, to designate or to revoke the designation of one or more\nthan one security officer as a peace officer. A security officer so\ndesignated shall have the powers of a peace officer as set forth in\nsection 2.20 of the criminal procedure law. A security officer\ndesignated as a peace officer must have satisfactorily completed or\ncomplete, within one year of the date of such designation, a course of\nlaw enforcement training prescribed by the municipal police training\ncouncil in consultation with the state university board of trustees. A\npeace officer so designated may possess and carry a firearm as a part of\non duty employment only if authorized to do so by the president of the\ncommunity college. The geographical area of employment of a peace\nofficer so designated is the campus and other property of the community\ncollege at which the peace officer serves, including that portion of a\npublic highway which crosses or abuts such property, and residential or\nother facilities owned, operated, or maintained by a not-for-profit\nentity associated with the community college for which such college\nprovides security.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The appointment of security officers at a community college shall\nbe governed by and conform with civil service laws, rules and\nregulations, if applicable to the community college and its employees.\nThe designation of a security officer as a peace officer shall be based\non qualifications established by the community college board of\ntrustees, and in accordance with seniority. For purposes of this\nsubdivision, "seniority" means total employment service with the\ncommunity college making such designation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A security officer who has been designated a peace officer may\nhave such designation suspended or removed pursuant to procedures\nestablished by the community college or in compliance with any local\ncollective bargaining agreement, if applicable to the community college\nand its employees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The designation of peace officers pursuant to this subdivision\nshall not be deemed to supersede in any way the authority of other peace\nofficers and police officers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>alter\nany existing collective bargaining agreement; (ii) diminish the rights\nof employees pursuant to an existing collective bargaining agreement;\n(iii) affect existing law with respect to an application to the public\nemployment relations board seeking designation by the board that certain\npersons are managerial or confidential; or (iv) alter or restrict the\npower of a county or community college sponsor or employee organization\nto negotiate with respect to an alternate method of appointment or\npromotion of security officers.\n  5. Two or more eligible counties appointing members to a community\ncollege regional board of trustees shall divide the local share of the\ncapital costs of a community college sponsored by such community college\nregion according to the respective equalized assessed valuations of such\ncounties or such other factors as may be prescribed by the state\nuniversity trustees. The local share of the operating expenses of a\ncommunity college sponsored by a community college region shall be\napportioned among those counties appointing members to the community\ncollege regional board of trustees on the basis of operating shares.\nSuch operating shares shall be allocated in proportion to the number of\nstudents attending the community college who are residents of the\nrespective counties participating on the community college regional\nboard, calculated on the basis of full-time equivalent students, in the\nsame manner as the allocable portion of the local sponsor's share of\noperating costs pursuant to section sixty-three hundred five of this\nchapter, and such other factors as may be prescribed by the state\nuniversity trustees. Any community college sponsored by a community\ncollege region may, under the provisions of section six thousand three\nhundred five of this chapter, elect to charge an allocable portion of\nthe operating costs incurred by the regional sponsor, and a further sum\non account of the regional sponsor's share of capita...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Credit card" means any credit card, credit plate, charge card,\ncharge plate, courtesy card, debit card, other identification card,\nvalue transfer device as defined by the state comptroller or device\nissued by a person to another person which may be used to obtain a cash\nadvance or a loan or credit, or to purchase or lease property or\nservices on the credit of the person issuing the credit card or a person\nwho has agreed with the issuer to pay obligations arising from the use\nof a credit card issued to another person.\n  (ii) "Card issuer" means an issuer of a credit card, charge card or\nother value transfer device.\n  (iii) "Financing agency" means any agency defined as such in\nsubdivision eighteen of section four hundred one of the personal\nproperty law.\n  (iv) "Person" means an individual, partnership, corporation or any\nother legal or commercial entity.\n  b. The community college regional board of trustees of any community\ncollege may determine, by resolution, that it is in the public interest\nto authorize such community college to enter into agreements with one or\nmore financing agencies or card issuers to provide for the acceptance,\nby such officers of the community college as may be designated pursuant\nto this subdivision, of credit cards as a means of payment of tuition,\nexpenses, fees, charges, revenue, financial obligations or other amounts\nowed by students to the community college. Any such agreement shall\ngovern the terms and conditions upon which a credit card proffered as a\nmeans of payment of tuition, expenses, fees, charges, revenue, financial\nobligations or other amounts shall be accepted or declined and the\nmanner in and conditions upon which the financing agency or card issuer\nshall pay to such community college the amount of tuition, expenses,\nfees, charges, revenue, financial obligations or other amounts paid by\nmeans of a credit card pursuant to such agreement. Any such agreement\nmay provide for the payment by such c...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the community college regional board of trustees of the community\ncollege has entered into a written agreement with the bank or trust\ncompany in which such funds have been deposited, prescribing the manner\nin which electronic or wire transfer of such funds shall be\naccomplished, identifying by number and name those accounts from which\nelectronic or wire transfers may be made, identifying which officer or\nofficers are authorized to order the electronic or wire transfer of\nfunds from those accounts, and implementing a security procedure as\ndefined in section 4-A-201 of the uniform commercial code; and\n  (ii) the bank or trust company processing the transfer shall provide\nto the officer ordering the electronic or wire transfer of funds written\nconfirmation of each such transaction no later than the business day\nfollowing the day on which the funds are transmitted.\n  b. It shall be the duty of the community college regional board of\ntrustees of the community college to adopt a system of internal controls\nfor the documentation and reporting of all transfers or disbursements of\nfunds accomplished by electronic or wire transfer.\n  16. a. The community college regional board of trustees of any\ncommunity college, may determine, by resolution, that it is in the\npublic interest and authorize such community college to provide for the\nacceptance of tuition, expenses, fees, charges, revenue, financial\nobligations or other amounts via a community college internet website.\nHowever, submission via the internet may not be required as the sole\nmethod for the collection of tuition, expenses, fees, charges and other\namounts.  Such payments shall be accepted via the internet in a manner\nand condition defined by such community college. Any method used to\nreceive internet payments shall comply with article one of the state\ntechnology law and any rules and regulations promulgated and guidelines\ndeveloped thereunder and, at a minimum must:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6310__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>authenticate the identity of the sender; and\n  (ii) ensure the security of the information transmitted.\n  b. Payments received via the internet shall be considered received by\nthe appropriate officer and paid by the payor at the time the internet\ntransaction is completed and sent by the payor.\n  c. The underlying debt, lien, obligation, bill, account or other\namount owed by the student to the community college for which payment by\ninternet is accepted by the community college shall not be expunged,\ncancelled, released, discharged or satisfied, and any receipt or other\nevidence of payment shall be deemed conditional, until the community\ncollege has received final and unconditional payment of the full amount\ndue.\n  d. The community college regional board of trustees, in enacting a\nresolution pursuant to this subdivision, shall designate which of its\nofficers, charged with the duty of collecting or receiving moneys on\nbehalf of the community college, shall be authorized to accept such\npayments via the internet.\n  17. Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter to the contrary, a\ncommunity college regional board of trustees of a community college\nregion shall be the local sponsor of such community college for the\npurposes of entering into agreements with the dormitory authority of the\nstate of New York on behalf of the community college pursuant to\nsubdivisions nine, ten, eleven, twelve, thirteen, fourteen and sixteen\nof section sixteen hundred eighty of the public authorities law and\nshall have full authority to perform, on behalf of such community\ncollege, all obligations of the college under its agreements with the\ndormitory authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>