<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6402"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6402"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6402"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6402">
        <num>6402</num>
        <heading>Enrollment grants to schools of medicine and dentistry</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6402__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Two thousand one hundred fifty dollars shall be apportioned for\neach full-time student enrolled.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6402__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An additional three thousand five hundred dollars shall be\napportioned for each full-time upper division student enrolled who is a\nresident of the state and who:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6402__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>participates in the coordinated transfer program of the\nassociation of American medical colleges; or\n  (ii) participates in the fifth pathway program; or\n  (iii) participated in and successfully completed in good standing the\nbiomedical education program of the city college of the city university\nof New York.\n  2. The commissioner shall apportion each year to each non-public\ninstitution of higher education offering an approved program in\ndentistry the sum of fifty-eight hundred dollars for each full-time\nstudent enrolled, except that aid distributed under this program shall\nnot exceed a sum based upon a total enrollment of eight hundred\nthirty-five students at New York University and two hundred forty\nstudents at Columbia University.\n  3. Receipt of aid for eligible students pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6402__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of this section shall preclude an institution from\nreceiving state aid for the same students under the provisions of\nsection sixty-four hundred one of this article.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6402__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To be eligible for assistance under this section an institution\nmust meet such standards of educational quality applicable to comparable\npublic institutions of higher education, as may be from time to time\nestablished by the regents.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6402__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition, to be eligible for assistance under subdivision two\nof this section an institution must annually submit to the commissioner\na complete and detailed report as to each major item of educational and\nother revenue and expenditure contained in the budget for such approved\nprogram of dentistry, for both the preceding and the current academic\nyears for which aid pursuant to this section has or will be received.\nSuch report shall also include enrollment and faculty data, and shall be\nin such form as the commissioner, with the approval of the director of\nthe budget, may prescribe.\n  The commissioner, upon review of the data contained in such report,\nshall be authorized to require such institutions to file an application\nwith the appropriate agency of the federal government for a Financial\nDistress Grant pursuant to Title VIII of the Health Professions\nEducational Assistance Act of 1976, as a condition of further receipt of\nassistance under subdivision two of this section.\n  5. The commissioner of education may promulgate rules and regulations\nto accomplish the purposes of this section.\n  6. Funds appropriated for the purposes of this section shall be paid\nin accordance with a payment schedule to be established by the\ncommissioner and approved by the director of the budget.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>