<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-10-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6436"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6436">
        <num>6436</num>
        <heading>Bias related and hate crime prevention information</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6436. Bias related and hate crime prevention information. Each\ncollege shall inform incoming students about bias related and hate crime\nprevention measures through programs which may include workshops,\nseminars, discussion groups, and film presentations, in order to\ndisseminate information about bias related and hate crimes, promote\ndiscussion, encourage reporting of incidents of bias related and hate\ncrimes, and facilitate prevention of such incidents. Such information\nshall include, but not be limited to:\n  1. the applicable laws, ordinances, and regulations on bias related\ncrime, including the provisions and coverage of the hate crimes act of\n2000 codified in article four hundred eighty-five of the penal law;\n  2. the penalties for commission of bias related and hate crimes;\n  3. the procedures in effect at the college for dealing with bias\nrelated and hate crimes;\n  4. the availability of counseling and other support services for the\nvictims of bias related and hate crimes;\n  5. the nature of and common circumstances relating to bias related and\nhate crimes on college campuses; and\n  6. the methods the college employs to advise and to update students\nabout security procedures.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>