<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6438-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6438-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6438-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6438-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6438-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6438-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6438-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6438_A">
        <num>6438-A</num>
        <heading>Opioid overdose prevention in college housing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6438-a. Opioid overdose prevention in college housing. 1. Every\ncampus of the state university of New York and every campus of the city\nuniversity of New York shall provide training in the administration of\nopioid antagonists pursuant to a program approved under section\nthirty-three hundred nine of the public health law to every resident\nassistant employed by such campus. Such campuses shall provide and\nmaintain onsite in each college-owned or college-operated housing opioid\nantagonists, as defined in section thirty-three hundred nine of the\npublic health law, in quantities and types deemed by the commissioner of\nhealth. Such opioid antagonists shall be accessible by every resident\nassistant for use during emergencies to any student, staff or other\nindividual on college-owned or college-operated housing premises\nsuspected of having an opioid overdose whether or not there is a\nprevious history of opioid abuse.\n  2. Each campus of the state university of New York and every campus of\nthe city university of New York may designate additional employees who\nvolunteer to administer opioid antagonists in the event a resident\nassistant is not physically present at a suspected overdose incident,\nprovided that such employee is trained in the administration of opioid\nantagonists by a program approved under section thirty-three hundred\nnine of the public health law.\n  3. Any person or entity acting reasonably and in good faith in\ncompliance with this section shall not be subject to criminal, civil or\nadministrative liability solely by reason of such action.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>