<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6444"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6444"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6444"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6444/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6444/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6444/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6444/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6444">
        <num>6444</num>
        <heading>Response to reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6444__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>notice\nto a respondent describing the date, time, location and factual\nallegations concerning the violation, a reference to the specific code\nof conduct provisions alleged to have been violated, and possible\nsanctions; (ii) an opportunity to offer evidence during an\ninvestigation, and to present evidence and testimony at a hearing, where\nappropriate, and have access to a full and fair record of any such\nhearing, which shall be preserved and maintained for at least five years\nfrom such a hearing and may include a transcript, recording or other\nappropriate record; and (iii) access to at least one level of appeal of\na determination before a panel, which may include one or more students,\nthat is fair and impartial and does not include individuals with a\nconflict of interest. In order to effectuate an appeal, a respondent and\nreporting individual in such cases shall receive written notice of the\nfindings of fact, the decision and the sanction, if any, as well as the\nrationale for the decision and sanction. In such cases, any rights\nprovided to a reporting individual must be similarly provided to a\nrespondent and any rights provided to a respondent must be similarly\nprovided to a reporting individual.\n  c. Throughout proceedings involving such an accusation of sexual\nassault, domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual\nactivity that may otherwise violate the institution's code of conduct,\nthe right:\n  i. For the respondent, accused, and reporting individual to be\naccompanied by an advisor of choice who may assist and advise a\nreporting individual, accused, or respondent throughout the judicial or\nconduct process including during all meetings and hearings related to\nsuch process. Rules for participation of such advisor shall be\nestablished in the code of conduct.\n  ii. To a prompt response to any complaint and to have the complaint\ninvestigated and adjudicated in an impartial, timely, and thorough\nmanner by individuals who receive...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6444__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6444__subsec_f__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(F)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6444__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>(I)-(VIII), institutions shall make a notation on the\ntranscript of students found responsible after a conduct process that\nthey were "suspended after a finding of responsibility for a code of\nconduct violation" or "expelled after a finding of responsibility for a\ncode of conduct violation." For the respondent who withdraws from the\ninstitution while such conduct charges are pending, and declines to\ncomplete the disciplinary process, institutions shall make a notation on\nthe transcript of such students that they "withdrew with conduct charges\npending." Each institution shall publish a policy on transcript\nnotations and appeals seeking removal of a transcript notation for a\nsuspension, provided that such notation shall not be removed prior to\none year after conclusion of the suspension, while notations for\nexpulsion shall not be removed. If a finding of responsibility is\nvacated for any reason, any such transcript notation shall be removed.\n  7. Institutions that lack appropriate on-campus resources or services\nshall, to the extent practicable, enter into memoranda of understanding,\nagreements or collaborative partnerships with existing community-based\norganizations, including rape-crisis centers and domestic violence\nshelters and assistance organizations, to refer students for assistance\nor make services available to students, including counseling, health,\nmental health, victim advocacy, and legal assistance, which may also\ninclude resources and services for the respondent.\n  8. Institutions shall, to the extent practicable, ensure that students\nhave access to a sexual assault forensic examination by employing the\nuse of a sexual assault nurse examiner in their campus health center or\nentering into memoranda of understanding or agreements with at least one\nlocal health care facility to provide such a service.\n  9. Nothing in this article shall be deemed to diminish the rights of\nany member of the institution's community under any applicab...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>