<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6449"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6449"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6449"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6449/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6449/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6449/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6449/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6449">
        <num>6449</num>
        <heading>Reporting aggregate data to the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6449. Reporting aggregate data to the department. 1. Institutions\nshall annually report to the department the following information about\nreports of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking and sexual\nassault:\n  a. The number of such incidents that were reported to the Title IX\nCoordinator.\n  b. Of those incidents in paragraph a of this subdivision, the number\nof reporting individuals who sought the institution's judicial or\nconduct process.\n  c. Of those reporting individuals in paragraph b of this subdivision,\nthe number of cases processed through the institution's judicial or\nconduct process.\n  d. Of those cases in paragraph c of this subdivision, the number of\nrespondents who were found responsible through the institution's\njudicial or conduct process.\n  e. Of those cases in paragraph c of this subdivision, the number of\nrespondents who were found not responsible through the institution's\njudicial or conduct process.\n  f. A description of the final sanctions imposed by the institution for\neach incident for which a respondent was found responsible, as provided\nin paragraph d of this subdivision, through the institution's judicial\nor conduct process.\n  g. The number of cases in the institution's judicial or conduct\nprocess that were closed prior to a final determination after the\nrespondent withdrew from the institution and declined to complete the\ndisciplinary process.\n  h. The number of cases in the institution's judicial or conduct\nprocess that were closed because the complaint was withdrawn by the\nreporting individual prior to a final determination.\n  2. The department shall create a reporting mechanism for institutions\nto efficiently and uniformly provide the information outlined in\nsubdivision one of this section.\n  3. The department shall not release the information, as provided for\nin this section, if it would compromise the confidentiality of reporting\nindividuals or any other party in the best judgment of the department.\n  4. Within one year of the effective date of this article, the\ndepartment shall issue regulations in consultation with representatives\nfrom the state university of New York, city university of New York, and\nprivate and independent colleges and universities, and within two years\nof the effective date of this article the department shall issue a\nreport to the governor, the temporary president of the senate, the\nspeaker of the assembly and the chairs of the higher education\ncommittees in each house regarding the data collected pursuant to this\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>