<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6453"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6453"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6453"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6453">
        <num>6453</num>
        <heading>Special nursing education program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 6453. Special nursing education program.  To grant greater\nopportunity in nursing education, the commissioner may:\n  1. Enter into contracts with any institution of higher education\nincorporated in this state, voluntary non-profit hospitals incorporated\nwithin this state or public hospitals located within this state for:\n  (1) A contract for conducting courses approved by the department to\nassist foreign trained nurses to qualify for a license as a registered\nprofessional nurse in this state.\n  (2) A contract for conducting refresher courses for residents of this\nstate who have been licensed as registered professional nurses but who\nare not actively engaged in nursing.\n  2. Enter into a contract to expand the enrollment of any institution\nof higher education incorporated within this state or any voluntary\nnon-profit hospital or municipal or county hospital incorporated within\nthis state providing either a regents' approved curriculum leading to a\nbaccalaureate degree in professional nursing or a regents' registered\nprogram in professional nursing, by paying an agreed sum to the\ninstitution for each additional student enrolled in each year of\ninstruction above the average enrollment in such year of instruction for\nthe last five years prior to the year for which the payment is made. The\nsum shall not be paid for more than ten additional students per year.\n  3. Promulgate regulations necessary for the implementation of these\nprograms.\n  * NB Section set out as 6443. Should read 6453\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>