<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6455"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6455"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6455"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6455/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6455/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6455/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6455/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6455">
        <num>6455</num>
        <heading>Collegiate science and technology entry program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6455__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6455__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Undergraduate science and\ntechnology entry program moneys may be used for tutoring, counseling,\nremedial and special summer courses, supplemental financial assistance,\nprogram administration, and other activities which the commissioner may\ndeem appropriate. To be eligible for undergraduate collegiate science\nand technology entry program support, a student must be a resident of\nNew York, or meet the requirements of subparagraph (ii) of this\nparagraph, and must be either economically disadvantaged or from a\nminority group historically under represented in the scientific,\ntechnical, health and health-related professions, and must demonstrate\ninterest in and a potential for a professional career if provided\nspecial services. Eligible students must be in good academic standing,\nenrolled full time in an approved, undergraduate level program of study,\nas defined by the regents.\n  (ii) An applicant who is not a legal resident of New York state, but\nwho is a United States citizen, a permanent lawful resident, an\nindividual who is granted U or T non-immigrant status pursuant to the\nVictims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000, a person\ngranted temporary protected status pursuant to the Federal Immigration\nAct of 1990, an individual of a class of refugees paroled by the\nattorney general of the United States under his or her parole authority\npertaining to the admission of noncitizens to the United States, or an\napplicant without lawful immigration status, shall be eligible for an\naward at the undergraduate level of study provided that the student:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6455__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>attended a registered New York state high school for two or more\nyears, graduated from a registered New York state high school and\napplied for attendance at the institution of higher education for the\nundergraduate study for which an award is sought within five years of\nreceiving a New York state high school diploma; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6455__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>attended an approved New York state program for a state high\nschool equivalency diploma, received a state high school equivalency\ndiploma and applied for attendance at the institution of higher\neducation for the undergraduate study for which an award is sought\nwithin five years of receiving a state high school equivalency diploma;\nor\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6455__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is otherwise eligible for the payment of tuition and fees at a\nrate no greater than that imposed for resident students of the state\nuniversity of New York, the city university of New York or community\ncolleges as prescribed in subparagraph eight of paragraph h of\nsubdivision two of section three hundred fifty-five or paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6455__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision seven of section sixty-two hundred six of this chapter.\n  Provided, further, that a student without lawful immigration status\nshall also be required to file an affidavit with such institution of\nhigher education stating that the student has filed an application to\nlegalize his or her immigration status, or will file such an application\nas soon as he or she is eligible to do so.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6455__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Applications for funding shall be submitted by eligible\ninstitutions to the department in accordance with requirements\nestablished by the commissioner. Priority consideration shall be given\nto institutions which coordinate their efforts to increase minority\naccess with similar activities for programs at the secondary level in\naccordance with this section. Grants shall be awarded based on criteria\nestablished by the commissioner.\n  3. Graduate programs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6455__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6455__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Graduate science and technology entry\nprogram moneys may be used for recruitment, academic enrichment, career\nplanning, supplemental financial assistance, review for licensing\nexaminations, program administration, and other activities which the\ncommissioner may deem appropriate. To be eligible for graduate\ncollegiate science and technology entry program support, a student must\nbe a resident of New York, or meet the requirements of subparagraph (ii)\nof this paragraph, and must be either economically disadvantaged or from\na minority group historically underrepresented in the scientific,\ntechnical and health-related professions. Eligible students must be in\ngood academic standing, enrolled full time in an approved graduate level\nprogram, as defined by the regents.\n  (ii) An applicant who is not a legal resident of New York state, but\neither is a United States citizen, a permanent lawful resident, an\nindividual who is granted U or T non-immigrant status pursuant to the\nVictims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000, a person\ngranted temporary protected status pursuant to the Federal Immigration\nAct of 1990, an individual of a class of refugees paroled by the\nattorney general of the United States under his or her parole authority\npertaining to the admission of noncitizens to the United States, or an\napplicant without lawful immigration status shall be eligible for an\naward at the graduate level of study provided that the student:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6455__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>attended a registered approved New York state high school for two\nor more years, graduated from a registered New York state high school\nand applied for attendance at the institution of higher education for\nthe graduate study for which an award is sought within ten years of\nreceiving a New York state high school diploma; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6455__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>attended an approved New York state program for a state high\nschool equivalency diploma, received a state high school equivalency\ndiploma and applied for attendance at the institution of higher\neducation for the graduate study for which an award is sought within ten\nyears of receiving a state high school equivalency diploma; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6455__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is otherwise eligible for the payment of tuition and fees at a\nrate no greater than that imposed for resident students of the state\nuniversity of New York, the city university of New York or community\ncolleges as prescribed in subparagraph eight of paragraph h of\nsubdivision two of section three hundred fifty-five or paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6455__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision seven of section sixty-two hundred six of this chapter.\n  Provided, further, that a student without lawful immigration status\nshall also be required to file an affidavit with such institution of\nhigher education stating that the student has filed an application to\nlegalize his or her immigration status, or will file such an application\nas soon as he or she is eligible to do so.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6455__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Applications for funding shall be made by eligible institutions in\naccordance with requirements established by the commissioner. Grants\nshall be awarded based on criteria established by the commissioner.\nPriority consideration shall be given to institutions which coordinate\ntheir efforts to increase minority access with similar activities at the\nundergraduate level.\n  4. Reporting requirements. Institutions participating in the science\nand technology entry program shall submit to the commissioner such\nreports or other information as he shall require. The commissioner shall\nprepare for the board of regents an annual report of the activities of\ninstitutions which receive state funds pursuant to this section\nconcerning, but not limited to, the effectiveness of the programs, the\nnumbers of students served, and future plans.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>