<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6456"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6456"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6456"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6456/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6456/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6456/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6456/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6456">
        <num>6456</num>
        <heading>Foster youth college success initiative</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6456__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are an orphan or (ii) are, or have been, either a child\nor youth in foster care as such term is defined in section thirty-two\nhundred forty-four of this chapter or ward of the court at any time\nafter their thirteenth birthday.\n  3. a. Funds appropriated in the two thousand fifteen--two thousand\nsixteen academic year for the purposes of this initiative shall be\nallocated by sector as follows: fifty-two percent for institutions in\nthe state university of New York; thirty percent for institutions in the\ncity university of New York; and eighteen percent for other\ndegree-granting institutions in New York with current Arthur O. Eve\nhigher education opportunity programs.\n  b. Funds appropriated in the two thousand sixteen--two thousand\nseventeen academic year and thereafter for the purposes of this\ninitiative shall be allocated by sector based on the percentage of\nfoster youth identified by each institution that will be served by this\ninitiative in the following academic year, in applications received by\nthe commissioner pursuant to subdivision six of this section, provided\nhowever that the award per student for foster youth first served in the\ntwo thousand fifteen--two thousand sixteen academic year shall be no\nless than the amount per student awarded for those students in the two\nthousand fifteen--two thousand sixteen academic year.\n  4. Funds for all programs under this section shall be awarded in equal\namounts per foster youth to each institution that applies for funding\nallocated to its sector distribution as provided in subdivision three of\nthis section and has an application that is approved by the\ncommissioner; provided, however, funds shall be awarded to a foster\nyouth based on his or her need as determined by the institution of\nhigher education where such foster youth is in attendance.\n  5. Moneys made available to institutions under this section shall be\nspent for the following purposes:\n  a. to provide additional services and expen...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>