<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-10-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6502"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6502">
        <num>6502</num>
        <heading>Duration and registration of a license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6502. Duration and registration of a license. 1. A license shall be\nvalid during the life of the holder unless revoked, annulled or\nsuspended by the board of regents or in the case of physicians,\nphysicians practicing under a limited permit, physician's assistants,\nspecialist's assistants and medical residents, the licensee is stricken\nfrom the roster of such licensees by the board of regents on the order\nof the state board for professional medical conduct in the department of\nhealth. A licensee must register with the department and meet the\nrequirements prescribed in section 3-503 of the general obligations law\nto practice in this state.\n  2. The department shall establish the beginning dates of the\nregistration periods for each profession and provide an application for\nregistration conforming to the requirements of section 3-503 of the\ngeneral obligations law to every licensee currently registered at least\nfour months prior to the beginning of the registration period for the\nrespective profession; provided however, the department shall mail an\napplication forty-five days prior to the end date of such registration\nperiod to any licensee who has not registered.\n  3. An application for registration and the required registration fee\nshall be submitted together with or as a part of the application for a\nlicense. A person initially licensed or a licensee resuming practice\nafter a lapse of registration during the last two years of a triennial\nregistration period shall receive a prorated refund of one-third of the\ntotal registration fee for each full year of the triennial period that\nhas elapsed prior to the date of registration. Except as provided in\nsubdivision three-a of this section, the department shall renew the\nregistration of each licensee upon receipt of a proper application, on a\nform prescribed by the department and conforming to the requirements of\nsection 3-503 of the general obligations law, and the registration fee.\nAny licensee who fails to register by the beginning of the appropriate\nregistration period shall be required to pay an additional fee for late\nfiling of ten dollars for each month that registration has been delayed.\nNo licensee resuming practice after a lapse of registration shall be\npermitted to practice without actual possession of the registration\ncertificate.\n  3-a. Prior to issuing any registration pursuant to this section and\nsection sixty-five hundred twenty-four of this chapter, the department\nshall request and review any information relating to an applicant which\nreasonably appears to relate to professional misconduct in his or her\nprofessional practice in this and any other jurisdiction. The department\nshall advise the director of the office of professional medical conduct\nin the department of health of any information about an applicant which\nreasonably appears to be professional misconduct as defined in sections\nsixty-five hundred thirty and sixty-five hundred thirty-one of this\nchapter, within seven days of its discovery. The registration or\nre-registration of such applicant shall not be delayed for a period\nexceeding thirty days unless the director finds a basis for recommending\nsummary action pursuant to subdivision twelve of section two hundred\nthirty of the public health law after consultation with a committee on\nprofessional conduct of the state board for professional medical\nconduct, if warranted. Re-registration shall be issued if the\ncommissioner of health fails to issue a summary order pursuant to\nsubdivision twelve of section two hundred thirty of the public health\nlaw within ninety days of notice by the department pursuant to this\nsubdivision. Re-registration shall be denied if the commissioner of\nhealth issues a summary order pursuant to subdivision twelve of section\ntwo hundred thirty of the public health law.\n  4. Any licensee who is not engaging in the practice of his profession\nin this state and does not desire to register shall so advise the\ndepartment. Such licensee shall not be required to pay an additional fee\nfor failure to register at the beginning of the registration period.\n  5. Licensees shall notify the department of any change of name or\nmailing address within thirty days of such change. Failure to register\nor provide such notice within one hundred eighty days of such change\nshall be willful failure under section sixty-five hundred thirty of this\nchapter.\n  6. The fee for replacement of a lost registration certificate or\nlicense or for registration of an additional office shall be ten\ndollars.\n  7. An additional fee of twenty-five dollars shall be charged for the\nlicensure or registration of any applicant who submits a bad check to\nthe department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>