<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6503-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6503-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6503-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6503-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6503-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6503-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6503-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6503_A">
        <num>6503-A</num>
        <heading>Waiver for entities providing certain professional services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6503_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>services provided under article one hundred fifty-four, one\nhundred sixty-three or one hundred sixty-seven of this title for which\nlicensure would be required, or\n  (ii) services constituting the provision of psychotherapy as defined\nin subdivision two of section eighty-four hundred one of this title and\nauthorized and provided under article one hundred thirty-one, one\nhundred thirty-nine, or one hundred fifty-three of this title.\n  Such services may be provided either directly through the entity's\nemployees or indirectly by contract with individuals or professional\nentities duly licensed, registered, or authorized to provide such\nservices.\n  b. The department may issue a waiver on or after July first, two\nthousand twelve to an entity which was created before, on, or after the\neffective date of this section if there is a demonstration of need of\nthe entity's services satisfactory to the department.\n  c. After the commissioner prescribes the application form and posts\nnotice of its availability on the department's website, any entity\ndescribed in paragraph a of this subdivision providing services on the\neffective date of this section, must apply for a waiver no later than\nFebruary first, two thousand twelve. Upon submission of an application,\nan entity may continue to operate and provide services until the\ndepartment shall either deny or approve the entity's application. After\nthe department renders a timely initial determination that the applicant\nhas submitted the information necessary to verify that the requirements\nof paragraphs d, e, and f of this subdivision are satisfied,\napplications for waivers shall be approved or denied within ninety days;\nprovided however, that if the waiver application is denied the entity\nshall cease providing professional services, pursuant to paragraph a of\nthis subdivision, in the state of New York.\n  d. Such waiver shall provide that services rendered pursuant to this\nsection, directly or indirectly, sh...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6503_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name of the entity,\n  (ii) the names of the directors and officers of such entity,\n  (iii) a listing of any other jurisdictions where the entity may\nprovide services, and\n  (iv) an attestation made by an officer authorized by the entity to\nmake such attestation that identifies the scope of services to be\nprovided; includes a list of professions under this title in which\nprofessional services will be provided by such entity; includes a\nstatement that, unless otherwise authorized by law, the entity shall\nonly provide professional services authorized under this section;\nincludes a statement that only a licensed professional, a person\notherwise authorized to provide such services, or a professional entity\nauthorized by law to provide such services shall provide such\nprofessional services as authorized under this section; and attests to\nthe adequacy of the entity's fiscal and financial resources to provide\nsuch services.\n  Such application shall also include any other information related to\nthe application as may be required by the department.\n  f. Each officer and director of such entity shall provide an\nattestation regarding his or her good moral character as required\npursuant to paragraph h of this subdivision. The commissioner shall be\nfurther authorized to promulgate rules or regulations relating to the\nstandards of the waiver for entities pursuant to this section. Such\nregulations shall include standards relating to the entity's ability to\nprovide services, the entity's maintenance of patient and business\nrecords, the entity's fiscal policies, and such other standards as may\nbe prescribed by the commissioner.\n  g. The entity operating pursuant to a waiver shall display, at each\nsite where professional services are provided to the public, a\ncertificate of such waiver issued by the department pursuant to this\nsection, which shall contain the name of the entity and the address of\nthe site. Such entities shall obtain from the departme...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>