<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6505-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6505_C">
        <num>6505-C</num>
        <heading>Articulation between military and civilian professional careers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6505-c. Articulation between military and civilian professional\ncareers. 1. The commissioner shall develop, jointly with the\ncommissioner of the department of veterans' services, a program to\nfacilitate articulation between participation in the military service of\nthe United States or the military service of the state and admission to\npractice of a profession. The commissioner and the commissioner of\nveterans' services shall identify, review and evaluate professional\ntraining programs offered through either the military service of the\nUnited States or the military service of the state which may, where\napplicable, be accepted by the department as equivalent education and\ntraining in lieu of all or part of an approved program. Particular\nemphasis shall be placed on the identification of military programs\nwhich have previously been deemed acceptable by the department as\nequivalent education and training, programs which may provide, where\napplicable, equivalent education and training for those professions\nwhich are critical to public health and safety and programs which may\nprovide, where applicable, equivalent education and training for those\nprofessions for which shortages exist in the state of New York.\n  2. The commissioner and the director shall prepare a list of those\nmilitary programs which have previously been deemed acceptable by the\ndepartment as equivalent education and training in lieu of all or part\nof an approved program no later than the thirtieth of August, two\nthousand three. On and after such date, such list shall be made\navailable to the public and applicants for admission to practice of a\nprofession.\n  3. The commissioner and the director shall prepare a list of those\nmilitary programs which may provide, where applicable, equivalent\neducation and training for those professions which are critical to\npublic health and safety, programs which may provide, where applicable,\nequivalent education and training for those professions for which\nshortages exist in the state of New York and any other military programs\nwhich may, where applicable, be accepted by the department as equivalent\neducation and training in lieu of all or part of an approved program no\nlater than the thirty-first of October, two thousand three. On and after\nsuch date, such list shall be made available to the public and\napplicants for admission to practice of a profession.\n  4. Such lists shall be prepared annually no later than the thirtieth\nof June thereafter with additions and deletions made jointly by the\ncommissioner and the director and made available to the public and\napplicants for admission to practice of a profession on such date.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>