<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6510-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6510_D">
        <num>6510-D</num>
        <heading>Voluntary non-disciplinary surrender of a license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6510-d. Voluntary non-disciplinary surrender of a license. A\nprofessional who is licensed pursuant to article one hundred thirty-nine\nof this title may voluntarily surrender a license to the committee on\ndrug and alcohol abuse when such licensee requests to be monitored\nand/or receive peer support services in relation to the use, misuse or\naddiction to drugs. The committee shall accept such voluntary\nnon-disciplinary surrender of a license and provide for expedited\nreinstatement of the license if the licensee meets criteria set by the\ncommittee. Such criteria will include, but not be limited to, confidence\nthat the licensee's use of drugs and/or alcohol has not resulted in harm\nto a patient or client and the licensee is not incapacitated, unfit for\npractice or a threat to the health, safety and welfare of the public.\nSuch voluntary surrender, if accepted by the committee, shall result in\nan immediate reinstatement of the license and shall provide immunity\nfrom a violation of subdivision three or four of section six thousand\nfive hundred nine of this article and cannot be deemed an admission or\nused as evidence in professional misconduct. Acceptance by the committee\nshall not require a report to the department of health or to any\nemployer or licensing authority of another jurisdiction, nor require any\ndisclosure to patients or to the public that such license has been\ntemporarily surrendered, except if it is subsequently determined by the\ndepartment that a participant being monitored by the department is found\nto have used drugs and/or alcohol which has resulted in harm to a\npatient or client.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>