<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6523"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6523"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-04-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6523"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6523/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6523/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6523/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6523/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6523">
        <num>6523</num>
        <heading>State board for medicine</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6523. State board for medicine. A state board for medicine shall be\nappointed by the board of regents on recommendation of the commissioner\nfor the purpose of assisting the board of regents and the department on\nmatters of professional licensing in accordance with section sixty-five\nhundred eight of this title. The board shall be composed of not less\nthan twenty physicians licensed in this state for at least five years,\ntwo of whom shall be doctors of osteopathy. To the extent such physician\nappointees are available for appointment, at least one of the physician\nappointees to the state board for medicine shall be an expert on\nreducing health disparities among demographic subgroups, and one shall\nbe an expert on women's health. The board shall also consist of not less\nthan two physician's assistants licensed to practice in this state. The\nparticipation of physician's assistant members shall be limited to\nmatters relating to article one hundred thirty-one-B of this chapter. An\nexecutive secretary to the board shall be appointed by the board of\nregents on recommendation of the commissioner and shall be either a\nphysician licensed in this state or a non-physician, deemed qualified by\nthe commissioner and board of regents.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>