<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6526"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6526"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6526"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6526/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6526/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6526/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6526/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6526">
        <num>6526</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6526__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any physician who is licensed and in good standing in another\nstate or territory, and who has a written agreement to provide medical\nservices to athletes and team personnel of a United States sports team\nrecognized by the United States Olympic committee or an out-of-state\nsecondary school, institution of postsecondary education, or\nprofessional athletic organization sports team, may provide medical\nservices to such athletes and team personnel at a discrete sanctioned\nteam sporting event in this state as defined by the commissioner in\nregulations, provided such services are provided only to such athletes\nand team personnel at the discrete sanctioned team sporting event. Any\nsuch medical services shall be provided only five days before through\nthree days after each discrete sanctioned team sporting event.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6526__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person practicing as a physician in New York state pursuant to\nthis subdivision shall be subject to the personal and subject matter\njurisdiction and disciplinary and regulatory authority of the board of\nregents and the state board for professional medical conduct established\npursuant to section two hundred thirty of the public health law as if he\nor she is a licensee and as if the exemption pursuant to this\nsubdivision is a license. Such individual shall comply with applicable\nprovisions of this title, the public health law, the rules of the board\nof regents, the state board for professional medical conduct established\npursuant to section two hundred thirty of the public health law, and the\nregulations of the commissioner and the commissioner of health, relating\nto professional misconduct, disciplinary proceedings and penalties for\nprofessional misconduct.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>