<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6541"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6541"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6541"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6541/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6541/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6541/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6541/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6541">
        <num>6541</num>
        <heading>Requirements for license</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6541__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at the time of application is at least twenty-one years of age;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6541__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is of good moral character;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6541__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has received an education including a bachelor's or equivalent\ndegree in accordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6541__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has satisfactorily completed an approved program for the training\nof physician assistants. The approved program for the training of\nphysician assistants shall include not less than forty weeks of\nsupervised clinical training and thirty-two credit hours of classroom\nwork.  Applicants for a license as a physician assistant who have\ncompleted an approved program leading to a bachelor's degree or\nequivalent in physician assistant studies shall be deemed to have\nsatisfied this paragraph. The commissioner is empowered to determine\nwhether an applicant possesses equivalent education and training, such\nas experience as a nurse or military corpsman, which may be accepted in\nlieu of all or part of an approved program; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6541__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of an applicant for a license as a physician\nassistant, has obtained a passing score on an examination acceptable to\nthe department.\n  2. The department shall furnish to each person applying for a license\npursuant to this section an application form calling for such\ninformation as the department deems necessary and shall issue to each\napplicant who satisfies the requirements of subdivision one of this\nsection a license as a physician assistant in a particular medical\nspecialty for the period expiring December thirty-first of the first\nodd-numbered year terminating subsequent to the issuance of such\nlicense.\n  3. Every licensee shall apply to the department for a renewal of his\nor her license. The department shall mail to every licensed physician\nassistant an application form for renewal, addressed to the licensee's\npost office address on file with the department. Upon receipt of such\napplication properly executed, together with evidence of satisfactory\ncompletion of such continuing education requirements as may be\nestablished by the commissioner of health pursuant to section\nthirty-seven hundred one of the public health law, the department shall\nissue a renewal. Renewal periods shall be triennial and the renewal fee\nshall be forty-five dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>