<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6546"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6546"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6546"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6546/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6546/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6546/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6546/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6546">
        <num>6546</num>
        <heading>Limited permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง  6546. Limited permits. Permits limited as to eligibility, practice\nand duration, shall be issued by the department to eligible applicants,\nas follows:\n  1. Eligibility. A person who fulfills all requirements to be licensed\nas a physician assistant except that relating to the examination shall\nbe eligible for a limited permit.\n  2. Limit of practice. A permittee shall be authorized to practice as a\nphysician assistant only under the direct supervision of a physician.\n  3. Duration. A limited permit shall expire one year from the date of\nissuance or upon notice to the permittee by the department that the\napplication for a license has been denied. A limited permit shall be\nextended upon application for one additional year, provided that the\npermittee's request for such extension is endorsed by a physician who\neither has supervised or will supervise the permittee, except that such\nextension may be denied by the department for cause which shall be\nstated in writing. If the permittee is awaiting the results of a\nlicensing examination at the time such limited permit expires, such\npermit shall continue to be valid until ten days after notification to\nthe permittee of the result of such examination.\n  4. Fees. The fee for each limited permit shall be one hundred five\ndollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>