<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6551"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6551"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6551"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6551/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6551/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6551/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6551/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6551">
        <num>6551</num>
        <heading>Definition of practice of chiropractic</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6551. Definition of practice of chiropractic.  1.  The practice of\nthe profession of chiropractic is defined as detecting and correcting by\nmanual or mechanical means structural imbalance, distortion, or\nsubluxations in the human body for the purpose of removing nerve\ninterference and the effects thereof, where such interference is the\nresult of or related to distortion, misalignment or subluxation of or in\nthe vertebral column.\n  2. a. A license to practice as a chiropractor shall not permit the\nholder thereof to use radio-therapy, fluoroscopy, or any form of\nionizing radiation except X-ray which shall be used for the detection of\nstructural imbalance, distortion, or subluxations in the human body.\n  b. The requirements and limitations with respect to the use of X-ray\nby chiropractors shall be enforced by the state commissioner of health\nand he is authorized to promulgate rules and regulations after\nconferring with the board to carry out the purposes of this subdivision.\n  c. Chiropractors shall retain for a period of three years all X-ray\nfilms taken in the course of their practice, together with the records\npertaining thereto, and shall make such films and records available to\nthe state commissioner of health or his representative on demand.\n  3. A license to practice chiropractic shall not permit the holder\nthereof to treat for any infectious diseases such as pneumonia, any\ncommunicable diseases listed in the sanitary code of the state of New\nYork, any of the cardio-vascular-renal or cardio-pulmonary diseases, any\nsurgical condition of the abdomen such as acute appendicitis, or\ndiabetes, or any benign or malignant neoplasms; to operate; to reduce\nfractures or dislocations; to prescribe, administer, dispense or use in\nhis practice drugs or medicines; or to use diagnostic or therapeutic\nmethods involving chemical or biological means except diagnostic\nservices performed by clinical laboratories which services shall be\napproved by the board as appropriate to the practice of chiropractic; or\nto utilize electrical devices except those devices approved by the board\nas being appropriate to the practice of chiropractic. Nothing herein\nshall be construed to prohibit a licensed chiropractor who has\nsuccessfully completed a registered doctoral program in chiropractic,\nwhich contains courses of study in nutrition satisfactory to the\ndepartment, from using nutritional counseling, including the dispensing\nof food concentrates, food extracts, vitamins, minerals, and other\nnutritional supplements approved by the board as being appropriate to,\nand as a part of, his or her practice of chiropractic. Nothing herein\nshall be construed to prohibit an individual who is not subject to\nregulation in this state as a licensed chiropractor from engaging in\nnutritional counseling.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>