<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6604-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6604_B">
        <num>6604-B</num>
        <heading>Restricted dental faculty license</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6604_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The completion of a total of no less than six academic years of\npre-professional and professional education, including:\n  i. courses in general chemistry, organic chemistry, biology or zoology\nand physics; and\n  ii. not less than four academic years of professional dental education\nsatisfactory to the department culminating in a degree, diploma or\ncertificate in dentistry recognized by the appropriate civil authorities\nof the jurisdiction in which the school is located as acceptable for\nentry into practice in the jurisdiction in which the school is located.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6604_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within the last five years, have two years of satisfactory\npractice as a dentist or have satisfactorily completed an advanced\neducation program in general dentistry or in a dental specialty,\nprovided such program is accredited by an organization accepted by the\ndepartment as a reliable authority for the purpose of accrediting such\nprograms (such as the commission on dental accreditation); and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6604_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Possesses good moral character as determined by the department.\n  3. The dean of the dental school shall notify the department in\nwriting upon the submission of an initial license application and yearly\nthereafter that the holder of the dental faculty license is employed\nfull-time at the dental school. Full-time employment means the holder of\nsuch dental faculty license devotes at least four full working days per\nweek in teaching or patient care, research or administrative duties at\nthe dental school where employed. The dean of the dental school and the\nholder of such dental faculty license shall each notify the department\nin writing within thirty days of the termination of full-time\nemployment.\n  4. In order to continue to practice dentistry, the holder of a\nrestricted dental faculty license shall apply for and hold a current\ntriennial registration which shall be subject to the same registration\nrequirements as apply to holders of unrestricted dental licenses, except\nthat such registration shall be issued only upon the submission of\ndocumentation satisfactory to the department of the holder's continued\nstatus as a full-time dental faculty member, provided that such\nregistration shall immediately terminate and the holder shall no longer\nbe authorized to practice if the holder ceases to be a full-time dental\nfaculty member at an approved New York state school of dentistry.\n  5. The holder of this restricted dental faculty license shall be\nsubject to the professional misconduct provisions set forth in article\none hundred thirty of this chapter and in the rules of the board of\nregents and the regulations of the commissioner.\n  6. The fee for each restricted dental faculty license shall be three\nhundred dollars, and the fee for initial registration and each\nsubsequent re-registration shall be three hundred dollars.\n  7. In order to be eligible for a restricted dental faculty license an\napplicant must be a United States citizen or a noncitize...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>