<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6605"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6605">
        <num>6605</num>
        <heading>Limited permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6605. Limited permits. 1. On recommendation of the board, the\ndepartment may issue a limited permit to a graduate of a dental college\nwho meets the educational qualifications for admission to the licensing\nexamination in dentistry for employment in a hospital or dental facility\napproved by an appropriate agency, while under the direction or\nsupervision of a licensed dentist. No such permit shall be issued or\nrenewed unless such graduate has a bona fide offer of a position in such\na hospital or dental facility.\n  2. On recommendation of the board, the department may issue a limited\npermit for instructing in dentistry to a dentist not licensed under this\narticle to be employed by a registered school of dentistry or dental\nhygiene to instruct and supervise clinical dentistry or dental hygiene\nfor students in such a registered school in the state, and in so doing\nto practice dentistry as defined in this article, but only on the\npremises of such registered school or such other premises as may be used\nfor instruction in the program of education conducted by such\ninstitution. No person shall be permitted or authorized to instruct and\nsupervise clinical dentistry for students unless such person is licensed\nin this state or holds the foregoing limited permit for instructing in\ndentistry.\n  3. The holder of a limited permit under this section may practice\ndentistry, as defined in this article, but only in the performance of\nduties required by the position for which the limited permit is issued.\nNothing in this section shall be construed to authorize such unlicensed\ndentist to engage in the private practice of dentistry.\n  4. A limited permit under this section shall be valid for one year or\nuntil ten days after notification of denial of an application for\nlicense. A limited permit may be renewed for one year, except if the\napplicant is serving in a residency program in a hospital or school of\ndentistry in this state. A limited permit may be renewed annually for\nthe duration of such residency program. The fee for each limited permit\nand for each renewal shall be one hundred five dollars.\n  5. Notwithstanding subdivision one of this section, dental school\ngraduates who meet the license requirement for education pursuant to\nsubdivision two of section sixty-six hundred four of this article shall\nbe deemed to be exempt persons pursuant to section sixty-six hundred ten\nof this article and shall not be required to obtain a limited permit,\nprovided that they are employed in an approved residency program for the\npurpose of fulfilling initial licensure requirements pursuant to section\nsixty-six hundred four of this article. Not later than sixty days after\nentry into an approved residency program, the dental resident shall\nregister on a form acceptable to the commissioner and pay to the\ndepartment a residency registration fee established by the department,\nwhich residency registration fee shall be reasonable and shall not\nexceed the limited permit fee specified in subdivision four of this\nsection. All persons deemed exempt pursuant to this section shall be\nsubject to all provisions of article one hundred thirty of this title,\nincluding but not limited to having disciplinary action taken against\ntheir residency registration status.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>