<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6606"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6606"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6606"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6606">
        <num>6606</num>
        <heading>Definition of practice of dental hygiene</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6606__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be signed and maintained by the dentist, the dental hygienist and\nauthorized setting;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6606__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be reviewed annually by the dentist and dental hygienist;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6606__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>include consideration for medically compromised patients, specific\nmedical conditions, and age- and procedure-specific practice protocols,\nincluding, but not limited to recommended intervals for the performance\nof dental hygiene services and a periodicity in which an examination by\na dentist should occur; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6606__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be made available to the department and other interested parties\nupon request.\n  3. Before performing services pursuant to a collaborative practice\nagreement, a dental hygienist, collaborative practice shall provide the\npatient with a written statement advising the patient that the dental\nhygiene services provided are not a substitute for a dental examination\nby a licensed dentist. If the dental hygienist makes any referrals to\nthe patient for further procedures, the dental hygienist shall fill out\na referral form and provide a copy of the form to the collaborating\ndentist.\n  4. The performance of services pursuant to a collaborative agreement\nis authorized in the following settings: a hospital as defined in\narticle twenty-eight of the public health law, an appropriately equipped\nschool, a federally qualified health center, a long-term care facility,\na group home servicing people with intellectual and developmental\ndisabilities, a facility serving veterans, a temporary housing facility,\na prison, a drug treatment facility, a domestic violence shelter, and\nappropriate settings in which homebound residents are unable to be\nrelocated for necessary treatment.\n  5. A registered dental hygienist, collaborative practice shall have no\nmore than one collaborative agreement with a dentist at one time.\n  6. A dentist shall not have a collaborative agreement with more than\nsix registered dental hygienists, collaborative practice at one time.\nThe department may grant an exception to such limitation for public\nhealth settings on a case-by-case basis.\n  7. A dental hygienist shall file an application with the department to\npractice as a registered dental hygienist, collaborative practice and\npay a fee determined by the department. As a condition of collaborative\npractice, the dental hygienist shall have been engaged in practice for\nthree years with a minimum of four thousand five hundred practice hours\nand shall complete an eight-hour continuing educa...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>