<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6633"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6633"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6633"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6633/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6633/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6633/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6633/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6633">
        <num>6633</num>
        <heading>Special provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6633. Special provisions. An individual who meets the requirements\nfor a license as a licensed perfusionist except for examination,\nexperience and education and who meets the requirements enumerated under\nsubdivisions one or two of this section may be licensed without meeting\nadditional requirements provided that such individual submits an\napplication to the department within two years of the effective date of\nthis section:\n  1. Applicants may be licensed if they have been practicing as a\nperfusionist for five years in the past ten years in an inpatient unit\nthat provides cardiac surgery services in a hospital approved by the\ndepartment of health or a substantially equivalent accrediting body\nacceptable to the committee and the department at least three of such\nyears of experience having occurred during the past five years;\n  2. Applicants who possess certification from a national certification\norganization acceptable to the committee and the department may be\nlicensed if they have been employed as a perfusionist for three of the\npast five years.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>