<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-664"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-664"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="664"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-664/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-664/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-664/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-664/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_664">
        <num>664</num>
        <heading>Concurrent awards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 664. Concurrent awards. 1. a. No person shall receive benefits\nconcurrently from more than one academic performance award under this\nchapter, except for the regents scholarship in Cornell university. Nor\nshall any person receive benefits from an academic performance award\nunder this chapter concurrently with any scholarship, grant, or\neducational assistance under federal law that, in the judgment of the\ncommissioner would duplicate the purpose of such academic performance\naward, except United States war orphan educational benefits or benefits\nunder the veterans' readjustment benefits act of nineteen hundred\nsixty-six.\n  b. A person may receive concurrently a tuition assistance program\naward, a regents award for children of deceased and disabled veterans\nand a regents award for children of deceased police officers,\nfirefighters and volunteer firefighters, and correction officers of the\nstate or any political subdivision thereof, and may also receive\nbenefits under one or all of these awards concurrently with an academic\nperformance award or federal or other awards. However, in the case of\nthe regents awards for children of deceased state correction officers\nand state civilian employees of a correctional facility received\npursuant to the provisions of section six hundred sixty-nine of this\narticle, no person shall receive benefits under this award concurrently\nwith any other general or academic performance award under this chapter,\nor with any scholarship, grant, or educational assistance under federal\nlaw that, in the judgment of the commissioner would duplicate the\npurposes of such award.\n  c. A person may receive concurrently a tuition assistance award and a\nscholarship for academic achievement pursuant to subdivision eighteen of\nsection three hundred fifty-five of this chapter.\n  2. Where concurrent use of two or more awards is not permitted under\nthis section, a student qualifying for two or more awards must choose\nwhich award he wishes to accept.\n  3. The board shall promulgate, subject to the approval of the regents,\nrules and regulations which shall govern the use of state awards and\nloans concurrently with awards and loans granted to a student by any\nother political entity or subdivision, institute, corporation, agency,\nor foundation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>