<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="667"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_667">
        <num>667</num>
        <heading>Tuition assistance program awards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the internal\nrevenue code for federal income tax purposes in the following amounts:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each year of undergraduate study, assistance shall be provided\nas computed on the basis of the amount which is the lesser of the\nfollowing:\n  (A)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of students who have not been granted an exclusion\nof parental income, who have qualified as an orphan, foster child, or\nward of the court for the purposes of federal student financial aid\nprograms authorized by Title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as\namended, or had a dependent for income tax purposes during the tax year\nnext preceding the academic year for which application is made, except\nfor those students who have been granted exclusion of parental income\nwho have a spouse but no other dependent:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Five thousand dollars, except starting in two thousand\nfourteen-two thousand fifteen such students shall receive five thousand\none hundred sixty-five dollars, and except starting in two thousand\ntwenty-one--two thousand twenty-two and thereafter such students shall\nreceive five thousand six hundred sixty-five dollars, provided however\nthat nothing herein shall be construed as increasing any award made\npursuant to this section for an academic year prior to two thousand\ntwenty-one--two thousand twenty-two; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For undergraduate students enrolled in a program of study at a\nnon-public degree-granting institution that does not offer a program of\nstudy that leads to a baccalaureate degree, or at a registered\nnot-for-profit business school qualified for tax exemption under section\n501</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the internal revenue code for federal income tax purposes\nthat does not offer a program of study that leads to a baccalaureate\ndegree, four thousand dollars, except starting in two thousand\ntwenty-one--two thousand twenty-two and thereafter such students shall\nreceive four thousand five hundred dollars. Provided, however, that this\nsubitem shall not apply to students enrolled in a program of study\nleading to a certificate or degree in nursing.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of students receiving awards pursuant to subparagraph\n(iii) of this paragraph and those students who have been granted\nexclusion of parental income who have a spouse but no other dependent\nbeginning in the two thousand twenty-one--two thousand twenty-two\nacademic year and thereafter, three thousand five hundred twenty-five\ndollars, provided that nothing herein shall be construed as increasing\nany award made for any prior academic year; or\n  (B)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Ninety-five percent of the amount of tuition (exclusive of\neducational fees) charged and, if applicable, the college fee levied by\nthe state university of New York pursuant to the April first, nineteen\nhundred sixty-four financing agreement with the New York state dormitory\nauthority.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the two thousand one--two thousand two academic year and\nthereafter one hundred percent of the amount of tuition (exclusive of\neducational fees) charged and, if applicable, the college fee levied by\nthe state university of New York pursuant to the April first, nineteen\nhundred sixty-four financing agreement with the New York state dormitory\nauthority.\n  (ii) Except for students as noted in subparagraph (iii) of this\nparagraph, the base amount as determined from subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nparagraph, shall be reduced in relation to income as follows:\nAmount of income                    Schedule of reduction\n                                    of base amount\n(A) Less than seven thousand        None\n    dollars\n(B) Seven thousand dollars or       Seven per centum of excess\n    more, but less than eleven      over seven thousand dollars\n    thousand dollars\n(C) Eleven thousand dollars or      Two hundred eighty dollars\n    more, but less than eighteen    plus ten per centum of excess\n    thousand dollars                over eleven thousand dollars\n(D) Eighteen thousand dollars or    Nine hundred eighty dollars\n    more, but not more than one     plus twelve per centum of\n    hundred twenty-five             excess over eighteen\n    thousand dollars                thousand dollars\n  (iii) (A) For students who have been granted exclusion of parental\nincome and were single with no dependent for income tax purposes during\nthe tax year next preceding the academic year for which application is\nmade, the base amount, as determined in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nparagraph, shall be reduced in relation to income as follows:\nAmount of income                    Schedule of reduction\n                                    of base amount\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Less than three thousand        None\n    dollars\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Three thousand dollars or       Thirty-one per centum of\n    more, but not more than thirty  amount in excess of three\n    thousand dollars                thousand dollars\n(B) For those students who have been granted exclusion of parental\nincome who have a spouse but no other dependent, for income tax purposes\nduring the tax year next preceding the academic year for which\napplication is made, the base amount, as determined in subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this paragraph, shall be reduced in relation to income as follows:\nAmount of income                    Schedule of reduction\n                                    of base amount\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Less than seven thousand        None\n    dollars\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Seven thousand dollars or       Seven per centum of excess\n    more, but less than eleven      over seven thousand dollars\n    thousand dollars\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Eleven thousand dollars or      Two hundred eighty dollars\n    more, but less than eighteen    plus ten per centum of excess\n    thousand dollars                over eleven thousand dollars\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Eighteen thousand dollars or    Nine hundred eighty dollars\n    more, but not more than sixty   plus twelve per centum of\n    thousand dollars                excess over eighteen\n                                    thousand dollars\n  (iv) If the amount of reduction is not a whole dollar, it shall be\nreduced to the next lowest whole dollar. In the case of any student who\nhas received four or more payments pursuant to any and all awards\nprovided for in this subdivision, for the two thousand--two thousand one\nacademic year the base amount shall be reduced by an additional one\nhundred fifty dollars for the two thousand one--two thousand two\nacademic year and thereafter the base amount shall be reduced by an\nadditional one hundred dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The award shall be the net amount of the base amount determined\npursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph reduced pursuant to\nsubparagraph (ii) or (iii) of this paragraph but the award shall not be\nreduced for the two thousand--two thousand one and two thousand one--two\nthousand two academic years below two hundred seventy-five dollars if\nthe amount of income is eighty thousand dollars or less and more than\nseventy thousand dollars, three hundred twenty-five dollars if the\namount of income is seventy thousand dollars or less and more than sixty\nthousand dollars and four hundred twenty-five dollars if the amount of\nincome is sixty thousand dollars or less.\n  (vi) For the two thousand two--two thousand three through two thousand\ntwenty-three--twenty-four academic years, the award shall be the net\namount of the base amount determined pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis paragraph reduced pursuant to subparagraph (ii) or (iii) of this\nparagraph but the award shall not be reduced below five hundred dollars.\n  (vii) For the two thousand twenty-four--two thousand twenty-five\nacademic year and thereafter, the award shall be the net amount of the\nbase amount determined pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph\nreduced pursuant to subparagraph (ii) or (iii) of this paragraph but the\naward shall not be reduced below one thousand dollars.\n  b. Amount. The president shall make awards to students enrolled in two\nyear programs offered in registered private business schools except for\nregistered not-for-profit business schools qualified for tax exemption\nunder section 501</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the internal revenue code for federal income\ntax purposes in the following amounts:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each year of study, assistance shall be provided as computed\non the basis of the amount which is the lesser of the following:\n  (A)</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>one thousand three hundred dollars, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for students receiving awards pursuant to subparagraph (iii) of\nthis paragraph, one thousand one hundred forty dollars; or\n  (B)</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Ninety-five percent of the amount of tuition (exclusive of\neducational fees) charged.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_667__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the two thousand one--two thousand two academic year and\nthereafter one hundred percent of the amount of tuition (exclusive of\neducational fees).\n  (ii) Except for students as noted in subparagraph (iii) of this\nparagraph, the base amount as determined in subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nparagraph, shall be reduced in relation to income as follows:\nAmount of income                    Schedule of reduction\n                                    of base amount\n(A) Less than seven thousand        None\n    dollars\n(B) Seven thousand dollars or       Seven per centum of the excess\n    more, but less than eleven       over seven thousand dollars\n    thousand dollars\n  (iii) For students who have been granted exclusion of parental income\nand were single with no dependent for income tax purposes during the tax\nyear next preceding the academic year for which application is made, the\nbase amount, as determined in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph, shall\nbe reduced in relation to income as follows:\nAmount of income                    Schedule of reduction of\n                                    base amount\n(A) Less than three thousand        None\n    dollars\n(B) Three thousand dollars or       Thirty-one per centum of the ex-\n    more, but not more than ten     cess over three thousand dollars\n    thousand dollars\n  (iv) If the amount of reduction is not a whole dollar, it shall be\nreduced to the next lowest whole dollar. In the case of any student who\nhas received four or more payments pursuant to any and all awards\nprovided for in this subdivision, for the two thousand--two thousand one\nacademic year the base amount shall be reduced by an additional one\nhundred fifty dollars for the two thousand one--two thousand two\nacademic year and thereafter the base amount shall be reduced by an\nadditional one hundred dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The award shall be the net amount of the base amount determined\npursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph reduced pursuant to\nsubparagraph (ii) or (iii) of this paragraph but the award shall not be\nreduced below one hundred dollars. If the income exceeds the maximum\namount of income allowable under subparagraph (ii) or (iii) of this\nparagraph, no award shall be made.\n  c. Restrictions. In no even shall shall any award:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be made unless the annual tuition (exclusive of educational fees)\nand, if applicable, the college fee levied by the state university of\nNew York pursuant to the April first, nineteen hundred sixty-four\nfinancing agreement with the New York state dormitory authority charged\nfor the program in which the student is enrolled total at least two\nhundred dollars; or\n  (ii) exceed the amount by which such annual tuition (exclusive of\neducational fees) and, if applicable, the college fee levied by the\nstate university of New York pursuant to the April first, nineteen\nhundred sixty-four financing agreement with the New York state dormitory\nauthority exceed the total of all other state, federal, or other\neducational aid that is received or receivable by such student during\nthe school year for which such award is applicable and that, in the\njudgment of the commissioner, would duplicate the purposes of the award;\nor\n  (iii) be made when income exceeds the maximum income set forth in this\nsubdivision. The commissioner shall list in his regulations all major\nstate and federal financial aid available to New York state students and\nidentify any forms of aid that are duplicative of the purposes of the\ntuition assistance program. For the purposes of this subdivision,\nneither United States war orphan educational benefits nor benefits under\nthe veterans' readjustment act of nineteen hundred sixty-six shall be\nconsidered as federal or other educational aid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>