<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="669-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_669_F">
        <num>669-F</num>
        <heading>New York state masters-in-education teacher incentive scholarship program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>earned an undergraduate degree from a\ncollege located in New York state;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>was a New York state resident\nwhile earning such undergraduate degree;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>achieved academic\nexcellence as an undergraduate student, as defined by the corporation in\nregulation;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>enrolls in full-time study in an approved master's\ndegree in education program at a New York state college, as defined in\nsubdivision two of section six hundred one of this title, leading to a\ncareer as a teacher in public elementary or secondary education;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nsigns a contract with the corporation agreeing to teach in a classroom\nsetting on a full-time basis for five years in a school located within\nNew York state providing public elementary or secondary education\nrecognized by the board of regents or the university of the state of New\nYork, including charter schools authorized pursuant to article fifty-six\nof this chapter; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>complies with the applicable provisions of this\narticle and all requirements promulgated by the corporation for the\nadministration of the program.\n  1-a. Preference for scholarship awards. Preference for the award of\nscholarships shall be given to eligible students matriculated at public\ncolleges, as defined in subdivision two of section six hundred one of\nthis title, in New York state. Remaining scholarships may be awarded to\nother eligible students matriculated at private colleges, as defined in\nsubdivision two of section six hundred one of this title, in New York\nstate.\n  2. Within amounts appropriated therefor, awards shall be granted to\napplicants that the corporation has certified are eligible to receive\nsuch awards. Up to five hundred awards may be granted to new recipients\nannually. Such awards shall be granted upon successful completion of\neach term, as defined by the corporation.\n  3. An award shall entitle the recipient to annual payments for not\nmore than two academic years of full-time graduate study leading to\ncertification as an elementary or secondary classroom teacher.\n  4. The corporation shall grant such awards in an amount equal to the\nannual tuition charged to state resident students attending a graduate\nprogram full-time at the state university of New York, or actual tuition\ncharged, whichever is less; provided, however,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a student who\nreceives educational grants and/or scholarships that cover the student's\nfull cost of attendance shall not be eligible for an award under this\nprogram; (ii) for a student who receives educational grants and/or\nscholarships that cover less than the student's full cost of attendance,\nsuch grants and/or scholarships shall not be deemed duplicative of this\nprogram and may be held concurrently with an award under this program,\nprovided that the combined benefits do not exceed the student's full\ncost of attendance; and (iii) an award under this program shall be\napplied to tuition after the application of all other educational grants\nand scholarships limited to tuition and shall be reduced in an amount\nequal to such educational grants and/or scholarships. Upon notification\nof an award under this program, the institution shall defer the amount\nof tuition equal to the award. No award shall be final until the\nrecipient's successful completion of a term has been certified by the\ninstitution. A recipient of an award under this program shall not be\neligible for an award under the New York state math and science teaching\nincentive program.\n  5. The corporation shall convert to a student loan the full amount of\nthe award granted pursuant to this section, plus interest, according to\na schedule to be determined by the corporation if:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two years after\nthe completion of the degree program and receipt of initial\ncertification it is found that a recipient is not teaching in a public\nschool located within New York state providing elementary or secondary\neducation recognized by the board of regents or the university of the\nstate of New York, including charter schools authorized pursuant to\narticle fifty-six of this chapter;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a recipient has not taught in a\npublic school located within New York state providing elementary or\nsecondary education recognized by the board of regents or the university\nof the state of New York, including charter schools authorized pursuant\nto article fifty-six of this chapter, for five of the seven years after\nthe completion of the graduate degree program and receipt of initial\ncertification;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a recipient fails to complete his or her graduate\ndegree program in education;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a recipient fails to receive or\nmaintain his or her teaching certificate or license in New York state\nfor the required period; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_F__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a recipient fails to respond to requests\nby the corporation for the status of his or her academic or professional\nprogress. The terms and conditions of this subdivision shall be deferred\nfor any interruption in graduate study or employment as established by\nthe rules and regulations of the corporation. Any obligation to comply\nwith such provisions as outlined in this section shall be cancelled upon\nthe death of the recipient. Notwithstanding any provisions of this\nsubdivision to the contrary, the corporation is authorized to promulgate\nrules and regulations to provide for the waiver or suspension of any\nfinancial obligation which would involve extreme hardship.\n  6. The corporation is authorized to promulgate rules and regulations,\nand may promulgate emergency regulations, necessary for the\nimplementation of the provisions of this section including, but not\nlimited to, the criteria for the provision of awards on a competitive\nbasis, and the rate of interest charged for repayment of the student\nloan.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>