<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="669-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_669_A">
        <num>669-A</num>
        <heading>Veterans tuition awards program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person who is a resident of this\nstate, (ii) who served in the armed forces of the United States in\nIndochina at any time from the first day of November, nineteen hundred\nfifty-five, to and including the seventh day of May, nineteen hundred\nseventy-five, and (iii) who was either discharged therefrom under\nhonorable conditions, including but not limited to honorable discharge,\ndischarge under honorable conditions, or general discharge, or has a\nqualifying condition, as defined in section one of the veterans'\nservices law, and has received a discharge other than bad conduct or\ndishonorable from such service, or is a discharged LGBT veteran, as\ndefined in section one of the veterans' services law, and has received a\ndischarge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from such service.\n  b. "Persian Gulf veteran" means</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person who is a resident of this\nstate (ii) who served in the armed forces of the United States in the\nhostilities that occurred in the Persian Gulf from the second day of\nAugust, nineteen hundred ninety through the end of such hostilities, and\n(iii) who was either discharged therefrom under honorable conditions,\nincluding but not limited to honorable discharge, discharge under\nhonorable conditions, or general discharge, or has a qualifying\ncondition, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law, and\nhas received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from\nsuch service, or is a discharged LGBT veteran, as defined in section one\nof the veterans' services law, and has received a discharge other than\nbad conduct or dishonorable from such service.\n  c. "Afghanistan veteran" means</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person who is a resident of this\nstate (ii) who served in the armed forces of the United States in the\nhostilities that occurred in Afghanistan from the eleventh day of\nSeptember, two thousand one, to the end of such hostilities, and (iii)\nwho was either discharged therefrom under honorable conditions,\nincluding but not limited to honorable discharge, discharge under\nhonorable conditions, or general discharge, or has a qualifying\ncondition, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law, and\nhas received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from\nsuch service, or is a discharged LGBT veteran, as defined in section one\nof the veterans' services law, and has received a discharge other than\nbad conduct or dishonorable from such service.\n  d. "Other eligible veteran" means: an individual who</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is a resident\nof this state, (ii) served in the armed forces of the United States</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_669_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\non active duty for at least four years, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_669_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in hostilities that\noccurred after February twenty-eighth, nineteen hundred sixty-one, as\nevidenced by their receipt of an Armed Forces Expeditionary Medal, Navy\nExpeditionary Medal, or Marine Corps Expeditionary Medal, and (iii) was\neither discharged under honorable conditions, including but not limited\nto honorable discharge, discharge under honorable conditions, or general\ndischarge, or has a qualifying condition, as defined in section one of\nthe veterans' services law, and has received a discharge other than bad\nconduct or dishonorable from such service, or is a discharged LGBT\nveteran, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law, and\nhas received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from\nsuch service.\n  e. "Part time study" means enrollment for at least three but less than\ntwelve semester hours per semester, or the equivalent, in an approved\nundergraduate or graduate program.\n  f. "Approved vocational training programs" means programs offer...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>was married to a qualified\nveteran who died as a result of military service; or (ii) was married to\nthe qualified veteran within fifteen years of their discharge from\nmilitary service in which the cause of death, disease or injury started\nor was aggravated; or (iii) was married to the veteran for at least one\nyear; or (iv) had a child with the qualified veteran and lived together\nwith the veteran continuously until the veteran's death or, if\nseparated, was not at fault for the separation.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2026\n  2. a. Tuition awards are available for all Vietnam, Persian Gulf,\nAfghanistan and other eligible veterans, as defined in subdivision one\nof this section, who are enrolled, pursuant to paragraph a of\nsubdivision four of section six hundred sixty-one of this part, in\napproved undergraduate or graduate programs at degree granting\ninstitutions or enrolled in approved vocational training programs and\nwho apply for a tuition assistance program award, for up to the\nequivalent of eight full-time semesters, pursuant to section six hundred\nsixty-seven of this subpart.\n  b. Eligibility for awards under this section shall be established as\nof the date the application is received by the corporation. All eligible\nrecipients shall receive an award in an amount as set forth in\nsubdivision four of this section.\n  3. a. No recipient shall receive awards for more than eight semesters\nof full time undergraduate study, or the equivalent of four academic\nyears, or, if an undergraduate program normally requires five academic\nyears of full time study, for more than ten semesters of full time\nstudy, or the equivalent of five academic years. Recipients enrolled in\na program of remedial study conforming to the provisions of this\narticle, approved by the commissioner in a degree granting institution,\nand intended to culminate in an undergraduate degree shall be considered\nas enrolled in a program normally requiring five years. No recipient\nenrolle...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the qualified veteran's death;\n  (ii) discharge or release for a medical condition that pre-existed\nservice;\n  (iii) discharge or release for hardship;\n  (iv) discharge or release for a physical or mental condition, not a\ndisability, that did not result from their willful misconduct but did\ninterfere with their performance of duty;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_A__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>discharge for a disability;\n  (vi) discharge for a reduction in force; or\n  (vii) involuntary force shaping.\n  d. The tuition award transfers designated by a qualified veteran\npursuant to this subdivision shall not exceed the award available to\nsuch veteran under this section.\n  e. The number of tuition award transfers under this subdivision shall\nnot exceed one hundred per year.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>