<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="670-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_670_A">
        <num>670-A</num>
        <heading>Empire state scholarships of excellence</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 670-a. Empire state scholarships of excellence.  1. Number and\ncertification. One thousand empire state scholarships of excellence\nshall be awarded each year. Such scholarships shall be allocated as\nprovided in article thirteen of this chapter to eligible students\ncertified to the president by the commissioner.\n  2. Duration. A scholarship shall entitle the recipient to an annual\naward for not more than four academic years of undergraduate study, or\nfive academic years if the program of study normally requires five years\nas defined by the commissioner pursuant to article thirteen of this\nchapter.\n  3. Amount. The annual award shall be in the amount of two thousand\ndollars provided in no event shall the amount of the annual award exceed\nthe recipient's cost of attendance at the institution attended. Cost of\nattendance shall mean tuition, required fees, laboratory and other\ninstruction related expenses, books, transportation, room and board. The\ncost of attendance however shall be reduced by the amount the recipient\nshall receive or would be entitled to receive as a Pell grant pursuant\nto section one thousand seventy-a of title twenty of the United States\nCode. Anything in this article to the contrary notwithstanding, a\nrecipient of an empire state scholarship of excellence may concurrently\nreceive with such award any other academic or general award for which he\nor she may be eligible provided however in no event shall the\ncombination of all such awards exceed the recipient's cost of attendance\nat the institution.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>