<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="670-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-670-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_670_B">
        <num>670-B</num>
        <heading>Scholarships for academic excellence</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_670_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the nineteen hundred ninety-seven--ninety-eight\nacademic year, there shall be two thousand scholarships in the amount of\none thousand dollars each and there shall be three thousand scholarships\nin the amount of five hundred dollars each.\n  (ii) For the nineteen hundred ninety-eight--ninety-nine academic year\nand thereafter, there shall be two thousand scholarships in the amount\nof one thousand five hundred dollars each and there shall be six\nthousand scholarships in the amount of five hundred dollars each.\n  (iii) Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, students\nawarded one thousand dollar scholarships in the nineteen hundred\nninety-seven--ninety-eight academic year shall be entitled in the\nnineteen hundred ninety-eight--ninety-nine academic year  and thereafter\nto an annual award of one thousand five hundred dollars.\n  b. In no event shall the amount of the annual award exceed the\nrecipient's cost of attendance at the institution attended.  Cost of\nattendance shall mean tuition, required fees, laboratory and other\ninstruction related expenses, books, transportation, room and board.\nAnything in this article to the contrary notwithstanding, a recipient of\na scholarship may concurrently receive with such award any other\nacademic or general award for which he or she may be eligible provided\nhowever in no event shall a recipient be awarded a scholarship in any\namount where the combination of all such awards would exceed the\nrecipient's cost of attendance at the institution.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>