<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6708"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6708"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6708"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6708/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6708/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6708/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6708/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6708">
        <num>6708</num>
        <heading>Definition of practice of veterinary technology</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6708. Definition of practice of veterinary technology.  1. The\npractice of the profession of veterinary technology is defined as the\nperformance of services within the field of veterinary medicine by a\nperson who, for compensation or personal profit, is employed by or under\nthe supervision of a veterinarian to perform such duties as are required\nin carrying out medical orders as prescribed by a licensed veterinarian\nrequiring an understanding of veterinary science, but not requiring\nprofessional service as set forth in section sixty-seven hundred one of\nthis article.\n  2. The commissioner shall promulgate regulations defining the\nfunctions an veterinary technician may perform that are consistent with\nthe training and qualifications for a license as an veterinary\ntechnician. The commissioner may further require that a licensee may\npractice within an area of specialization only upon the successful\ncompletion of an examination established for the purpose of establishing\ncompetence in a specific area of practice in the field of veterinary\ntechnology.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>