<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-671"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-671"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="671"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-671/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-671/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-671/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-671/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_671">
        <num>671</num>
        <heading>Regents professional education in nursing scholarships</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The annual award shall be five hundred dollars, but if the income\nexceeds one thousand eight hundred dollars, the award shall be reduced\nby one dollar for each ten dollars, or part thereof, of the excess. The\nminimum award shall be two hundred dollars. If the annual amount of\ntuition and educational fees payable by the student is more than three\nhundred fifty dollars, the award shall not exceed the amount of such\ntuition and fees; if the amount of such tuition and educational fees is\nthree hundred fifty dollars, or less, the award shall not exceed three\nhundred fifty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The annual award for any scholarship awarded pursuant to this\nsection and effective subsequent to the nineteen hundred\nseventy-three--nineteen hundred seventy-four school year shall be two\nhundred fifty dollars.  Provided, however, in the case of any student\nwho has received an award effective with the nineteen hundred\nseventy-four--nineteen hundred seventy-five school year, if the award of\ntwo hundred fifty dollars when combined with any award made pursuant to\nthe provisions of subdivision four of section six hundred sixty-seven of\nthis article would be less than the total of the combined awards he\nmight otherwise be entitled to receive pursuant to the provisions of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision and of subdivision three of section\nsix hundred sixty-seven, he shall be entitled to receive the combined\namount computed pursuant to the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision and of subdivision three of section six hundred sixty-seven.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>