<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6711-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6711_B">
        <num>6711-B</num>
        <heading>Mandatory continuing education for veterinary technicians</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6711_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each veterinary technician, licensed pursuant to this article,\nrequired to register triennially with the department to practice in this\nstate shall comply with the provisions of the mandatory continuing\neducation requirements, except as set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6711_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6711_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision. Veterinary technicians who do not satisfy the\nmandatory continuing education requirements shall not practice until\nthey have met such requirement and have been issued a registration or\nconditional registration certificate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6711_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Veterinary technicians shall be exempt from the mandatory\ncontinuing education requirement for the triennial registration period\nduring which they are first licensed. In accordance with the intent of\nthis section, adjustments to the mandatory continuing education\nrequirement may be granted by the department for reasons of health,\ncertified by a physician, for extended active duty with the armed forces\nof the United States, or for other good cause acceptable to the\ndepartment which may prevent compliance. Veterinary technicians engaged\non a full-time basis in the teaching of veterinary medicine at a\nveterinary education program registered by the department or an\naccrediting organization acceptable to the department shall be exempt\nfrom the requirements of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6711_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A licensed veterinary technician, not engaged in professional\npractice shall be exempt from the mandatory continuing education\nrequirement upon the filing of a statement with the department declaring\nsuch status. Any licensee who returns to the practice of veterinary\ntechnology shall notify the department prior to reentering the\nprofession and shall meet such mandatory continuing education\nrequirements as shall be prescribed by regulation of the commissioner.\n  2. During each triennial registration period an applicant for\nregistration shall complete a minimum of twenty-four hours of acceptable\nformal continuing education, a maximum of twelve hours of which may be\nself-instructional coursework acceptable to the department. Any\nveterinary technician whose first registration date following the\neffective date of this section occurs less than three years from such\neffective date, but on or after January first, two thousand twelve,\nshall complete continuing education hours on a prorated basis at the\nrate of one and one-quarter hours per month for the period beginning\nJanuary first, two thousand twelve up to the first registration date\nthereafter. A licensee who has not satisfied the mandatory continuing\neducation requirements shall not be issued a triennial registration\ncertificate by the department and shall not practice unless and until a\nconditional registration certificate is issued as provided in\nsubdivision three of this section, or until he or she has otherwise met\nthe requirements of this section. The individual licensee shall\ndetermine the selection of courses or programs of study pursuant to\nsubdivision four of this section.\n  3. The department, in its discretion, may issue a conditional\nregistration to a licensee who fails to meet the continuing education\nrequirements established in subdivision two of this section but who\nagrees to make up any deficiencies and take any additional education\nwhich the department may require. The fee f...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>