<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-672-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-672-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="672-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-672-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-672-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-672-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-672-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_672_A">
        <num>672-A</num>
        <heading>Regents professional education in optometry scholarships</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 672-a. Regents professional education in optometry scholarships.  1.\nNumber and certification. Five regents professional education in\noptometry scholarships shall be awarded each year. Such scholarships\nshall be allocated as provided in article thirteen to eligible students\nas certified to the president by the commissioner.\n  2. Duration. Such scholarship shall entitle the recipient to an award\nfor not more than four academic years while matriculated in an approved\nprogram, as defined by the commissioner pursuant to article thirteen.\n  3. Amount. The president shall make academic year awards in the amount\nof one thousand dollars, but if the income exceeds one thousand eight\nhundred dollars, the award shall be reduced by the amount of one dollar\nfor each eight dollars, or part thereof, of the excess, except that in\nno event shall the award be less than three hundred fifty dollars. If\nthe annual amount of tuition and educational fees payable by the student\nis more than three hundred fifty dollars, the award shall not exceed the\namount of such tuition and fees.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall only apply to any recipient\nwho receives his or her first award payment prior to the nineteen\nhundred eighty-five--nineteen hundred eighty-six academic year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>