<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6735"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6735"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6735"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6735/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6735/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6735/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6735/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6735">
        <num>6735</num>
        <heading>Limited permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6735. Limited permits. a. The department of education shall issue a\nlimited permit to an applicant who meets all requirements for admission\nto the licensing examination.\n  b. All practice under a limited permit shall be under the supervision\nof a licensed physical therapist in a public hospital, an incorporated\nhospital or clinic, a licensed proprietary hospital, a licensed nursing\nhome, a public health agency, a recognized public or non-public school\nsetting, the office of a licensed physical therapist, or in the civil\nservice of the state or political subdivision thereof.\n  c. Limited permits shall be for six months and the department may for\njustifiable cause renew a limited permit provided that no applicant\nshall practice under any limited permit for more than a total of one\nyear.\n  d. Supervision of a permittee by a licensed physical therapist shall\nbe on-site supervision and not necessarily direct personal supervision\nexcept that such supervision need not be on-site when the supervising\nphysical therapist has determined, through evaluation, the setting of\ngoals and the establishment of a treatment plan, that the program is one\nof maintenance as defined pursuant to title XVIII of the federal social\nsecurity act.\n  e. The fee for each limited permit and for each renewal shall be\nseventy dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>