<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6742-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6742_A">
        <num>6742-A</num>
        <heading>Mandatory continuing education</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6742_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each licensed\nphysical therapist and licensed physical therapist assistant required\nunder this article to register triennially with the department to\npractice in the state shall comply with the provisions of the mandatory\ncontinuing education requirements prescribed in subdivision two of this\nsection except as set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6742_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6742_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision. Licensed physical therapist and licensed physical therapist\nassistants who do not satisfy the mandatory continuing education\nrequirements shall not practice until they have met such requirements,\nand they have been issued a registration certificate, except that a\nlicensed physical therapist or licensed physical therapist assistant may\npractice without having met such requirements if he or she is issued a\nconditional registration certificate pursuant to subdivision three of\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6742_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each licensed physical therapist and licensed physical therapist\nassistant shall be exempt from the mandatory continuing education\nrequirement for the triennial registration period during which they are\nfirst licensed. In accordance with the intent of this section,\nadjustment to the mandatory continuing education requirement may be\ngranted by the department for reasons of health certified by an\nappropriate health care professional, for extended active duty with the\narmed forces of the United States, or for other good cause acceptable to\nthe department which may prevent compliance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6742_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A licensed physical therapist and licensed physical therapist\nassistant not engaged in practice, as determined by the department,\nshall be exempt from the mandatory continuing education requirement upon\nthe filing of a statement with the department declaring such status. Any\nlicensee who returns to the practice of physical therapy during the\ntriennial registration period shall notify the department prior to\nreentering the profession and shall meet such mandatory education\nrequirements as shall be prescribed by regulations of the commissioner.\n  2. During each triennial registration period an applicant for\nregistration as a licensed physical therapist or licensed physical\ntherapist assistant shall complete a minimum of thirty-six hours of\nacceptable formal continuing education, as specified in subdivision four\nof this section. Any licensed physical therapist or licensed physical\ntherapist assistant whose first registration date following the\neffective date of this section occurs less than three years from such\neffective date, but on or after January first, two thousand ten, shall\ncomplete continuing education hours on a prorated basis at the rate of\none-half hour per month for the period beginning January first, two\nthousand ten up to the first registration date thereafter. A licensee\nwho has not satisfied the mandatory continuing education requirements\nshall not be issued a triennial registration certificate by the\ndepartment and shall not practice unless and until a conditional\nregistration certificate is issued as provided for in subdivision three\nof this section. Continuing education hours taken during one triennium\nmay not be transferred to a subsequent triennium.\n  3. The department, in its discretion, may issue a conditional\nregistration to a licensee who fails to meet the continuing education\nrequirements established in subdivision two of this section but who\nagrees to make up any deficiencies and complete any additional education\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>