<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-676"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-676"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="676"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-676/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-676/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-676/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-676/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_676">
        <num>676</num>
        <heading>Empire state challenger fellowships for teachers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 676. Empire state challenger fellowships for teachers.  1. Number\nand certification. Two hundred full-time academic study fellowships and\ntwo hundred part-time academic study fellowships shall be awarded each\nyear. All such fellowships shall be awarded to eligible students\ncertified to the president by the commissioner pursuant to article\nthirteen of this chapter.\n  2. Duration. Each fellowship award pursuant to paragraph b or c of\nsubdivision eight of section six hundred five of this chapter shall\nentitle the recipient to an award for one academic year of full-time\nstudy while matriculated in an approved graduate program, as defined by\nthe commissioner pursuant to article thirteen of this chapter. Each\nfellowship awarded pursuant to paragraph d of subdivision eight of\nsection six hundred five of this chapter shall entitle the recipient to\nan award for not more than two academic years of part-time study while\nmatriculated in any approved graduate program, as defined by the\ncommissioner pursuant to article thirteen of this chapter. No recipient\nshall receive an award subsequent to completion of an approved graduate\nprogram leading to permanent certification as a teacher in the field or\nfields for which the fellowship was awarded.\n  3. Amount. The president shall make full-time academic study awards up\nto a maximum annual amount of four thousand dollars. The president shall\nmake part-time academic study awards up to a maximum annual amount of\none thousand dollars. Awards shall not exceed the recipient's cost of\nattendance at the institution. Cost of the attendance shall mean\ntuition, required fees, laboratory and other instruction related\nexpenses, books, transportation, room and board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>