<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="679-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_679_E">
        <num>679-E</num>
        <heading>New York state district attorney and indigent legal services attorney loan forgiveness program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Eligible attorney" means an attorney, who is a\nresident of and is admitted to practice law in New York state, who is\nemployed full-time as either a district attorney, as defined in\nsubparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, or an indigent legal services\nattorney, as defined in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, who is\nadmitted to practice law in this state for not more than eleven years or\nwho was within the eligible period as defined in paragraph b of this\nsubdivision during the time for which such person is seeking a student\nloan expense grant. Notwithstanding the foregoing, an eligible attorney\nshall include those district attorney applicants who were awarded\nprogram eligibility and who provided qualified service between April\nfirst, two thousand eight and March thirty-first, two thousand eleven;\nsuch an eligible attorney shall remain eligible to participate in the\nprogram provided they are within an eligible period measured from six\nyears from the date which such attorney was first employed as a district\nattorney.\n  (ii) "District attorney" means the district attorney of one of the\ncounties of the state or an employee of the office of any such district\nattorney.\n  (iii) "Indigent legal services attorney" means an attorney who is an\nemployee of (A) any agency designated by subdivisions one and two of\nsection seven hundred twenty-two of the county law, who is engaged in\nthe practice of criminal law on behalf of persons charged with a crime\nwho are financially unable to obtain counsel; (B) a not-for-profit\ncorporation that is exempt from the payment of federal income taxes\npursuant to section 501</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_679_E__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the internal revenue code and\nestablished for the purpose of providing legal services that include\ncivil legal services to persons within New York state who are\nfinancially unable to obtain counsel; or (C) an agency specified in\nclause (A) of this subparagraph and/or a corporation specified in clause\n(B) of this subparagraph and who provides a combination of the civil and\ncriminal services specified therein.\n  b. "Eligible period" means the six-year period after completion of the\nthird year and before the commencement of the tenth year of employment\nas an eligible attorney. For purposes of this section, all periods of\ntime during which an admitted attorney was employed as an eligible\nattorney and all periods of time during which a law school graduate\nawaiting admission to the New York state bar was employed by a\nprosecuting or criminal defense agency as permitted by section four\nhundred eighty-four of the judiciary law shall be combined.\n  c. "Student loan expense" me...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an application\ndeadline and (ii) a method of selecting recipients if in any given year\nthere are insufficient funds to cover the needs of all the applicants.\nAwards shall be within the amounts appropriated for such purpose and\nbased on availability of funds.\n  b. An eligible attorney may apply after the completion of the fourth\nyear of qualified service, and annually thereafter after the completion\nof the fifth through ninth year of qualified service, and may seek a\nstudent loan expense grant for only the previous year of qualified\nservice within the time periods prescribed by the president. An eligible\nattorney may receive student loan expense grants for no more than six\nyears of qualified service within an eligible period.\n  4. Rules and regulations. The president shall promulgate rules and\nregulations for the administration of this program. The president may\npromulgate rules and regulations to delegate to the entities employing\nthe eligible attorneys the responsibility to certify the employment\nstatus and the student loan balance of the applicants.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>