<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6812"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6812"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6812"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6812">
        <num>6812</num>
        <heading>Special provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6812. Special provisions. 1. Where any pharmacy, manufacturer,\nwholesaler or outsourcing facility registered by the department is\ndamaged by fire the board shall be notified within a period of\nforty-eight hours, and the board shall have power to impound all drugs\nfor analysis and condemnation, if found unfit for use. Where a pharmacy\nis discontinued, the owner of its prescription records shall notify the\ndepartment as to the disposition of said prescription records, and in no\ncase shall records be sold or given away to a person who does not\ncurrently possess a registration to operate a pharmacy.\n  2. Nothing in this article shall be construed as requiring the\nprosecution or the institution of injunction proceedings for minor\nviolations of this article whenever the public interest will be\nadequately served by a suitable written notice of warning.\n  3. The executive secretary of the state board of pharmacy is\nauthorized to conduct examinations and investigations for the purposes\nof this article through officers and employees of the United States, or\nthrough any health, food, or drug officer or employee of any city,\ncounty or other political subdivision of this state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>