<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6821"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6821"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6821"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6821/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6821/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6821/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6821/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6821">
        <num>6821</num>
        <heading>Poison schedules; register</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6821. Poison schedules; register.  1. The following schedules shall\nremain in force until revised by the board and approved by the\ndepartment.\n  Schedule A. Arsenic, atropine, corrosive sublimate, potassium cyanide,\nchloral hydrate, hydrocyanic acid, strychnine and all other poisonous\nvegetable alkaloids and their salts and oil of bitter almond containing\nhydrocyanic acid.\n  Schedule B. Aconite, belladonna, cantharides, colchicum, conium cotton\nroot, digitalis, ergot, hellebore, henbane, phytolacca, strophanthus,\noil of savin, oil of tansy, veratrum viride and their pharmaceutical\npreparations, arsenical solutions, carbolic acid, chloroform, creosote,\ncroton oil, white precipitate, methyl or wood alcohol, mineral acids,\noxalic acid, paris green, salts of lead, salts of zinc, or any drug,\nchemical or preparation which is liable to be destructive to adult human\nlife in quantities of sixty grains or less.\n  2. It shall be unlawful for any person to sell at retail or to furnish\nany of the poisons of schedules A and B without affixing or causing to\nbe affixed to the bottle, box, vessel or package, a label with the name\nof the article and the word "poison" distinctly shown and with the name\nand place of business of the seller all printed in red ink together with\nthe name of such poisons printed or written thereupon in plain, legible\ncharacters.\n  3. Manufacturers and wholesale dealers in drugs, medicines,\npharmaceutical preparations, chemicals or poisons shall affix or cause\nto be affixed to every bottle, box, parcel or outer inclosure of any\noriginal package containing any of the articles of schedule A a suitable\nlabel or brand in red ink with the word "poison" upon it.\n  4. Every person who disposes of or sells at retail or furnishes any\npoisons included in schedule A shall before delivering the same enter in\na book kept for that purpose the date of sale, the name and address of\nthe purchaser, the name and the quantity of the poison, the purpose for\nwhich it is purchased and the name of the dispenser. The poison register\nmust be always open for inspection by the proper authorities and must be\npreserved for at least five years after the last entry.  Such person\nshall not deliver any of the poisons of schedule A or schedule B until\nhe has satisfied himself that the purchaser is aware of its poisonous\ncharacter and that the poison is to be used for a legitimate purpose.\nThe provisions of this paragraph do not apply to the dispensing of drugs\nor poisons on a doctor's prescription.\n  5. The board may add to or may delete from any of the schedules from\ntime to time as such action becomes necessary for the protection of the\npublic.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>