<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-689"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-689"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="689"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-689/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-689/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-689/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-689/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_689">
        <num>689</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 689. Transfer of officers and employees.  1. Officers and employees\nof state departments and agencies may be transferred to the corporation\nand officers and employees of the corporation may be transferred to\nstate departments and agencies without examination and without loss of\nany civil service status or rights. No such transfer may, however, be\nmade except with the approval of the head of the state department or\ndivision involved and the director of the budget and the president of\nthe corporation and in compliance with the rules and regulations of the\nstate civil service commission.\n  2. Promotions from positions in state departments and agencies to\npositions in the corporation, and vice versa, may be made from\ninterdepartmental promotion lists resulting from promotion examinations\nin which both employees of the corporation and employees of the state\nare eligible to participate.\n  3. In computing seniority for purposes of promotion or for purposes of\nsuspension or demotion upon the abolition of positions in the service of\nthe corporation or in the service of the state, in the case of an\nemployee of the corporation a period of prior employment in the service\nof the state shall be counted in the same manner as though such period\nof employment had been in the service of the corporation, and in the\ncase of an employee of the state a period of prior employment in the\nservice of the corporation shall be counted in the same manner as though\nsuch period of employment had been in the service of the state.  For the\npurposes of the establishment and certification of preferred lists,\nemployees suspended from the corporation shall be eligible for\nreinstatement in the service of the state, and employees suspended from\nthe service of the state shall be eligible for reinstatement in the\nservice of the corporation, in the same manner as though the corporation\nwere a department of the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>