<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6905"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6905"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-06-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6905"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6905">
        <num>6905</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a license as a registered professional nurse</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6905. Requirements for a license as a registered professional nurse.\nTo qualify for a license as a registered professional nurse, an\napplicant shall fulfill the following requirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education, and a diploma or degree in\nprofessional nursing, in accordance with the commissioner's regulations,\nand in order to continue to maintain registration as a registered\nprofessional nurse in New York state, have attained a baccalaureate\ndegree or higher in nursing within ten years of initial licensure in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations. The department, in its\ndiscretion, may issue a conditional registration to a licensee who fails\nto complete the baccalaureate degree but who agrees to meet the\nadditional requirement within one year. The fee for such a conditional\nregistration shall be the same as, and in addition to, the fee for the\ntriennial registration. The duration of such conditional registration\nshall be for one year and may be extended, with the payment of a fee,\nfor no more than one additional year, unless the applicant can show good\ncause for non-compliance acceptable to the department. The department,\nin its discretion, may issue a temporary educational exemption to a\nlicensee who is unable to complete the baccalaureate degree due to a\nlack of access to educational programs. Licensees seeking a temporary\neducational exemption shall provide evidence of applying on at least two\noccasions to a baccalaureate degree program or programs and subsequently\nbeing denied access to such program or programs on at least two\noccasions due to there being a limited number of seats. Such denials\nshall also be corroborated by the higher education institution or\ninstitutions that the licensee applied to. Temporary educational\nexemptions issued pursuant to this subdivision shall be for a single two\nyear period. Licensees shall only be eligible for either a conditional\nregistration or a temporary educational exemption. The fee for such a\ntemporary educational exemption shall be the same as, and in addition\nto, the fee for the triennial registration. Any licensee who is notified\nof the denial of a registration for failure to complete the additional\neducational requirements and who practices as a registered professional\nnurse without such registration may be subject to disciplinary\nproceedings pursuant to section sixty-five hundred ten of this title;\n  (3) Experience: meet no requirement as to experience;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (5) Age: be at least eighteen years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship: meet no requirement as to United States citizenship;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of one hundred fifteen dollars to the department\nfor admission to a department conducted examination and for an initial\nlicense, a fee of forty-five dollars for each reexamination, a fee of\nseventy dollars for an initial license for persons not requiring\nadmission to a department conducted examination, and a fee of fifty\ndollars for each triennial registration period.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>