<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6906"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6906"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-06-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6906"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6906">
        <num>6906</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a license as a licensed practical nurse</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6906. Requirements for a license as a licensed practical nurse. To\nqualify for a license as a licensed practical nurse, an applicant shall\nfulfill these requirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education including completion of high\nschool or its equivalent, and have completed a program in practical\nnursing, in accordance with the commissioner's regulations, or\ncompletion of equivalent study satisfactory to the department in a\nprogram conducted by the armed forces of the United States or in an\napproved program in professional nursing;\n  (3) Experience: meet no requirement as to experience;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations, provided, however, that\nthe educational requirements set forth in subdivision two of this\nsection are met prior to admission for the licensing examination;\n  (5) Age: be at least seventeen years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship: meet no requirements as to United States citizenship;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of one hundred fifteen dollars to the department\nfor admission to a department conducted examination and for an initial\nlicense, a fee of forty-five dollars for each reexamination, a fee of\nseventy dollars for an initial license for persons not requiring\nadmission to a department conducted examination, and a fee of fifty\ndollars for each triennial registration period.\n  * (9) In conjunction with and as a condition of each triennial\nregistration, the department shall ask and a licensed practical nurse\nshall indicate whether the licensed practical nurse is or has previously\nbeen authorized as an advanced home health aide pursuant to subdivision\ntwo of section sixty-nine hundred eight of this article. The department\nshall provide responses to the department of health and the department\nof health shall include such information in reports related to advanced\nhome health aides.\n  * NB Repealed March 31, 2029\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>