<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-695-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-695-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-07-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="695-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-695-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-695-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-695-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-695-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_695_E">
        <num>695-E</num>
        <heading>Program requirements; family tuition account</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_695_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name, address and social security number, employer\nidentification number, or individual taxpayer identification number of\nthe account owner unless a family tuition account that was in effect\nprior to the effective date of the chapter of the laws of two thousand\nnineteen that amended this subparagraph does not allow for a taxpayer\nidentification number, in which case a taxpayer identification number\nshall be allowed upon the expiration of the contract;\n  (ii) the designation of a designated beneficiary;\n  (iii) the name, address, and social security number, employer\nidentification number, or individual taxpayer identification number of\nthe designated beneficiary, unless a family tuition account that was in\neffect prior to the effective date of the chapter of the laws of two\nthousand nineteen that amended this subparagraph does not allow for a\ntaxpayer identification number, in which case a taxpayer identification\nnumber shall be allowed upon the expiration of the contract; and\n  (iv) such other information as the program may require.\n  b. The comptroller and the corporation may establish a nominal fee for\nsuch application.\n  3. Any person, including the account owner, may make contributions to\nthe account after the account is opened.\n  4. Contributions to accounts may be made in cash or may be deposited\nby a taxpayer who has elected to contribute all or a portion of a refund\nof personal income tax to an account that has been established under\nthis article.\n  a. Taxpayer contributions shall be made by direct deposit to the\ndesignated account. The amount elected to be contributed by the taxpayer\nmust be at least twenty-five dollars and may be applied as a\ncontribution only for the tax year in which the refund is issued.\n  b. The election shall be made on a form prescribed by the department\nof taxation and finance and filed with the taxpayer's tax return for the\ntax year or at such other time and in such other manner as the\ndepartment ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_695_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_695_E__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, may open and\nbecome the account owner of an account to fund scholarships for persons\nwhose identity will be determined upon disbursement.\n  b. In the case of any account opened pursuant to paragraph a of this\nsubdivision the requirement set forth in subdivision two of this section\nthat a designated beneficiary be designated when an account is opened\nshall not apply and each individual who receives an interest in such\naccount as a scholarship shall be treated as a designated beneficiary\nwith respect to such interest.\n  13. An annual fee may be imposed upon the account owner for the\nmaintenance of the account.\n  14. The program shall disclose the following information in writing to\neach account owner and prospective account owner of a family tuition\naccount:\n  a. the terms and conditions for purchasing a family tuition account;\n  b. any restrictions on the substitution of beneficiaries;\n  c. the person or entity entitled t...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>