<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6955"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6955"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6955"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6955/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6955/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6955/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6955/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6955">
        <num>6955</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a professional license</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6955__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>complete educational preparation (degree or diploma granting) for\nthe practice of nursing, followed by or concurrently with educational\npreparation for the practice of midwifery in accordance with the\ncommissioner's regulations, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6955__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>submit evidence of license or certification, the educational\npreparation for which is determined by the department to be equivalent\nto the foregoing, from any state or country, satisfactory to the\ndepartment and in accordance with the commissioner's regulations, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6955__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>complete a program determined by the department to be equivalent\nto the foregoing and in accordance with the commissioner's regulations.\n  3. Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the department and\nin accordance with the commissioner's regulations.\n  4. Age: be at least twenty-one years of age.\n  5. Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment.\n  6. Citizenship or immigration status: be a United States citizen or a\nnoncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United\nStates.\n  7. Fee: pay a fee of one hundred ninety dollars to the department for\nadmission to a department conducted examination for an initial license,\na fee of one hundred dollars for each re-examination, a fee of one\nhundred fifteen dollars for an initial license for persons not requiring\nadmission to a department conducted examination, a fee of one hundred\neighty dollars for each triennial registration period and a fee of\nseventy dollars for a limited permit.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>