<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7004"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7004"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7004"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7004/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7004/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7004/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7004/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7004">
        <num>7004</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a professional license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7004. Requirements for a professional license.  To qualify for a\nlicense as a podiatrist, an applicant shall fulfill the following\nrequirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education, including a doctoral degree\nin podiatry, in accordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (3) Experience: have experience satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (5) Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship: meet no requirements as to United States citizenship;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of two hundred twenty dollars to the department\nfor admission to a department conducted examination and for an initial\nlicense, a fee of one hundred fifteen dollars for each reexamination, a\nfee of one hundred thirty-five dollars for an initial license for\npersons not requiring admission to a department conducted examination,\nand a fee of two hundred ten dollars for each triennial registration\nperiod.\n  (9) Continuing education: In accordance with the requirements of\nsection sixty-five hundred two of the education law, at the time of\nre-registration with the department, each applicant shall present\nsatisfactory evidence to the state board for podiatry that in the years\nprior to the filing for re-registration he attended the education\nprograms conducted by the podiatry society of the state of New York or\nthe equivalent of such educational programs as approved by the state\nboard for podiatry in accordance with the commissioner's regulations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>