<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7006"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7006"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7006"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7006">
        <num>7006</num>
        <heading>Special provision</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7006. Special provision. 1. No corporation, except a hospital\ncorporation authorized under article forty-three of the insurance law or\na corporation organized and existing under the laws of the state of New\nYork which, on or before the first day of March, nineteen hundred\nforty-two, was legally incorporated to practice podiatry, shall practice\npodiatry, and then only through licensed podiatrists and shall conform\nto board of regents rules. No corporation organized to practice podiatry\nshall change its name or sell its franchise or transfer its corporate\nrights directly or indirectly, by transfer of capital stock control or\notherwise, to any person or to another corporation without permission\nfrom the department and any corporation so changing its name or so\ntransferring its franchise or corporate rights without such permission\nor found guilty of violating a board of regents rule shall be deemed to\nhave forfeited its right to exist and shall be dissolved by a proceeding\nbrought by the attorney general.\n  2. Any manufacturer or merchant may sell, advertise, fit, or adjust\nproprietary foot remedies, arch supports, corrective foot appliances or\nshoes.\n  3. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, any licensed podiatrist who voluntarily and without the\nexpectation of monetary compensation renders first aid or emergency\ntreatment at the scene of an accident or other emergency, outside of a\nhospital or any other place having proper and necessary medical\nequipment, to a person who is unconscious, ill or injured shall not be\nliable for damages for injuries alleged to have been sustained by such\nperson or for damages for the death of such person alleged to have\noccurred by reason of an act or omission in the rendering of such first\naid or emergency treatment unless it is established that such injuries\nwere or such death was caused by gross negligence on the part of such\npodiatrist. Nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed or construed to\nrelieve a licensed podiatrist from liability for damages for injuries or\ndeath caused by an act or omission on the part of a podiatrist while\nrendering professional services in the normal and ordinary course of\npractice.\n  4. An unlicensed person may provide supportive services to a\npodiatrist incidental to and concurrent with such podiatrist personally\nperforming a service or procedure. Nothing in this subdivision shall be\nconstrued to allow an unlicensed person to provide any service which\nconstitutes the practice of podiatry as defined in this article. An\nunlicensed person providing supportive services to a podiatrist may\noperate radiographic equipment under direct supervision for the sole\npurpose of foot radiography provided that such person completes a course\nof study acceptable to the department in consultation with the\ndepartment of health.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>