<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7009"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7009"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7009"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7009/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7009/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7009/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7009/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7009">
        <num>7009</num>
        <heading>Podiatric ankle surgery privileges</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7009__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have graduated on or after June first, two thousand six from a\nthree-year residency program in podiatric medicine and surgery that was\naccredited by an accrediting agency acceptable to the department, and be\ncertified in reconstructive rearfoot and ankle surgery by a national\ncertifying board having certification standards acceptable to the\ndepartment; or\n  (ii) have graduated on or after June first, two thousand six from a\nthree-year residency program in podiatric medicine and surgery that was\naccredited by an accrediting agency acceptable to the department, be\nboard qualified but not yet certified in reconstructive rearfoot and\nankle surgery by a national certifying board having certification\nstandards acceptable to the department, and provide documentation that\nhe or she has acceptable training and experience in standard or advance\nmidfoot, rearfoot and ankle procedures that has been approved by the\ndepartment; or\n  (iii) have graduated before June first, two thousand six from a\ntwo-year residency program in podiatric medicine and surgery that was\naccredited by an accrediting agency acceptable to the department, be\ncertified in reconstructive rearfoot and ankle surgery by a national\ncertifying board having certification standards acceptable to the\ndepartment, and provide documentation that he or she has acceptable\ntraining and experience in standard or advanced midfoot, rearfoot and\nankle procedures that has been approved by the department;\n  d. Fees: pay a fee to the department of two hundred twenty dollars for\nthe issuance of a privilege to perform podiatric standard ankle surgery.\n  2. For issuance of a privilege to perform podiatric advanced ankle\nsurgery, as that term is used in subdivision two of section seven\nthousand one of this article, the applicant shall fulfill the following\nrequirements:\n  a. Application: file an application with the department;\n  b. License: be licensed as a podiatrist in the state;\n  c. Experience and...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7009__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have graduated on or after June first, two thousand six from a\nthree-year residency program in podiatric medicine and surgery that was\naccredited by an accrediting agency acceptable to the department, be\ncertified in reconstructive rearfoot and ankle surgery by a national\ncertifying board having certification standards acceptable to the\ndepartment, and provide documentation that he or she has acceptable\ntraining and experience in advanced midfoot, rearfoot and ankle\nprocedures that has been approved by the department; or\n  (ii) have graduated before June first, two thousand six from a\ntwo-year residency program in podiatric medicine and surgery that was\naccredited by an accrediting agency acceptable to the department, be\ncertified in reconstructive rearfoot and ankle surgery, by a national\ncertifying board having certification standards acceptable to the\ndepartment, and provide documentation that he or she has acceptable\ntraining and experience in advanced midfoot, rearfoot and ankle\nprocedures that has been approved by the department.\n  d. Fees: pay a fee to the department of two hundred twenty dollars for\nthe issuance of a privilege to perform podiatric advanced ankle surgery.\n  3. Duration and registration of privileges. A privilege issued under\nthis section shall be valid for the life of the holder, unless revoked,\nannulled, or suspended by the board of regents. Such a privilege shall\nbe subject to the same oversight and disciplinary provisions as licenses\nissued under this title. The holder of a privilege issued under this\nsection shall register with the department as a privilege holder in the\nsame manner and subject to the same provisions as required of a licensee\npursuant to section six thousand five hundred two of this title,\nprovided that, at the time of each registration, the privilege holder\nshall certify that he or she continues to meet the requirements for the\nprivilege set forth in this section. The fee for such registration...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>