<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7125"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7125"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7125"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7125">
        <num>7125</num>
        <heading>Exemptions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7125. Exemptions.  Nothing in this article shall be construed to\naffect or prevent:\n  a. An unlicensed person from performing merely mechanical work upon\ninert matter in an optical office, laboratory or shop; or\n  b. A student from engaging in clinical practice, under the supervision\nof a licensed ophthalmic dispenser or licensed optometrist or licensed\nphysician, in an ophthalmic dispensing school or college registered by\nthe department; or\n  c. The department from issuing a limited permit to an applicant who\nmeets all requirements for admission to the licensing examination;\nprovided, however, that:\n  (1) Practice under a limited permit shall be under the supervision of\na licensed physician, optometrist or ophthalmic dispenser.\n  (2) A limited permit shall expire after two years, or upon notice to\nthe applicant that the application for licensure has been denied, or ten\ndays after notification to the applicant of failure on the professional\nlicensing examination, whichever shall first occur. Notwithstanding the\nforegoing provisions of this subdivision, if the applicant is waiting\nthe result of a licensing examination at the time such limited permit\nexpires, such permit shall continue to be valid until ten days after\nnotification to the applicant of the results of such examination. A\nlimited permit which has not expired as a result of notice of denial of\nlicensure or of failure on the licensing examination may be renewed for\na period of not more than one additional year, upon a showing\nsatisfactory to the department that the applicant could not obtain a\nlicense within two years.\n  (3) Supervision of a permittee by a licensed physician, optometrist or\nophthalmic dispenser shall be on-site supervision but not necessarily\ndirect personal supervision.\n  (4) The fee for each limited permit and for each renewal shall be\nthirty-five dollars. The fee for issuance of a training permit shall be\nthirty dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>