<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7206"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7206">
        <num>7206</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a license as a professional engineer</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7206. Requirements for a license as a professional engineer. 1. To\nqualify for a license as a professional engineer an applicant shall\nfulfill the following requirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education, including a bachelor's or\nhigher degree based on a program in engineering or the substantial\nequivalent, in accordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (3) Experience: have at least four years in work satisfactory to the\nboard, provided that the board may accept study beyond the bachelor's\ndegree in partial fulfillment of this requirement;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (5) Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship or immigration status: be a United States citizen or a\nnoncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United\nStates;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of one hundred thirty-five dollars for an initial\nlicense and a fee of two hundred ten dollars for each triennial\nregistration period.\n  2. For an identification card as an "engineer in training", an\napplicant shall fulfill the requirements of paragraphs one, two, four\nand seven of subdivision one of this section. The fee for examination\nand identification card as an "engineer in training" shall be seventy\ndollars.\n  3. On recommendation of the board, the department may waive specific\nrequirements, except as to age, character and citizenship, in the case\nof applicants who are possessed of established and recognized standing\nin the engineering profession and who have practiced lawfully for more\nthan fifteen years.\n  4. Applicants who file with the department within two years of the\neffective date of this subdivision an application and fee requirements\npursuant to paragraphs one and eight of subdivision one of this section\nand who, at such time or anytime thereafter, demonstrate to the\nsatisfaction of the department that they have twelve years of practical\nexperience in work satisfactory to the board may substitute such\nexperience for the degree and experience requirements specified in\nparagraphs two and three of subdivision one of this section, provided\nthat each full year of study in engineering satisfactory to the\ndepartment may at the discretion of the board be accepted in lieu of up\nto two years of the required twelve years of experience.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>