<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7208-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7208-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7208-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7208-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7208-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7208-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7208-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7208_A">
        <num>7208-A</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons in or related to the profession of geology</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7208-a. Exempt persons in or related to the profession of geology.\nNothing in this article shall be construed to affect or prevent:\n  1. The employment and supervision of interns and other persons\nqualified by education or experience by professional geologists as\nassistants in the performance of geological services, or as consultants\nor employees in special fields related to but not uniquely geology,\nprovided that the professional geologist employing or supervising such\npersons shall not be relieved of any responsibility whatsoever by\ndelegation to such persons.\n  2. The practice of professional engineering by a professional engineer\nlicensed pursuant to this article to practice engineering in this state\nor an entity authorized pursuant to section seventy-two hundred ten of\nthis article to provide engineering in this state, including the\ninvestigation, acquisition, evaluation, and interpretation of the\nphysical and chemical properties of the soil, rock, groundwater, earth\nmaterials and data related thereto, and the performance of activities as\nspecified in section seventy-two hundred four-a of this article,\nprovided that no such person shall use the designation, or hold himself\nor herself out as a "professional geologist," unless licensed as such in\nthis state, and provided further that nothing in this chapter shall\npreclude a licensed professional engineer or authorized entity from\noffering to provide or providing the work enumerated in this\nsubdivision, however categorized, on the grounds that such licensed\nprofessional engineer or authorized entity is not licensed to practice\ngeology.\n  3. The practice of land surveying by any person that is licensed or\notherwise authorized to practice land surveying in this state, provided\nthat no such person shall use the designation or hold himself or herself\nout as a "professional geologist" unless licensed as such in this state.\n  4. The execution of work by contractors or by others of work prepared\nby a professional geologist, or the superintendence of such work as a\nsuperintendent, foreman or inspector.\n  5. The practice of the profession of geology by officers and employees\nof this state practicing solely as officers and employees; provided,\nhowever, that this exemption shall not apply to officers and employees\nof the state of New York who commence employment or the performance of\nwork related activities after the effective date of this section.\n  6. The execution of geological research and/or teaching conducted at\naccredited educational institutions and not-for-profit research\ninstitutions, conducted solely through those institutions.\n  7. Work customarily performed by physical or natural scientists\nprovided such work does not include geological investigations, being in\nresponsible charge of geological work, or the drawing of geological\nconclusions and recommendations.\n  8. Work customarily performed by water well drillers who have received\na certificate of registration pursuant to section 15-1525 of the\nenvironmental conservation law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>