<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7211"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7211">
        <num>7211</num>
        <heading>Mandatory continuing education for professional engineers, land surveyors and professional geologists</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each licensed\nprofessional required under this article to register triennially with\nthe department to practice in this state shall comply with provisions of\nthe mandatory continuing education requirements prescribed in\nsubdivision two of this section except as set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. Licensed professionals who do not satisfy\nthe mandatory continuing education requirements shall not practice until\nthey have met such requirements, and have been issued a registration\ncertificate, except that a licensed professional may practice without\nhaving met such requirements if he or she is issued a conditional\nregistration certificate pursuant to subdivision three of this section.\nFor purposes of this section the term "licensed professional" shall mean\nany individual licensed under this article as a professional engineer,\nland surveyor or professional geologist.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Licensed professionals shall be exempt from the mandatory\ncontinuing education requirement for the triennial registration period\nduring which they are first licensed. In accordance with the intent of\nthis section, adjustment to the mandatory continuing education\nrequirement may be granted by the department for reasons of health\ncertified by an appropriate health care professional, for extended\nactive duty with the armed forces of the United States, or for other\ngood cause acceptable to the department which may prevent compliance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A licensed professional not engaged in practice as determined by\nthe department shall be exempt from the mandatory continuing education\nrequirement upon the filing of a statement with the department declaring\nsuch status. Any licensee who returns to the practice of his or her\nprofession during the triennial registration period shall notify the\ndepartment prior to reentering the profession and shall meet such\nmandatory education requirements as shall be prescribed by regulations\nof the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7211__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Professional engineers directly employed on a full time basis by\nthe state of New York, its agencies, public authorities, public benefit\ncorporations or local governmental units prior to January first, two\nthousand four and who are represented by a collective bargaining unit or\nwho are designated managerial or confidential pursuant to article\nfourteen of the civil service law, at all times when so employed shall\nbe deemed to have satisfied the continuing education requirements of\nthis section, provided however that any such licensees who thereafter\nleave such employment and enter the practice of professional engineering\nin other capacities in New York, or otherwise engage in such practice,\nshall satisfy the requirements of this section in such manner as shall\nbe prescribed by regulations of the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7211__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Professional geologists directly employed on a full-time basis by\nthe state of New York, its agencies, public authorities, public benefit\ncorporations or local governmental units prior to January first, two\nthousand twenty-two and who are represented by a collective bargaining\nunit or who are designated managerial or confidential pursuant to\narticle fourteen of the civil service law, at all times when so employed\nshall be deemed to have satisfied the continuing education requirements\nof this section, provided however that any such licensees who thereafter\nleave such employment and enter the practice of professional geology in\nother capacities in New York, or otherwise engage in such practice,\nshall satisfy the requirements of this section in such manner as shall\nbe prescribed by regulations of the commissioner.\n  2. During each triennial registration period an applicant for\nregistration as a professional engineer and/or a professional geologist\nshall complete a minimum of thirty-six hours of acceptable continuing\neducation and an applicant for registration as a land surveyor shall\ncomplete a minimum of twenty-four hours of acceptable continuing\neducation as specified in subdivision four of this section. Any\nprofessional geologist whose first registration date following the\neffective date of the chapter of the laws of two thousand twenty which\namended this section occurs less than three years from such effective\ndate, but on or after January first, two thousand twenty-three, shall\ncomplete continuing education hours on a prorated basis at the rate of\none hour per month for the period beginning January first, two thousand\ntwenty-two up to the first registration date thereafter. A licensee who\nhas not satisfied the mandatory continuing education requirements shall\nnot be issued a triennial registration certificate by the department and\nshall not practice unless and until a conditional registration\ncertificate is issued as provided for in sub...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>