<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7304"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7304">
        <num>7304</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a professional license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7304. Requirements for a professional license.  1.  To qualify for a\nlicense as an architect, an applicant shall fulfill the following\nrequirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education, including a bachelor's or\nhigher degree in architecture, in accordance with the commissioner's\nregulations;\n  (3) Experience: have experience satisfactory to the board in\nappropriate architectural work and of sufficient amount so that the\ncombined college study and experience total eight years;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (5) Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship: meet no requirement as to United States citizenship;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of three hundred forty-five dollars to the\ndepartment for admission to a department conducted examination and for\nan initial license, a fee of one hundred seventy dollars for each\nreexamination, a fee of one hundred thirty-five dollars for an initial\nlicense for persons not requiring admission to a department conducted\nexamination, and a fee of two hundred ten dollars for each triennial\nregistration period.  The fee for a department conducted examination may\nbe prorated for candidates taking parts of the examination.\n  2. In lieu of degree and experience requirements specified in\nsubparagraphs (2) and (3) of subdivision one of this section, twelve\nyears of practical experience in architectural work of a grade and\ncharacter satisfactory to the board may be accepted by the department,\nprovided that each complete year of college study satisfactory to the\ndepartment may at the discretion of the board be accepted in lieu of two\nyears of experience but not to exceed nine years toward the required\ntotal of twelve years.\n  3. In lieu of degree, experience and examination requirements\nspecified in subparagraphs (2), (3) and (4) of subdivision one of this\nsection, ten years of lawful practice of architecture outside the state\nsatisfactory to the board may be accepted by the department upon the\npassing of a practical examination satisfactory to the board.\n  4. In lieu of degree, experience and examination requirements\nspecified in subparagraphs (2), (3) and (4) of subdivision one of this\nsection, a certificate of qualification issued by the national council\nof architectural registration boards on the basis of the fulfillment of\nrequirments satisfactory to the board may be accepted by the department,\nprovided further that the board shall be authorized to prepare and\nconduct examinations leading to certification of applicants by the\nnational council of architectural registration boards.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>