<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7306"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7306">
        <num>7306</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7306. Exempt persons.  1. This article shall not be construed to\naffect or prevent:\n  a. The preparation of details and shop drawings by persons, other than\narchitects, for use in connection with the execution of their work;\n  b. Employees of those lawfully practicing as architects under the\nprovisions of this article from acting under the instruction, control or\nsupervision of their employers;\n  c. Builders, or superintendents employed by such builders, from\nsupervising the construction or structural alteration of buildings or\nstructures; or\n  d. A holder of a valid certificate of the national council of\narchitectural registration boards, not licensed in this state, from\ncoming into the state for interview, but not to perform any\narchitectural services or enter into any contract until such time as he\nis licensed as an architect in this state.\n  e. The practice of engineering or land surveying by an engineer or\nland surveyor licensed in this state, or the practice of landscape\narchitecture by a landscape architect licensed in this state, provided\nthat no such engineer, land surveyor or landscape architect shall use\nthe designation "architect," or "architectural" or "architecture" unless\nlicensed as an architect in this state.\n  f. Employment of any person as a junior or assistant architect by the\nCity of New York in a position the title of which was approved and in\nuse as of July first, nineteen hundred seventy-one, provided such person\nacts under the general direction of a licensed architect.\n  g. Contractors or builders from engaging in construction management\nand administration of construction contracts.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>