<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7307"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7307">
        <num>7307</num>
        <heading>Special provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7307. Special provisions. 1. Every architect shall have a seal,\napproved by the board, which shall contain the name of the architect and\neither the words "Registered Architect" and such other words or figures\nas the board may deem necessary. All working drawings and\nspecifications, prepared by such architect or by a full-time or\npart-time subordinate employed under his supervision, shall be stamped\nwith such seal and shall also be signed on the original with the\npersonal signature of such architect when filed with public officials.\nExcept for plans and specifications excluded from the provisions of this\narticle by section seventy-three hundred six of this article, no\nofficial of this state, or of any county, city, town or village therein,\ncharged with the enforcement of laws, ordinances or regulations relating\nto the construction or alteration of buildings or structures, shall\naccept or approve any plans or specifications that are not stamped:\n  a. With the seal of an architect or professional engineer registered\nin this state and bearing the authorized facsimile of the signature of\nsuch architect or professional engineer; or\n  b. With the official seal and authorized facsimile of the signature of\nan architect or professional engineer not a resident of this state and\nhaving no established business in this state, but who is legally\nqualified to practice as such in his own state or country, provided that\nsuch person holds a limited permit issued by the department, and\nprovided further that the plans or specifications are accompanied by and\nhave attached thereto written authorization issued by the department for\nthe specific project.\n  2. Engineers, land surveyors, geologists, architects and landscape\narchitects may join in the formation of a joint enterprise, or a\npartnership or a professional service corporation or a design\nprofessional service corporation or may form any desired combination of\nsuch professions and may use in the name of such corporation the title\nof any of the professions which will be practiced. After the name of\neach member his or her profession shall be indicated.\n  3. A firm name may be continued by employees having at least fifteen\nyears of continuous service if the retired members and legal\nrepresentatives of deceased members consent to such continuance.\n  4. It shall be lawful for a corporation organized and existing under\nthe laws of the state of New York, and which on or before the twelfth\nday of April nineteen hundred twenty-nine and continuously thereafter\nwas lawfully practicing in New York state to continue such practice,\nprovided that the chief executive officer of such corporation in the\nstate of New York shall be an architect licensed under this article, and\nprovided further that the construction of buildings and structures shall\nbe under the personal supervision of such architect and that drawings,\nplans, and specifications shall be prepared under the personal direction\nand supervision of such architect and bear the stamp of his official\nseal, and the drawings or specifications shall also be signed on the\noriginal, with the personal signature of such architect. No such\ncorporation shall be permitted to change its name and continue to\npractice architecture, except upon the written approval of the\ndepartment.\n  5. This article shall not apply to: 1. Farm buildings, including\nbarns, sheds, poultry houses and other buildings used directly and\nsolely for agricultural purposes; nor to residence buildings of gross\narea of fifteen hundred square feet or less, not including garages,\ncarports, porches, cellars, or uninhabitable basements or attics; or\n  2. Alterations, costing ten thousand dollars or less, to any building\nor structure within the city of New York and twenty thousand dollars or\nless, to any building or structure outside the city of New York which do\nnot involve changes affecting the structural safety or public safety\nthereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>