<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7327"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7327"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7327"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7327/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7327/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7327/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7327/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7327">
        <num>7327</num>
        <heading>Special provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7327. Special provisions. 1. Every landscape architect shall have a\nseal, approved by the board, which shall contain the name of the\nlandscape architect and either the words "Registered Landscape\nArchitect" and such other words or figures as the board may deem\nnecessary. All working drawings and specifications prepared by such\nlandscape architect relating to the setting, approaches or environment\nfor structures or other improvements or under the supervision of such\nlandscape architect, shall be stamped with such seal and signed on the\noriginal, with the personal signature of such landscape architect when\nfiled with public officials, or with the official seal and personal\nsignature of a landscape architect granted a limited permit under\nsection seventy-three hundred twenty-five of this article when such\ndrawings and specifications are accompanied by a written authorization\nfrom the department for the specific project concerned.\n  2. Engineers, land surveyors, geologists, architects and landscape\narchitects may join in the formation of a joint enterprise, or a\npartnership or a professional service corporation or a design\nprofessional service corporation or may form any desired combination of\nsuch professions and may use in the name of such corporation the title\nof any of the professions which will be practiced. After the name of\neach member his or her profession shall be indicated.\n  3. A firm name may be continued by employees having at least fifteen\nyears of continuous service if the retired members and legal\nrepresentatives of deceased members consent to such continuance.\n  4. It shall be lawful for a corporation organized and existing under\nthe laws of the state of New York, and which on or before the first day\nof April nineteen hundred sixty-one was legally incorporated to practice\nlandscape architecture, while conforming to the provisions of this\ntitle, and which has been continuously engaged in such practice since\nsuch time to continue such practice provided that the chief executive\nofficer of such corporation in the state of New York shall be a\nlandscape architect licensed under this article, and provided further\nthat the supervision of such projects shall be under the personal\nsupervision of such landscape architect and that such plans and designs\nshall be prepared under the personal direction and supervision of such\nlandscape architect and bear the stamp of his official seal, and such\ndrawings or specifications shall also be signed on the original, with\nthe personal signature of such landscape architect. No such corporation\nshall be permitted to change its name and continue to practice landscape\narchitecture, except upon the written approval of the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>