<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-752"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-752"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="752"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-752/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-752/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-752/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-752/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_752">
        <num>752</num>
        <heading>Loan of computer software</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 752. Loan of computer software.  1. In the several cities and school\ndistricts of the state, boards of education, trustees or such body or\nofficers as perform the function of such boards shall have the power and\nduty to loan upon request of an individual or a group of individual\npupils, to all pupils defined in subdivision three of section seven\nhundred fifty-one of this article, software programs. Software programs\nloaned to such pupils attending private schools shall be software\nprograms which are designated for use in any public elementary or\nsecondary schools of the state or are approved by any board of\neducation, trustees or other school authorities. Such software programs\nare to be loaned free to such children subject to such rules and\nregulations as are or may be prescribed by the board of regents and such\nboards of education, trustees or other school authorities.\n  2. No school district shall be required to loan software programs in\nexcess of the software programs owned or acquired by such district\npursuant to section seven hundred fifty-one of this article. Such\nsoftware programs shall be loaned on an equitable basis to children\ndefined in subdivision three of section seven hundred fifty-one of this\narticle attending in the current year. The payment of tuition under\narticle eighty-nine of this chapter is deemed to be an equitable loan to\nchildren for whom such tuition is paid.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>