<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-754"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-754"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="754"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-754/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-754/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-754/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-754/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_754">
        <num>754</num>
        <heading>Loan of instructional computer hardware</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 754. Loan of instructional computer hardware. 1. In the several\ncities and school districts of the state, school authorities, as defined\nin subdivision twelve of section two of this chapter, shall have the\npower and duty, to the extent provided in this section, to loan, upon\nrequest of an individual or a group of individual pupils, to all pupils\nlegally attending nonpublic elementary or secondary schools located in\nthe school district, instructional computer hardware which is designated\nfor use in any public elementary or secondary schools of the state or is\napproved by any school authorities. Such instructional computer hardware\nis to be loaned free to such children, commencing with the two thousand\nseven--two thousand eight school year, subject to such rules and\nregulations as are or may be prescribed by the board of regents and such\nschool authorities.\n  2. No school district shall be required to loan instructional computer\nhardware in excess of the instructional computer hardware acquired by\nsuch district pursuant to section seven hundred fifty-three of this\narticle. Such instructional computer hardware shall be loaned on an\nequitable basis to children attending nonpublic schools in the district\nin the current year, provided that nothing in this article shall be\nconstrued to require a school district to loan to children attending\nnonpublic schools, pursuant to this section, instructional computer\nhardware purchased with local or federal funds or with state funds other\nthan funds apportioned pursuant to this article. The payment of tuition\nunder article eighty-nine of this chapter is deemed to be an equitable\nloan to children for whom such tuition is paid, and the provisions of\nthis section shall not apply.\n  3. School authorities shall adopt regulations specifying the date by\nwhich requests for the purchase and loan of instructional computer\nhardware must be received by the district. Notice of such date shall be\ngiven to all non-public schools in the school district. Such date shall\nnot be earlier than the first day of June of the school year prior to\nthat for which such instructional computer hardware is being requested,\nprovided, however, that a parent or guardian of a child not attending a\nparticular non-public school prior to June first of the school year may\nsubmit a written request for instructional computer hardware within\nthirty days after such child is enrolled in such non-public school. In\nno event, however, shall a request made later than the times otherwise\nprovided pursuant to this subdivision be denied where a reasonable\nexplanation is given for the delay in making the request.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>