<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-755"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-755"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="755"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-755/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-755/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-755/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-755/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_755">
        <num>755</num>
        <heading>Loan of smart schools classroom technology</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 755. Loan of smart schools classroom technology. 1. In the several\ncities and school districts of the state, school authorities, as defined\nin subdivision twelve of section two of this chapter, shall have the\npower and duty, to the extent provided in this section, to loan, upon\nrequest of an individual or a group of individual pupils, to all pupils\nlegally attending nonpublic elementary or secondary schools located in\nthe school district, smart schools classroom technology acquired\npursuant to subdivision sixteen of section thirty-six hundred forty-one\nof this chapter which is designated for use in any public elementary or\nsecondary schools of the state or is approved by any school authorities.\nSuch smart schools classroom technology made available to nonpublic\nstudents shall be limited to that allowable under both paragraph seven\nof subdivision sixteen of section thirty-six hundred forty-one of this\nchapter and section seven hundred fifty-four of this article. Such smart\nschools classroom technology is to be loaned free to such children,\ncommencing with the two thousand fourteen--two thousand fifteen school\nyear, subject to such rules and regulations as are or may be prescribed\nby the board of regents and such school authorities.\n  2. No school district shall be required to loan smart schools\nclassroom technology in excess of the smart schools classroom technology\nacquired by such district pursuant to subdivision sixteen of section\nthirty-six hundred forty-one of this chapter. Such smart schools\nclassroom technology shall be loaned on an equitable basis to children\nattending nonpublic schools in the district in the current year,\nprovided that nothing in this article shall be construed to require a\nschool district to loan to children attending nonpublic schools,\npursuant to this section, classroom technology purchased with local or\nfederal funds or with state funds other than funds apportioned pursuant\nto subdivision sixteen of section three hundred sixty-four of this\nchapter, and provided further that no school district may loan smart\nschools classroom technology in an aggregate amount greater than two\nhundred fifty dollars multiplied by the nonpublic school enrollment in\nthe base year, at time of enactment, as defined in subparagraph three of\nparagraph n of subdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this\nchapter. The payment of tuition under article eighty-nine of this\nchapter is deemed to be an equitable loan to children for whom such\ntuition is paid, and the provisions of this section shall not apply.\n  3. School authorities shall adopt regulations specifying the date by\nwhich requests for the purchase and loan of smart schools classroom\ntechnology must be received by the district. Notice of such date shall\nbe given to all non-public schools in the school district. For the two\nthousand fourteen--two thousand fifteen school year, such date shall not\nbe earlier than the first day of January of such school year, and for\nthe two thousand fifteen--two thousand sixteen school year and\nthereafter, such date shall not be earlier than the first day of June of\nthe school year prior to that for which such smart schools classroom\ntechnology is being requested, provided, however, that a parent or\nguardian of a child not attending a particular non-public school prior\nto January first or June first of the school year, as applicable, may\nsubmit a written request for smart schools classroom technology within\nthirty days after such child is enrolled in such non-public school. In\nno event, however, shall a request made later than the times otherwise\nprovided pursuant to this subdivision be denied where a reasonable\nexplanation is given for the delay in making the request.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>