<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7807"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7807"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7807"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7807">
        <num>7807</num>
        <heading>Mandatory continuing education</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7807__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each massage therapist\nlicensed pursuant to this article required to register triennially with\nthe department to practice in the state shall comply with the provisions\nof the mandatory continuing education requirements prescribed in\nsubdivision two of this section except as set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7807__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7807__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. Massage therapists who do not satisfy the\nmandatory continuing education requirements shall not practice until\nthey have met such requirements, and they have been issued a\nregistration certificate, except that a massage therapist may practice\nwithout having met such requirements if he or she is issued a\nconditional registration certificate pursuant to subdivision three of\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7807__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Massage therapists shall be exempt from the mandatory continuing\neducation requirement for the triennial registration period during which\nthey are first licensed. In accord with the intent of this section,\nadjustments to the mandatory continuing education requirement may be\ngranted by the department for reasons of health certified by an\nappropriate health care professional, for extended active duty with the\narmed forces of the United States, or for other good cause acceptable to\nthe department which may prevent compliance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7807__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A licensed massage therapist not engaged in professional practice,\nas determined by the department, shall be exempt from the mandatory\ncontinuing education requirement upon the filing of a statement with the\ndepartment declaring such status. Any licensee who returns to the\npractice of massage therapy during the triennial registration period\nshall notify the department prior to reentering the profession and shall\nmeet such mandatory education requirements as shall be prescribed by\nregulations of the commissioner.\n  2. During each triennial registration period an applicant for\nregistration as a massage therapist shall complete a minimum of\nthirty-six hours of acceptable formal continuing education, a maximum of\ntwelve hours of which may be self-instructional course work acceptable\nto the department. Any massage therapist whose first registration date\nfollowing the effective date of this section occurs less than three\nyears from such effective date, shall complete continuing education\nhours on a prorated basis at the rate of one hour per month for the\nperiod beginning January first, two thousand twelve up to the first\nregistration date thereafter. A licensee who has not satisfied the\nmandatory continuing education requirements shall not be issued a\ntriennial registration certificate by the department and shall not\npractice unless and until a conditional registration certificate is\nissued as provided for in subdivision three of this section, or until he\nor she has otherwise met the requirements of this section.\n  3. The department, in its discretion, may issue a conditional\nregistration to a licensee who fails to meet the continuing education\nrequirements established in subdivision two of this section but who\nagrees to make up any deficiencies and complete any additional education\nwhich the department may require. The fee for such a conditional\nregistration shall be the same as, and in addition to, the fee for the\ntriennial registration. The...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>