<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7905"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7905"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7905"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7905">
        <num>7905</num>
        <heading>Limited permits</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7905__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An occupational therapist who has graduated from an occupational\ntherapy curriculum with a baccalaureate degree or certificate in\noccupational therapy which is substantially equivalent to a\nbaccalaureate degree satisfactory to the board of occupational therapy\nand in accordance with the commissioner's regulations; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7905__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign occupational therapist who is in this country on a\nnon-immigration visa for the continuation of occupational therapy study,\npursuant to the exchange student program of the United States Department\nof State.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7905__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An occupational therapy assistant who has graduated from an\naccredited occupational therapy assistant curriculum with an associate's\ndegree satisfactory to the board of occupational therapy and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7905__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A limited permittee shall be authorized to practice occupational\ntherapy, or in the case of a limited permit issued pursuant to paragraph\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7905__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this section, only under the direct\nsupervision of a licensed occupational therapist or a licensed physician\nand shall practice only in a public, voluntary, or proprietary hospital,\nhealth care agency or in a preschool or an elementary or secondary\nschool for the purpose of providing occupational therapy as a related\nservice for a handicapped child.\n  For purposes of this subdivision, supervision of an individual with a\nlimited permit to practice occupational therapy issued by the department\nshall be direct supervision as defined by the commissioner's\nregulations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7905__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A limited permit shall be valid for one year. It may be renewed\nonce for a period not to exceed one additional year, at the discretion\nof the department, upon the submission of an explanation satisfactory to\nthe department for an applicant's failure to become licensed within the\noriginal one-year period.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7905__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fee for a limited permit shall be seventy dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>