<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="803-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_803_B">
        <num>803-B</num>
        <heading>Courses of study in prevention of child sexual exploitation and child sexual abuse</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 803-b. Courses of study in prevention of child sexual exploitation\nand child sexual abuse. 1. All pupils in grades K-8 in all public\nschools in the state shall receive instruction designed to prevent child\nsexual exploitation and child sexual abuse. Such program shall be\ndefined by the commissioner in regulations after consultation with the\ndepartment of health and be designed to educate students, parents and\nschool personnel about the prevention of child sexual exploitation and\nchild sexual abuse in grades kindergarten through eight. Such program\nshall include, but not be limited to students and parents. Nothing in\nthis section shall prevent the department from making model curriculum\nand resource materials available on the department's website.\n  2. The commissioner may provide technical assistance to assist in the\ndevelopment of curricula for such courses of study which shall be age\nappropriate and developed according to the needs and abilities of pupils\nat successive grade levels in order to provide awareness, skills,\ninformation, self-confidence and support to aid in the prevention of\nchild sexual exploitation and child sexual abuse.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>