<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="804-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_804_A">
        <num>804-A</num>
        <heading>Comprehensive school health education demonstration program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_804_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such grants shall include the development, implementation, and\nevaluation of a comprehensive health education program including such\nactivities as:\n  (A) coordination of health instruction with other available programs\nin the school and the community related to health education;\n  (B) provision of inservice training and materials for elementary level\nschool teachers in comprehensive health education;\n  (C) development and implementation of evaluation procedures to measure\nstudents' knowledge, skills, behaviors, and attitudes prior to and after\nproject implementation; and\n  (D) development and implementation of a mechanism for project\nmaintenance and long-range programming.\n  (ii) Upon successful completion of the above activities and the\navailability of funds, such grant recipients will assist other local\neducational agencies with replication.\n  b. Health education regional training centers. Regional training\ncenters for the purpose of developing materials and providing training\nprograms to meet the needs of teachers statewide in the implementation\nof comprehensive school health education programs at the elementary\nlevel will be established.\n  c. Statewide advocacy for comprehensive health education. Development\nand implementation of a statewide advocacy program to create an\nawareness on the part of school administrators of the need to develop\nstrategies for implementing comprehensive school health education\nprograms at the elementary level.\n  d. Replication of validated health education programs. Grants will be\nawarded to local school districts or boards of cooperative educational\nservices for the replication of nationally or state-validated exemplary\nhealth education programs.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>