<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-807"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-807"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="807"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_807">
        <num>807</num>
        <heading>Fire and emergency drills</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 807. Fire and emergency drills. 1. It shall be the duty of the\nprincipal or other person in charge of every public or private school or\neducational institution within the state, other than colleges or\nuniversities, to instruct and train the pupils by means of drills, so\nthat they may in a sudden emergency be able to respond appropriately in\nthe shortest possible time and without confusion or panic. Such drills\nshall be held at least twelve times in each school year, eight of which\nrequired drills shall be held between September first and December\nthirty-first of each such year. Eight of all such drills shall be\nevacuation drills, four of which shall be through use of the fire\nescapes on buildings where fire escapes are provided or through the use\nof identified secondary means of egress. Four of all such required\ndrills shall be lock-down drills. Drills shall be conducted at different\ntimes of the school day. Pupils shall be instructed in the procedure to\nbe followed in the event that a fire occurs during the lunch period or\nassembly, provided however, that such additional instruction may be\nwaived where a drill is held during the regular school lunch period or\nassembly. Four additional drills shall be held in each school year\nduring the hours after sunset and before sunrise in school buildings in\nwhich students are provided with sleeping accommodations. At least two\nadditional drills shall be held during summer school in buildings where\nsummer school is conducted, and one of such drills shall be held during\nthe first week of summer school.\n  1-a. In the case of after-school programs, events or performances\nwhich are conducted within a school building and which include persons\nwho do not regularly attend classes in such school building, the\nprincipal or other person in charge of the building shall require the\nteacher or person in charge of such after-school program, event or\nperformance to notify persons in attendance at the beginning of each\nsuch program, event or performance, of the procedures to be followed in\nthe event of an emergency so that they may be able to respond in a\ntimely, orderly manner.\n  2. It shall be the duty of the board of education or school board or\nother body having control of the schools in any district or city to\ncause a copy of this section to be printed in the manual or handbook\nprepared for the guidance of teachers, where such manual or handbook is\nin use or may hereafter come into use.\n  3. It shall be the duty of the person in charge of every public or\nprivate college or university within the state, to instruct and train\nthe students by means of drills, so that they may in a sudden emergency\nbe able to leave the college or university building in the shortest\npossible time and without confusion or panic. Such drills shall be held\nat least three times in each year, one of which required drills shall be\nheld between September first and December first of each such year. In\nbuildings where summer sessions are conducted, one of such required\ndrills shall be held during the first week of such summer session. At\nleast one of such required drills shall be through use of the fire\nescapes on buildings where fire escapes are provided. At least one\nadditional drill shall be held in each year during the hours after\nsunset and before sunrise in college or university buildings in which\nstudents are provided with sleeping accommodations.\n  4. Neglect by any principal or other person in charge of any public or\nprivate school or educational institution to comply with the provisions\nof this section shall be a misdemeanor punishable at the discretion of\nthe court by a fine not exceeding fifty dollars; such fine to be paid to\nthe pension fund of the local fire department where there is such a\nfund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>