<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-809"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-809"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="809"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-809/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-809/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-809/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-809/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_809">
        <num>809</num>
        <heading>Instruction in the humane treatment of animals</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>micro-organisms which\ncause disease in humans or animals, (ii) ionizing radiation, (iii) known\ncancer producing agents, (iv) chemicals at toxic levels,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>drugs\nproducing pain or deformity, (vi) severe extremes of temperature, (vii)\nelectric or other shock, (viii) excessive noise, (ix) noxious fumes,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nexercise to exhaustion, (xi) overcrowding, (xii) paralysis by muscle\nrelaxants or other means, (xiii) deprivation or excess of food, water or\nother essential nutrients, (xiv) surgery or other invasive procedures,\n(xv) other extreme stimuli, or (xvi) termination of life.\n  b. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this section, the\ncommissioner may, upon the submission of a written program plan, issue\nto such school a written waiver of such restrictions for students\nsubject to the following provisions:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the student shall be in grade\nten, eleven, or twelve; and (ii) the student shall be under the\nsupervision of one or more teachers certified in science; and (iii) the\nstudent shall be pursuing an accelerated course of study in the sciences\nas defined by the commissioner in preparation for taking a state or\nnational advanced placement examination. The commissioner shall issue a\nwaiver of such restrictions for any teacher certified in science\ninstructing such student. The written program plan shall include, but\nnot be limited to:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the educational basis for requesting a waiver;\n(ii) the objective of the lesson or experiment; (iii) the methods and\ntechniques to be used; and (iv) any other information required by the\ncommissioner.\n  6. Report. On or before the first day of January next succeeding the\neffective date of this amended section, the commissioner shall annually\nsubmit a report to the governor and the legislature which shall include,\nbut not be limited to, the number of written program plan proposals\nsubmitted by schools and the number of such proposals subsequently\napproved by the commissioner. In those cases where a program plan\nproposal has been approved by the commissioner, such plan shall be\nappended to and become a part of the commissioner's annual report.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>