<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8207"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8207">
        <num>8207</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8207. Exempt persons.  This article shall not be construed as\nprohibiting:\n  (1) The practice of any other professions licensed or registered under\nthis title.\n  (2) Any person employed by the federal, state or a local government or\nby a public or non-public elementary or secondary school or an\ninstitution of higher learning from performing the duties of a\nspeech-language pathologist, an audiologist, a teacher of the speech and\nhearing handicapped, or a teacher of the deaf in the course of such\nemployment.\n  (3) Any person from engaging in clinical or academic practice under\nthe supervision of a licensed speech-language pathologist or audiologist\nfor such period of time as may be necessary to complete an experience\nrequirement for a professional license, as provided in this article and\nin rules or regulations approved by the board of regents with the advice\nof the state board for speech-language pathology and audiology.\n  (4) A person from another state from performing speech-language\npathology or audiology services in this state provided such services are\nperformed for no more than thirty days in any calendar year and provided\nthat such services are performed in conjunction with and/or under the\nsupervision of a speech-language pathologist or audiologist licensed\nunder this article.\n  (5) Any hearing aid dealer from performing hearing measurements by\nmeans of an audiometer or other testing equipment when used solely for\nthe purpose of selecting, fitting, selling or dispensing an instrument\ndesigned to aid or improve human hearing, including the taking of\nimpressions for the making and fitting of ear molds and the\ndemonstration of use and instructions of persons in the use of such\nhearing aids and accessories thereto.\n  (6) A student from engaging in clinical practice, under the\nsupervision of a licensed audiologist or a licensed speech-language\npathologist as part of a nationally accredited program or a state\nlicensure qualifying program in speech-language pathology or audiology,\npursuant to subdivision three of section eighty-two hundred six of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>