<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8208"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8208"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8208"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8208">
        <num>8208</num>
        <heading>Special provisions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8208__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association certificate of\nclinical competence in speech-language pathology and/or audiology, or\nthe equivalent thereof as determined by the board in accordance with the\ncommissioner's regulations; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8208__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a masters degree in speech-language pathology, audiology or\ncommunication disorders appropriate to the license being sought and a\ntotal of five years experience; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8208__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bachelors degree in speech-language pathology, audiology or\ncommunication disorders appropriate to the license being sought and\nthirty postgraduate semester hours in subjects satisfactory to the board\nand a total of five years experience; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8208__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bachelors degree and sufficient postgraduate study to be the\nequivalent of a masters degree in speech-language pathology, audiology\nor communication disorders as determined by the board in accordance with\nthe commissioner's regulations and a total of five years experience.\n  Applications for a license under this section shall be submitted by\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred eighty and applicants shall have until\nthat date to fulfill the requirements set forth by this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8208__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This article shall not prohibit the practice of speech-language\npathology or audiology by a corporation provided that such practice is\ncarried on by a licensed speech-language pathologist or audiologist or\npersons exempt under this article and a violation of this provision\nshall be a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8208__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person or firm offering the services of a speech-language\npathologist or audiologist shall employ only persons licensed or exempt\nunder this article and a violation of this provision shall be a Class A\nmisdemeanor.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8208__subsec_d__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8208__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, pursuant to the recommendation of the board\nshall promulgate regulations defining appropriate standards of conduct\nfor the dispensing of hearing aids by licensed audiologists. Such\nregulations shall also define continuing education requirements which\nsuch dispensing audiologist shall meet as a condition of maintaining\nregistration pursuant to this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8208__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Audiologists engaged in the practice of dispensing hearing aids\nshall comply with the applicable provisions of article thirty-seven-a of\nthe general business law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>