<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8209"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8209">
        <num>8209</num>
        <heading>Mandatory continuing competency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8209__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each licensed\nspeech-language pathologist and audiologist required under this article\nto register triennially with the department to practice in the state\nshall comply with the provisions of the mandatory continuing competency\nrequirements prescribed in subdivision two of this section, except as\nprovided in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8209__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8209__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. Speech-language\npathologists and audiologists who do not satisfy the mandatory\ncontinuing competency requirements shall not be authorized to practice\nuntil they have met such requirements, and they have been issued a\nregistration certificate, except that a speech-language pathologist or\naudiologist may practice without having met such requirements if he or\nshe is issued a conditional registration pursuant to subdivision three\nof this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8209__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Speech-language pathologists and audiologists shall be exempt from\nthe mandatory continuing competency requirement for the triennial\nregistration period during which they are first licensed. Adjustment to\nthe mandatory continuing competency requirements may be granted by the\ndepartment for reasons of health of the licensee where certified by an\nappropriate health care professional, for extended active duty with the\narmed forces of the United States, or for other good cause acceptable to\nthe department which may prevent compliance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8209__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A licensed speech-language pathologist or audiologist not engaged\nin practice, as determined by the department, shall be exempt from the\nmandatory continuing competency requirement upon the filing of a\nstatement with the department declaring such status. Any licensee who\nreturns to the practice of speech-language pathology or audiology during\nthe triennial registration period shall notify the department prior to\nreentering the profession and shall meet such mandatory continuing\ncompetency requirements as shall be prescribed by regulations of the\ncommissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8209__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>During each triennial registration period an applicant for\nregistration as either a speech-language pathologist or audiologist\nshall complete a minimum of thirty hours of learning activities which\ncontribute to continuing competence, as specified in subdivision four of\nthis section, provided further that at least twenty hours shall be in\nrecognized areas of study pertinent to the licensee's professional scope\nof practice of speech language pathology and/or audiology. Any\nspeech-language pathologist or audiologist whose first registration date\nfollowing the effective date of this section occurs less than three\nyears from such effective date, but on or after January first, two\nthousand one, shall complete continuing competency hours on a prorated\nbasis at the rate of one-half hour per month for the period beginning\nJanuary first, two thousand one up to the first registration date.\nThereafter, a licensee who has not satisfied the mandatory continuing\ncompetency requirements ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8209__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department, in its discretion, may issue a conditional\nregistration to a licensee who fails to meet the continuing competency\nrequirements established in subdivision two of this section, but who\nagrees to make up any deficiencies and complete any additional learning\nactivities which the department may require. The fee for such a\nconditional registration shall be the same as, and in addition to, the\nfee for the triennial registration. The duration of such conditional\nregistration shall be determined by the department but shall not exceed\none year. Any licensee who is notified of the denial of registration for\nfailure to submit evidence, satisfactory to the department, of required\ncontinuing competency learning activities and who practices without such\nregistration, may be subject to disciplinary proceedings pursuant to\nsection sixty-five hundred ten of this title.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8209__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in subdivision two of this section, "acceptable learning\nactivities" shall mean activities which contribute to professional\npractice in speech-language pathology and/or audiology, and which meet\nthe standards prescribed in the regulations of the commissioner. Such\nlearning activities shall include, but not be limited to, collegiate\nlevel credit and non-credit courses, self-study activities, independent\nstudy, formal mentoring activities, publications in professional\njournals, professional development programs and technical sessions; such\nlearning activities may be offered and sponsored by national, state and\nlocal professional associations and other organizations or parties\nacceptable to the department, and any other organized educational and\ntechnical learning activities acceptable to the department. The\ndepartment may, in its discretion and as needed to contribute to the\nhealth and welfare of the public, require the completion of continuing\ncompetency learning a...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8209__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Speech-language pathologists and audiologists shall maintain\nadequate documentation of completion of acceptable continuing competency\nlearning activities and shall provide such documentation at the request\nof the department. Failure to provide such documentation upon the\nrequest of the department shall be an act of misconduct subject to\ndisciplinary proceedings pursuant to section sixty-five hundred ten of\nthis title.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8209__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The mandatory continuing competency fee shall be fifty dollars,\nshall be payable on or before the first day of each triennial\nregistration period, and shall be paid in addition to the triennial\nregistration fee required by section eighty-two hundred six of this\narticle.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>