<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8213"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8213"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8213"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8213">
        <num>8213</num>
        <heading>State board for acupuncture</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8213. State board for acupuncture.  (1) There is hereby established\nwithin the department a state board for acupuncture. The board shall\nconsist of not less than eleven members to be appointed by the board of\nregents on the recommendation of the commissioner for the purpose of\nassisting the board of regents and the department on matters of\nprofessional licensing and professional conduct in accordance with\nsection sixty-five hundred eight of this chapter, four of whom shall be\nlicensed acupuncturists, four of whom shall be licensed physicians\ncertified to use acupuncture and three of whom shall be public members\nrepresenting the consumer and community. Of the acupuncturists first\nappointed to the board, one may be a registered specialist's\nassistant-acupuncture provided that the term of such registered\nspecialist's assistant-acupuncture shall not be more than four years. Of\nthe members first appointed, three shall be appointed for a one year\nterm, three shall be appointed for a two year term and three shall be\nappointed for a three year term, and two shall be appointed for a four\nyear term. Thereafter all members shall serve for five year terms. In\nthe event that more than eleven members are appointed, a majority of the\nadditional members shall be licensed acupuncturists. The members of the\nboard shall select one of themselves as chairman to serve for a one year\nterm.\n  (2) An executive secretary to the board shall be appointed by the\nboard of regents on recommendation of the commissioner.\n  (3) The board of regents and the commissioner shall promulgate such\nrules and regulations as they deem necessary and appropriate to\neffectuate the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>