<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8304"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8304">
        <num>8304</num>
        <heading>State board for interior design</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8304. State board for interior design.  1. A state board for\ninterior design shall be appointed by the board of regents on\nrecommendation of the commissioner for the purpose of assisting the\nboard of regents and the department on matters of certification and\nprofessional conduct in accordance with section sixty-five hundred eight\nof this title. The board shall be composed of nine members, four of whom\nshall be interior designers certified in this state, two of whom shall\nbe licensed architects who practice primarily interior design in this\nstate, one who shall be a professional engineer in this state with an\nexpertise in interior design, one who shall be a full-time interior\ndesign educator in this state and one who shall be the public\nrepresentative. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the members of the first\nboard who are interior designers need not be certified prior to their\nappointment to the board.\n  2. Two interior designers and a licensed architect who practices\nprimarily interior design shall serve initial five year terms. Two\ninterior designers and a professional engineer with an expertise in\ninterior design shall serve initial four year terms. One licensed\narchitect who practices primarily interior design, the interior design\neducator, and the public representative shall serve initial two year\nterms. Following the establishment of the initial membership of the\nboard, all succeeding appointments shall be for five year terms. Any\nvacancy on the board shall be filled by appointment for the remainder of\nsuch member's terms in accordance with the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>