<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8404"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8404">
        <num>8404</num>
        <heading>Creative arts therapy</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the assessment, evaluation, and the therapeutic intervention and\ntreatment, which may be either primary, parallel or adjunctive, of\nmental, emotional, developmental and behavioral disorders through the\nuse of the arts as approved by the department; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the use of assessment instruments and mental health counseling and\npsychotherapy to identify, evaluate and treat dysfunctions and disorders\nfor purposes of providing appropriate creative arts therapy services.\n  2. Practice of creative arts therapy and use of the titles "creative\narts therapist" and "licensed creative arts therapist". Only a person\nlicensed or exempt under this article shall practice creative arts\ntherapy or use the title "creative arts therapist". Only a person\nlicensed under this article shall use the title "licensed creative arts\ntherapist" or any other designation tending to imply that the person is\nlicensed to practice creative arts therapy.\n  3. Requirements for a professional license. To qualify for a license\nas a "licensed creative arts therapist", an applicant shall fulfill the\nfollowing requirements:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Application: File an application with the department;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Education: Have received an education, including a master's or\nhigher degree in creative arts therapy from a program registered by the\ndepartment or determined by the department to be the substantial\nequivalent thereof, in accordance with the commissioner's regulations.\nThe graduate coursework shall include, but not be limited to, the\nfollowing areas:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>human growth and development;\n  (ii) theories in therapy;\n  (iii) group dynamics;\n  (iv) assessment and appraisal of individuals and groups;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>research and program evaluation;\n  (vi) professional orientation and ethics;\n  (vii) foundations of creative arts therapy and psychopathology; and\n  (viii) clinical instruction;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Experience: Have completed at least fifteen hundred hours of\npostmaster's supervised experience in one or more creative arts\ntherapies satisfactory to the department and in accordance with the\ncommissioner's regulations. Satisfactory experience obtained in an\nentity operating under a waiver issued by the department pursuant to\nsection sixty-five hundred three-a of this title may be accepted by the\ndepartment, notwithstanding that such experience may have been obtained\nprior to the effective date of such section sixty-five hundred three-a\nand/or prior to the entity having obtained a waiver. The department may,\nfor good cause shown, accept satisfactory experience that was obtained\nin a setting that would have been eligible for a waiver but which has\nnot obtained a waiver from the department or experience that was\nobtained in good faith by the applicant under the belief that\nappropriate authorization had been obtained for the experience, provided\nthat such experience meets all other requirements for acceptable\nexperience;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Examination: Pass an examination in creative arts therapy\nsatisfactory to the department and in accordance with the commissioner's\nregulations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Age: Be at least twenty-one years of age;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Character: Be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8404__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fees: Pay a fee of one hundred seventy-five dollars for an initial\nlicense and a fee of one hundred seventy dollars for each triennial\nregistration period.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>