<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8405"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8405"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8405"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8405">
        <num>8405</num>
        <heading>Psychoanalysis</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the observation, description, evaluation, and interpretation of\ndynamic unconscious mental processes that contribute to the formation of\npersonality and behavior in order to identify and resolve unconscious\npsychic problems which affect interpersonal relationships and emotional\ndevelopment, to facilitate changes in personality and behavior through\nthe use of verbal and nonverbal cognitive and emotional communication,\nand to develop adaptive functioning; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the use of assessment instruments and mental health counseling and\npsychotherapy to identify, evaluate and treat dysfunctions and disorders\nfor purposes of providing appropriate psychoanalytic services.\n  2. Practice of psychoanalysis and use of the titles "psychoanalyst"\nand "licensed psychoanalyst". Only a person licensed or exempt under\nthis article shall practice psychoanalysis or use the title\n"psychoanalyst".  Only a person licensed under this article shall use\nthe title "licensed psychoanalyst" or any other designation tending to\nimply that the person is licensed to practice psychoanalysis.\n  3. Requirements for a professional license. To qualify for a license\nas a "licensed psychoanalyst", an applicant shall fulfill the following\nrequirements:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Application: File an application with the department;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Education: Have received a master's degree or higher from a\ndegree-granting program registered by the department or the substantial\nequivalent and have completed a program of study registered by the\ndepartment in a psychoanalytic institute chartered by the board of\nregents or the substantial equivalent as determined by the department.\nThe program of study in a psychoanalytic institute shall include\ncoursework substantially equivalent to coursework required for a\nmaster's degree in a health or mental health field of study. The\ncoursework shall include, but not be limited to, the following areas:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>personality development;\n  (ii) psychoanalytic theory of psychopathology;\n  (iii) psychoanalytic theory of psychodiagnosis;\n  (iv) sociocultural influence on growth and psychopathology;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>practice technique (including dreams and symbolic processes);\n  (vi) analysis of resistance, transference, and countertransference;\n  (vii) case seminars on clinical practice;\n  (viii) practice in psychopathology and psychodiagnosis;\n  (ix) professional ethics and psychoanalytic research methodology; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a minimum of three hundred hours of personal analysis and one\nhundred fifty hours of supervised analysis;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Experience: Have completed a minimum of fifteen hundred hours of\nsupervised clinical practice satisfactory to the department and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations. Satisfactory experience\nobtained in an entity operating under a waiver issued by the department\npursuant to section sixty-five hundred three-a of this title may be\naccepted by the department, notwithstanding that such experience may\nhave been obtained prior to the effective date of such section\nsixty-five hundred three-a and/or prior to the entity having obtained a\nwaiver. The department may, for good cause shown, accept satisfactory\nexperience that was obtained in a setting that would have been eligible\nfor a waiver but which has not obtained a waiver from the department or\nexperience that was obtained in good faith by the applicant under the\nbelief that appropriate authorization had been obtained for the\nexperience, provided that such experience meets all other requirements\nfor acceptable experience;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Examination: Pass an examination in psychoanalysis satisfactory to\nthe department and in accordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Age: Be at least twenty-one years of age;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Character: Be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8405__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fees: Pay a fee of one hundred seventy-five dollars for an initial\nlicense and a fee of one hundred seventy dollars for each triennial\nregistration period.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>