<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-915-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-915-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="915-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-915-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-915-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-915-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-915-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_915_A">
        <num>915-A</num>
        <heading>Universal free school meals</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_915_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the combined state and federal\nreimbursement rate for a reduced-price or paid meal, respectively, for\nthe current school year and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_915_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the combined state and federal\nreimbursement rate for a free meal for the current school year, provided\nthat the total reimbursement rate for each meal served shall equal the\ncombined state and federal reimbursement rate for a free meal for the\ncurrent school year.\n  3. The department, in consultation with the office of temporary and\ndisability assistance, shall promulgate any rule or regulation needed\nfor school districts, charter schools and non-public schools to promote\nthe supplemental nutrition assistance program to a student or person in\nparental relation to a student by providing either application\nassistance or a direct referral to an outreach partner identified to the\ndepartment by the office of temporary and disability assistance to\nmaximize the number of students directly certified for free school\nmeals.\n  4. In addition to fulfilling any other applicable state and federal\nrequirements, the department shall provide technical assistance to\nassist school districts, charter schools, and non-public schools in the\ntransition to universal school meals to ensure successful program\noperations and to maximize federal funding, including but not limited to\nthe following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_915_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Assisting school food authorities with one or more schools\nqualifying for the community eligibility provision in meeting any state\nand federal requirements necessary in order to maximize reimbursement\nthrough the community eligibility provision, including assisting such\nschool food authorities in maximizing participation in the community\neligibility provision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_915_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a school food authority is ineligible to participate in and\nreceive reimbursement through the community eligibility provision,\nassisting the school food authority in achieving and maximizing\neligibility and, if that is not feasible, assisting the school food\nauthority in determining the viability of using Provision 2 or other\nspecial federal provisions available to schools to maximize federal\nreimbursement.\n  5. School districts, charter schools, and non-public schools shall\nmaximize the number of students eligible for free meals by conducting\nthe Direct Certification Matching Process at a minimum of three times\nper year, designating children as "Other Source Categorically Eligible",\nas defined by federal regulations, or, for schools not participating in\nthe Community Eligibility Provision or Provision 2, by annually\ncollecting the free and reduced-price meal application.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>