<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-10-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="917-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_917_A">
        <num>917-A</num>
        <heading>On-site cardiac automated external defibrillator in nonpublic schools</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_917_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section three thousand-b of the public health law, in\nquantities and types deemed by the commissioner in consultation with the\ncommissioner of health to be adequate to ensure ready and appropriate\naccess for use during emergencies. Nonpublic schools shall cause such\nAED to be maintained and tested according to such applicable standards\nof the manufacturer and any appropriate government agency.\n  2. Whenever nonpublic school facilities pursuant to subdivision one of\nthis section are used for school-sponsored or school-approved curricular\nor extracurricular events or activities and whenever a school-sponsored\nathletic contest is held at any location, the nonpublic school officials\nand administrators responsible for such school facility or athletic\ncontest shall ensure the presence of at least one staff person who is\ntrained, pursuant to subdivision three of this section in the operation\nand use of an AED. Where a school-sponsored competitive athletic event\nis held at a site other than a nonpublic school facility, the nonpublic\nschool officials shall ensure that AED equipment is provided on-site.\n  3. No person may operate an AED in a nonpublic school facility unless\nthe person has successfully completed a training course in the operation\nof an AED approved by a nationally-recognized organization as defined in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section three thousand-b of the\npublic health law or the state emergency medical services council.\nHowever, this section shall not prohibit operation of an AED:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a health care practitioner licensed or certified under title\neight of this chapter or a person certified under article thirty of the\npublic health law acting within their lawful scope of practice;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a person acting pursuant to a lawful prescription; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a person who operates the AED other than as part of or\nincidental to their employment or regular duties, who is acting in good\nfaith, with reasonable care, and without expectation of monetary\ncompensation, to provide first aid that includes operation of an AED;\nnor shall this section limit any good samaritan protections provided in\nsection three thousand-a of the public health law.\n  4. Every use of an AED on a patient in a nonpublic school shall be\nimmediately reported to the appropriate local emergency medical services\nsystem, emergency communications center or emergency vehicle dispatch\ncenter, as appropriate.\n  5. Nonpublic schools shall notify the appropriate regional emergency\nservices council of the existence, location and type of any AED they\npossess.\n  6. A nonpublic school shall post a sign or notice at the main entrance\nto the facility or building in which the automated external\ndefibrillator is stored, indicating the location where any such\nautomated external defibrillator is stored or maintained in such\nbuilding or facility on a regular basis.\n  7.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Operation of an AED pursuant to this section in a nonpublic\nschool shall be considered first aid or emergency treatment for the\npurpose of any statute relating to liability; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Operation of an AED pursuant to this section in a nonpublic school\nshall not constitute the unlawful practice of a profession under title\neight of this chapter.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>