<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="917"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-917/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_917">
        <num>917</num>
        <heading>On-site cardiac automated external defibrillator</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_917__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section three thousand-b of the public health law, in\nquantities and types deemed by the commissioner in consultation with the\ncommissioner of health to be adequate to ensure ready and appropriate\naccess for use during emergencies.\n  * NB Effective until January 20, 2026\n  * 1. School districts, boards of cooperative educational services,\ncounty vocational education and extension boards and charter schools\nshall provide and maintain on-site in each instructional school facility\nautomated external defibrillator (AED) equipment, as defined in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section three thousand-b of the\npublic health law, in quantities and types deemed by the commissioner in\nconsultation with the commissioner of health to be adequate to ensure\nready and appropriate access for use during emergencies. Such automated\nexternal defibrillators shall be clearly marked, accessible, and\nmaintained consistent with guidelines set by the American Heart\nAssociation, or other nationally recognized guidelines focused on\nemergency cardiovascular care.\n  * NB Effective January 20, 2026\n  2. Whenever public school facilities pursuant to subdivision one of\nthis section are used for school sponsored or school approved curricular\nor extracurricular events or activities and whenever a school-sponsored\nathletic contest is held at any location, the public school officials\nand administrators responsible for such school facility or athletic\ncontest shall ensure the presence of at least one staff person who is\ntrained, pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of section three\nthousand-b of the public health law, in the operation and use of an AED.\nWhere a school-sponsored competitive athletic event is held at a site\nother than a public school facility, the public school officials shall\nassure that automated external defibrillator equipment is provided\non-site.\n  3. Public school facilities and staff pursuant to subdivisions one and\ntwo of this section shall be deemed a "public access defibrillation\nprovider" as defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_917__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section\nthree thousand-b of the public health law and shall be subject to the\nrequirements and limitations of such section.\n  4. Pursuant to section three thousand-a and three thousand-b of the\npublic health law, any public access defibrillation provider, or any\nemployee or other agent of the provider who, in accordance with the\nprovisions of this section, voluntarily and without expectation of\nmonetary compensation renders emergency medical or first aid treatment\nusing an AED which has been made available pursuant to this section, to\na person who is unconscious, ill or injured, shall be liable only\npursuant to section three thousand-a of the public health law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>