<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-923"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-923"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="923"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-923/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-923/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-923/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-923/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_923">
        <num>923</num>
        <heading>Sudden cardiac arrest</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 923. Sudden cardiac arrest. a. The commissioner shall review the\ninformation developed by the commissioner of health required by\nsubdivision thirty-one of section two hundred six of the public health\nlaw to assist in the education and awareness of the signs and symptoms\nof pending or increased risk of sudden cardiac arrest. Such information\nshall be posted on the department's website. In addition, each school\nshall be required to include such information developed by the\ndepartment of health, in conjunction with the department, in any\npermission form or parent or person in parental relation consent form or\nsimilar document that may be required for a student's participation in\ninterscholastic athletics and shall also include such information, or\nreference how to obtain such information from the department and the\ndepartment of health's websites, on the school's website, if one exists.\n  b. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations requiring\nthat any student displaying signs or symptoms of pending or increased\nrisk of sudden cardiac arrest shall be immediately removed from athletic\nactivities and shall not resume athletic activity until he or she has\nbeen evaluated by and received written and signed authorization from a\nlicensed physician. Such authorization shall be kept on file in the\npupil's permanent health record.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>