<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-160.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-160.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-160.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-160.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-160.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-160.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_30">
        <num>160.30</num>
        <heading>Fingerprinting; duties of division of criminal justice services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 160.30 Fingerprinting; duties of division of criminal justice\n             services.\n  1.  Upon receiving fingerprints from a police officer or agency\npursuant to section 160.20 of this chapter, the division of criminal\njustice services must, except as provided in subdivision two of this\nsection, classify them and search its records for information concerning\na previous record of the defendant, including any adjudication as a\njuvenile delinquent pursuant to article three of the family court act,\nor as a youthful offender pursuant to article seven hundred twenty of\nthis chapter, and promptly transmit to such forwarding police officer or\nagency a report containing all information on file with respect to such\ndefendant's previous record, if any, or stating that the defendant has\nno previous record according to its files.  Such a report, if certified,\nconstitutes presumptive evidence of the facts so certified.\n  2.  If the fingerprints so received are not sufficiently legible to\npermit accurate and complete classification, they must be returned to\nthe forwarding police officer or agency with an explanation of the\ndefects and a request that the defendant's fingerprints be retaken if\npossible.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>