<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.70"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.70"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190.70"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.70/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.70/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.70/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.70/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190_70">
        <num>190.70</num>
        <heading>Grand jury; direction to file prosecutor's information and related matters</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_190_70__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the evidence before it is\nlegally sufficient to establish that such person committed such offense,\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_190_70__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>competent and admissible evidence before it provides reasonable\ncause to believe that such person committed such offense.  In such case,\nthe grand jury must, through its foreman or acting foreman, file such\ndirection with the court by which it was impaneled.\n  2.  Such direction must be signed by the foreman or acting foreman.\nIt must contain a plain and concise statement of the conduct\nconstituting the offense to be charged, equivalent in content and\nprecision to the factual statement required to be contained in an\nindictment pursuant to subdivision seven of section 200.50.  Subject to\nthe rules prescribed in sections 200.20 and 200.40 governing joinder in\na single indictment of multiple offenses and multiple defendants, such\ngrand jury direction may, where appropriate, specify multiple offenses\nof less than felony grade and multiple defendants, and may direct that\nthe prospective prosecutor's information charge a single defendant with\nmultiple offenses, or multiple defendants jointly with either a single\noffense or multiple offenses.\n  3.  Upon the filing of such grand jury direction, the court must,\nunless such direction is insufficient on its face, issue an order\napproving such direction and ordering the district attorney to file such\na prosecutor's information in a designated local criminal court having\ntrial jurisdiction of the offense or offenses in question.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>