<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-190.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190_20">
        <num>190.20</num>
        <heading>Grand jury; formation, organization and other matters preliminary to assumption of duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_190_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At any time before a grand jury is sworn, discharge the panel and\nsummon another panel if it finds that the original panel does not\nsubstantially conform to the requirements of the judiciary law; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_190_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At any time after a grand juror is drawn, refuse to swear him, or\ndischarge him after he has been sworn, upon a finding that he is\ndisqualified from service pursuant to the judiciary law, or incapable of\nperforming his duties because of bias or prejudice, or guilty of\nmisconduct in the performance of his duties such as to impair the proper\nfunctioning of the grand jury.\n  3. After a grand jury has been impaneled, the court must appoint one\nof the grand jurors as foreman and another to act as foreman during any\nabsence or disability of the foreman. At some time before commencement\nof their duties, the grand jurors must appoint one of their number as\nsecretary to keep records material to the conduct of the grand jury's\nbusiness.\n  4. The grand jurors must be sworn by the court. The oath may be in any\nform or language which requires the grand jurors to perform their duties\nfaithfully.\n  5. After a grand jury has been sworn, the court must deliver or cause\nto be delivered to each grand juror a printed copy of all the provisions\nof this article, and the court may, in addition, give the grand jurors\nany oral and written instructions relating to the proper performance of\ntheir duties as it deems necessary or appropriate.\n  6. If two or more grand juries are impaneled at the same court term,\nthe court may thereafter, for good cause, transfer grand jurors from one\npanel to another, and any grand juror so transferred is deemed to have\nbeen sworn as a member of the panel to which he has been transferred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>