<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="210.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_210_10">
        <num>210.10</num>
        <heading>Requirement of and methods of securing defendant's appearance for arraignment upon indictment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any\npolice officer to whom it is addressed or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other police officer\ndelegated to execute it under circumstances prescribed in subdivisions\nfive and six.\n  5. The issuing court may authorize the delegation of such warrant.\nWhere the issuing court has so authorized, a police officer to whom a\nsuperior court warrant of arrest is addressed may delegate another\npolice officer to whom it is not addressed to execute such warrant as\nhis agent when:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>He has reasonable cause to believe that the defendant is in a\nparticular county other than the one in which the warrant is returnable;\nand\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The geographical area of employment of the delegated police\nofficer embraces the locality where the arrest is to be made.\n  6. Under circumstances specified in subdivision five, the police\nofficer to whom the warrant is addressed may inform the delegated\nofficer, by telecommunication, mail or any other means, of the issuance\nof the warrant, of the offense charged in the underlying accusatory\ninstrument and of all other pertinent details, and may request such\nofficer to act as his or her agent in arresting the defendant pursuant\nto such warrant. Upon such request, the delegated police officer is to\nthe same extent as the delegating officer, authorized to make such\narrest pursuant to the warrant within the geographical area of such\ndelegated officer's employment.  Upon so arresting the defendant, he or\nshe must without unnecessary delay deliver the defendant or cause the\ndefendant to be delivered to the custody of the police officer by whom\nhe or she was so delegated, and the latter must then without unnecessary\ndelay bring the defendant before a court in which such warrant is\nreturnable. If such court is not available, the delegating officer may\nbring the defendant to the local correctional facility of the county in\nwhich such court sits, to be detained there until not later than the\ncommencement of the next session of such court occurring on the next\nbusiness day.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>