<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.45"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.45"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="210.45"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.45/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.45/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.45/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-210.45/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_210_45">
        <num>210.45</num>
        <heading>Motion to dismiss indictment; procedure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The moving papers allege a ground constituting legal basis for\nthe motion pursuant to subdivision one of section 210.20; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such ground, if based upon the existence or occurrence of facts,\nis supported by sworn allegations of all facts essential to support the\nmotion; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sworn allegations of fact essential to support the motion are\neither conceded by the people to be true or are conclusively\nsubstantiated by unquestionable documentary proof.\n  5.  The court may deny the motion without conducting a hearing if:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The moving papers do not allege any ground constituting legal\nbasis for the motion pursuant to subdivision one of section 210.20; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The motion is based upon the existence or occurrence of facts,\nand the moving papers do not contain sworn allegations supporting all\nthe essential facts; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An allegation of fact essential to support the motion is\nconclusively refuted by unquestionable documentary proof.\n  6.  If the court does not determine the motion pursuant to subdivision\nfour or five, it must conduct a hearing and make findings of fact\nessential to the determination thereof.  The defendant has a right to be\npresent in person at such hearing but may waive such right.\n  7.  Upon such a hearing, the defendant has the burden of proving by a\npreponderance of the evidence every fact essential to support the\nmotion.\n  8.  When the court dismisses the entire indictment without authorizing\nresubmission of the charge or charges to a grand jury, it must order\nthat the defendant be discharged from custody if he is in the custody of\nthe sheriff, or if he is at liberty on bail it must exonerate the bail.\n  9.  When the court dismisses the entire indictment but authorizes\nresubmission of the charge or charges to a grand jury, such\nauthorization is, for purposes of this subdivision, deemed to constitute\nan order holding the defendant for the action of a grand jury with\nrespect to such charge or charges.  Such order must be accompanied by a\nsecuring order either releasing the defendant on his own recognizance or\nfixing bail or committing him to the custody of the sheriff pending\nresubmission of the case to the grand jury and the grand jury's\ndisposition thereof.  Such securing order remains in effect until the\nfirst to occur of any of the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement to the court by the people that they do not intend to\nresubmit the case to a grand jury;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Arraignment of the defendant upon an indictment or prosecutor's\ninformation filed as a result of resubmission of the case to a grand\njury.  Upon such arraignment, the arraigning court must issue a new\nsecuring order;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The filing with the court of a grand jury dismissal of the case\nfollowing resubmission thereof;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The expiration of a period of forty-five days from the date of\nissuance of the order; provided that such period may, for good cause\nshown, be extended by the court to a designated subsequent date if such\nbe necessary to accord the people reasonable opportunity to resubmit the\ncase to a grand jury.\n  Upon the termination of the effectiveness of the securing order\npursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, the court must immediately order\nthat the defendant be discharged from custody if he is in the custody of\nthe sheriff, or if he is at liberty on bail it must exonerate the bail.\nAlthough expiration of the period of time specified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_210_45__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nwithout any resubmission or grand jury disposition of the case\nterminates the effectiveness of the securing order, it does not\nterminate the effectiveness of the order authorizing resubmission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>