<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.55"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.55"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="245.55"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_245_55">
        <num>245.55</num>
        <heading>Flow of information</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_55__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision one of section 245.20 of this article.\n  2. Provision of law enforcement agency files. Absent a court order or\na requirement that defense counsel obtain a security clearance mandated\nby law or authorized government regulation, upon request by the\nprosecution, each New York state and local law enforcement agency shall\nmake available to the prosecution a complete copy of its complete\nrecords and files related to the investigation of the case or the\nprosecution of the defendant for compliance with this article.\n  3. 911 telephone call and police radio transmission electronic\nrecordings, police worn body camera recordings and other police\nrecordings.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_55__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever an electronic recording of a 911 telephone call\nor a police radio transmission or video or audio footage from a police\nbody-worn camera or other police recording was made or received in\nconnection with the investigation of an apparent criminal incident, the\narresting officer or lead detective shall expeditiously notify the\nprosecution in writing upon the filing of an accusatory instrument of\nthe existence of all such known recordings. The prosecution shall\nexpeditiously take whatever reasonable steps are necessary to ensure\nthat all known electronic recordings of 911 telephone calls, police\nradio transmissions and video and audio footage and other police\nrecordings made or available in connection with the case are preserved.\nUpon the defendant's timely request and designation of a specific\nelectronic recording of a 911 telephone call, the prosecution shall also\nexpeditiously take whatever reasonable steps are necessary to ensure\nthat it is preserved.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_55__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the prosecution fails to disclose such an electronic recording\nto the defendant pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_55__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_55__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_55__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\none of section 245.20 of this article due to a failure to comply with\nthis obligation by police officers or other law enforcement or\nprosecution personnel, the court upon motion of the defendant shall\nimpose an appropriate remedy or sanction pursuant to section 245.80 of\nthis article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>