<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.35"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.35"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="270.35"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_270_35">
        <num>270.35</num>
        <heading>Trial jury; discharge of juror; replacement by alternate juror</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_270_35__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In determining pursuant to this section whether a juror is\nunable to continue serving by reason of illness or other incapacity, or\nis for any other reason unavailable for continued service, the court\nshall make a reasonably thorough inquiry concerning such illness,\nincapacity or unavailability, and shall attempt to ascertain when such\njuror will be appearing in court. If such juror fails to appear, or if\nthe court determines that there is no reasonable likelihood such juror\nwill be appearing, in court within two hours of the time set by the\ncourt for the trial to resume, the court may presume such juror is\nunavailable for continued service and may discharge such juror. Nothing\ncontained in this paragraph shall affect the court's discretion, under\nthis or any other provision of law, to discharge a juror who repeatedly\nfails to appear in court in a timely fashion.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_270_35__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall afford the parties an opportunity to be heard\nbefore discharging a juror. If the court discharges a juror pursuant to\nthis subdivision, it shall place on the record the facts and reasons for\nits determination that such juror is ill, incapacitated or unavailable\nfor continued service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_270_35__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing contained in this subdivision shall affect the\nrequirements of subdivision one of this section pertaining to the\ndischarge of a juror where the trial jury has begun its deliberations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>