<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-300.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-300.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="300.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-300.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-300.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-300.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-300.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_300_10">
        <num>300.10</num>
        <heading>Court's charge; in general</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_300_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Guilty" of the offense submitted, if there be but one; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_300_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where appropriate, "guilty" of a specified one of two or more\noffenses submitted under the same count in the alternative pursuant to\nsection 300.40; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_300_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Not guilty"; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_300_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where appropriate, "not responsible by reason of mental disease\nor defect."\n  5.  Both before and after the court's charge, the parties may submit\nrequests to charge, either orally or in writing, and the court must rule\npromptly upon each request.  A failure to rule upon a request is deemed\na denial thereof.\n  6. In a prosecution involving a charge of enterprise corruption, as\ndefined in article four hundred sixty of the penal law, the court must\nspecifically designate and separately submit for jury consideration\nthose criminal acts which are contained and charged in the indictment\nand which are supported by legally sufficient trial evidence. Every\ncriminal act which is not so supported shall be dismissed  and stricken\nfrom the indictment. If legally sufficient trial evidence exists to\nsupport a lesser included offense which is also a criminal act within\nthe meaning of subdivision one of section 460.10 of the penal law, such\nlesser offense shall be substituted. Such determination must be made and\nthe parties informed thereof, prior to the summations. In its charge,\nthe court must define each criminal act so submitted and, as when it may\nor must do so pursuant to sections 300.40 and 300.50 of this article,\nany lesser included offense that is also a criminal act within the\nmeaning of subdivision one of section 460.10 of the penal law. It must\ninstruct the jury to render a verdict separately and specifically upon\neach criminal act (and where necessary, any submitted lesser included\noffense) submitted to it with respect to each defendant. It must further\nexplain to the jury that they may not consider a charge of enterprise\ncorruption against any defendant until they have separately and\nunanimously agreed that the defendant has committed each of at least\nthree criminal acts alleged as part of the pattern of criminal activity,\nincluding any submitted lesser included offenses.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>