<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-340.40"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-340.40"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="340.40"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-340.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-340.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-340.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-340.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_340_40">
        <num>340.40</num>
        <heading>Modes of trial</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 340.40 Modes of trial.\n  1. Except as otherwise provided in this section, a trial of an\ninformation in a local criminal court must be a single judge trial.\n  2. In any local criminal court a defendant who has entered a plea of\nnot guilty to an information which charges a misdemeanor must be\naccorded a jury trial, conducted pursuant to article three hundred\nsixty. The defendant may at any time before trial waive a jury trial in\nthe manner prescribed in subdivision two of section 320.10 of this\nchapter, and consent to a single judge trial.\n  3. A defendant entitled to a jury trial pursuant to subdivision two of\nthis section, shall be so entitled even though the information also\ncharges an offense for which he is otherwise not entitled to a jury\ntrial. In such case, the defendant is not entitled both to a jury trial\nand a separate single judge trial and the court may not order separate\ntrials.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any local criminal\ncourt the trial of a person who is an eligible youth within the meaning\nof the youthful offender procedure set forth in article seven hundred\ntwenty of this chapter and who has not prior to commencement of the\ntrial been convicted of a crime or adjudicated a youthful offender must\nbe a single judge trial.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>