<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-370.25"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-370.25"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-06-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="370.25"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-370.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-370.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-370.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-370.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_370_25">
        <num>370.25</num>
        <heading>Procedure for the surrender of firearms, rifles and shotguns upon judgment of conviction for a felony or a serious offense</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_370_25__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nparagraph one of subdivision a of section 265.20 of the penal law and\nsubdivision six of section 400.05 of the penal law, of any or all\nfirearms, rifles and shotguns owned or possessed by the defendant.\n  2. The court ordering the surrender of any firearms, rifles or\nshotguns as provided in this section shall immediately notify the duly\nconstituted police authorities of the locality of such action and the\ndivision of state police at its office in the city of Albany. The court\nshall direct the authority receiving such surrendered firearms, rifles\nand shotguns to immediately notify the court of such surrender.\n  3. The disposition of any firearms, rifles or shotguns surrendered\npursuant to this section shall be in accordance with the provisions of\nsubdivision six of section 400.05 of the penal law.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall not be deemed to limit,\nrestrict or otherwise impair the authority of the court to order and\ndirect the surrender of any or all firearms, rifles and shotguns owned\nor possessed by a defendant pursuant to any other provision of law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>