<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-08-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="420.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_420_30">
        <num>420.30</num>
        <heading>Remission of fines, restitution or reparation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any superior court which has imposed a fine,\nrestitution or reparation for any offense may, in its discretion, on\nfive days notice to the district attorney of the county in which such\nfine, restitution or reparation was imposed and to each person otherwise\nrequired to be given notice of restitution or reparation pursuant to\nsubdivision one of section 420.10, remit such fine, restitution or\nreparation or any portion thereof. In case of a fine, restitution or\nreparation imposed by a local criminal court for any offense, a superior\ncourt holding a term in the county in which the fine, restitution or\nreparation was imposed may, upon like notice, remit such fine,\nrestitution or reparation or any portion thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall give each person given notice a reasonable\nopportunity to be heard on the question of remitting an order of\nrestitution or reparation. If the court remits such restitution or\nreparation, or any part thereof, the reasons therefor shall be placed\nupon the record.\n  3. Restrictions. Except as provided for in subdivision two-a of\nsection 420.35 of this article, in no event shall a mandatory surcharge,\nsex offender registration fee, DNA databank fee or crime victim\nassistance fee be remitted.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>