<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-440.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-440.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="440.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-440.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-440.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-440.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-440.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_440_20">
        <num>440.20</num>
        <heading>Motion to set aside sentence; by defendant</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_440_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_440_20__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_440_20__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_440_20__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_440_20__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section 440.10 as applied to a separate sentencing\nproceeding under section 400.27, provided, however, that to the extent\nthe ground or grounds asserted include one or more of the aforesaid\nparagraphs of subdivision one of section 440.10, the court must also\napply subdivisions two and three of section 440.10, other than paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_440_20__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of such section, in determining the motion. In\nthe event the court enters an order granting a motion to set aside a\nsentence of death under this section, the court must either direct a new\nsentencing proceeding in accordance with section 400.27 or, to the\nextent that the defendant cannot be resentenced to death consistent with\nthe laws of this state or the constitution of this state or of the\nUnited States, resentence the defendant to life imprisonment without\nparole or to a sentence of imprisonment for the class A-I felony of\nmurder in the first degree other than a sentence of life imprisonment\nwithout parole. Upon granting the motion upon any of the grounds set\nforth in the aforesaid paragraphs of subdivision one of section 440.10\nand setting aside the sentence, the court must afford the people a\nreasonable period of time, which shall not be less than ten days, to\ndetermine whether to take an appeal from the order setting aside the\nsentence of death. The taking of an appeal by the people stays the\neffectiveness of that portion of the court's order that directs a new\nsentencing proceeding.\n  2.  Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one, the court must\ndeny such a motion when the ground or issue raised thereupon was\npreviously determined on the merits upon an appeal from the judgment or\nsentence, unless since the time of such appellate determination there\nhas been a retroactively effective change in the law controlling such\nissue.\n  3.  Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one, the court may\ndeny such a motion when the ground or issue raised thereupon was\npreviously determined on the merits upon a prior motion or proceeding in\na court of this state, other than an appeal from the judgment, or upon a\nprior motion or proceeding in a federal court, unless since the time of\nsuch determination there has been a retroactively effective change in\nthe law controlling such issue.  Despite such determination, how...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>