<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.43"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.43"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="510.43"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.43/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.43/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.43/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.43/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_510_43">
        <num>510.43</num>
        <heading>Court appearances: additional notifications</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 510.43 Court appearances: additional notifications.\n  1. The court or, upon direction of the court, a certified pretrial\nservices agency, shall notify all principals released under non-monetary\nconditions and on recognizance of all court appearances in advance by\ntext message, telephone call, electronic mail or first class mail. The\nchief administrator of the courts shall, pursuant to subdivision one of\nsection 10.40 of this chapter, develop a form which shall be offered to\nthe principal at court appearances. On such form, which upon completion\nshall be retained in the court file, the principal may select one such\npreferred manner of notice.\n  2. Such form may request the information necessary for the defendant\nto be provided with notice in accordance with such single, selected\nmanner of notice. After notice of such consequence, a defendant who\nintentionally declines to provide the information necessary for the\ndefendant to be provided with such notice pursuant to this section shall\nforfeit the opportunity to receive such notice until such information is\ntimely provided. Any failure by the court or certified pretrial services\nagency to provide notice of a scheduled court appearance in the manner\nprovided in this section shall not in and of itself constitute grounds\nor authorization for the defendant to fail to appear for such scheduled\ncourt appearance.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>