<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="520.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_520_30">
        <num>520.30</num>
        <heading>Bail and bail bonds; examination as to sufficiency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The background, character and reputation of any obligor, and, in\nthe case of an insurance company bail bond, the qualifications of the\nsurety-obligor and its executing agent; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The source of any money or property deposited by any obligor as\nsecurity, and whether any such money or property constitutes the fruits\nof criminal or unlawful conduct; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_30__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The source of any money or property delivered or agreed to be\ndelivered to any obligor as indemnification on the bond, and whether any\nsuch money or property constitutes the fruits of criminal or unlawful\nconduct; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_30__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The background, character and reputation of any person who has\nindemnified or agreed to indemnify an obligor upon the bond; and whether\nany such indemnitor, not being licensed by the superintendent of\nfinancial services in accordance with the insurance law, has within a\nperiod of one month prior to such indemnity transaction given\nindemnification or security for like purpose in more than two cases not\narising out of the same transaction; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_30__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The source of any money posted as cash bail, and whether any such\nmoney constitutes the fruits of criminal or unlawful conduct;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_30__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The background, character and reputation of the person posting\ncash bail.\n  2. Upon such inquiry, the court may examine, under oath or otherwise,\nthe obligors and any other persons who may possess material information.\nThe district attorney has a right to attend such inquiry, to call\nwitnesses and to examine any witness in the proceeding. The court may,\nupon application of the district attorney, adjourn the proceeding for a\nreasonable period to allow him to investigate the matter.\n  3. At the conclusion of the inquiry, the court must issue an order\neither approving or disapproving the bail.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>