<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-06-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="530.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_530_30">
        <num>530.30</num>
        <heading>Order of recognizance, release under non-monetary conditions or bail; by superior court judge when action is pending in local criminal court</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Lacks authority to issue such an order, pursuant to the relevant\nprovisions of section 530.20 of this article; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Has denied an application for recognizance, release under\nnon-monetary conditions or bail; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_30__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Has fixed bail, where authorized, which is excessive; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_30__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Has set a securing order of release under non-monetary conditions\nwhich are more restrictive than necessary to reasonably assure the\ndefendant's return to court.\n  In such case, such superior court judge may vacate the order of such\nlocal criminal court and release the defendant on recognizance or under\nnon-monetary conditions, or where authorized, fix bail in a lesser\namount or in a less burdensome form, or order non-monetary conditions in\nconjunction with fixing bail, including fixing bail in a lesser amount\nor in a less burdensome form, the determination for which shall be made\nin accordance with section 510.10 of this title. The court shall explain\nthe basis for its determination and choice of securing order on the\nrecord or in writing.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nwhen the defendant is charged with a felony in a local criminal court, a\nsuperior court judge may not order recognizance, release under\nnon-monetary conditions or, where authorized, bail unless and until the\ndistrict attorney has had an opportunity to be heard in the matter and\nsuch judge and counsel for the defendant have been furnished with a\nreport as described in subparagraph (ii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\ntwo of section 530.20 of this article.\n  3. Not more than one application may be made pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>