<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-610.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-610.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="610.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-610.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-610.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-610.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-610.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_610_30">
        <num>610.30</num>
        <heading>Securing attendance of witnesses by subpoena; where subpoena may be served</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 610.30  Securing attendance of witnesses by subpoena; where subpoena\n             may be served.\n  1.  A subpoena of any criminal court, issued pursuant to section\n610.20, may be served anywhere in the county of issuance or anywhere in\nan adjoining county.\n  2.  A subpoena of a superior court or of a superior court judge\nsitting as a local criminal court, issued pursuant to section 610.20,\nmay be served anywhere in the state.\n  3.  A subpoena of a district court or of the New York City criminal\ncourt, issued pursuant to section 610.20, may be served anywhere in the\nstate; provided that, if such subpoena is issued by a prosecutor or by\nan attorney for a defendant, it may be served in a county other than the\ncounty of issuance or an adjoining county only if such court, upon\napplication of such prosecutor or attorney, endorses upon such subpoena\nan order for the attendance of the witness.\n  4.  A subpoena of a city court or a town court or a village court,\nissued pursuant to section 610.20, may be served in a county other than\nthe one of issuance or an adjoining county if a judge of a superior\ncourt, upon application of the issuing court or the district attorney or\nan attorney for the defendant, endorses upon such subpoena an order for\nthe attendance of the witness.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>