<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-620.60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-620.60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="620.60"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-620.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-620.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-620.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-620.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_620_60">
        <num>620.60</num>
        <heading>Material witness order; vacation, modification and amendment thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 620.60  Material witness order; vacation, modification and amendment\n             thereof.\n  1.  At any time after a material witness order has been issued the\ncourt must, upon application of such witness, with notice to the party\nupon whose application the order was issued, and with opportunity to be\nheard, make inquiry whether by reason of new or changed facts or\ncircumstances the material witness order is no longer necessary or\nwarranted, or, if it is, whether the original bail currently appears\nexcessive.  Upon making any such determination, the court must vacate\nthe order.  If its determination is that the order is no longer\nnecessary or warranted, it must, as the situation requires, either\ndischarge the witness from custody or exonerate the bail.  If its\ndetermination is that the bail is excessive, it must issue a new order\nfixing bail in a lesser amount or on less burdensome terms.\n  2.  At any time when a witness is at liberty upon bail pursuant to a\nmaterial witness order, the court may, upon application of the party\nupon whose application the order was issued, with notice to the witness\nif possible and to his attorney if any and opportunity to be heard, make\ninquiry whether, by reason of new or changed facts or circumstances, the\noriginal bail is no longer sufficient to secure the future attendance of\nthe witness at the pending action.  Upon making such a determination,\nthe court must vacate the order and issue a new order fixing bail in a\ngreater amount or on terms more likely to secure the future attendance\nof the witness.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>