<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-65.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-65.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="65.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-65.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-65.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-65.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-65.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_65_20">
        <num>65.20</num>
        <heading>Closed-circuit television; procedure for application and grounds for determination</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any of the provisions of article forty-five of\nthe civil practice law and rules, any physician, psychologist, nurse or\nsocial worker who has treated a child witness may testify at a hearing\nconducted pursuant to subdivision five of this section concerning the\ntreatment of such child witness as such treatment relates to the issue\npresented at the hearing, provided that any otherwise applicable\nstatutory privileges concerning communications between the child witness\nand such physician, psychologist, nurse or social worker in connection\nwith such treatment shall not be deemed waived by such testimony alone,\nexcept to the limited extent of permitting the court alone to examine in\ncamera reports, records or documents, if any, prepared by such\nphysician, psychologist, nurse or social worker. If upon such\nexamination the court determines that such reports, records or\ndocuments, or any one or portion thereof, contain information material\nand relevant to the issue of whether the child witness is a vulnerable\nchild witness, the court shall disclose such information to both the\nattorney for the defendant and the district attorney.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At any time after a motion has been made pursuant to subdivision\none of this section, upon the demand of the other party the moving party\nmust furnish the demanding party with a copy of any and all of such\nrecords, reports or other documents in the possession of such other\nparty and must, in addition, supply the court with a copy of all such\nreports, records or other documents which are the subject of the demand.\nAt any time after a demand has been made pursuant to this paragraph, the\nmoving party may demand that property of the same kind or character in\npossession of the party that originally made such demand be furnished to\nthe moving party and, if so furnished, be supplied, in addition, to the\ncourt.\n  9.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prior to the commencement of the hearing conducted pursuant to\nsubdivision six of this section, the district attorney shall, subject to\na protective order, comply with the provisions of subdivision one of\nsection 245.20 of this chapter as they concern any witness whom the\ndistrict attorney intends to call at the hearing and the child witness.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Before a defendant calls a witness at such hearing, he or she\nmust, subject to a protective order, comply with the provisions of\nsubdivision four of section 245.20 of this chapter as they concern all\nthe witnesses the defendant intends to call at such hearing.\n  10. The court may consider, in determining whether there are factors\nwhich would cause the child witness to suffer serious mental or\nemotional harm, a finding that any one or more of the following\ncircumstances have been established by clear and convincing evidence:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The manner of the commission of the offense of which the defendant\nis accused was particularly heinous or was characterized by aggravating\ncircumstances.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The child witness is particularly young or otherwise particularly\nsubject to psychological harm on account of a physical or mental\ncondition which existed before the alleged commission of the offense.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the time of the alleged offense, the defendant occupied a\nposition of authority with respect to the child witness.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The offense or offenses charged were part of an ongoing course of\nconduct committed by the defendant against the child witness over an\nextended period of time.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A deadly weapon or dangerous instrument was allegedly used during\nthe commission of the crime.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The defendant has inflicted serious physical injury upon the child\nwitness.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A threat, express or implied, of physical violence to the child\nwitness or a third person if the child witness were to report the\nincident to any person or communicate information to or cooperate with a\ncourt, grand jury, prosecutor, police officer or peace officer\nconcerning the incident has been made by or on behalf of the defendant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A threat, express or implied, of the incarceration of a parent or\nguardian of the child witness, the removal of the child witness from the\nfamily or the dissolution of the family of the child witness if the\nchild witness were to report the incident to any person or communicate\ninformation to or cooperate with a court, grand jury, prosecutor, police\nofficer or peace officer concerning the incident has been made by or on\nbehalf of the defendant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A witness other than the child witness has received a threat of\nphysical violence directed at such witness or to a third person by or on\nbehalf of the defendant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The defendant, at the time of the inquiry,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is living in the\nsame household with the child witness, (ii) has ready access to the\nchild witness or (iii) is providing substantial financial support for\nthe child witness.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The child witness has previously been the victim of an offense\ndefined in article one hundred thirty of the penal law or incest as\ndefined in section 255.25, 255.26 or 255.27 of such law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_20__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>According to expert testimony, the child witness would be\nparticularly suceptible to psychological harm if required to testify in\nopen court or in the physical presence of the defendant.\n  11. Irrespective of whether a motion was made pursuant to subdivision\none of this section, the court, at the request of either party or on its\nown motion, may decide that a child witness may be vulnerable based on\nits own observations that a child witness who has been called to testify\nat a criminal proceeding is suffering severe mental or emotional harm\nand therefore is physically or mentally unable to testify or to continue\nto testify in open court or in the physical presence of the defendant\nand that the use of live, two-way closed-circuit television is necessary\nto enable the child witness to testify. If the court so decides, it must\nconduct the same hearing that subdivision five of this section requires\nwhen a motion is made pursuant to subdivision one of this section, and\nit must make findings of fact pursuant to subdivisions nine and eleven\nof this section, before determining that the child witness is\nvulnerable.\n  12. In deciding whether a child witness is vulnerable, the court shall\nmake findings of fact which reflect the causal relationship between the\nexistence of any one or more of the factors set forth in subdivision\nnine of this section or other relevant factors which the court finds are\nestablished and the determination that the child witness is vulnerable.\nIf the court is satisfied that the child witness is vulnerable and that,\nunder the facts and circumstances of the particular case, the\ndefendant's constitutional rights to an impartial jury or of\nconfrontation will not be impaired, it may enter an order granting the\napplication for the use of live, two-way closed-circuit television.\n  13. When the court has determined that a child witness is a vulnerable\nchild witness, it shall make a specific finding as to whether placing\nthe defenda...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>