<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.55"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.55"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="700.55"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_700_55">
        <num>700.55</num>
        <heading>Eavesdropping and video surveillance warrants; custody of warrants, applications and recordings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 700.55 Eavesdropping and video surveillance warrants; custody of\n             warrants, applications and recordings.\n  1.  Applications made and warrants issued under this article shall be\nsealed by the justice.  Any eavesdropping or video surveillance warrant,\ntogether with a copy of papers upon which the application is based,\nshall be delivered to and retained by the applicant as authority for the\neavesdropping or video surveillance authorized therein.  A copy of such\neavesdropping or video surveillance warrant, together with all the\noriginal papers upon which the application was based, must be retained\nby the justice issuing the same, and, in the event of the denial of an\napplication for such an eavesdropping or video surveillance warrant, a\ncopy of the papers upon which the application was based must be retained\nby the justice denying the same.  Such applications and warrants may be\ndisclosed only upon a showing of good cause before a court and may not\nbe destroyed except on order of the issuing or denying justice, and in\nany event must be kept for ten years.\n  2.  Custody of the recordings made pursuant to subdivision three of\nsection 700.35 may be wherever the justice orders.  They may not be\ndestroyed except upon an order of the justice who issued the warrant and\nin any event must be kept for ten years.  Duplicate recordings may be\nmade for use or disclosure pursuant to the provisions of subdivisions\none and two of section 700.65 for investigations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>