<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-710.60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-710.60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="710.60"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-710.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-710.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-710.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-710.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_710_60">
        <num>710.60</num>
        <heading>Motion to suppress evidence; procedure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_710_60__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The motion papers comply with the requirements of subdivision one\nand the people concede the truth of allegations of fact therein which\nsupport the motion; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_710_60__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The people stipulate that the evidence sought to be suppressed\nwill not be offered in evidence in any criminal action or proceeding\nagainst the defendant.\n  3. The court may summarily deny the motion if:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_710_60__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The motion papers do not allege a ground constituting legal basis\nfor the motion; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_710_60__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sworn allegations of fact do not as a matter of law support\nthe ground alleged; except that this paragraph does not apply where the\nmotion is based upon the ground specified in subdivision three or six of\nsection 710.20.\n  4. If the court does not determine the motion pursuant to subdivisions\ntwo or three, it must conduct a hearing and make findings of fact\nessential to the determination thereof. All persons giving factual\ninformation at such hearing must testify under oath, except that unsworn\nevidence pursuant to subdivision two of section 60.20 of this chapter\nmay also be received. Upon such hearing, hearsay evidence is admissible\nto establish any material fact.\n  5. A motion to suppress evidence made during trial may be in writing\nand may be litigated and determined on the basis of motion papers as\nprovided in subdivisions one through four, or it may, instead, be made\norally in open court. In the latter event, the court must, where\nnecessary, also conduct a hearing as provided in subdivision four, out\nof the presence of the jury if any, and make findings of fact essential\nto the determination of the motion.\n  6. Regardless of whether a hearing was conducted, the court, upon\ndetermining the motion, must set forth on the record its findings of\nfact, its conclusions of law and the reasons for its determination.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>