<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-09-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="722.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_722_20">
        <num>722.20</num>
        <heading>Proceedings upon felony complaint; juvenile offender</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If there is reasonable cause to believe that the defendant\ncommitted a crime for which a person under the age of sixteen is\ncriminally responsible, the court must order that the defendant be held\nfor the action of a grand jury; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If there is not reasonable cause to believe that the defendant\ncommitted a crime for which a person under the age of sixteen is\ncriminally responsible but there is reasonable cause to believe that the\ndefendant is a "juvenile delinquent" as defined in subdivision one of\nsection 301.2 of the family court act, the court must specify the act or\nacts it found reasonable cause to believe the defendant did and direct\nthat the action be removed to the family court in accordance with the\nprovisions of article seven hundred twenty-five of this title; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If there is not reasonable cause to believe that the defendant\ncommitted any criminal act, the court must dismiss the felony complaint\nand discharge the defendant from custody if he is in custody, or if he\nis at liberty on bail, it must exonerate the bail.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions two and three of\nthis section, the court shall, at the request of the district attorney,\norder removal of an action against a juvenile offender to the family\ncourt pursuant to the provisions of article seven hundred twenty-five of\nthis title if, upon consideration of the criteria specified in\nsubdivision two of section 722.22 of this article, it is determined that\nto do so would be in the interests of justice. Where, however, the\nfelony complaint charges the juvenile offender with murder in the second\ndegree as defined in section 125.25 of the penal law, rape in the first\ndegree as defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one, paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision two and paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of section 130.35\nof the penal law, rape in the first degree as formerly defined in\nsubdivision one of section 130.35 of the penal law; a crime formerly\ndefined in subdivision one of section 130.50 of the penal law, or an\narmed felony as defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision forty-one of\nsection 1.20 of this chapter, a determination that such action be\nremoved to the family court shall, in addition, be based upon a finding\nof one or more of the following factors:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>mitigating circumstances\nthat bear directly upon the manner in which the crime was committed; or\n(ii) where the defendant was not the sole participant in the crime, the\ndefendant's participation was relatively minor although not so minor as\nto constitute a defense to the prosecution; or (iii) possible\ndeficiencies in proof of the crime.\n  5. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision two, three, or four\nof this section, if a currently undetermined felony complaint against a\njuvenile offender is pending, and the defendant has not waived a hearing\npursuant to subdivision two of this section and a hearing pursuant to\nsubdivision three of this section has not commenced, the defendant may\nmove to remove the action to family court pursuant to 722.22 of this\narticle. The procedural rules of subdivisions one and two of section\n210.45 of this chapter are applicable to a motion pursuant to this\nsubdivision. Upon such motion, the court shall proceed and determine the\nmotion as provided in section 722.22 of this article; provided, however,\nthat the exception provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsection 722.22 of this article shall not apply when there is not\nreasonable cause to believe that the juvenile offender committed one or\nmore of the crimes enumerated therein, and in such event the provisions\nof paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>thereof shall apply.\n  6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court orders removal of the action to family court, it\nshall state on the record the factor or factors upon which its\ndetermination is based, and the court shall give its reasons for removal\nin detail and not in conclusory terms.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The district attorney shall state upon the record the reasons for\nhis consent to removal of the action to the family court where such\nconsent is required. The reasons shall be stated in detail and not in\nconclusory terms.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purpose of making a determination pursuant to subdivision\nfour or five of this section, the court may make such inquiry as it\ndeems necessary. Any evidence which is not legally privileged may be\nintroduced. If the defendant testifies, his testimony may not be\nintroduced against him in any future proceeding, except to impeach his\ntestimony at such future proceeding as inconsistent prior testimony.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a motion for removal by the defendant pursuant to\nsubdivision five of this section has been denied, no further motion\npursuant to this section or section 722.22 of this article may be made\nby the juvenile offender with respect to the same offense or offenses.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, this\nsection shall not be construed to limit the powers of the grand jury.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_722_20__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a motion by the defendant pursuant to subdivision five of\nthis section has been granted, there shall be no further proceedings\nagainst the juvenile offender in any local or superior criminal court\nincluding the youth part of the superior court for the offense or\noffenses which were the subject of the removal order.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>