<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="105-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_105_I">
        <num>105-I</num>
        <heading>Partial reimbursement by state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 105-i. Partial reimbursement by state.  Each county shall be\nentitled to partial reimbursement by the state for payments by the\ncounty of indemnification on account of damages resulting from rabies as\nprovided in this article, to the extent of fifty per centum of the\namount of its approved expenditures for such indemnification. Not later\nthan the last day in each of the months of June, September, December and\nMarch the county treasurer of each county which has made payments to\nclaimants during the three months' period ending on such days pursuant\nto the provisions of this article shall make a report to the\ncommissioner of agriculture and markets of the amount of its\nexpenditures for payments to claimants under this article and apply for\nstate reimbursement to the extent of fifty per centum of its approved\nexpenditures therefor. Such report and application shall be in such form\nand contain such information as may be required by such commissioner.\nThe commissioner shall thereupon promptly certify to the comptroller for\npayment the amount of state reimbursement due the county thereon. The\namounts so certified by the commissioner of agriculture and markets,\nafter audit by and on the warrant of the comptroller, shall be paid to\nthe county treasurers of the respective counties to which such\nreimbursement is due, from any moneys available by appropriation\ntherefor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>