<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="105-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-105-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_105_F">
        <num>105-F</num>
        <heading>Review by commissioner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 105-f. Review by commissioner.  If the claimant desires to appeal\nthe county treasurer's disapproval of his claim or if he is dissatisfied\nwith the amount of the damage as set forth in the assessor's report, he\nmay, within ten days after the receipt of the report, present to the\ncommissioner a request for a review. The county treasurer may, within\nten days after receiving the report of the assessor, if dissatisfied\nwith the damages stated in the report, present to the commissioner a\nrequest for a review. Upon receipt of such request, from either the\nclaimant or the county treasurer, the commissioner shall cause an\ninvestigation to be made of the facts surrounding the death of the\nanimal or animals described therein and the amount of damage incurred\nthereby for which indemnification should be made in accordance with the\nintent of this article. The claimant shall permit the commissioner or\nhis duly authorized representative to enter the premises where the\nanimal or animals for which indemnification is claimed were kept,\nharbored or pastured, and shall furnish to the commissioner or his duly\nauthorized representative whatever information and proof may be\navailable to the claimant and deemed necessary by the commissioner or\nhis representative to complete the investigation. After the completion\nof such investigation the commissioner shall make his decision in\nwriting as set forth in the preceding section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>