<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="107"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_107">
        <num>107</num>
        <heading>Application</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 107. Application. 1. This article shall apply to all areas of the\nstate except any city having a population of over two million.\n  2. In the event that any dog owned by a resident of any city having a\npopulation of over two million or by a non-resident of this state is\nharbored within this state outside of any such city, the licensing\nmunicipality in which such animal is harbored may exempt such dog from\nthe identification and licensing provisions of this article for a period\nof thirty days provided such dog is licensed pursuant to the provisions\nof law of the area of residence.\n  3. This article shall not apply to any dog confined to the premises of\nany public or private hospital devoted solely to the treatment of sick\nanimals, or confined for the purposes of research to the premises of any\ncollege or other educational or research institution.\n  4. This article shall not apply to any dog confined to the premises of\nany person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of breeding or\nraising dogs for profit and licensed as a class A dealer under the\nFederal Laboratory Animal Welfare Act.\n  5. Nothing contained in this article shall prevent a municipality from\nadopting its own program for the control of dangerous dogs; provided,\nhowever, that no such program shall be less stringent than this article,\nand no such program shall regulate such dogs in a manner that is\nspecific as to breed. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one\nof this section, this subdivision and sections one hundred twenty-three,\none hundred twenty-three-a and one hundred twenty-three-b of this\narticle shall apply to all municipalities including cities of two\nmillion or more.\n  6. Nothing contained in this article shall be construed to prohibit a\ncounty from administering a dog licensing program for the municipalities\nwithin its jurisdiction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>