<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11">
        <num>11</num>
        <heading>Other officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11. Other officers and employees. There shall be such agents,\ninspectors, chemists, experts, statisticians, accountants and other\nassistants and employees, as the commissioner shall deem necessary for\nthe exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties of the\ndepartment under this chapter.\n  Such officers and employees shall be appointed by the commissioner and\nhold office during the pleasure of the commissioner. The officers and\nemployees of the department who are in office when this chapter takes\neffect shall continue in office during the pleasure of the commissioner.\n  The commissioner may transfer officers or employees from their\npositions to other positions in the department, or abolish or\nconsolidate such positions.\n  Prior to the appointment of inspectors and investigators by the\ndepartment, applicants for such positions shall be fingerprinted as a\ncondition of employment. Such fingerprints shall be submitted to the\ndivision of criminal justice services for a state criminal history\nrecord check, as defined in subdivision one of section three thousand\nthirty-five of the education law, and may be submitted to the federal\nbureau of investigation for a national criminal history record check.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>