<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-113"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-113"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="113"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_113">
        <num>113</num>
        <heading>Dog control officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 113. Dog control officers. 1. Each town and city, and each village\nin which licenses are issued, shall appoint, and any other village and\nany county may appoint, one or more dog control officers for the purpose\nof assisting, within the appointing municipality, with the control of\ndogs and the enforcement of this article.\n  2. In lieu of or in addition to the appointment of a dog control\nofficer or officers, any town or city, or any village in which licenses\nare issued shall, and any other village and any county may, contract for\ndog control officer services with any other municipality or with any\nincorporated humane society or similar incorporated dog protective\nassociation, or shall appoint, jointly with one or more other\nmunicipalities, one or more dog control officers having jurisdiction in\neach of the cooperating municipalities.\n  3. Every dog control officer shall have the power to issue an\nappearance ticket pursuant to section 150.20 of the criminal procedure\nlaw, to serve a summons and to serve and execute any other order or\nprocess in the execution of the provisions of this article. In addition,\nany dog control officer or any peace officer, when acting pursuant to\nhis special duties, or police officer, who is authorized by a\nmunicipality to assist in the enforcement of this article may serve any\nprocess, including an appearance ticket, a uniform appearance ticket and\na uniform appearance ticket and simplified information, related to any\nproceeding, whether criminal or civil in nature undertaken in accord\nwith the provisions of this article or any local law or ordinance\npromulgated pursuant thereto.\n  4. Every dog control officer, peace officer, when acting pursuant to\nhis special duties or police officer shall promptly make and maintain a\ncomplete record of any seizure and subsequent disposition of any dog.\nSuch record shall include, but not be limited to, a description of the\ndog, the date and hour of seizure, the official identification number of\nsuch dog, if any, the location where seized, the reason for seizure, and\nthe owner's name and address, if known.\n  5. Every dog control officer shall file and maintain such records for\nnot less than three years following the creation of such record, and\nshall make such reports available to the commissioner upon request.\n  6. The governing body of any municipality in which licenses are\nissued, may, either individually or in cooperation with other municipal\nentities, require its dog control officer or animal control officer or\nany other authorized agent to ascertain and list the names of all\npersons in the municipality owning or harboring dogs, or in lieu\nthereof, such municipality may contract to have the same done.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>