<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-128-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-128-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-05-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="128-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-128-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-128-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-128-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-128-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_128_A">
        <num>128-A</num>
        <heading>Licenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_128_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any statement in the application or upon which it was issued is or\nwas false or misleading;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_128_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>facilities of the applicant are not maintained in a manner as\nrequired by rules and regulations duly promulgated by the commissioner;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_128_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the maintenance and operation of the establishment of the\napplicant is such that the commercial feed produced therein is or may be\nadulterated, misbranded, or not maintained in any manner as required by\nthis article;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_128_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant or licensee, or an officer, director, partner or\nholder of ten per centum or more of the voting stock of the applicant or\nlicensee, has failed to comply with any of the provisions of this\narticle or rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_128_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant or licensee is a partnership or corporation and any\nindividual holding any position or interest or power of control therein\nhas previously been responsible in whole or in part for any act on\naccount of which an application for licensure may be denied or a license\nrevoked pursuant to the provisions of this article.\n  3. Inspection in accordance with section one hundred thirty-five-a of\nthis article, the results of which establish compliance with the\nprovisions of this article, shall precede issuance of a license or\nrenewal thereof under this section.\n  4. Upon validation by the commissioner, the application shall become\nthe license of the person.\n  5. The commissioner shall provide a copy of the license to the\nlicensee.  The commissioner shall also retain a copy of the license.\n  6. No licensee shall publish or advertise the sale of any commercial\nfeed unless the publication or advertisement is accompanied by such\nlicensee's license number.\n  7. Commercial feed licenses shall be conspicuously displayed on the\npremises so that they may be readily seen by officers and employees of\nthe department.\n  8. Notwithstanding the definition of commercial feed under subdivision\nseven of section one hundred twenty-eight of this article, the\nprovisions of this section shall not apply to a person who conducts a\nbusiness of selling pet food and specialty pet food.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>