<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-135-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-135-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="135-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-135-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-135-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-135-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-135-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_135_B">
        <num>135-B</num>
        <heading>Detained commercial feeds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 135-b. Detained commercial feeds. 1. Stop sale order: When the\ncommissioner or his authorized agent has probable cause to believe any\nlot of commercial feed is being, or is about to be distributed in\nviolation of any of the provisions of this article or any of the rules\nand regulations adopted pursuant thereto, the commissioner or his\nauthorized agent may issue and enforce a written stop sale order,\nwarning the distributor not to remove or dispose of the lot of\ncommercial feed in any manner until written permission for removal or\ndisposal is given by the commissioner or his authorized agent. The\ncommissioner or his authorized agent shall release the lot of feed so\ndetained if and when said provisions and regulations have been complied\nwith. If compliance is not obtained within fifteen days, the\ncommissioner may begin, or upon request of the distributor or registrant\nshall begin, seizure proceedings in accordance with the provisions of\nsection two hundred two-b of this chapter.\n  2. Seizure: Whenever the commissioner or his authorized agent shall\nfind distributed, or about to be distributed, any lot of commercial feed\nwhich is unfit or unsafe for use as commercial feed, and its\ncondemnation is required to protect the public health, the commissioner\nor his authorized agent may seize, destroy or denature such feed so that\nit cannot thereafter be used for commercial feed.\n  Whenever the commissioner or his authorized agent finds, or has\nprobable cause to believe, that any lot of commercial feed is\nadulterated or misbranded within the meaning of this article, or if any\nperson fails to comply with a stop sale order duly issued pursuant to\nthe preceding subdivision, the commissioner or his authorized agent\nshall seize such feed in accordance with the provisions of section two\nhundred two-b of this chapter.\n  All proceedings subsequent to seizure, including if necessary\ndestruction of the feed after ten days' notice in writing to the\ndistributor and an opportunity to be heard, shall be had in accordance\nwith the provisions of section two hundred two-b. Prior to destruction\nof any commercial feed pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision,\nexcept where a commercial feed is unfit or unsafe for use as commercial\nfeed and its condemnation is required to protect the public health, the\ncommissioner or his authorized agent, upon request by the distributor,\nmay afford the distributor an opportunity to reprocess or relabel said\nfeed to bring it into compliance.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>