<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="142-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142_B">
        <num>142-B</num>
        <heading>The New York native plant seed supply, development and enhancement program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_142_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>increase the production of native plant seeds, as provided for in\nsubdivision three of this section, at plant nurseries in the state; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_142_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>increase the use of native plant seeds, as provided for in\nsubdivision three of this section, in public land management, roadside\nlandscaping, reforestation, pollinator promotion, habitat restoration,\nregular groundskeeping and maintenance on state lands, and other\nprojects as determined by the commissioners of the department, the\ndepartment of environmental conservation, and economic development.\n  3. No later than one year after the effective date of this section,\nthe commissioners shall develop a list of plant seeds eligible for\nconsideration to participate in such program and/or for use in\nconnection with the requirement of subdivision six of this section. The\nlist shall be updated by the commissioners at least once every three\nyears or if determined necessary by the commissioners.\n  4. Funds for the program shall be subject to appropriation and may be\nused to establish growing operations managed by the state or to support\nprivate entities that can increase the state's native plant seed supply.\n  5. As used in this section, "native plant seed" means:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_142_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>non-invasive herbaceous and woody plant species that are\nindigeneous to New York state and are likely to maintain their range or\nsuccessfully adapt to anticipated climate changes in New York state and\nthe northeastern United States, or native, non-invasive plants found\nelsewhere in the United States that are likely to shift or expand their\nrange into New York state and the northeastern United States in response\nto the anticipated climate change; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_142_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>germinating seeds, or other plant parts, used to propagate\ndesirable native plants representing a wide variety of species and\ngenotypes of plants.\n  6. Whenever possible and practicable, the state shall make use of\nnative plant seeds when engaging in public land management, roadside\nlandscaping, reforestation, pollinator promotion, habitat restoration,\nregular groundskeeping and maintenance on state lands, and other\nprojects as determined by the commissioners of the department, the\ndepartment of environmental conservation, and the department of economic\ndevelopment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>