<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="142-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142_CC">
        <num>142-CC</num>
        <heading>Label or accompanying statement and weigh slip</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 142-cc. Label or accompanying statement and weigh slip. No\nagricultural liming material shall be sold, offered, or exposed for\nsale, bartered, given or otherwise supplied in this state unless there\nshall be affixed to each package in a conspicuous place on the outside\nthereof a plainly printed, stamped or otherwise marked label, tag or\nstatement or in the case of bulk sales or transfers there shall be\nprovided a certified weigh slip plainly printed, stamped or otherwise\nmarked, which shall certify as follows:\n  1. The name, principal office address and plant location of the\nmanufacturer, producer or distributor.\n  2. The identification of the product as to the type of liming\nmaterial.\n  3. The brand under which it is sold or supplied.\n  4. A statement expressing the minimum total neutralizing value stated\nas calcium carbonate equivalence and the minimum fineness, at time of\ndelivery.\n  5. The net weight of the material.\n  6. The kind and amount of adulterant or foreign material therein, if\nany, expressed by weight of the material.\n  7. In the case of any material which has been damaged, hydrated,\nadulterated or otherwise changed subsequent to the original packaging,\nlabelling, or loading thereof and before delivery to the consumer, a\nplainly marked notice to that effect shall be affixed by the vendor to\nthe package or accompanying statement, such notice to identify the kind\nand degree of such damage, hydration, adulteration or other change\ntherein.\n  8. A guarantee of the calcium and magnesium content expressed as a\npercentage by weight of each such element.\n  9. For agricultural liming material sold in bulk, a guarantee of the\npercentage of its effective neutralizing value, as determined in\naccordance with regulations adopted by the commissioner. Such value\nshall also be expressed separately as the weight of such bulk material\nnecessary to equal one ton of agricultural liming material having an\neffective neutralizing value of one hundred percent.\n  At every site, from which agricultural liming products are delivered\nin bulk, and at every place where consumer orders for bulk deliveries\nare placed, there shall be conspicuously posted a copy of the statement\nrequired by this section for each brand of material.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>