<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="142"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-142/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142">
        <num>142</num>
        <heading>Implementation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 142. Implementation. The commissioner may adopt and promulgate such\nrules and regulations to supplement and give full effect to the\nprovisions of this article as he may deem necessary. The commissioner or\nhis authorized agents may remove from further sale or prohibit from sale\nany unlabeled seed or any seeds which are found to be so unclean as to\nbe unfit for seeding purposes until they have been properly recleaned\nand may prohibit further sale or may destroy seeds which are found to be\nso weak or low in germination as to be unfit for seeding purposes.\n  The commissioner may, through promulgation of regulations, add to, or\nsubtract noxious weed seeds from definition seven, section one hundred\nthirty-six of this article, whenever he finds, after public hearing,\nthat such addition or subtraction is in the best interests of the\nagriculture of this state.\n  In promulgating the initial germination standard for each kind of\nflower, tree and shrub seed, the commissioner shall publish the proposed\nstandard at least three years previous to its effective date and shall\narrange a public hearing for consideration of the proposed standard\nprior to its final adoption. The commissioner may, at his discretion,\ntemporarily suspend any flower seed germination standard thus\npromulgated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>