<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="146-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_146_C">
        <num>146-C</num>
        <heading>Reports and fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 146-c. Reports and fees. Each licensee who distributes commercial\nfertilizers in this state shall furnish the commissioner with a written\nstatement of the tonnage of each grade of commercial fertilizer,\nincluding zero tonnage if applicable, sold by him or her in this state\nduring the calendar year to persons not required to be licensed under\nthis article. The tonnage of grades of which less than fifty tons were\nsold shall be reported, either individually or combined under the\nheading of miscellaneous sales. This report shall be submitted in the\nform and with such frequency as the commissioner shall require by\nregulation. The licensee shall pay to the commissioner a sum equal to\nten cents for each ton or portion thereof of commercial fertilizer\ndistributed in this state to persons not required to be licensed under\nthis article provided that such annual tonnage fee shall not be less\nthan fifty dollars. This fee shall be remitted on or before February\nfirst and calculated based on the calendar year immediately preceding.\n  No information furnished under this section shall be disclosed in such\na way as to divulge the method or scope of the operation of any person.\n  The commissioner shall publish at least annually a summary of the\ntonnage reports submitted pursuant to this section.\n  The licensee shall make such other reports as the commissioner may\nrequire.\n  Failure to make such reports or to pay such fee shall be grounds for\nrevocation of the license hereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>