<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="146"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-146/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_146">
        <num>146</num>
        <heading>Licensing</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_146__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall distribute in this state any\ntype of fertilizer until a license to distribute the same has been\nobtained from the commissioner by the person whose labelling is applied\nto such fertilizer upon payment of a one hundred fifty dollar fee. The\ninitial license issued hereunder shall expire on December thirty-first\nof the next even numbered year following the year in which it was issued\nand each renewal of that license shall be for a two year period, ending\non December thirty-first. Application for a renewal of such license\nshall be made biennially, upon a form prescribed by the commissioner and\nbe submitted no later than thirty days prior to the expiration of the\nexisting license.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_146__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The application shall include:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_146__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name and address of\nlicensee;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_146__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Name and address of each manufacturing plant, blending plant and\nbulk storage facility within New York state which distributes commercial\nfertilizer, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_146__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A list of the brand and product name of all commercial fertilizer\ndistributed in this state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_146__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The licensee shall inform the commissioner in writing of\nadditional distribution points established during the period of the\nlicense.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_146__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner is authorized and empowered to revoke the license\nof any distributor of commercial fertilizer, or to refuse to grant or to\nrenew the license of any distributor as herein provided, upon\nsatisfactory evidence that the licensee or applicant has used fraudulent\nor deceptive practices in the evasion or attempted evasion of the\nprovisions of this article, or of any rules or regulations promulgated\nhereunder or if the license application or the information furnished\nupon the sale of the commercial fertilizer is misleading or deceptive or\ntends to mislead or deceive as to its quality or the constituents or\nmaterials of which it is composed. No license shall be revoked or\nrefused until the distributor shall have been given an opportunity to\nappear for a hearing before the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>