<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-147-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-147-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="147-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-147-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-147-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-147-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-147-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_147_B">
        <num>147-B</num>
        <heading>License</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 147-b. License. No person shall sell, offer or expose for sale in\nthis state any soil or plant inoculant unless licensed as provided in\nthis section. Application for a license shall be made upon a form\nprescribed by the commissioner and shall include a statement as to\nwhether the inoculant is represented as effective for inoculating\nlegumes or for some other purpose, and, if represented as effective for\nthe inoculation of legumes, for which legume or legumes it is so\nrepresented. With the application, the applicant shall present a\nrepresentative sample of the soil or plant inoculant described in the\napplication. The commissioner, if satisfied that the inoculant may be\ndepended upon to produce an effective inoculation for the purpose\nrepresented, shall issue to such applicant a license for the sale of\nsuch inoculant, expiring on December thirty-first of the next even\nnumbered year following its issuance.  Application for renewal of such\nlicense for a period of two years shall be made biennially upon a form\nprescribed by the commissioner and submitted no later than thirty days\nprior to the expiration of the existing license.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>