<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-148-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-148-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="148-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-148-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-148-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-148-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-148-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_148_D">
        <num>148-D</num>
        <heading>Vegetable and potato pest management</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 148-d. Vegetable and potato pest management. Within the integrated\npest management program, there shall be established a vegetable and\npotato pest management program. Such program shall be conducted in such\na manner to achieve the following objectives:\n  1. determine the occurrence and severity of pest problems in\ncommercial fields, and identify the specific environmental factors\ninfluencing these events. Document the current pesticide usage and\nassess the effectiveness of current pest management practices;\n  2. determine accurate and time-efficient sampling procedures and\nforecasting methods which can be utilized by private consultants or\nthrough cooperative extension. Determine the economic relationship of\npest incidence to yield or quality loss. Develop non-pesticide methods\nof pest management in the areas of cultural practices, biological\ncontrol and crop resistance. In addition the proper timing, selection\nand use of pesticides will be integrated into the overall management\nprograms;\n  3. aid growers in executing the most optimal crop protection program\nby providing them with timely reports on pest presence and population\ndensity levels, forecasted pest occurrences, crop growth, weather and\nother environmental information, and providing the most current\ninterpretation of the data;\n  4. increase efforts to educate growers in the principles and tactics\nof integrated pest management and demonstrate the economic advantages of\nsuch a program;\n  5. develop concepts, techniques, and cultivars for integration of pest\nresistance with other management tactics in potato production (e.g. crop\nrotation, biological control, optimum use of pesticides);\n  6. develop pest sampling procedures, sound action thresholds,\nforecasting procedures, and economic data necessary for effective\ndecisions in use of pest resistant cultivars and other tactics for\nmanagement of pests;\n  7. demonstrate the benefits and reliability of improved pest\nmanagement tactics to the New York potato industry; and\n  8. monitor performance of the proposed integrated pest management\nprogram during its initial phase of implementation by the potato\nindustry.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>