<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-06-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="151-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_151_N">
        <num>151-N</num>
        <heading>Climate resilient farming initiative</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 151-n. Climate resilient farming initiative. 1. The department, in\ncooperation with the state soil and water conservation committee, and\nother partners working on climate resilient farming shall encourage\nagricultural producers in urban, suburban and rural communities to\nreduce the effects of farming on climate change, such as greenhouse gas\nemissions, and adapt to and mitigate the impact of climate change by\nimproving and maintaining water management systems and soil health and\nresiliency.\n  2. The department shall promote best management practices for climate\nmitigation and soil resiliency, as informed by state policy, by the\nUnited States Department of Agriculture Natural Resources Conservation\nService Field Office Technical Guide and by research conducted by New\nYork state institutions of higher education with expertise in soil\nhealth, and approved by the New York state soil and water conservation\ncommittee.\n  3. The department shall coordinate the climate resilient farming\ninitiative with the agricultural environmental management program\nestablished in article eleven-A of this chapter and section eleven of\nthe soil and water conservation districts law.\n  4. The commissioner and the state soil and water conservation\ncommittee are each empowered to promulgate such rules and regulations\nand to prescribe such forms as each shall deem necessary to effectuate\nthe purpose of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>