<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-06-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="151-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-151-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_151_M">
        <num>151-M</num>
        <heading>Soil health initiative</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_151_M__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>improving, enhancing, or otherwise maximizing soil health and\nquality, and minimizing soil erosion and sedimentation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_151_M__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>improving, enhancing, or otherwise maximizing water infiltration\nrates and water holding capacities of soils for improved storm water\nmanagement and flood control, drought resilience, and groundwater\nsupply; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_151_M__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>managing and enhancing the healthy cycling of nutrients within\nfields, to minimize nutrient runoff and reduce downstream nutrient\nloading, improve watershed health and reliable water availability,\nrestore and enhance wildlife habitat, and manage water runoff and\ndrainage water for improved local and downstream water quality.\n  3. The department, in the development of efforts to promote and\nencourage soil health, shall conduct public virtually accessible\nstakeholder meetings and provide opportunity for written public comment\nand consult with stakeholders, as appropriate, including, but not\nlimited to: the state soil and water conservation committee, the\ndepartment of environmental conservation, agricultural producers\nincluding historically marginalized producers, not-for-profit\nconservation organizations, environmental protection organizations\nincluding environmental justice, the United States Department of\nAgriculture's National Resources Conservation Services, the New York\nstate college of agriculture and life sciences established in section\nfifty-seven hundred twelve of the education law including Cornell\nCooperative Extension, other institutions of higher education in New\nYork state working on soil health, and any other organization designated\nby the commissioner.\n  4. The department, in cooperation with the state soil and water\nconservation committee, the New York state college of agriculture and\nlife sciences established in section fifty-seven hundred twelve of the\neducation law, and with input from other organizations with expertise in\nsoil health and regional stakeholders, shall establish appropriate\nvoluntary standards and objectives for soil health and quality,\nreflective of the different geographic regions, soil types, and farming\noperations. Such standards should include soil quality indicators for\nbiological, physical, and chemical properties of soil and reflect the\nlatest scientific advancements.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>