<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-152"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-152"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="152"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-152/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-152/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-152/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-152/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_152">
        <num>152</num>
        <heading>Adulteration and sale of turpentine; notification of purchaser</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 152. Adulteration and sale of turpentine; notification of purchaser.\nNo person shall manufacture, mix for sale, sell or offer for sale under\nthe name of turpentine, spirits of turpentine, or wood turpentine or any\ncompounding of the word turpentine, or under any name or device\nillustrating or suggesting turpentine or spirits of turpentine, any\narticle which is not wholly distilled or derived from resin, crude\nturpentine gum, or scrapings from pine trees, and unmixed and\nunadulterated with oil, benzine or any other substance of any kind\nwhatever, unless the package containing the same shall be stenciled or\nmarked, with legible black letters in the English language not less than\ntwo inches high and one inch in width, "adulterated spirits of\nturpentine." Nor shall any person, firm or corporation sell or deliver\nsuch adulterated spirits of turpentine without informing the purchaser\nat the time of sale that the article is not pure spirits of turpentine,\nand the invoice shall accordingly read, "adulterated spirits of\nturpentine." Every container in which such mixed or adulterated spirits\nof turpentine is contained shall, in addition to the labeling before\nmemtioned, be marked or stenciled in legible black letters in the\nEnglish language, with the percentage of adulterant or adulterants which\nare contained in such mixture.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>