<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-GG"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-GG"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156-GG"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_GG">
        <num>156-GG</num>
        <heading>Branding closed packages of potatoes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 156-gg. Branding closed packages of potatoes.  1. No person shall\nsell, expose for sale, or transport for sale, potatoes in closed\npackages which are not branded or marked with the grade of the potatoes\ncontained therein in conformity with official standards and grades for\npotatoes established and promulgated by the commissioner under the\nprovisions of this article, or, with the official standards of the\nUnited States commonly known as U.S. grades, except that potatoes packed\nin consumer packages in retail stores containing fifteen pounds or less\nand exposed for sale therein need not be so marked provided they are\nexposed for sale immediately adjacent and conform in variety, grade,\nsize and condition to a bulk display of such potatoes which includes as\na part thereof a display sign conspicuously marked as to the grade of\nthe potatoes in conformity with the foregoing requirements of this\nsection. Potatoes in closed packages containing more than sixty pounds\nnet not graded and classified as to quality in accordance with such\nstandards and grades, nor branded or marked in conformity therewith,\nshall be branded or marked "unclassified".\n  2. For the purpose of this section, a closed package shall mean any\ncontainer the entire contents of which cannot be adequately inspected\nwithout opening it.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>