<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_C">
        <num>156-C</num>
        <heading>Farm products; official standards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 156-c. Farm products; official standards.  The commissioner is\nhereby authorized and empowered, after investigation and public hearing,\nto establish and promulgate official definitions and standards for\ngrading or classifying, packing and labeling farm products, or any of\nthem, packed or repacked within the state; and to change such official\nstandards from time to time.  The commissioner, in establishing such\nofficial standards, shall, among other things, take into account so far\nas applicable the factors of maturity, condition, soundness, color,\nshape, size and freedom from defects. Such official standards shall not\nbe lower in their requirements than the minimum requirements of the\nofficial standards for corresponding grades or classifications, as\npromulgated from time to time by the secretary of agriculture of the\nUnited States, commonly known as U. S. grades. The use of such official\nstandards when established shall be optional, but if and when used in\nrelation to any farm products they must be in conformance with such\nstandards.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>