<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_H">
        <num>156-H</num>
        <heading>Food and farm products promotion</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>New York state grown farm\nproducts packed within this state in accordance with official standards\nestablished as provided by this article, article thirteen, article\nthirteen-a, article thirteen-b, article thirteen-c and article\nthirteen-d of this chapter or New York state produced or landed aquatic\nproducts, subject to and in accordance with rules and regulations to be\npromulgated by the commissioner; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>New York state processed food products, manufactured within this\nstate in accordance with official standards established by the\ncommissioner pursuant to regulation, which are essentially composed of\nNew York state grown farm products, provided, however, that whenever the\ncommissioner determines, after public hearing, that the use of\ningredients not grown or produced in this state is necessary or\nbeneficial in manufacturing a particular product because such\ningredients are either not grown in New York or unavailable in\nsufficient quantity or at a reasonable price to allow the product to be\ncomposed of only New York state grown farm products, the standard for\nsuch product may authorize the inclusion of ingredients not produced in\nthis state, except that in no event shall an official brand or mark be\napproved for use on a food product unless at least fifty-one percent of\nits content is derived from New York state grown farm products.\n  3. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision two of this section,\nsuch brand or mark may be imprinted upon packages or labels attached to\npackages containing cheddar or American type cheese packed outside this\nstate provided that such product is manufactured within the state and\nmeets all other requirements for the inclusion or attachment of such\nbrand or mark.\n  4. No such label shall be imprinted on or attached to any package of\nfresh or processed products unless said products have been produced and\npacked in accordance with an official quality control program\nestablished by the commissioner. The rules and regulations shall provide\nfor a charge to be made for any inspections, except the commissioner, at\nhis or her discretion, need not make a charge for inspections carried\nout for the purposes of research and development of grades, standards,\ninspection and quality control techniques. The commissioner shall cause\nto be printed labels bearing a state brand in sufficient quantities to\nmeet the demand there...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>