<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-156-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_I">
        <num>156-I</num>
        <heading>Publicity fund</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 156-i. Publicity fund. All moneys received by the commissioner from\nsources other than the general fund or federal funds in the exercise of\nthe powers and duties set forth in subdivisions two, two-a, two-b,\ntwo-c, five-a, eight, nine, ten, sixteen, eighteen and twenty-one of\nsection sixteen of this chapter and all moneys received pursuant to\nsection one hundred fifty-six-h of this article, including moneys\nreceived from any source for or arising from publicity and promotional\nactivities, shall be transmitted to the state comptroller for deposit in\nan account or accounts within the miscellaneous special revenue fund.\nThe commissioner may accept contributions of money to an account within\nthe miscellaneous special revenue fund for services to aid in publicity\nwork undertaken by him or her. All such moneys shall be paid out of such\nfund on vouchers approved by the commissioner, after audit by and upon\nthe warrant of the comptroller. If a product ceases to be packed under\nthe state brand for a period of two consecutive years, the commissioner,\nat his or her discretion, may distribute moneys remaining in the fund\nand to the account of such products to the accounts of any or all\nproducts continuing to be packed under the state brand and expend such\nmoneys as this section provides.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>