<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-158"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-158"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="158"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-158/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-158/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-158/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-158/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_158">
        <num>158</num>
        <heading>Apples; adoption of grades; branding</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 158. Apples; adoption of grades; branding. The commissioner is\nhereby authorized and empowered, after investigation and public hearing,\nto fix and promulgate official standards for grading and classifying\napples packed or repacked within the state, and to change any of them\nfrom time to time. In establishing such standards he shall take into\naccount the factors of maturity, soundness, color and shape. The\nofficial standards so fixed and promulgated shall not be lower in their\nrequirements than the minimum requirements of the official standards for\ncorresponding grades of apples as promulgated from time to time by the\nsecretary of agriculture of the United States, which standards are\ncommonly known as the "United States grades."\n  Each closed package of apples, when sold, exposed for sale or\ntransported for sale, shall be plainly and conspicuously branded to\nshow:\n  (1) Variety.\n  (2) Grade.\n  (3) Minimum diameter or numerical count.\n  (4) Quantity of contents.\n  (5) Name and address of packer or repacker.\n  If the true name of the variety is not known to the packer or\nrepacker, the statement shall include the words "variety unknown" in\nplace of the name of the variety.\n  In case the branding upon any closed package of apples is changed, the\nperson making the change shall cancel the name and address of the\noriginal packer and substitute therefor his own name and address.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>