<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-16"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-16"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-16/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-16/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-16/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-16/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16">
        <num>16</num>
        <heading>General powers and duties of department</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>assist county legislative bodies, agricultural and farmland\nprotection boards and departments in creating and reviewing agricultural\ndistricts pursuant to sections three hundred three, three hundred\nthree-a and three hundred three-b of this chapter; and\n  (ii) assist the commissioner of taxation and finance to support\ntraining of assessors and any other local government officials who have\nresponsibility for agricultural assessment and taxation.\n  2-f. Aid in the promotion, marketing and sale of New York state farm\nproducts used for holiday celebrations and decorations, including, but\nnot limited to, Christmas trees, wreaths, pumpkins, flowers and other\nsimilar products in cooperation with the empire state development\ncorporation by providing listings of such growers and suppliers to\nvendors selling such products and to municipalities that may provide\nsuch information to vendors selling such products on municipal\nsidewalks, lots or streets.\n  2-g. Aid, in cooperation with the department of economic development,\nin the promotion, marketing and sale, both within and outside the state,\nof New York state animal and plant fiber and products made from such\nfiber.  For the purposes of this subdivision animal fiber means natural\nfibers that have formed the covering, or fleece, of sheep or other hairy\nanimals such as goats or alpacas, shorn for the purposes of creating\ntextile products, and plant fiber means natural fibers that are obtained\nfrom plants and used to create textile products including, but not\nlimited to, hemp. Such aid shall include, but not be limited to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the opportunity for producers of animal and plant fibers in the\nstate to participate in programs that offer seals or logos identifying\nsuch fibers as grown in New York state and certified for their quality,\nfor product labeling, advertising, and displays; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the development of educational materials about animal and plant\nfiber, especially for young people, in cooperation with cooperative\nextension, boards of cooperative educational services, local fairs, and\nthe state fair.\n  2-h. In cooperation with the department of environmental conservation,\noffer seals or logos identifying native plants as grown in New York\nstate and certified for their quality, product labeling, advertising,\nand displays. The department, in cooperation with the department of\nenvironmental conservation, shall establish appropriate standards and\nguidelines for such designation. The department shall further provide\neducational materials promoting awareness and understanding of native\nplants under the New York native plants designation to horticultural\nproducers, garden centers, consumers, educational institutions, Cornell\ncooperative extension, and relevant agricultural and environmental\norganizations. For the purposes of this subdivision, "native plants"\nshall mean non-invasive herbaceous and woody plant species that are\nindigenous to New York state and are likely to maintain their range or\nsuccessfully adapt to anticipated climate changes in New York state and\nthe northeastern United States.\n  3. Investigate the cost of food production and marketing in all its\nphases.\n  4. Investigate the sources of food supply for the state, the\nproduction, transportation, storage, marketing and distribution of food\nsold, offered for sale, stored or held within the state, the cost of\ntransportation to the leading centers of population and of distribution\nto consumers.\n  5. Collect and disseminate accurate data and statistics as to the food\nproduced, stored or held within the state, the quantities available from\ntime to time and the location thereof, and so far as practicable and\navailable collect such like statistics from without the state, as are of\nvalue to producers and consumers within the state.\n  5-a. Establish an information n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establish, in cooperation with the commissioner of education,\na farm-to-school program to facilitate and promote the purchase of New\nYork farm products by schools, universities and other educational\ninstitutions under the jurisdiction of the education department. The\ndepartment shall solicit information from the education department\nregarding school districts and other educational institutions interested\nin purchasing New York farm products, including but not limited to, the\ntype and amount of such products schools wish to purchase and the name\nof the appropriate contact person from the interested school district.\nThe department shall make this information readily available to\ninterested New York farmers, farm organizations and businesses that\nmarket New York farm products. The department shall provide information\nto the education department and interested school districts and other\neducational institutions about the availability of New York farm\nproducts, including but not limited to, the types and amount of\nproducts, and the names and contact information of farmers, farm\norganizations and businesses marketing such products. The commissioner\nshall report to the legislature on the need for changes in law to\nfacilitate the purchases of such products by schools and educational\ninstitutions.\n  The department shall also coordinate with the education department,\nand school food service, education, health and nutrition, farm, and\nother interested organizations in establishing a promotional event, to\nbe known as New York Harvest For New York Kids Week, in early October\neach year, that will promote New York agriculture and foods to children\nthrough school meal programs and the classroom, at farms and farmers'\nmarkets and other locations in the community.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cooperate with the department of health in implementing the\nchildhood obesity prevention program pursuant to title eight of article\ntwenty-five of the public health law and with the commissioner of\neducation to encourage the production and consumption of fresh locally\nproduced fruits and vegetables by elementary and secondary school aged\nchildren pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision to help combat\nthe increasing incidence of childhood obesity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cooperate with federal, other state and municipal agencies to\nencourage the expansion of community gardens pursuant to article two-C\nof this chapter to help encourage the production and consumption of\nfresh locally produced fruits and vegetables to help combat the\nincreasing incidence of adult and child obesity.\n  5-c. Cooperate with the commissioner of education, pursuant to\nsubdivision fifty-six of section three hundred five of the education\nlaw, to develop guidelines for the voluntary implementation by school\ndistricts and institutions of higher education of programs which\nencourage the donation of excess, unused, edible food from meals served\nat such educational facilities to local voluntary food assistance\nprograms.\n  6. Investigate and recommend useful methods of co-operative\nproduction, marketing and distribution of foods within the state.\n  6-a. Establish the New York state council on hunger and food policy.\nThe purpose of the council shall be to advise the state on the\ndevelopment of comprehensive, coordinated state food policies with the\ngoal of:  ensuring that all citizens of the state are able to eat a\nhealthy diet and avoid food insecurity while consuming New York grown\nand produced foods as much as possible. The council shall work to:\nsupport and facilitate the growth of a New York-based local farm and\nfood product economy that revitalizes rural, suburban and urban\ncommunities, creates jobs, and supports economic growth through\npromoting and developing local farm and food businesses and their\nproducts and helps to make them more available to New York residents;\nand promote healthy eating through a plentiful, accessible, affordable,\nsafe and nutritious food supply with access to fresh and minimally\nprocessed foods including a readily available supply of such food during\nemergencies.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The priorities of the council shall include, but are not limited\nto, developing and recommending policies and plans to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ensure the availability of and expand access to an adequate supply\nof affordable, fresh and nutritious food to its residents;\n  (ii) expand agricultural production and processing, including\nlocally-grown and organically-grown food;\n  (iii) assist local farm and food businesses to succeed and grow,\nespecially beginning and new owners and those historically\nunderrepresented or marginalized in agriculture or the food industry, to\nidentify and secure necessary resources and equipment to begin,\nmaintain, and expand projects and networks necessary for the development\nof local farm or food products;\n  (iv) reduce barriers affecting food-insecure populations in rural and\nurban spaces;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>facilitate the building of infrastructure, including, but not\nlimited to, aggregation, processing, storage, packaging, distribution,\nand marketing facilities necessary to move local farm or food products\nto local and other markets;\n  (vi) support and expand programs that recruit, train, and provide\ntechnical assistance to New York farmers, food producers, food\nprocessors and residents in order to encourage the production and\nprocessing of local farm or food products;\n  (vii) coordinate interagency programs, initiatives, and procedures\npromoting local farm and food products in New York communities, by\nworking with and involving state, federal, and local agencies, as well\nas community-based organizations, educational institutions, and trade\norganizations in executing the purposes of this section;\n  (viii) eliminate statutory and legal barriers hindering the\ndevelopment of a local farm and food economy by working with federal,\nstate, and local agencies, other agencies and applicable entities, to\nensure consistent and compatible laws and regulations for the\nproduction, processing, storage, distribution, and marketing of local\nfarm or food products;\n  (ix) facilitate the use of public lands for growing local farm or food\nproducts by working with governmental entities at the local, state, and\nfederal levels;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>initiate and facilitate public awareness campaigns about the\neconomic benefits of a local farm and food economy;\n  (xi) improve access to nutrition assistance programs and\ntransportation options, enhance infrastructure, and decrease\nsocio-economic disparities that contribute to the prevalence of food\ninsecurity;\n  (xii) alleviate geographic and economic barriers to improve access to\nhealthy fresh food and reduce hunger among New Yorkers;\n  (xiii) eliminate barriers impacting a consumer's ability to purchase\nhealthy food; and\n  (xiv) encourage state agencies and community partners to share ideas\nfor reducing food-related chronic disease and promoting well-balanced\nchild nutrition.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The council shall consist of twenty-five members designated by the\ncommissioner as follows:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the commissioner, the commissioner of\nhealth, the commissioner of the office of temporary and disability\nassistance, the commissioner of education, the commissioner of the\ndepartment of economic development, and the director of the office for\nthe aging;\n  (ii) eight members with experience and expertise related to\nagriculture, nutrition, or food policy, of which four shall be\ndesignated on the recommendation of the legislative leaders, one each by\nthe temporary president of the senate, the speaker of the assembly, the\nminority leader of the senate, and the minority leader of the assembly;\n  (iii) the dean of the New York state college of agriculture and life\nsciences;\n  (iv) one member representing farm organizations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member representing school food administrators;\n  (vi) one member representing consumers;\n  (vii) two members representing an organization that provides food\nassistance;\n  (viii) one member representing anti-hunger advocates;\n  (ix) one member who is a nutritionist; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>three members representing the food industry, including producers,\ndistributors, processors or retailers who are residents of and work in\nthe state of New York, at least one of whom produces organic food.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall serve as the chairperson of the council.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The council shall issue a written report on the thirtieth day of\nJanuary each year on:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the activities of the council during the\npreceding year; (ii) recommended food policies and actions for the\nstate; (iii) an account of the progress made in achieving the goals of\nthe council; and (iv) actions which are necessary to implement the\nrecommendations of the council and effectuate its purposes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state governmental agencies represented on the council may\nre-direct existing staff, as appropriations permit; assist in executing\nthe purposes of this subdivision; and provide office space, meeting\nspace, and other research and communication services as appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No member of the council shall be disqualified from holding any\npublic office or employment, nor shall he or she forfeit any such office\nor employment by virtue of his or her appointment hereunder. Members of\nthe council shall receive no compensation for their services but shall\nbe allowed their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their functions hereunder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The council shall set forth the time and place of its meetings and\nmeet as frequently as business requires, but shall meet at least twice\neach year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every agency, department, office, division or public authority of\nthe state shall cooperate with the council and furnish such information\nand assistance as the council determines is reasonably necessary to\naccomplish its purpose.\n  7. Aid in the organization and operation of co-operative associations\nand corporations among producers and consumers of farm products, and\nalso aid in the organization and operation of co-operative associations,\ncorporations or other agencies for the purpose of increasing the\nproduction, improving the quality, grading or bringing together of farm\nproducts for wholesale marketing.\n  7-a. Call conferences of co-operative associations of producers of\nfarm products organized under or subject to the provisions of chapter\nseventy-seven of the consolidated laws for discussion of cost of\nproduction, transportation and marketing, of market conditions and\nprices for sale of farm products to the end that the marketing operating\noperations for such co-operative associations may be facilitated, made\nmore efficient and the producers may obtain the reasonable cost of\nproduction, plus cost of compliance with sanitary regulations affecting\nproduction or marketing. Such conferences shall be held under the\nsupervision of the commissioner. Neither such conferences nor any\nagreements or arrangements resulting therefrom, if such agreements or\narrangements are approved by the commissioner, shall be deemed or\nconstrued to be acts, conspiracies, agreements or arrangements in\nrestraint of trade or commerce or injurious to public welfare. The\npowers hereby conferred may also be exercised in conjunction with\nofficials or representatives of the federal government.\n  8. Co-operate with and aid farmers and other producers of food, and\ndistributors and consumers thereof, in improving and maintaining\neconomic and efficient systems of production, storage, distribution and\nmarketing, and in reaching advantageous markets. The commissioner may\nd...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establish a program in the state for the planning, design and\nimplementation of integrated pest management. Under such a program the\ndepartment may contract with Cornell university or the New York state\ncollege of agriculture and life sciences at Cornell university, and\nshall encourage such contractor to seek federal and private sources of\nfunds for such program. The department shall submit a quinquennial\nreport of such integrated pest management program to the governor, the\nsenate finance committee and the assembly ways and means committee on or\nbefore January first, two thousand seven and on or before January first\nof each fifth year thereafter. Such report shall include, but not be\nlimited to:\n  i. an identification of all revenue sources, including non-state\nfunds, and an identification of expenditures made within each\nagricultural production area, as described in article eleven of this\nchapter;\n  ii. an evaluation and description of the status of implementation with\neach agricultural production area and the achievements of each objective\noutlined in such article eleven made in the previous five years; and\n  iii. the overall status of the program and multi-year timetable for\nthe future implementation of the program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Between report due dates, the department shall maintain the\nnecessary records and data to satisfy such report requirements and to\nsatisfy information requests received from the governor, the senate\nfinance committee and the assembly ways and means committee, between\nsuch report due dates.\n  40. Establish and administer, together with the state soil and water\nconservation committee and the Cornell cooperative extension, a\nvoluntary program to encourage agricultural environmental planning and\nimplementation. The program shall promote farming practices which are\ncompatible with state water quality and other environmental objectives,\nand may include training and certification of agricultural planners;\neducational outreach to producers of farm products; technical and\nfinancial assistance to farm operators; consultation and coordination\nwith federal, state and local agencies; and periodic evaluation and\nassessment of program effectiveness.\n  41.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establish and maintain New York state domestic animal health\nassurance programs, voluntary, on-farm, integrated disease prevention\nprograms, directed at improving animal health and promoting a safe and\nwholesome food supply. Such programs may include but are not limited to\nthe New York state cattle and horse health assurance programs. To carry\nout such programs, the department may contract with public, private and\nacademic entities and shall encourage such entities to seek federal and\nprivate sources of funds for such programs.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any proprietary farm protocol, animal or herd testing information\nand/or producer herd data maintained in confidence and voluntarily\nprovided by an owner or operator of a farm operation as defined in\nsection three hundred one of this chapter to participate in a voluntary\ncattle health program established pursuant to this subdivision shall be\nexempt from public disclosure. The submission of any such information or\nrecords by the owner or operator of a farm operation does not constitute\na waiver of any applicable privilege or protection under federal or\nstate law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The exemption described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall\nnot apply to:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_16__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>information collected or created as part of a federal,\nstate, or local health agency investigation or official action taken in\nconnection with a public health risk; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_16__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>records that do not\nidentify and cannot be used to discern the identity of any participating\nfarm.\n  42.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of making timely determinations and consulting\nwith the chairman of the state liquor authority pursuant to subdivision\nfive of section seventy-six-a of the alcoholic beverage control law,\ninvestigate and compile information relative to natural disasters, acts\nof God, or continued adverse weather conditions which shall affect:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe crop of grapes or other fruit products used in the production of\nwine; and/or (ii) the crop of apples used in the production of cider.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of making timely determinations and consulting with\nthe chairman of the state liquor authority pursuant to subdivision\neleven of section fifty-one-a of the alcoholic beverage control law,\ninvestigate and compile information relative to natural disasters, acts\nof God, or continued adverse weather conditions which shall affect:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe necessary ingredients for brewing beer; and/or (ii) the crop of\napples used in the production of cider.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of making timely determinations and consulting with\nthe chairman of the state liquor authority pursuant to subdivision\ntwelve of section fifty-one-a and subdivision eleven of section\nfifty-eight-c of the alcoholic beverage control law, investigate and\ncompile information relative to natural disasters, acts of God, or\ncontinued adverse weather conditions which shall affect the crop of\napples used in the production of cider.\n  43. Cooperate with the department of environmental conservation and\nthe environmental facilities corporation to establish methods to\nfacilitate loans to New York state's agricultural community, to develop\neducational materials for farmers about the low-interest loans available\nthrough the water pollution control linked deposit program, and to\ndevelop an application form to be provided to lenders for linked deposit\nloan requests. The department may promulgate rules and regulations\nnecessary and reasonable for the operation of the program.\n  44. Encourage and support the practice of forestry and manufacture of\nwood products in the state, in coordination with the departments of\nenvironmental conservation and economic development; and provide for the\noperation of the wood products development council as established in\nsection two hundred twenty-five of this chapter.\n  45. When considering plans, policies, regulations and programs\npursuant to article fourteen of this chapter, the commissioner shall\ntake into consideration the impact on the horticulture and other plant\nbased industries in the state of New York, including but not limited to\ngreenhouse, nursery, and fruit and vegetable production.\n  46. Within the amount of monies appropriated or otherwise made\navailable therefor, establish, administer and operate, or provide for\nthe administration and operation of, a program, which may include\nestablishment of a revolving loan fund, to assist in the development,\nimplementation and operation of agricultural prog...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>