<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_B">
        <num>160-B</num>
        <heading>Establishment of grades or standards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-b. Establishment of grades or standards.  It shall be the duty\nof the state department of agriculture and markets to enforce the\nprovisions of this article and the commissioner of agriculture and\nmarkets is hereby vested with full power to establish forthwith and from\ntime to time specific grades or standards of quality and size or weight\nto govern the sale of eggs to the consumer, and to establish different\ngrades or prescribe different terms indicative of size or weight,\nquality and manner of preparation of eggs for human consumption for use\nin sales between the producer and wholesaler, between the wholesaler and\njobber, and between the wholesaler or jobber and the retailer. The\ncommissioner of agriculture and markets shall have full authority to\nmake rules and regulations for carrying out and enforcing the provisions\nof this act, provided however, that the grades or standards of quality\nestablished by him shall not permit the sale of any eggs for human\nconsumption of poorer quality than permitted by the lowest grade or\nstandard for edible eggs established from time to time by the United\nStates secretary of agriculture. All rules, regulations and standards of\nquality and size or weight established under the authority of this\nstatute shall have the force of law and shall be filed and open for\npublic inspection in the office of the state department of agriculture\nand markets.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>