<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-160-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_I">
        <num>160-I</num>
        <heading>Grades or standards; establishment; sale</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-i. Grades or standards; establishment; sale.  The commissioner\nis hereby authorized and empowered, after investigation, to establish\nand promulgate official standards of quality for grading, classifying\nand packing grapes packed or repacked within the state, and to change\nany of them from time to time. In establishing such standards he shall\ntake into account, among other things, the factors of maturity, color,\nfirmness of attachment to capstems, compactness of bunches, and damage\ncaused by freezing or by disease or insects. The official standards so\nestablished and promulgated shall not be lower in their requirements\nthan the minimum requirements of the official standards for\ncorresponding grades of grapes as promulgated from time to time by the\nsecretary of agriculture of the United States, which standards are\ncommonly known as "United States grades."\n  From and after the establishment of specific grades or standards of\nquality as hereinbefore provided, grapes in packages shall not be\nshipped for sale or thereafter sold or exposed for sale except by the\ngrades or standards so established; provided, however, that grapes not\ngraded and classified as to quality may be shipped for sale or sold or\nexposed for sale as unclassified if so marked in a conspicuous manner on\nan irremovable-part of the container in accordance with rules to be\nadopted by the commissioner as hereinafter provided.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>