<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-163-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-163-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="163-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-163-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-163-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-163-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-163-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_163_B">
        <num>163-B</num>
        <heading>Registration to sell</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 163-b. Registration to sell.  1. The commissioner after a nursery\nhas been found to be apparently free from injurious insects and plant\ndiseases shall register each nursery grower desiring to sell, or\nselling, or handling for sale, or otherwise disposing of nursery stock\nin this state in accordance with the intent disclosed in the application\nand shall issue a certificate, upon a form to be prescribed by the\ncommissioner, declaring that such nursery grower is duly registered and\nauthorized to do business in this state. If such nursery grower is\nmaintaining or operating premises in connection with his or her business\nin more than one place within the state then he or she shall obtain an\nadditional registration for each place of business, provided there shall\nbe no additional fee for such additional registrations.\n  2. The commissioner shall register each nursery dealer desiring to\nsell or selling, or handling for sale, or otherwise disposing of nursery\nstock in this state in accordance with the intent disclosed in his or\nher application and shall issue a certificate, upon a form prescribed by\nthe commissioner, declaring that such nursery dealer is duly registered\nand authorized to do business in this state. If such nursery dealer is\nmaintaining or operating premises in connection with his or her business\nin more than one place within the state, he or she shall obtain a\nseparate registration, upon proper application, for each location.\n  3. Such certificates shall be conspicuously posted at each place of\nbusiness, maintained by such nursery grower or nursery dealer.\n  4. Each person doing a mail order business in nursery stock from an\naddress in this state is required to register as a nursery grower or\nnursery dealer whether or not the nursery stock sold or offered for sale\nis within the state.\n  5. It shall be unlawful to affix a reproduction or facsimile of a\nnursery dealer's registration on plant materials which have not been\ninspected by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>