<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-173"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-173"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="173"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-173/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-173/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-173/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-173/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_173">
        <num>173</num>
        <heading>Apiary industry advisory committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 173. Apiary industry advisory committee. 1. There is hereby\nestablished within the department an apiary industry advisory committee\nwhich shall consist of no more than fifteen members to be appointed by\nthe commissioner based on their experience and expertise in the apiary\nindustry. Of the members so appointed, at least two members shall\nrepresent each of the three sectors of the apiary industry, commercial\nbeekeepers, part-time beekeepers and hobbyist beekeepers; at least one\nmember shall represent the horticulture or vegetable industry and one\nmember shall be an officer or employee of the Cornell cooperative\nextension service or the New York state college of agriculture and life\nsciences at Cornell university. Members shall be appointed for a term of\nthree years and may serve until their successors are chosen provided,\nhowever, that of the members first appointed, five shall serve for a\nterm of one year, five shall serve for a term of two years, and five\nshall serve for a term of three years. Members shall serve without\nsalary. The commissioner or his or her designee shall be the chairperson\nof the committee.\n  2. The duties and responsibilities of the apiary industry advisory\ncommittee shall include providing advice, comments and recommendations\nto the commissioner regarding state government plans, policies and\nprograms affecting the apiary industry and such other matters as the\ncommissioner may request in relation to this article.\n  3. The advisory committee shall meet at least once annually, at times\nand places set by the commissioner.\n  4. The commissioner may ask other individuals to attend the\ncommittee's meetings or work with it as needed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>