<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-175-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-175-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="175-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-175-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-175-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-175-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-175-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_175_N">
        <num>175-N</num>
        <heading>Application for permit; fee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 175-n. Application for permit; fee.  Any person who desires to offer\nbaby chicks for sale at public auction or community sale shall apply for\na permit to do so prior to the date of the proposed sale to the\ndepartment of agriculture and markets on a form which shall be\nprescribed and furnished by such department. The application shall be\nsigned by the person who proposes to conduct such sale. The application\nshall designate the date of the proposed sale, the number and the breed\nof the baby chicks which are to be offered for sale, and the person by\nwhom they were produced, and shall be accompanied by a fee in the sum of\nten dollars for each and every day or fraction thereof during or on\nwhich it is proposed to sell baby chicks. The department of agriculture\nand markets is hereby authorized in its discretion to grant or deny the\npermit requested in such application.  If the department deems\nadvisable, it may require the applicant, as a condition precedent to the\ngranting of such permit, to submit a certificate in such form as the\ndepartment may prescribe, certifying that the baby chicks which are to\nbe offered for sale are in a healthy condition and free from any such\ndisease as the department may designate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>