<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-18"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-18"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="18"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-18/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-18/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-18/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-18/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_18">
        <num>18</num>
        <heading>Rules of department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 18. Rules of department. Subject and in conformity to this chapter\nand the constitution and laws of the state, the commissioner may enact,\namend and repeal necessary rules which shall\n  1. Regulate and control the transaction of business by the department,\nprovide for the exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties\nof the department and prescribe the powers and duties of the bureaus and\nof the directors of bureaus and other officers and employees thereof;\n  2. Provide for carrying into effect the provisions of this chapter and\nof the laws of the state in respect of food and food traffic;\n  3. Regulate the conduct of investigations, inquiries and hearings\nauthorized by this chapter and prescribe necessary forms and notices;\n  4. Establish official grades for foods and farm products and prescribe\nthe use of such grades, and provide for the marking, packing and\nshipping of foods and farm products so graded.\n  5. Establish uniform tolerances or amounts of reasonable variation for\ncontainers of food and provide uniform regulations for carrying out the\nprovisions of this chapter in relation to such containers.\n  6. Provide generally for the exercise of the powers and performance of\nthe duties of the department as prescribed in this chapter and the laws\nof the state and for the enforcement of their provisions and the\nprovisions of the rules enacted as herein provided.\n  The rules of the department in force at the time this chapter takes\neffect shall continue as the rules of the department, until amended or\nrepealed by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>