<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-184"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-184"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="184"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-184/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-184/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-184/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-184/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_184">
        <num>184</num>
        <heading>Condemnation, seizure or repair of false devices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 184. Condemnation, seizure or repair of false devices. 1.  Whenever\nany weights and measures official inspects any weighing or measuring\ndevice or system and finds that it does not correspond with the\nstandards in his possession or does not meet the specifications,\ntolerances and variations allowable as established by the commissioner,\nhe shall condemn the same and either seize it or order it repaired or\nremoved. In the case of seizure, such device or system may be disposed\nof only as directed by the commissioner or his authorized agent.\n  2. No person shall use or attempt to use, for the purpose of\ndetermining the weight, quantity or price of any commodity sold, or\noffered or exposed for sale, any weighing or measuring device or system\nto which there has been affixed or upon which there has been placed any\ncondemnation tag unless such condemnation tag has been removed therefrom\nby a weights and measures official.\n  3. No person, except a weights and measures official, shall remove\nfrom any weighing or measuring device or system any condemnation tag\nwhich has been affixed thereto or placed thereon or obliterate, cover,\nobstruct or deface the same or cause any of the foregoing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>