<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190_B">
        <num>190-B</num>
        <heading>Sale of meat in bulk or on a gross or hanging weight basis</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_190_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for beef, the primal\nsources are the round, flank, loin, rib, plate, brisket, chuck and\nshank; (ii) for veal and lamb or mutton, the primal sources are the leg,\nflank, loin, rack (rib) and shoulder; and (iii) for pork, the primal\nsources are the belly, loin, ham, spareribs, shoulder and jowl.\n  b. "Seller" means any person, partnership, corporation, or\nassociation, however organized, engaged in the sale at retail of meat\nprovided however that this section shall not apply to any seller whose\ntotal annual retail sales are less than ten thousand dollars.\n  c. "Cutting loss" means the weight of meat, fat and bone removed from\nthe carcass, side, quarter or primal source during standard or custom\ncutting procedures.\n  d. "Gross or hanging weight" means the weight of any single carcass,\nside, quarter or primal source of meat prior to cutting or trimming such\nmeat into any constituent part.\n  2. Sale of a single carcass, side, quarter or primal source of meat.\nSellers of a single carcass, side, quarter or primal source of meat may\nsell such meat on a gross or hanging weight basis, provided such meat is\nderived from a single carcass, side, quarter or primal source of meat.\nWith respect to any other retail sale of meat, the seller shall disclose\nin writing to the buyer the net weight, the selling price per pound and\nthe total selling price of each cut.\n  3. Disclosures required. A seller of a single carcass, side, quarter\nor primal source on a gross or hanging weight basis must provide to\nbuyers, in writing, the following at the times indicated:\n  a. Prior to sale:\n  i. the name and address of the seller;\n  ii. the estimated gross or hanging weight of the order;\n  iii. the U.S.D.A. quality grade of the meat to be supplied, if so\ngraded;\n  iv. the estimated total price of the order;\n  v. the estimated cutting loss on the order;\n  vi. a list, by name and estimated count, of each cut to be derived\nfrom each primal source;\n  vii. the price per po...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>