<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-04-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-190/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190">
        <num>190</num>
        <heading>Method of sale of food and food products</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_190__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the net\nweight, standard measure or numerical count;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_190__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the selling price per\npound or unit of standard measure and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_190__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total selling price.\nProvided that in the case of food or food products packed at one place\nfor subsequent shipment to and sale at another, the price and weight\nsections of the label may be left blank, to be filled in prior to being\noffered or exposed for sale at retail.\n  5. Wherever food or food products are packaged or wrapped for sale by\na retailer in advance of being sold, or offered or exposed for sale, an\naccurate computing scale of sufficient capacity shall be maintained.\nSuch scale shall be placed as to be easily accessible to customers and a\nprominent and conspicuous sign reading "for customer use" shall be\ndisplayed on or near such scale.\n  6. The provisions of this section shall not apply to commodities\ndispensed for consumption on the premises, or to packaging or\nreceptacles used merely for the purposes of carrying or delivering\ncommodities or containers which comply with the provisions of this\nsection, or to a commodity in a container if the container contains</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_190__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nin the case of a commodity not a drug or cosmetic, less than one-half\nounce avoirdupois, less than one-half fluid ounce or less than seven\nunits,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_190__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of a drug, less than seven units, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_190__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the\ncase of a cosmetic, less than one-fourth ounce avoirdupois, less than\none-eighth fluid ounce or less than seven units. The commissioner shall\nby regulation prescribe comparable metric quantities for the exceptions\nprovided by this subdivision. The exceptions involving declarations in\nterms of count shall be permitted only if the units of commodity can\neasily be counted without opening the container.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>