<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-192"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-192"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="192"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-192/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-192/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-192/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-192/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_192">
        <num>192</num>
        <heading>Sale and delivery of petroleum products</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_192__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>post and keep posted on the dispensing device from which such\nmotor fuel is sold or offered for sale a sign or placard, at least\ntwelve inches in height and at least twelve inches in width, stating\nclearly and legibly with the whole cent numerals at least nine inches in\nheight and at least two inches in width, the selling price per gallon of\nsuch motor fuel; or\n  (ii) where such individual pump or dispensing device dispenses more\nthan two differently priced grades of motor fuel, only the highest and\nlowest selling price per gallon of such motor fuel dispensed therefrom\nmust be posted thereon in conformance with all other provisions of this\nsubdivision; or\n  (iii) where a multiple product dispensing device is capable of\ndispensing multiple products at multiple prices, then the selling price\nper gallon may be posted thereon with numerals at least one-half that\nheight and one-half that width required by subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_192__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nparagraph, although numerals representing tenths of a cent may be\ndisplayed at no less than one-half those dimensions which disclose the\nselling price per gallon of such motor fuel dispensed therefrom.\n  The signs and selling prices shall be posted so as to be clearly\nvisible to the driver of an approaching motor vehicle or motorboat. The\nname, trade name, brand, mark or symbol, and grade of quality\nclassification, if any of such motor fuel shall be permanently imprinted\non said motor fuel dispensing device. The provisions of this subdivision\nshall not apply to a city, county, town or village which has already\nenacted and continues in effect a local law, ordinance, rule or\nregulation in substantial conformity with this subdivision. The\nprovisions of this subdivision shall be enforced in the counties outside\nthe city of New York by the county or city director of weights and\nmeasures, as the case may be, and in the city of New York by the\ndepartment of consumer affairs.\n  b. Any person who shall violate the provisions of this subdivision\nshall be liable to a civil penalty of not more than one hundred dollars\nand for any subsequent violation shall be liable to a civil penalty of\nnot more than five hundred dollars.\n  6. Gasoline stations; air pumps required. a. Definition. As used in\nthis subdivision: "dealer" shall mean any person owning or operating a\npremise or facility with four or more gas dispensing nozzles for the\nretail sale of motor fuels for use in motor vehicles.\n  b. Any dealer must provide on the premises where motor fuel is sold at\nretail for use in motor vehicles a functioning motor driven air\ncompressor capable of inflating automobile tires for use by customers\nduring hours in which such station is open for business. Jurisdiction in\nall matters pertaining to this subdivision shall be vested exclusively\nin the state. Any provision of any local law or ordinance or any rule or\nregulation promulgated thereto governing ti...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>