<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-195"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-195"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="195"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-195/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-195/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-195/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-195/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_195">
        <num>195</num>
        <heading>Licensing of weighmasters; duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 195. Licensing of weighmasters; duties. 1. No person shall act as a\nweighmaster, issue or sign any weight tickets, or carry out any\nfunctions of a weighmaster unless licensed pursuant to this section.\n  2. Upon application, a weighmaster's license may be issued by the\ncommissioner to an employee of a person, firm, partnership or\ncorporation whose business requires, by contract or otherwise, that\nmaterials or commodities manufactured, produced, distributed, sold or\nhandled by such person, firm, partnership or corporation be weighed by a\nlicensed weighmaster; or such license may be issued to an individual\nengaged in the weighing of materials or commodities. The applicant shall\nfurnish satisfactory evidence of good character and of ability to weigh\naccurately and to make correct weight tickets. He shall also furnish\nevidence that he owns, leases or has access to a stationary scale within\nthe state suitable for weighing the materials or commodities to be\nweighed by him or that he is regularly employed by a person, firm,\npartnership or corporation who owns, leases or has access to such a\nscale which has been tested and sealed by the weights and measures\nofficial charged with such duty. The applicant shall pay a fee of\nfifteen dollars. A license shall be for a period not exceeding three\nyears and may be renewed in the discretion of the commissioner upon\npayment of the fee aforesaid. Such license shall be kept at the place\nwhere the weighmaster is engaged in weighing and shall be open to\ninspection. An application may be denied or a license may be revoked by\nthe commissioner, after a hearing upon due notice to the applicant or\nlicensee, for dishonesty, incompetency, inaccuracy or a violation of the\nprovisions of this article or the rules and regulations adopted pursuant\nthereto.\n  3. Each weight ticket issued by a weighmaster shall contain the date,\nfull signature and license number of the weighmaster.\n  4. Each weighmaster shall retain for a period of one year a copy of\nevery weight ticket he has issued.\n  5. No weighmaster shall make or issue a false or incorrect weight\nticket, nor shall any person solicit him to do so. No person shall\nknowingly use a false or incorrect weight ticket. No weighmaster shall\npermit any weight ticket to be issued or used which purports to bear his\nsignature and was not in fact signed by him, or which expresses a weight\nnot ascertained by him.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>