<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-199"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-199"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="199"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-199/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-199/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-199/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-199/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_199">
        <num>199</num>
        <heading>Application of article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 199. Application of article. 1. The provisions of this article\nregarding the selling of food shall be considered to include the\nmanufacture, production, processing, packing, transportation, exposure,\noffer, possession, and holding of any such article for sale; the sale,\ndispensing, and giving of any such article; and the supplying or\napplying of any such articles in the conduct of any food establishment.\n  2. The provisions of this article regarding adulteration shall not\napply to food or food products for animals, provided, however, that\nanimal food and food products which are or may be adulterated within the\nmeaning of this article may only be manufactured, produced, processed,\npacked, transported, exposed, offered, possessed, and held for sale\npursuant to rules and regulations promulgated under authority of section\ntwo hundred fourteen-b of this article. Such rules and regulations shall\nprovide for the safety of humans by requiring, among other things, the\ndecharacterization of such products and the prominent labeling thereof\nas unfit for human consumption, and for the health of animals by\nprohibiting the use of certain adulterated products or the use of\ncarcasses of animals or poultry or parts thereof affected with diseases\nof particular concern to public and animal health, and may require such\nother safeguards, including heat processing, as are necessary to protect\nanimal health.\n  3. The provisions of this article regarding misbranding shall not\napply to commercial feed as defined in article eight of this chapter,\nprovided such feed complies with the provisions of such article eight\nand the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder.\n  4. The provisions of this article shall not apply to game or wild\ngame.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>