<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-08-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="200"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_200">
        <num>200</num>
        <heading>Adulteration of food</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a pesticide chemical in or on a\nraw agricultural commodity,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a food additive, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a color\nadditive, which is unsafe within the meaning of section two hundred two,\nor if it is a raw agricultural commodity and it bears or contains a\npesticide chemical which is unsafe within the meaning of section four\nhundred eight-a of the federal food, drug and cosmetic act, as amended,\nor if it is, or it bears or contains, any food additive which is unsafe\nwithin the meaning of section four hundred nine of such federal act, as\namended; provided, that where a pesticide chemical has been used in or\non a raw agricultural commodity in conformity with an exemption granted\nor a tolerance prescribed under section four hundred eight of such\nfederal act, and such raw agricultural commodity has been subjected to\nprocessing such as canning, cooking, freezing, dehydrating or milling,\nthe residue of such pesticide chemical remaining in or on such processed\nfood shall not be deemed unsafe if such residue in or on the raw\nagricultural commodity has been removed to the extent possible in good\nmanufacturing practice, and the concentration of such residue in the\nprocessed food, when ready to eat, is not greater than the tolerance\nprescribed for the raw agricultural commodity.\n  3. If it consists in whole or in part of a diseased, contaminated,\nfilthy, putrid or decomposed substance, or if it is otherwise unfit for\nfood.\n  4. If it has been produced, prepared, packed or held under insanitary\nconditions whereby it may have become contaminated with filth, or\nwhereby it may have been rendered diseased, unwholesome or injurious to\nhealth.\n  5. If it is the product of a diseased animal or of an animal which has\ndied otherwise than by slaughter, or that has been fed upon the uncooked\noffal from a slaughterhouse.\n  6. If its container is composed in whole or in part of any poisonous\nor deleterious substance which may render the contents injurious to\nhealth.\n  6-a. If it has been intentionally subjected to radiation, unless the\nuse of the radiation was in c...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not be sold to individuals under twenty-one years of age;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bear a statement on the label that sale of the product to\nindividuals under twenty-one years of age is prohibited;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bear a statement on the label that the product contains alcohol up\nto five percent by volume;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bear the following statement: "Notice: This product contains\nalcohol used as a flavoring and, as with any product that contains\nalcohol:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>women should not consume alcohol during pregnancy because\nof the risk of birth defects, and (ii) consumption of alcohol impairs\nyour ability to drive a car or operate machinery, and may cause health\nproblems; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be sold, either alone or in conjunction with other confectionery\ncontaining no alcohol or less than one-half of one per centum by volume\nof alcohol derived solely from the use of flavoring extracts, in\nquantities of at least one-half pound or in a package or container\ncontaining at least twenty-four pieces.\n  If the confectionery is sold in bulk to be packaged by the retailer at\nthe time of sale to a consumer, the statements required by paragraphs\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall appear on the box, bag or other\ncontainer in which the confectionery is placed by the retailer and\nfurnished to the consumer and the statement required by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision shall appear either on the box, bag or other container\nin which the confectionery is placed by the retailer and furnished to\nthe consumer or shall appear on a card enclosed within such box, bag or\nother container. In addition, the manufacturer and/or distributor of\nsuch confectionery in bulk shall provide written notice to the retailer\nwith each shipment</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the confectionery in the shipment may not be\nsold to individuals under twenty-one years of age; and (ii) that the\npackaging in which such confectionery is furnished to the consumer must\nbear the statements required by paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision; and (iii) that the statement required by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision must appear on the packaging in which such\nconfectionery is furnished to the consumer or on a card enclosed within\nsuch packaging; and (iv) that the confectionery must be sold in\nquantities of at least one-half pound or twenty-four pieces.\n  14. If it is ice cream or other frozen desserts made with liquor,\nwine, beer or cider bearing or containing more than five percent of\nalcohol by volume.\n  15. With respect to the manufacture and sale of ice cream or other\nfrozen desserts made with liquor, wine, beer or cider bearing or\ncontaining more than one-half of one percent, but not more than five\npercent of alcohol by volume:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall sell at retail packages of ice cream or other\nfrozen desserts made with liquor, wine, beer or cider for consumption\noff the premises where sold unless:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>each package is a sealed package, as received from the\nmanufacturer or distributor;\n  (ii) each sealed package, as received from the manufacturer or\ndistributor, in a format to be established or approved by the\ncommissioner, prominently bears the following statements, provided that\nsuch statements may refer to either liquor, wine, beer or cider or a\ncombination thereof:\n  (A) The sale of this product to individuals under the age of\ntwenty-one years is prohibited.\n  (B) This product is made with (insert liquor, wine, beer and/or cider)\nand contains alcohol up to five percent by volume.\n  (C) Notice. This product contains alcohol used as a flavoring and, as\nwith any product that contains alcohol:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_200__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>women should not consume alcohol during pregnancy because of the\nrisk of birth defects, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_200__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>consumption of alcohol impairs your ability to drive a car or\noperate machinery, and may cause health problems.\n  (iii) the following advisory, on a sign or poster not less than seven\ninches by five inches, in a format to be established or approved by the\ncommissioner, is displayed prominently at each location where packages\nof ice cream or other frozen desserts made with liquor, wine, beer or\ncider are made available to the public provided that such sign or poster\nmay refer to either liquor, wine, beer or cider or a combination\nthereof:\n "THIS AREA CONTAINS (INSERT LIQUOR, WINE, BEER AND/OR CIDER) ICE CREAM\n                        OR OTHER FROZEN DESSERTS\n  The sale of (INSERT LIQUOR, WINE, BEER AND/OR CIDER) ICE CREAM OR\nOTHER FROZEN DESSERTS to individuals under the age of twenty-one years\nis prohibited.\n  (INSERT LIQUOR, WINE, BEER AND/OR CIDER) ICE CREAM OR OTHER FROZEN\nDESSERTS contain alcohol up to five percent by volume.\n  NOTICE: (INSERT LIQUOR, WINE, BEER AND/...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_200__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>women should not consume alcohol during pregnancy because of the\nrisk of birth defects, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_200__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>consumption of alcohol impairs your ability to drive a car or\noperate machinery, and may cause health problems.\n  IT IS A VIOLATION PUNISHABLE UNDER LAW FOR ANY PERSON UNDER THE AGE OF\nTWENTY-ONE TO PRESENT ANY WRITTEN EVIDENCE OF AGE WHICH IS FALSE,\nFRAUDULENT OR NOT ACTUALLY HIS OR HER OWN FOR THE PURPOSE OF ATTEMPTING\nTO PURCHASE (INSERT LIQUOR, WINE, BEER AND/OR CIDER) ICE CREAM OR OTHER\nFROZEN DESSERTS."\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No manufacturer and/or distributor of ice cream or other frozen\ndesserts made with liquor, wine, beer or cider shall sell such product:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to a person intending to sell at retail individual servings of ice\ncream or other frozen desserts made with liquor, wine, beer or cider,\nunless, with each shipment, such manufacturer and/or distributor\nprovides:\n  (A) a written notice that individual servings of ice cream or other\nfrozen desserts made with liquor, wine, beer or cider may be sold at\nretail only where the retailer complies with all of the requirements set\nforth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, and\n  (B) a written copy of such requirements; and\n  (ii) to a person intending to sell at retail packages of ice cream or\nother frozen desserts made with liquor, wine, beer or cider for\nconsumption off the premises, unless, with each shipment, such\nmanufacturer and/or distributor provides:\n  (A) a written notice that packages of ice cream or other frozen\ndesserts made with liquor, wine, beer or cider may be sold at retail\nonly where the retailer complies with all of the requirements set forth\nin paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, and\n  (B) a written copy of such requirements.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>