<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="201-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_201_B">
        <num>201-B</num>
        <heading>Retail sale of kosher food or food products</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 201-b. Retail sale of kosher food or food products. 1. Any person\nwho sells or offers for sale in the same place of business meat, meat\npreparations, meat by-products, poultry or other food or food products\nthat are represented as both kosher and non-kosher shall indicate in\nwindow signs, in block letters at least four inches in height, "kosher\nand non-kosher meat sold here" or "kosher and non-kosher food sold\nhere."\n  2. All fresh meat, meat preparations, meat by-products and poultry\nsold or offered for sale at retail as kosher shall be marked on the\nlabel when packaged, or by a sign when not packaged, with the words\n"soaked and salted" or "not soaked and salted," as the case may be. Such\nwords, when marked on a label or a sign, shall be in letters at least as\nlarge as the letters of the words on the label or sign designating such\nmeat, meat preparations, meat by-products and poultry as kosher.\n  3. Any person who sells or offers for sale as kosher, at wholesale or\nretail, any meat, meat preparations, meat by-products or poultry shall\nmaintain a record of each purchase from a manufacturer or packer, which\nshall include, but not be limited to, a bill of sale, and retain all\nrecords with respect to the origin of such meat, meat preparations, meat\nby-products or poultry for a period of two years after the sale to which\nthe records relate, and shall make such records available to the\ndepartment upon request. Meat, meat preparations, meat by-products and\npoultry packed off-premises and labeled as kosher by the packer thereof\nshall be exempt from the record keeping requirements of this\nsubdivision, provided that the package contains the name and address of\nthe manufacturer or packer and the name of the person certifying such\nfood or food products as kosher.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>