<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="201-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-201-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_201_E">
        <num>201-E</num>
        <heading>Halal food and food products; packaging</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 201-e. Halal food and food products; packaging. 1. All food and food\nproducts packaged in any container and sold or offered for sale as\n"halal" shall have a "halal" label affixed by the manufacturer or packer\nat its premises. No person other than such manufacturer or packer shall\naffix such label.\n  2. All food or food products that are not packaged in a container and\nare sold or offered for sale as "halal" shall have a "halal" label\naffixed thereto. No person other than such manufacturer or packer shall\naffix such label.\n  3. Any food or food product in package form that is certified or\nlabeled as "halal" shall not be sold or offered for sale by the producer\nor distributor of such food or food product until the producer or the\ndistributor shall have registered with the department the name, current\naddress and telephone number of the person certifying the food as halal.\n  4. Any food or food product in package form that is marked with a\ngeneric marking used to convey that such food or food product is halal,\nexcept a registered trademark not used to represent such food or food\nproduct as halal, shall not be sold or offered for sale by the producer\nor distributor of such food or food product until such producer or\ndistributor shall have registered with the department the name, current\naddress and telephone number of the person certifying the food or food\nproduct as halal.\n  5. As used in this section, the term "food or food product in package\nform" means a food or food product not intended for consumption at the\npoint of manufacture that is put up or packaged in any manner in advance\nof sale in units suitable for retail sale.\n  6. Any advertisement for food or food products representing that such\nfood or food products are halal shall identify the name of the person or\nentity certifying such food or food products as halal.\n  7. Where a producer or distributor is required to register a\ncertifying person pursuant to the provisions of this section, such\nproducer or distributor shall immediately notify the department of any\nchange in the registration information.\n  8. No liability for misrepresentation shall be incurred by any\ndistributor if it has received written representation from a\nmanufacturer of food and food products that its certifying information\nhas been filed with the commissioner; provided, however, that if such\ndistributor has received notice from the commissioner that the\ninformation filed by such manufacturer is no longer valid, the\ndistributor will be liable for the sale of misrepresented products\nunless the distributor files valid certifying information.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>