<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-07-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="203"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Manufacture and sale of imitation maple, birch, walnut or beech sugar and syrup prohibited</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>1. No person shall manufacture for sale,\nkeep for sale, or offer or expose for sale, any sugar in imitation or\nsemblance of maple sugar which is not pure maple sugar, nor any syrup in\nimitation or semblance of maple syrup, which is not pure maple syrup,\nnor shall any person manufacture, offer or expose for sale any sugar as\nand for maple sugar which is not pure maple sugar, nor any syrup as and\nfor maple syrup which is not pure maple syrup.\n  2. For the purpose of this article the term "maple sugar" shall be\ndeemed to mean sugar made from pure maple sap or pure maple syrup, and\nthe term "maple syrup" shall be deemed to mean syrup made from pure\nmaple sap.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>1. No person shall manufacture for sale, keep for sale, or offer\nor expose for sale, any sugar in imitation or semblance of birch sugar\nwhich is not pure birch sugar, nor any syrup in imitation or semblance\nof birch syrup, which is not birch syrup, nor shall any person\nmanufacture, offer or expose for sale any sugar as and for birch sugar\nwhich is not pure birch sugar, nor any syrup as and for birch syrup\nwhich is not pure birch syrup.\n  2. For the purpose of this article the term "birch sugar" shall be\ndeemed to mean sugar made from pure birch sap or pure birch syrup, and\nthe term "birch syrup" shall be deemed to mean syrup made from pure\nbirch sap.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>1. No person shall manufacture for sale, keep for sale, or offer\nor expose for sale, any sugar in imitation or semblance of walnut sugar\nwhich is not pure walnut sugar, nor any syrup in imitation or semblance\nof walnut syrup, which is not pure walnut syrup, nor shall any person\nmanufacture, offer or expose for sale any sugar as and for walnut sugar\nwhich is not pure walnut sugar, nor any syrup as and for walnut syrup\nwhich is not walnut syrup.\n  2. For the purpose of this article the term "walnut sugar" shall be\ndeemed to mean sugar made from pure walnut sap or pure walnut syrup, and\nthe term "walnut syrup" shall be deemed to mean syrup made from pure\nwalnut sap.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>1. No person shall manufacture for sale, keep for sale, or offer\nor expose for sale, any sugar in imitation or semblance of beech sugar\nwhich is not pure beech sugar, nor any syrup in imitation or semblance\nof beech syrup, which is not pure beech syrup, nor shall any person\nmanufacture, offer or expose for sale any sugar as and for beech sugar\nwhich is not pure beech sugar, nor any syrup as and for beech syrup\nwhich is not pure beech syrup.\n  2. For the purpose of this article the term "beech sugar" shall be\ndeemed to mean sugar made from pure beech sap or pure beech syrup, and\nthe term "beech syrup" shall be deemed to mean syrup made from pure\nbeech sap.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>