<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-204-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-204-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="204-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-204-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-204-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-204-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-204-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_204_A">
        <num>204-A</num>
        <heading>Olive oil mixtures</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Olive oil" means the olive oil obtained solely from the fruit of\nthe olive tree (olea europaea), to the exclusion of oils obtained using\nsolvents or reesterification processes and of any mixture with oils of\nother kinds. For the purpose of product labeling such term means oil\nconsisting of a blend of refined olive oil, and virgin olive oils fit\nfor consumption as they are with a free acidity, expressed as oleic\nacid, of not more than one gram per hundred grams.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Olive-pomace oil" means oil obtained by treating olive pomace\nwith solvents or other physical treatments, to the exclusion of oils\nobtained by reesterification processes and of any mixture with oils of\nother kinds.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Refined olive oil" means the olive oil obtained from virgin olive\noils by refining methods which do not lead to alterations in the initial\nglyceridic structure. It has free acidity, expressed as oleic acid, of\nnot more than 0.3 grams per hundred grams.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Virgin olive oil" means those oils obtained from the fruit of the\nolive tree solely by mechanical or other physical means under\nconditions, particularly thermal conditions, that do not lead to\nalterations in the oil, and which have not undergone any treatment other\nthan washing, decanting, centrifuging and filtration. Virgin olive oils\nfit for consumption as they are include:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204_A__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"extra virgin olive oil" which means virgin olive oil which has a\nfree acidity, expressed as oleic acid, of not more than 0.8 grams per\nhundred grams.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204_A__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"virgin olive oil" which means olive oil which has a free acidity,\nexpressed as oleic acid, of not more than two grams per hundred grams.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204_A__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"ordinary virgin olive oil" which means virgin olive oil which has\na free acidity, expressed as oleic acid, of not more than 3.3 grams per\nhundred grams.\n  2.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No additives are permitted in virgin olive oils.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The addition of alpha-tocopherol to refined olive oil, olive oil,\nrefined olive-pomace oil and olive-pomace oil is permitted to restore\nnatural tocopherol lost in the refining process. The concentration of\nalpha-tocopherol in the final product shall not exceed 220mg/kg.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations for the\nproduction and labeling of olive oils and olive-pomace oils presented\nand sold for human consumption in intrastate commerce. Those regulations\nshall substantially comply with the standards for the production and\nlabeling of olive oil and olive-pomace oils of the prevailing\ninternational voluntary consensus trade organization formed for the\ndevelopment of standards on characteristics and performance of olive\nproducts and the promotion of trade and knowledge related to the\naccurate and honest presentation of such products, as amended, in the\nabsence of specific federal standards of identity for olive oil.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Failure to meet the standards promulgated pursuant to paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall render olive oil sold in intrastate\ncommerce in the state misbranded.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>