<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="206"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_206">
        <num>206</num>
        <heading>Relative to selling a commodity in imitation or semblance of honey</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 206. Relative to selling a commodity in imitation or semblance of\nhoney.  No person or persons shall package, label, sell, keep for sale,\nexpose or offer for sale, any article or product in imitation or\nsemblance of honey depicting thereon a picture or drawing of a bee,\nbeehive or honeycomb, or branded as "honey," "liquid or extracted\nhoney," "strained honey" or "pure honey" which is not pure honey. No\nperson or persons, firm, association, company or corporation, shall\nmanufacture, sell, expose or offer for sale, any compound or mixture\nbranded or labeled as and for honey which shall be made up of honey\nmixed with any other substance or ingredient. There may be printed on\nthe package containing such compound or mixture a statement giving the\ningredients of which it is made; if honey is one of such ingredients it\nshall be so stated in the same size type as are the other ingredients,\nbut it shall not be packaged, sold, exposed for sale, or offered for\nsale as honey; nor shall such compound or mixture be branded or labeled\nwith the word "honey" in any form other than as herein provided; nor\nshall any product in semblance of honey, whether a mixture or not, be\nsold, exposed or offered for sale as honey, or branded or labeled with\nthe word "honey," unless such article is pure honey. A product which is\nin semblance or imitation of liquid honey shall be labeled as "honey\nflavored syrup" or "artificially honey flavored syrup", as is\nappropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>