<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207">
        <num>207</num>
        <heading>Definition of vinegars and adulterated vinegars</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 207. Definition of vinegars and adulterated vinegars.\n  1. The terms "cider vinegar," "apple cider vinegar," or words of\nsimilar import, shall be construed to mean the product made exclusively\nfrom the expressed juice of clean, sound, fresh apples, or parts of such\napples, by alcoholic and subsequent acetous fermentations without\ndistillation.  The term "dried apple vinegar," or words of similar\nimport, shall be construed to mean the product resulting from the\nalcoholic and subsequent acetous fermentations without distillation of\nthe juice produced from clean, sound, dried apples, clean, sound, dried\nchopped apples, clean, sound, dried apple skins or cores, or clean,\nsound dried pomace.\n  2. The term "sugar vinegar" shall be construed to mean the product\nmade by the alcoholic and subsequent acetous fermentations without\ndistillation of solutions of sugar, syrup, molasses or refiner's syrup.\n  3. The term "malt vinegar" shall be construed to mean the product made\nby the alcoholic and subsequent acetous fermentations of an infusion of\nbarley malt and/or cereals or a concentrate thereof which has been\nenzymatically converted by the malting process.\n  4. The terms "wine vinegar," "grape vinegar," shall be construed to\nmean the product made by the alcoholic and subsequent acetous\nfermentations of the juice of grapes or the acetous fermentation of\nwine, produced according to federal regulations.\n  5. The term "glucose vinegar" shall be construed to mean the product\nmade by the alcoholic and subsequent acetous fermentations of sugar,\nmolasses and/or other nutritive carbohydrate sweeteners.\n  6. The terms "spirit vinegar," "distilled vinegar," "grain vinegar,"\n"white distilled vinegar," "white vinegar," shall be construed to mean\nthe product made by the acetous fermentations of dilute ethyl alcohol.\n  7. All vinegars which contain less than four grams of acetic acid in\none hundred cubic centimeters of the vinegar at twenty degrees\ncentigrade, shall be deemed adulterated. Nothing herein shall be deemed\nto prohibit the manufacture of vinegar for consumption elsewhere than\nwithin this state, of such acid content as may be elsewhere required.\n  8. The product made by the destructive distillation of wood, known as\npyroligneous acid, shall not be sold, offered, exposed or had in\npossession for sale, for food.\n  9. The terms blended vinegar, mixed vinegar, compound vinegar shall be\nconstrued to mean the product made by acetous fermentation of a blend of\nraw materials or a blend of two or more vinegars, suitably labeled\naccording to law. The product may also be described as "_________\nvinegar," the blank being filled in by any suitable and non-deceptive\nterm that does not represent or suggest that the product consists solely\nof a vinegar described in subdivisions one through six of this section.\n  9-a. Manufacture and sale of vinegar and vinegar products defined in\nsubdivisions one through six of this section shall not be deemed to be\nmisbranded provided the product so defined is labeled in compliance with\nsubdivision three of section two hundred one of this article.\n  10. Vinegar products other than those defined in subdivisions one\nthrough six of this section shall not be deemed to be misbranded or\nadulterated provided that the product source of the raw material shall\nbe identified on the label by its common or usual name. This includes\nother fruit vinegars which shall be entitled "________ vinegar," the\nblank being filled in by the name of the fruit or fruit juices. Packages\ncontaining vinegars made from wine or fruits which have been reduced\nwith water must be plainly marked or branded "reduced to ......... per\ncentum acid strength," indicating the acidity to which they have been so\nreduced, or words equivalent thereto.\n  11. The manufacture and sale of the products made by the addition of\nsafe and suitable flavorings and/or coloring ingredients to vinegars\ndescribed in subdivisions one through ten of this section, and suitably\nlabeled according to law shall not be deemed to be misbranded.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>