<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-22"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-22"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="22"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-22/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-22/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-22/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-22/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_22">
        <num>22</num>
        <heading>Power to administer oaths and compel testimony</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 22. Power to administer oaths and compel testimony. The\ncommissioner, a deputy commissioner, the secretary or counsel of the\ndepartment, or any other officer or employee duly authorized by the\ncommissioner, may administer oaths and take affidavits in relation to\nany matter or proceeding in the exercise of the powers and duties of the\ndepartment under this chapter. The commissioner, or a deputy\ncommissioner may subpoena and require the attendance of witnesses and\nthe production of books, papers and documents pertaining to the\ninvestigations and inquiries which such commissioner or deputy\ncommissioner is authorized to conduct, and examine them in relation to\nany matter to be investigated by them and issue commissions for the\nexamination of witnesses who are out of the state or unable to attend or\nexcused from attendance.\n  Any person who shall wilfully testify falsely as to any material\nmatter pending in an investigation or proceeding under this chapter\nshall be guilty of and punishable for perjury.\n  An officer who serves the subpoenas issued as above provided and\nwitnesses attending in response thereto shall be entitled to the same\nfees as are allowed to officers and witnesses in civil actions in courts\nof record, to be audited and paid in the same manner as other expenses\nof the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>