<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-225"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-225"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225">
        <num>225</num>
        <heading>Wood products development council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 225. Wood products development council. 1. There is hereby\nestablished within the department a wood products development council.\nSuch council shall consist of the commissioner, the commissioners of\nenvironmental conservation and economic development, or their designees,\nand ten other persons to be appointed by the governor, including one\nmember on the recommendation of the temporary president of the senate;\none member on the recommendation of the speaker of the assembly; one\nmember on the recommendation of the minority leader of the senate; and\none member on the recommendation of the minority leader of the assembly.\nOf the members so appointed, at least one member shall be a sawmill\nowner, one member shall be a secondary wood products manufacturer, one\nmember shall be a logger, one member shall be a maple syrup producer,\none member shall be a commercial forest owner, one member shall be a\nnonindustrial forest owner, one member shall be a representative of a\nstatewide forest industry organization, and one member shall be a\nrepresentative of a statewide forest landowners association. Members\nshall be appointed for a term of three years and may serve until their\nsuccessors are chosen, provided, however, that of the members first\nappointed, three shall serve for a term of one year, three shall serve\nfor a term of two years, and four shall serve for a term of three years.\nThe governor shall select a member of the council to serve as\nchairperson. Council members shall not receive compensation for their\nservices, but may be paid their actual and necessary expenses incurred\nin serving upon the council.\n  2. The council shall work with wood-using manufacturers to increase\nthe economic contributions and employment opportunities related to the\npractice of forestry and manufacture of wood products in New York state.\nThe council shall give priority to increasing private investment in\nworking forests; maintaining access to working and family forests;\ncoordinating policy and permitting issues with state agencies, academia\nand the private sector; working to improve public understanding of and\nappreciation for forestry and forest products; and increasing export and\nmarket opportunities for New York forest products. The council shall\ndeliver an annual report outlining its work and making recommendations\nwith regard to economic development and marketing initiatives and\nresearch and development initiatives consistent with the purposes of the\ncouncil. The report shall be delivered to the governor, the speaker of\nthe assembly, the temporary president of the senate, the minority leader\nof the assembly and the minority leader of the senate.\n  3. The department shall provide necessary support services to the\ncouncil, including, within funds available, the appointment of an\nexecutive director to coordinate the work of the council.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>