<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="24"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_24">
        <num>24</num>
        <heading>Publication of department bulletins, publications and reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 24. Publication of department bulletins, publications and reports.\nThere may be published by the department from time to time bulletins or\nother publications and reports containing accurate data, statistics and\ninformation.\n  1. As to agriculture, agricultural production, agricultural labor and\nthe agricultural conditions of the state, and the development and\nimprovement thereof, with a view of increasing farm production and\nvalues;\n  2. As to the sources, supply and prices of foods, their storage and\naccumulation at different places, and the quantities and location of the\navailable supply thereof;\n  3. As to the market prices of foods;\n  4. As to facilities afforded for transportation, marketing and\ndistribution of foods within the state;\n  5. As to matters pertaining generally to the production of foods, the\nactual food value of articles used as foods, and the sale and\ndistribution thereof to the consumers, which in the opinion of the\ncommissioner will prove valuable or of interest to the public;\n  6. As to investigations, hearings and inquiries conducted as provided\nin this chapter, the conclusions reached as to the matters involved\ntherein, and the orders and recommendations made as a result thereof;\n  7. As to any other matter which the commissioner deems proper.\n  Such bulletins, publications and reports and the information contained\ntherein shall be published and distributed in the manner deemed best by\nthe commissioner for the dissemination of knowledge as to the\nagricultural and dairy interests of the state and the production, sale,\npurchase, storage, marketing and distribution of foods, and the economic\nand food value of articles used as food.  The cost of publishing such\nbulletins, publications and reports shall be paid in the same manner as\nother expenses of the department out of appropriations made therefor.\nCopies of the bulletins, publication and reports of the department may\nalso be sold to the public at the estimated cost thereof, in accordance\nwith a schedule of charges which the commissioner is hereby authorized\nto adopt.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>