<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-249"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-249"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="249"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-249/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-249/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-249/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-249/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_249">
        <num>249</num>
        <heading>Granting, revoking or suspending licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 249. Granting, revoking or suspending licenses. The commissioner may\ndecline to grant or renew a license, or revoke or suspend a license\nalready granted, upon due notice and opportunity for a hearing to the\napplicant or licensee, and upon finding of one or more of the following:\n  1. That the licensee or applicant has violated any provision of\nsection two hundred forty-six of this article.\n  2. That the licensee has made a general assignment for the benefit of\ncreditors or is insolvent or where a money judgment has been secured\nagainst him or her, upon which an execution has been returned\nunsatisfied and the time to appeal therefrom has expired.\n  3. That there has been a continued course of dealing or operation of\nthe business of the applicant or licensee of such a nature as to satisfy\nthe commissioner of the inability or the unwillingness of the applicant\nor licensee to conduct his or her business in compliance with the\nprovisions of this chapter, or of such rules and regulations as the\ncommissioner may adopt.\n  4. That there has been a continued failure to keep records required by\nthe commissioner or by law.\n  5. That the applicant or licensee has failed to provide such security\nas required by the commissioner pursuant to this article.\n  6. That the applicant or licensee has been a party to or is conspiring\nto enter a combination to fix prices contrary to law.\n  7. That the applicant or licensee has solicited, purchased or received\nfarm products contracted to another licensee.\n  8. That the applicant or licensee has failed to comply with any other\nprovisions of this chapter, article or rules and regulations promulgated\nthereunder.\n  9. That the applicant or licensee has made any false or misleading\nstatement in his or her application to the commissioner for a license,\nor concerning any matter enumerated in this article.\n  10. That the applicant or licensee or any individual holding any\nposition or interest or power of control of the applicant or licensee\nhad previously been responsible in whole or in part for any act on\naccount of which a license may have been suspended or revoked pursuant\nto the provisions of this article.\n  11. That the licensee has violated the posting requirements of section\ntwo hundred forty-eight of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>