<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-250-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-250-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="250-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-250-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-250-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-250-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-250-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_250_F">
        <num>250-F</num>
        <heading>Stated grape price</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 250-f. Stated grape price. Notwithstanding any provision of\nsubdivision one of section two hundred fifty-e of this article, except\nwith respect to such cooperative member patrons, it shall be unlawful\nfor any processor doing business in New York to purchase or receive or\nattempt to purchase or receive grapes grown in New York state unless the\nprocessor sets forth and makes available to any selling or delivering\nparty, not later than August fifteenth in the year in which the grapes\nare to be delivered, the sum total in dollars and cents of all amounts\npaid or to be paid per unit; provided, however, that a processor and a\nproducer may negotiate without restriction a price for up to five tons\nof grapes per variety, not to exceed a maximum of twenty tons of grapes\ntotal, other than the price originally set forth pursuant to this\nsection provided that any such negotiated prices shall be set forth in\nwriting by the processor no later than the date of delivery of said\ngrapes. Where a selling or delivering party has a contract for delivery\nof such grapes to a processor, the processor shall, not later than\nAugust fifteenth in the year in which such grapes are to be delivered,\nmail to the delivering or selling party written notice of the stated\ngrape price and of the opportunity to refuse to so deliver with respect\nthereto. Such notice may also be provided by facsimile, or other\nelectronic means to selling or delivering parties who have the ability\nto accept notice in that manner and have agreed to accept service by\nsuch means. The processor shall also provide to the commissioner by\nmail, facsimile, or other electronic means, no later than August\nfifteenth of each year in which such grapes are to be delivered, a\nwritten statement of the stated grape price to be paid for such grapes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>