<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-256-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-256-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="256-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-256-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-256-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-256-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-256-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_256_A">
        <num>256-A</num>
        <heading>Audits of books and accounts of milk dealers and cooperatives</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 256-a. Audits of books and accounts of milk dealers and\ncooperatives. It shall be the duty of the commissioner to examine and\naudit from time to time, as the commissioner deems necessary and proper,\nthe books and accounts of milk dealers and cooperatives licensed or\nsubject to license under this article, for the purpose of determining\nhow payments to producers for the milk handled are computed, whether the\namounts of such payments are fair, and whether any provisions of this\nchapter affecting such payments, directly or indirectly, have been or\nare being violated, and for the purpose of determining the costs of the\nhandling, distribution and marketing of milk and milk products, and for\nthe purpose of determining the manner of disposition of the total income\nof each and every milk dealer and cooperative. For the purposes hereof,\nthe commissioner or any employee designated for that purpose shall have\naccess to and may enter at all reasonable hours all places where milk is\nbeing stored, bottled or manufactured or where milk and milk products\nare being bought, sold or handled, and where books, papers, records or\ndocuments relating to such purchase or sale are kept, and shall have\npower to inspect and copy and audit all of said books and accounts.  No\nperson or corporation shall in any way hinder or delay the commissioner\nor any employee in conducting such examination or audit. The\ncommissioner may reveal any of the findings of such examination or audit\nto the producers interested therein, or may publish all or any part of\nsuch findings, as in his judgment will best serve the public interest\nand accomplish the purposes of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>