<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-257-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-257-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="257-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-257-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-257-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-257-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-257-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_257_A">
        <num>257-A</num>
        <heading>Transportation and storage of milk</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 257-a. Transportation and storage of milk. 1. Any vehicle\ntransporting pasteurized milk for retail sale in the same container\nshall be transported in a vehicle capable of maintaining milk at a\ntemperature of at least forty-five degrees fahrenheit or cooler.\n  2. It shall be unlawful for milk excluding UHT/aseptic packaged milk\nand milk products to be shipped or stored in the same enclosed\nrefrigerated compartment which contains any hazardous or toxic\nchemicals, or solid waste.  "Toxic and hazardous chemicals" shall not\nmean common household products normally sold in grocery stores and\nsupermarkets or those products normally provided to commercial\nestablishments by a food service company, that are packaged and handled\nin a manner which avoids contamination of milk or milk products. "Solid\nwaste" shall not mean any packaging that is approved for reuse such as\nreturnable milk bottles.\n  3. It shall be the responsibility of any milk dealer who sells milk or\ndairy products intended for resale to another distributor to obtain\ncertification from such distributor that the requirements for proper\nrefrigeration transportation as provided in this section are met.\n  4. The commissioner may exempt persons who purchase or handle milk in\na total quantity not exceeding twenty gallons per day from the\nrequirements of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>