<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-258-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-258-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="258-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-258-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-258-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-258-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-258-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_258_N">
        <num>258-N</num>
        <heading>Interstate and federal compacts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 258-n. Interstate and federal compacts. The commissioner is hereby\nauthorized to confer with legally constituted authorities of other\nstates and of the United States with respect to uniform milk control,\nincluding sanitary requirements with states and/or as between states,\nand with the federal government in its control of milk handled in\ninterstate commerce, and may exercise his powers hereunder to effect\nsuch uniform milk control. He may join with such other authorities\nfederal and state in conducting joint investigations, holding joint\nhearings and issue joint or concurrent orders, or orders supplementary\nto those of the federal government, and shall have the power to employ\nor designate a joint agent or joint agencies to carry out and enforce\nsuch joint, concurrent or supplementary orders.\n  In order to carry out the policies set forth in sections two hundred\nfifty-eight-k and two hundred fifty-eight-p, the commissioner is hereby\nvested with the authority to enter into a compact or compacts or other\ntypes of agreements, with the legally constituted authorities of other\nstates and/or the United States to provide for uniform milk control and,\nin order to effectuate such uniform milk control, he may join with an\nagent or agencies to exercise under such compact or compacts or other\ntypes of agreements the powers conferred upon him by this article with\nrespect to the administration of uniform milk control. In the case of\nmarket orders including those covering prices, any such compact or\ncompacts or other types of agreements may provide for necessary\nassessments upon the handlers regulated thereunder, in order to cover\nthe cost of administering such uniform milk control, including, without\nlimitation, the cost of auditing milk dealers' classifications.\n  The commissioner may effectuate this section by any type of agreement\nother than a formal compact if a formal compact is not constitutionally\nrequired.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>