<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-259"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-259"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="259"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-259/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-259/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-259/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-259/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_259">
        <num>259</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 259. Legislative findings. The legislature hereby finds and declares\nthat farmers' markets provide a vital and highly effective marketing\nmechanism for thousands of New York farmers, improve the access of\nconsumers and wholesalers to New York farm products, and contribute to\nthe economic revitalization of the areas in which the markets are\nlocated. The legislature further declares that farmers' markets provide\nconsumers with access to a wide range of high quality, nutritious, farm\nfresh and processed New York state agricultural and food products;\nfacilitate expanded wholesale distribution of New York state farm\nproducts to retail stores, restaurants, institutions and other wholesale\nfood buyers; provide new and expanded farm and city jobs in agricultural\nproduction, marketing, and sales, and in market facilities development\nand operation; promote consumer awareness of New York state agriculture\nand agricultural products; and foster economic and social interaction\nbetween urban and rural residents of the state.\n  It is therefore the intent of the legislature and the purpose of this\narticle to encourage farmers' markets in the state by providing state\nassistance to municipalities and public and private agencies interested\nin developing new markets or expanding or reconstructing existing farm\nmarket operations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>