<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-282"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-282"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="282"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-282/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-282/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-282/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-282/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_282">
        <num>282</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 282. Definitions. As used in this article:\n  1. "Direct marketing" means the sale of farm and food products\ndirectly from producers to consumers and food buyers.\n  2. "Farm and food product" means any agricultural, horticultural,\nforest, or other product of the soil or water that has been grown,\nharvested, or produced wholly within the state of New York. Such\nproducts shall include but not be limited to: fruits, vegetables, eggs,\ndairy products, meat and meat products, poultry and poultry products,\nfish and fish products, grain and grain products, honey, nuts,\npreserves, maple sap products, apple cider, fruit juice, ornamental or\nvegetable plants, nursery products, flowers, firewood, fermented\nagricultural products, and Christmas trees.\n  3. "Producer" means any person who grows, produces, or causes to be\ngrown or produced any farm and food products in New York state. This\nterm shall also include members of the producer's family and the\nproducer's employees.\n  4. "Farmers' market" means any building, structure or place, the\nproperty of a municipal corporation or under lease to or in possession\nof a public or private agency, used or intended to be used by two or\nmore producers for the direct sale of farm and food products from\nproducers to consumers and food buyers. Such market may also include\nfacilities for the packing, shipping, first-instance processing or\nstorage of farm and food products, and shall include all equipment used\nor intended to be used in connection with such facilities. Such market\nmay also include other businesses which reasonably serve the public or\nmake the market more convenient, efficient, profitable or successful,\nincluding, but not limited to, food service, baking, and non-food\nretailing.\n  5. "Public or private agencies" means any department, division,\nbureau, or program of the federal or state government, or local\ngovernments, public benefit corporations, private non-profit\norganizations, or educational institutions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>