<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-303-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-303-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-05-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="303-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-303-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-303-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-303-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-303-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_303_A">
        <num>303-A</num>
        <heading>Agricultural districts; review</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_303_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement of the time, date and place of the public hearing; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_303_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the district, any proposed modifications and any\nrecommendations of the county agricultural and farmland protection\nboard.\n  3. a. The county legislative body, after receiving the report and\nrecommendation of the county agricultural and farmland protection board,\nand after public hearing, shall make a finding whether the district\nshould be continued, terminated or modified. If the county legislative\nbody finds that the district should be terminated, it may do so at the\nend of such eight year period by filing a notice of termination with the\ncounty clerk and the commissioner.\n  b. The county legislative body may adopt any modification of the\ndistrict review plan it deems appropriate.\n  c. If the county legislative body finds that the district should be\ncontinued or modified, it shall submit the district review plan to the\ncommissioner. The district review plan shall include a description of\nthe district, including a map delineating the exterior boundaries of the\ndistrict which shall conform to tax parcel boundaries; the tax map\nidentification numbers for every parcel in the district; a copy of the\nreport of the county agricultural and farmland protection board required\nby paragraph b of subdivision two of this section; and a copy of the\ntestimony given at the public hearing required by paragraph c of\nsubdivision two of this section or a copy of the minutes of such\nhearing.\n  4. The county legislative body shall complete the review process\ndescribed in this section by either terminating, continuing, or\nmodifying the district on or before the district's anniversary date. The\ncommissioner may, upon application by the county legislative body and\nfor good cause shown, extend the period for a district review once for\nup to six additional months. If the county legislative body does not\nact, or if a modification of a district is rejected by the county\nlegislative body, the district shall continue as originally constituted,\nunle...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>