<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-304-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-304-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="304-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-304-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-304-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-304-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-304-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_304_A">
        <num>304-A</num>
        <heading>Agricultural assessment values</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_304_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adjusted net farm income shall be the sum of net farm income,\ntaxes on farm real estate and the amount of mortgage interest debt\nattributable to farmland, less a management charge of one percent of\nrealized gross farm income plus seven percent of adjusted production\nexpenses.\n  (ii) The amount of mortgage interest debt attributable to farmland\nshall be the product of the interest on mortgage debt and the percentage\nof farm real estate value attributable to land.\n  (iii) The percentage of farm real estate value attributable to land\nshall be the difference between farm real estate value and farm\nstructure value divided by farm real estate value.\n  (iv) Adjusted production expenses shall be production expenses, less\nthe sum of the taxes on farm real estate and the interest on mortgage\ndebt.\n  d. The following data, required for calculations pursuant to this\nsubdivision, shall be as published by the United States department of\nagriculture for all farming in New York state:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Farm real estate value shall be the total value of farmland and\nbuildings, including improvements.\n  (ii) Farm structure value shall be the total value of farm buildings,\nincluding improvements.\n  (iii) Interest on mortgage debt shall be the total interest paid on\nfarm real estate debt.\n  (iv) Net farm income shall be realized gross income less production\nexpenses, as adjusted for change in inventory.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304_A__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Production expenses shall be the total cost of production.\n  (vi) Realized gross income shall be the total of cash receipts from\nfarm marketings, government payments, nonmoney income and other farm\nincome.\n  (vii) Taxes on farm real estate shall be the total real property taxes\non farmland and buildings, including improvements.\n  (viii) Number of acres harvested including all reported crops.\n  (ix) Value of production shall be the total estimated value of all\nreported crops.\n  e. In the event that the data required for calculation pursuant to\nthis subdivision is not published by the United States department of\nagriculture or is incomplete, such required data shall be obtained from\nthe New York state department of agriculture and markets.\n  f. Upon completion of each annual calculation of agricultural\nassessment values, the commissioner of taxation and finance shall\npublish an annual report, which shall include a schedule of values,\ncitations to data sources and presentation of all calculations.\n  The commissioner of taxation and finance shall thereupon certify the\nschedule of agricultural assessment values and shall transmit a schedule\nof such certified values to each assessor. Beginning in the year two\nthousand six and every five years thereafter, the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance shall transmit copies of such annual reports for\nthe five years previous to such transmittal, to the governor and\nlegislature, the advisory council on agriculture, and other appropriate\nstate agencies and interested parties.\n  g. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section to the\ncontrary, in no event shall the change in the base agricultural\nassessment value for any given year exceed two percent of the base\nagricultural assessment value of the preceding year.\n  5. a. In carrying out their responsibilities under this section, the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance and the commissioner shall keep the\nadvisory council on agriculture fully appr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>