<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="305"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_305">
        <num>305</num>
        <heading>Agricultural districts; effects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nin the year of a revaluation or update of assessments, as those terms\nare defined in section one hundred two of the real property tax law, the\napplication may be filed with the assessor no later than the thirtieth\nday prior to the day by which the tentative assessment roll is required\nto be filed by law; or (ii) an application for such an assessment may be\nfiled with the assessor of the assessing unit after the appropriate\ntaxable status date but not later than the last date on which a petition\nwith respect to complaints of assessment may be filed, where failure to\nfile a timely application resulted from:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a death of the applicant's\nspouse, child, parent, brother or sister,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an illness of the\napplicant or of the applicant's spouse, child, parent, brother or\nsister, which actually prevents the applicant from filing on a timely\nbasis, as certified by a licensed physician, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the occurrence of a\nnatural disaster, including, but not limited to, a flood, or the\ndestruction of such applicant's residence, barn or other farm building\nby wind, fire or flood. If the assessor is satisfied that the applicant\nis entitled to an agricultural assessment, the assessor shall approve\nthe application and the land shall be assessed pursuant to this section.\nNot less than ten days prior to the date for hearing complaints in\nrelation to assessments, the assessor shall mail to each applicant, who\nhas included with the application at least one self-addressed, pre-paid\nenvelope, a notice of the approval or denial of the application. Such\nnotice shall be on a form prescribed by the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance which shall indicate the manner in which the total assessed\nvalue is apportioned among the various portions of the property subject\nto agricultural assessment and those other portions of the property not\neligible for agricultural assessment as determined for the tentative\nassessment roll and the latest final assessment roll. Failure to mail\nany such notice or failure of the owner to receive the same shall not\nprevent the levy, collection and enforcement of the payment of the taxes\non such real property.\n  b. That portion of the value of land utilized for agricultural\nproduction within an agricultural district which represents an excess\nabove the agricultural assessment as determined in accordance with this\nsubdivision shall not be subject to real property taxation. Such excess\namount if any shall be entered on the assessment roll in the manner\nprescribed by the commissioner of taxation and finance.\n  c.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The assessor shall utilize the agricultural assessment values\nper acre certified pursuant to section three hundred four-a of this\narticle in determining the amount of the assessment of lands eligible\nfor agricultural assessments by multiplying those values by the number\nof acres of land utilized for agricultural production and adjusting such\nresult by application of the latest state equalization rate or a special\nequalization rate as may be established and certified by the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance for the purpose of computing the\nagricultural assessment pursuant to this paragraph. This resulting\namount shall be the agricultural assessment for such lands.\n  (ii) Where the latest state equalization rate exceeds one hundred, or\nwhere a special equalization rate which would otherwise be established\nfor the purposes of this section would exceed one hundred, a special\nequalization rate of one hundred shall be established and certified by\nthe commissioner for the purpose of this section.\n  (iii) Where a special equalization rate has been established and\ncertified by the commissioner for the purposes of this paragraph, the\nassessor is directed and authorized to recompute the agricultural\nassessment on the assessment roll by applying such special equalization\nrate instead of the latest state equalization rate, and to make the\nappropriate corrections on the assessment roll, subject to the\nprovisions of title two of article twelve of the real property tax law.\n  d.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If land within an agricultural district which received an\nagricultural assessment is converted parcels, as described on the\nassessment roll which include land so converted shall be subject to\npayments equalling five times the taxes saved in the last year in which\nthe land benefited from an agricultural assessment, plus interest of six\npercent per year compounded annually for each year in which an\nagricultural assessment was granted, not exceeding five years. The\namount of taxes saved for the last year in which the land benefited from\nan agricultural assessment shall be determined by applying the\napplicable tax rates to the excess amount of assessed valuation of such\nland over its agricultural assessment as set forth on the last\nassessment roll which indicates such an excess. If only a portion of a\nparcel as described on the assessment roll is converted, the assessor\nshall apportion the assessment and agricultural assessment attributable\nto the converted portion, as determined for the last assessment roll for\nwhich the assessment of such portion exceeded its agricultural\nassessment. The difference between the apportioned assessment and the\napportioned agricultural assessment shall be the amount upon which\npayments shall be determined. Payments shall be added by or on behalf of\neach taxing jurisdiction to the taxes levied on the assessment roll\nprepared on the basis of the first taxable status date on which the\nassessor considers the land to have been converted; provided, however,\nthat no payments shall be imposed if the last assessment roll upon which\nthe property benefited from an agricultural assessment, was more than\nfive years prior to the year for which the assessment roll upon which\npayments would otherwise be levied is prepared.\n  (ii) Whenever a conversion occurs, the owner shall notify the assessor\nwithin ninety days of the date such conversion is commenced. If the\nlandowner fails to make such notification within the ninety day pe...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An assessor who determines that there is liability for\npayments and any penalties assessed pursuant to subparagraph (ii) of\nthis paragraph shall notify the landowner by mail of such liability at\nleast ten days prior to the date for hearing complaints in relation to\nassessments. Such notice shall indicate the property to which payments\napply and describe how the payments shall be determined. Failure to\nprovide such notice shall not affect the levy, collection or enforcement\nor payment of payments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Liability for payments shall be subject to administrative and\njudicial review as provided by law for review of assessments.\n  (iv) If such land or any portion thereof is converted to a use other\nthan for agricultural production by virtue of oil, gas or wind\nexploration, development, or extraction activity or by virtue of a\ntaking by eminent domain or other involuntary proceeding other than a\ntax sale, the land or portion so converted shall not be subject to\npayments. If the land so converted constitutes only a portion of a\nparcel described on the assessment roll, the assessor shall apportion\nthe assessment, and adjust the agricultural assessment attributable to\nthe portion of the parcel not subject to such conversion by subtracting\nthe proportionate part of the agricultural assessment attributable to\nthe portion so converted. Provided further that land within an\nagricultural district and eligible for an agricultural assessment shall\nnot be considered to have been converted to a use other than for\nagricultural production solely due to the conveyance of oil, gas or wind\nrights associated with that land.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An assessor who imposes any such payments shall annually, and\nwithin forty-five days following the date on which the final assessment\nroll is required to be filed, report such payments to the commissioner\nof taxation and finance on a form prescribed by the commissioner.\n  (vi) The assessing unit, by majority vote of the governing body, may\nimpose a minimum payment amount, not to exceed five hundred dollars.\n  (vii) The purchase of land in fee by the city of New York for\nwatershed protection purposes or the conveyance of a conservation\neasement by the city of New York to the department of environmental\nconservation which prohibits future use of the land for agricultural\npurposes shall not be a conversion of parcels and no payment shall be\ndue under this section.\n  e. Notwithstanding any inconsistent general, special or local law to\nthe contrary, if a natural disaster, act of God, or continued adverse\nweather conditions shall destroy the agricultural production and such\nfact is certified by the cooperative extension service and, as a result,\nsuch production does not produce an average gross sales value of ten\nthousand dollars or more, the owner may nevertheless qualify for an\nagricultural assessment provided the owner shall substantiate in such\nmanner as prescribed by the commissioner of taxation and finance that\nthe agricultural production initiated on such land would have produced\nan average gross sales value of ten thousand dollars or more but for the\nnatural disaster, act of God or continued adverse weather conditions.\n  3. Policy of state agencies. It shall be the policy of all state\nagencies to encourage the maintenance of viable farming in agricultural\ndistricts and their administrative regulations and procedures shall be\nmodified to this end insofar as is consistent with the promotion of\npublic health and safety and with the provisions of any federal\nstatutes, standards, criteria, rules, regulations, or policies, and any\nother requ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a detailed description of the proposed action and its agricultural\nsetting;\n  (ii) the agricultural impact of the proposed action including\nshort-term and long-term effects;\n  (iii) any adverse agricultural effects which cannot be avoided should\nthe proposed action be implemented;\n  (iv) alternatives to the proposed action;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any irreversible and irretrievable commitments of agricultural\nresources which would be involved in the proposed action should it be\nimplemented;\n  (vi) mitigation measures proposed to minimize the adverse impact of\nthe proposed action on the continuing viability of a farm enterprise or\nenterprises within the district;\n  (vii) any aspects of the proposed action which would encourage\nnon-farm development, where applicable and appropriate; and\n  (viii) such other information as the commissioner may require.\n  The commissioner shall promptly determine whether the notice is\ncomplete or incomplete. If the commissioner does not issue such\ndetermination within thirty days, the notice shall be deemed complete.\nIf the notice is determined to be incomplete, the commissioner shall\nnotify the party proposing the action in writing of the reasons for that\ndetermination.  Any new submission shall commence a new period for\ndepartment review for purposes of determining completeness.\n  c. The provisions of paragraph b of this subdivision shall not apply\nand shall be deemed waived by the owner of the land to be acquired where\nsuch owner signs a document to such effect and provides a copy to the\ncommissioner.\n  d. Upon notice from the commissioner that he or she has accepted a\nnotice as complete, the county agricultural and farmland protection\nboard may, within thirty days, review the proposed action and its\neffects on farm operations and agricultural resources within the\ndistrict, and report its findings and recommendations to the\ncommissioner and to the party proposing the action in the case of\nactions proposed by a state agency or public benefit corporation, and\nadditionally to the county legislature in the case of actions proposed\nby local government agencies.\n  e. Upon receipt and acceptance of a notice, the commissioner shall\nthereupon forward a copy of such notice to the commissioner of\nenvironmental conservation and the advisory council on agricul...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>issue an order\nwithin the forty-five day period directing the state agency, public\nbenefit corporation or local government not to take such action for an\nadditional period of sixty days immediately following such forty-five\nday period; and (ii) review the proposed action to determine whether any\nreasonable and practicable alternative or alternatives exist which would\nminimize or avoid the adverse impact on agriculture in order to sustain\na viable farm enterprise or enterprises within the district.\n  The commissioner may hold a public hearing concerning such proposed\naction at a place within the district or otherwise easily accessible to\nthe district upon notice in a newspaper having a general circulation\nwithin the district and posted on the home page of the department's\nwebsite, and individual notice, in writing by first class mail, to the\nmunicipalities whose territories encompass the district, the\ncommissioner of environmental conservation, the advisory council on\nagriculture and the state agency, public benefit corporation or local\ngovernment proposing to take such action. On or before the conclusion of\nsuch additional sixty day period, the commissioner shall report his or\nher findings to the agency, corporation or government proposing to take\nsuch action, to any public agency having the power of review of or\napproval of such action, and, in a manner conducive to the wide\ndissemination of such findings, to the public. If the commissioner\nconcludes that a reasonable and practicable alternative or alternatives\nexist which would minimize or avoid the adverse impact of the proposed\naction, he or she shall propose that such alternative or alternatives be\naccepted. If the agency, corporation or government proposing the action\naccepts the commissioner's proposal, then the requirements of the notice\nof intent filing shall be deemed fulfilled. If the agency, corporation\nor government rejects the commissioner's proposal, then it shall provide\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The owner of such land has entered into a written agreement which\nshall indicate his consent for site consideration; or\n  (ii) The applicant for a permit has made a commitment in the permit\napplication to fund a farm land protection conservation easement within\na reasonable proximity to the proposed project in an amount not less\nthan the dollar value of any such farm land purchased for the project;\nor\n  (iii) The commissioner in concurrence with the commissioner of\nenvironmental conservation has determined that any such agricultural\nland to be taken, constitutes less than five percent of the project\nsite.\n  For purposes of this paragraph, "solid waste management facility"\nshall have the same meaning as provided in title seven of article\ntwenty-seven of the environmental conservation law, but shall not\ninclude solid waste transfer stations or land upon which sewage sludge\nis applied, and determinations regarding agricultural district\nboundaries and agricultural assessments will be based on those in effect\nas of the date an initial determination is made, pursuant to article\neight of the environmental conservation law, as to whether an\nenvironmental impact statement needs to be prepared for the proposed\nproject.\n  i. This subdivision shall not apply to any emergency project which is\nimmediately necessary for the protection of life or property or to any\nproject or proceeding to which the department is or has been a statutory\nparty.\n  j. The commissioner may bring an action to enforce any mitigation\nmeasures proposed by a public benefit corporation or a local government,\nand accepted by the commissioner, pursuant to a notice of intent filing,\nto minimize or avoid adverse agricultural impacts from the proposed\naction.\n  5. Limitation on power to impose benefit assessments, special ad\nvalorem levies or other rates or fees in certain improvement districts\nor benefit areas. Within improvement districts or areas deemed benefited\nby municipal i...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>