<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-308-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-308-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="308-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-308-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-308-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-308-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-308-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_308_A">
        <num>308-A</num>
        <heading>Fees and expenses in certain private nuisance actions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_308_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the facts\nsupporting the claim that the party is a prevailing party and is\neligible to receive an award under this section, (ii) the amount sought,\nand (iii) an itemized statement from every attorney or expert witness\nfor which fees or expenses are sought stating the actual time expended\nand the rate at which such fees and other expenses are claimed.\n  3. Interest. If the plaintiff appeals an award made pursuant to this\nsection and the award is affirmed in whole or in part, interest shall be\npaid on the amount of the award. Such interest shall run from the date\nof the award through the day before the date of the affirmance.\n  4. Applicability. a. Nothing contained in this section shall be\nconstrued to alter or modify the provisions of the civil practice law\nand rules where applicable to actions other than actions as defined by\nthis section.\n  b. Nothing contained in this section shall affect or preclude the\nright of any party to recover fees or other expenses authorized by\ncommon law or by any other statute, law or rule.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>