<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="31-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31_B">
        <num>31-B</num>
        <heading>State fair</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 31-b. State fair. It shall be the duty of the department to hold a\nstate fair to be known as the New York state fair at such times as it\nmay deem proper, and between January first and February fifteenth in\neach calendar year to publish the time for holding said fair in such\nyear. If such fair be held on the first Monday of September, known as\nlabor day, the department shall designate such day as "organized labor\nday." It shall not be lawful for any corporation, association or\nindividual to hold or conduct any trotting or pacing race or races\nduring the week in which the New York state fair is held, except upon\nhalf-mile tracks, and except at the fairs held by agricultural societies\nwhich have received moneys from the state, and no corporation,\nassociation or individual holding such races during said week shall be\nentitled to any of the benefits conferred by article twenty of the\nmembership corporations law, or by any general or special law. The\ndepartment may make, alter, suspend or repeal needed rules relating to\nsuch fair, including the times and duration thereof, the terms and\nconditions of entries and admissions, exhibits, sale of privileges,\npayments of premiums, and any other matters which it may deem proper in\nconnection with such fair. It shall furnish to each person who, on the\nseventeenth day of January, nineteen hundred, was a life member of the\nstate agricultural society, a free admission to the fair ground during\nthe fair of each year during the life of such member.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>