<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="31-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31_C">
        <num>31-C</num>
        <heading>Receipts and disbursements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 31-c. Receipts and disbursements.  The department shall receive all\nmoneys payable to the state on account of said fair and make all\ndisbursements therefrom and also from any appropriation made for that\npurpose by the legislature as may be needed, from time to time, in\ncarrying on the work of the department. The provisions of section one\nhundred twenty-one of the state finance law requiring that money\nreceived for or on behalf of the state shall be paid monthly into the\nstate treasury shall not apply to the proceeds of the state fair, and\nthe department may pay from the race and other entry fees, gate\nadmissions and other receipts of such fair such expenses as shall be\nnecessary for the proper conduct of the New York state fair and the\npurposes of the department.  Any balance remaining in its hands received\nin connection with the state fair shall be retained by the department of\nagriculture and markets as a special fund for such permanent\nconstructions on the state fair grounds or for administration expenses\nas shall be approved by the director of the budget, the chairman of the\nfinance committee of the senate and the chairman of the ways and means\ncommittee of the assembly.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>