<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="31"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-31/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31">
        <num>31</num>
        <heading>Fair grounds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 31. Fair grounds. The property described in the conveyance to the\nstate by the New York state agricultural society of its property in the\ntown of Geddes, Onondaga County, New York, by deed dated July\ntwenty-eight, eighteen hundred and ninety-nine, and recorded in the\noffice of the comptroller and any other property heretofore or hereafter\nacquired by the state for state fair purposes shall be under the\nmanagement and control of the department, and it may, from time to time,\nmake rules and provide for the care, preservation and improvement\nthereof. When the exhibition buildings and facilities are not in use for\nstate fair purposes, the commissioner of agriculture and markets may\nmanage and lease such exhibition buildings and facilities and may lease\nspace in such buildings, and may execute contracts in relation to such\nrentals and fix, impose and collect rentals and license fees therefor.\nAll rental and license fees and such other income as may be provided by\nthe leasing of such buildings, space and facilities shall be considered\nmoneys payable to the state on account of said fair in accordance with\nthe provisions of section thirty-one-c of this article. The commissioner\nof agriculture and markets may convey to the industrial exhibit\nauthority certain real property in the town of Geddes, Onondaga county,\nNew York, as heretofore or hereafter acquired by the state for state\nfair purposes. The commissioner is authorized to execute and file in the\nOnondaga county clerk's office an instrument in writing defining\nspecifically the plot or plots of land transferred to the industrial\nexhibit authority pursuant to this section provided, however, that such\nplot or plots of land shall be no more than is sufficient to accomplish\nthe purposes described in the instrument. When such written instrument\nis so filed it shall vest the authority with the title to the real\nproperty defined therein provided, however, that nothing herein shall\nprevent the industrial exhibit authority from transferring back to the\nstate and vesting title in the state for state fair purposes under the\nmanagement and control of the department of agriculture and markets any\nland which the authority heretofore received as state fair land or any\nstate fair land which the authority may hereafter receive pursuant to\nthis section. In the event that the industrial exhibit authority shall\nbe abolished or for any reason cease to exist the title to all lands\nheld by the authority which were formerly state fair lands shall revert\nto the state for state fair purposes under the management and control of\nthe department of agriculture and markets.  All conveyances heretofore\nmade between the commissioner of agriculture and markets and the\nindustrial exhibit authority are hereby confirmed and recognized as\nvalid and sufficient to convey good title.\n  The maintenance and repair of the improved roads on said property\nshall however be under the direct supervision and control of the\nsuperintendent of public works who is hereby authorized and directed to\nmaintain and repair the same, and the cost of such maintenance and\nrepair shall be paid out of any funds available for the maintenance,\nrepair and reconstruction of improved state highways.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>