<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-310"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-310"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="310"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-310/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-310/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-310/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-310/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_310">
        <num>310</num>
        <heading>Disclosure</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 310. Disclosure. 1. When any purchase and sale contract is presented\nfor the sale, purchase, or exchange of real property located partially\nor wholly within an agricultural district established pursuant to the\nprovisions of this article, the prospective grantor shall present to the\nprospective grantee a disclosure notice which states the following:\n  "It is the policy of this state and this community to conserve,\nprotect and encourage the development and improvement of agricultural\nland for the production of food, and other products, and also for its\nnatural and ecological value. This disclosure notice is to inform\nprospective residents that the property they are about to acquire lies\npartially or wholly within an agricultural district and that farming\nactivities occur within the district. Such farming activities may\ninclude, but not be limited to, activities that cause noise, dust and\nodors. Prospective residents are also informed that the location of\nproperty within an agricultural district may impact the ability to\naccess water and/or sewer services for such property under certain\ncircumstances.  Prospective purchasers are urged to contact the New York\nState Department of Agriculture and Markets to obtain additional\ninformation or clarification regarding their rights and obligations\nunder article 25-AA of the Agriculture and Markets Law."\n  1-a. Such disclosure notice shall be signed by the prospective grantor\nand grantee prior to the sale, purchase or exchange of such real\nproperty.\n  2. Receipt of such disclosure notice shall be recorded on a property\ntransfer report form prescribed by the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance as provided for in section three hundred thirty-three of the\nreal property law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>