<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-325-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-325-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="325-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-325-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-325-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-325-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-325-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_325_A">
        <num>325-A</num>
        <heading>State assistance payments to not-for-profit conservation organizations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 325-a. State assistance payments to not-for-profit conservation\norganizations. 1. Subject to the availability of funds, a program is\nhereby established for the purpose of awarding state assistance to\nnot-for-profit conservation organizations for activities that will\nassist counties and municipalities with their agricultural and farmland\nprotection efforts. To be eligible, an organization shall have at least\none active farmer on their board of directors at the time of application\nor shall provide for the appointment of a farmer to such board of\ndirectors in a manner approved by the commissioner.\n  2. Awards of state assistance payments shall be made on a competitive\nbasis through a request for proposal process which shall set forth the\nstandards for the selection process, the required proposal format, the\ncosts which are eligible for funding, reporting requirements, and such\nother provisions as the commissioner may deem necessary, proper or\ndesirable to achieve the purposes of this section. Applications for\nstate assistance payments must be endorsed by the agricultural and\nfarmland protection board for the county or counties in which the funded\nactivities would be implemented.\n  3. In evaluating applications, the commissioner shall give priority to\nactivities that will assist counties and municipalities with their\nagricultural and farmland protection efforts by disseminating\ninformation and providing technical assistance to county and municipal\ngovernments, owners of agricultural lands and other agricultural\ninterests.\n  4. Upon receipt of an application for state assistance, the\ncommissioner shall review the request, consult with the advisory council\non agriculture and, within ninety days from the receipt of a complete\napplication, make a determination as to whether or not the application\nwill be funded.\n  5. State assistance payments awarded to an applicant shall be used in\na manner which does not in any way unreasonably restrict or regulate\nfarm operations in contravention of the purposes of article\ntwenty-five-AA of this chapter.\n  6. State assistance payments awarded pursuant to this section shall\nnot exceed fifty thousand dollars to any applicant in any fiscal year,\nand shall not exceed five hundred thousand dollars to all applicants in\nany fiscal year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>