<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-332"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-332"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="332"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-332/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-332/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-332/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-332/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_332">
        <num>332</num>
        <heading>Disposition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 332. Disposition. Any person having in his or her care, custody, or\ncontrol any abandoned animal, as defined in section three hundred\nthirty-one of this article, may deliver such animal to any duly\nincorporated society for the prevention of cruelty to animals or any\nduly incorporated humane society having facilities for the care and\neventual disposition of such animals, or, in the case of dogs, cats and\nother small animals, to any pound maintained by or under contract or\nagreement with any county, city, town, or village within which such\nanimal was abandoned. The person with whom the animal was abandoned\nshall, however, on the day of divesting himself or herself of possession\nthereof, notify the person who had placed such animal in his or her\ncustody of the name and address of the animal society or pound to which\nthe animal has been delivered, such notice to be by registered letter\nmailed to the last known address of the person intended to be so\nnotified. If an animal is not claimed by its owner within five days\nafter being so delivered to such duly incorporated society for the\nprevention of cruelty to animals, duly incorporated humane society or\npound, such animal may at any time thereafter be placed for adoption in\na suitable home or euthanized in accordance with the provisions of\nsection three hundred seventy-four of this chapter. In no event,\nhowever, shall the use of a decompression chamber or decompression\ndevice of any kind be used for the purpose of destroying or disposing of\nsuch animal.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>