<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-353-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-353-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-08-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="353-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-353-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-353-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-353-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-353-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_353_D">
        <num>353-D</num>
        <heading>Confinement of companion animals in vehicles: extreme temperatures</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 353-d. Confinement of companion animals in vehicles: extreme\ntemperatures. 1. A person shall not confine a companion animal in a\nmotor vehicle in extreme heat or cold without proper ventilation or\nother protection from such extreme temperatures where such confinement\nplaces the companion animal in imminent danger of death or serious\nphysical injury due to exposure to such extreme heat or cold.\n  2. Where the operator of such a vehicle cannot be promptly located, a\npolice officer, peace officer, peace officer acting as an agent of a\nduly incorporated humane society, emergency medical services personnel,\npaid firefighter, or volunteer firefighter who in the performance of\nsuch volunteer firefighter's duties are directed to respond to a call\nfor assistance for such animal may take necessary steps to remove the\nanimal or animals from the vehicle.\n  3. Police officers, peace officers, peace officers acting as agents of\na duly incorporated humane society, emergency medical services\npersonnel, paid firefighters, or volunteer firefighters who in the\nperformance of such volunteer firefighters' duties or emergency medical\nservices personnel are directed to respond to a call for assistance for\nsuch animal removing an animal or animals from a vehicle pursuant to\nthis section shall place a written notice on or in the vehicle, bearing\nthe name of the officer or agent, and the department or agency and\naddress and other contact information, if available, where the animal or\nanimals will be taken.\n  4. An animal or animals removed from a vehicle pursuant to this\nsection shall, after receipt of any necessary emergency veterinary\ntreatment, be delivered to the duly incorporated humane society or\nsociety for the prevention of cruelty to animals, or designated agent\nthereof, in the jurisdiction where the animal or animals were seized.\n  5. Any person who knowingly violates the provisions of subdivision one\nof this section shall be guilty of a violation, punishable by a fine of\nnot less than fifty dollars nor more than one hundred dollars for a\nfirst offense, and a fine of not less than one hundred dollars nor more\nthan two hundred and fifty dollars for a second and subsequent offenses.\n  6. Officers, emergency medical services personnel and firefighters\nshall not be held criminally or civilly liable for actions taken\nreasonably and in good faith in carrying out the provisions of this\nsection.\n  7. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to affect any\nother protections afforded to companion animals under any other\nprovisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>