<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-354"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-354"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="354"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_354">
        <num>354</num>
        <heading>Sale of baby chicks and baby rabbits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 354. Sale of baby chicks and baby rabbits. 1. No person shall sell,\noffer for sale, barter or give away living baby chicks, ducklings or\nother fowl or baby rabbits unless such person provides proper brooder\nfacilities where appropriate for the care of such baby chicks, ducklings\nor other fowl or baby rabbits during the time they are in the possession\nof such person. For the purposes of this section, a baby rabbit shall be\na rabbit of less than two months of age.\n  2. No person shall sell, offer for sale, barter or display living baby\nchicks, ducklings or other fowl or baby rabbits which have been dyed,\ncolored or otherwise treated so as to impart to them an artificial\ncolor.\n  2-a. No provision of subdivision two shall be interpreted or applied\nto prevent or restrict teachers and qualified instructors of youth under\nthe guidance and supervision of the New York state cooperative extension\nservice from using eggs for non-profit educational purposes or from\nobserving fowl hatched from such eggs for non-profit educational\npurposes.\n  3. No person shall sell, offer for sale, barter or give away living\nbaby chicks, ducklings or other fowl or baby rabbits under two months of\nage in any quantity less than six.\n  4. A violation of the provisions of this section is a misdemeanor,\npunishable by imprisonment for not more than one year, or by a fine of\nnot more than five hundred dollars, or by both.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>