<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="359-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_359_A">
        <num>359-A</num>
        <heading>Transportation of horses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 359-a. Transportation of horses. 1. Every vehicle utilized for the\ntransportation of more than six horses shall meet the following\nrequirements:\n  a. The interiors of compartments containing horses shall be\nconstructed of smooth materials, containing no sharp objects or\nprotrusions which are hazardous;\n  b. The floors shall be of such construction or covered with abrasive\nmaterial so as to prevent horses from skidding or sliding;\n  c. There shall be sufficient apertures to insure adequate ventilation;\n  d. There shall be sufficient insulation or coverings to maintain an\nadequate temperature in the compartment containing horses;\n  e. Partitions of sturdy construction shall be placed a maximum of ten\nfeet apart in vehicles which do not have stalls;\n  f. Doorways shall be of sufficient height to allow safe ingress and\negress of each horse contained in the compartment;\n  g. Each compartment containing horses shall be of such height so as to\nallow sufficient clearance above the poll and withers of each horse in\nthe compartment;\n  h. Ramps sufficient for loading and unloading horses shall be provided\nif the vertical distance from the floor of the compartment containing\nhorses to the ground is greater than fifteen inches; and\n  i. There shall be at least two doorways for ingress and egress, which\nshall not be on the same side.\n  2. Every vehicle utilized for the transportation of more than six\nhorses over a highway shall have no more than one tier.\n  3. a. Transporting a horse in violation of this section shall be a\nviolation punishable by a fine of not more than two hundred fifty\ndollars.\n  b. Any subsequent violation of this section on a date following a\nconviction under the provisions of this section shall be a misdemeanor\npunishable by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars or\nimprisonment for not more than one year, or both.\n  4. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations, including\nsize specifications, and establish guidelines in order to facilitate\ncompliance with the provisions of this section.\n  5. a. The term "horse" as used throughout this section shall apply to\nthe entire family of equidae.\n  b. The term "vehicle" as used throughout this section shall apply to\nevery device in, upon, or by which any person or property is or may be\ntransported or drawn upon a highway, except devices moved by human power\nor used exclusively upon stationary rails or tracks.\n  6. The court in which a conviction under the provisions of this\nsection is obtained, shall, within thirty days of such conviction,\ntransmit a copy of the record of conviction to the department which\nshall maintain a record of such conviction for the purpose of\nidentifying subsequent violations of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>