<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="359"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-359/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_359">
        <num>359</num>
        <heading>Carrying animal in a cruel manner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 359. Carrying animal in a cruel manner. 1. A person who carries or\ncauses to be carried in or upon any vessel or vehicle or otherwise, any\nanimal in a cruel or inhuman manner, or so as to produce torture, is\nguilty of a misdemeanor, punishable by imprisonment for not more than\none year, or by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars, or by\nboth.\n  2. A railway corporation, or an owner, agent, consignee, or person in\ncharge of any horses, sheep, cattle, or swine, in the course of, or for\ntransportation, who confines, or causes or suffers the same to be\nconfined, in cars for a longer period than twenty-eight consecutive\nhours, or thirty-six consecutive hours where consent is given in the\nmanner hereinafter provided, without unloading for rest, water and\nfeeding, during five consecutive hours, unless prevented by storm or\ninevitable accident, is guilty of a misdemeanor. The consent which will\nextend the period from twenty-eight to thirty-six hours shall be given\nby the owner, or by person in custody of a particular shipment, by a\nwriting separate and apart from any printed bill of lading or other\nrailroad form. In estimating such confinement, the time during which the\nanimals have been confined without rest, on connecting roads from which\nthey are received, must be computed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>