<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-36-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-36-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="36-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-36-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-36-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-36-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-36-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_36_A">
        <num>36-A</num>
        <heading>Petition for revocation or modification of rule or order of the commissioner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 36-a. Petition for revocation or modification of rule or order of\nthe commissioner.  Any person subject to a rule or order of the\ncommissioner, promulgated under the provisions of article four, article\nfour-a, or article twenty-one of this chapter, may file a written\npetition with the commissioner stating that any such rule or order or\nprovision thereof or any obligation imposed in connection therewith is\nnot in accordance with law and praying for the revocation or\nmodification thereof. He shall thereupon be given an opportunity for a\nhearing and ruling upon such petition in accordance with the provisions\nof subdivision five of section thirty-six of this article. The decision\nof the commissioner shall be final unless within thirty days after its\nissuance one of the parties shall institute a proceeding for the review\nthereof, as provided in the next section, provided further that the\npendency of any such proceeding shall not impede or prevent the\ncommissioner from taking any action authorized under section thirty-five\nof this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>