<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-365"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-365"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="365"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-365/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-365/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-365/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-365/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_365">
        <num>365</num>
        <heading>Clipping or cutting the ears of dogs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 365. Clipping or cutting the ears of dogs. 1. Whoever clips or cuts\noff or causes or procures another to clip or cut off the whole or any\npart of an ear of any dog unless an anaesthetic shall have been given to\nthe dog and the operation performed by a licensed veterinarian, is\nguilty of a misdemeanor, punishable by imprisonment for not more than\none year, or a fine of not more than one thousand dollars, or by both.\n  2. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any dog or person\nwho is the owner or possessor of any dog whose ear or a part thereof has\nbeen clipped or cut off prior to September first, nineteen hundred\ntwenty-nine.\n  3. Each applicant for a dog license must state on such application\nwhether any ear of the dog for which he applies for such license has\nbeen cut off wholly or in part.\n  4. Nothing herein contained shall be construed as preventing any dog\nwhose ear or ears shall have been clipped or cut off wholly or in part,\nnot in violation of this section, from being imported into the state\nexclusively for breeding purposes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>