<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-366"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-366"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="366"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-366/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-366/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-366/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-366/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_366">
        <num>366</num>
        <heading>Companion animal stealing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 366. Companion animal stealing. It shall be unlawful for any person:\n  1. To remove or cause to be removed the collar, identification tag or\nany other identification by which the owner may be ascertained from any\ndog, cat or any other companion animal as defined in subdivision five of\nsection three hundred fifty of this chapter, or to entice any identified\ndog, cat or other such companion animal into or out of any house or\nenclosure for the purpose of removing its collar, tag or any other\nidentification, except with the owner's permission;\n  2. To entice, seize or molest any companion animal, while it is being\nheld or led by any person or while it is properly muzzled or wearing a\ncollar with an identification tag attached, except where such action is\nincidental to the enforcement of some law or regulation;\n  3. To transport any companion animal, not lawfully in his possession,\nfor the purpose of killing or selling such companion animal.\n  Any person violating any of the provisions of this section, upon\nconviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine not exceeding one\nthousand dollars, or by imprisonment not to exceed six months, or by\nboth.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>