<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-370"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-370"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="370"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-370/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-370/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-370/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-370/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_370">
        <num>370</num>
        <heading>Protection of the public from attack by wild animals and reptiles</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 370. Protection of the public from attack by wild animals and\nreptiles. Any person owning, possessing or harboring a wild animal or\nreptile capable of inflicting bodily harm upon a human being, who shall\nfail to exercise due care in safeguarding the public from attack by such\nwild animal or reptile, is guilty of a misdemeanor, punishable by\nimprisonment for not more than one year, or by a fine of not more than\nfive hundred dollars, or by both. "Wild animal" within the meaning of\nthis section, shall not include a dog or cat or other domestic animal.\n  Previous attacks upon a human being by such wild animal or reptile, or\nknowledge of the vicious propensities of such wild animal or reptile, on\nthe part of the possessor or harborer thereof, shall not be required to\nbe proven by the people upon a prosecution hereunder; and neither the\nfact that such wild animal or reptile has not previously attacked a\nhuman being, nor lack of knowledge of the vicious propensities of such\nwild animal or reptile on the part of the owner, possessor or harborer\nthereof shall constitute a defense to a prosecution hereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>