<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-383"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-383"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="383"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-383/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-383/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-383/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-383/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_383">
        <num>383</num>
        <heading>Examination of seized animals or animals taken possession of</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_383__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Check such animal for all forms of identification, including, but\nnot limited to, tags, microchips, tattoos or licenses; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_383__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If practicable and if the necessary technology and equipment are\navailable, for the purposes of this paragraph, make available to the\npublic on the internet on a website or social media maintained by or\notherwise made available to such officer, society, pound or shelter by\nthe municipal or county government in which such officer, society, pound\nor shelter is located, a photograph, and a general description of the\nanimal to assist the owner or owners in finding the animal, including\nthe breed or breeds, if known. Information about the animal may be\nwithheld if deemed appropriate to facilitate finding the owner or\notherwise protect the safety of the animal. The notice required by this\nparagraph may be made by means other than the internet if use of the\ninternet is impracticable.\n  2. No later than twenty-four hours or as soon as practicable after the\nseizure or taking possession of such animal potentially identifiable by\na form of identification, including a license, tag, tattoo or microchip,\nor records or reports that are readily available of animals reported to\nbe lost, reasonable efforts shall be made to identify and provide actual\nnotice to the owner of the animal by any means reasonably calculated to\nprovide actual notice to the owner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>