<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-385"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-385"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-04-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="385"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-385/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-385/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-385/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-385/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_385">
        <num>385</num>
        <heading>Prohibition of slaughtering horses for human or animal consumption</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_385__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "horseflesh" shall mean the flesh of a dead horse,\nincluding the animal's viscera, skin, hide, hooves, and bones; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_385__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "slaughter" shall mean the intentional killing, or having\nanother kill a horse if such person knows that the purpose of such\nkilling is using any part of such horse for human or animal consumption.\n  5. A violation of this section is a misdemeanor punishable by a fine\nof not more than one thousand dollars per horse for an individual\nperson, and up to two thousand five hundred dollars per horse for a\ncorporation, association, or other entity, for the first violation. Any\nsubsequent violation shall be punishable by a fine of up to two thousand\ndollars per horse for an individual person, and up to five thousand\ndollars per horse for a corporation, association, or other entity.\n  6. The provisions of this section shall be in addition to, and not in\nlieu of, any other laws protecting animal welfare. This section shall\nnot be construed to limit any state law or rules protecting the welfare\nof animals or to prevent a local governing body from adopting and\nenforcing its own animal welfare laws and regulations. Nothing in this\nsection shall prohibit a person from otherwise lawful disposition of a\ndeceased horse or any part of such horse.\n  7. If any provision of this section, or the application thereof to any\nperson or circumstances, is held invalid or unconstitutional, such\ninvalidity or unconstitutionality shall not affect other provisions or\napplications of this section that can be given effect without the\ninvalid or unconstitutional provision or application, and to such end\nthe provisions of this section shall be severable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>