<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-402"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-402"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="402"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_402">
        <num>402</num>
        <heading>Records of purchase and sale</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 402. Records of purchase and sale. Each pet dealer shall keep and\nmaintain records for each animal purchased, acquired, held, sold, or\notherwise disposed of. The records shall include the following:\n  1. The name and address of the person from whom each animal was\nacquired. If the person from whom the animal was obtained is a dealer\nlicensed by the United States department of agriculture, the person's\nname, address, and federal dealer identification number. If the person\nfrom whom the animal was obtained is a dealer licensed by the\ndepartment, the person's name, address, and state dealer identification\nnumber. In the case of cats, if a cat is placed in the custody or\npossession of the pet dealer and the source of origin is unknown, the\npet dealer shall state the source of origin as unknown, accompanied by\nthe date, time, and location of receipt. Notwithstanding the provisions\nof this subdivision, no pet dealer shall knowingly buy, sell, exhibit,\ntransport, or offer for sale, exhibition, or transportation any stolen\nanimal. No pet dealer shall knowingly sell any cat or dog younger than\neight weeks of age.\n  2. The original source of each animal if different than the person\nrecorded in subdivision one of this section.\n  3. The date each animal was acquired.\n  4. A description of each animal showing age, color, markings, sex,\nbreed, and any inoculation, worming, or other veterinary treatment or\nmedication information available. Records shall also include any other\nsignificant identification, if known, for each animal, including any\nofficial tag number, tattoo, or implant.\n  5. The name and address of the person to whom any animal is sold,\ngiven, or bartered or to whom it is otherwise transferred or delivered.\nThe records shall indicate the date and method of disposition.\n  6. Records for each animal shall be maintained for a period of two\nyears from the date of sale or transfer, whichever occurs later. During\nnormal business hours, the records shall be made available to persons\nauthorized by law to enforce the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>