<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-405"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-405"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="405"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_405">
        <num>405</num>
        <heading>Inspection of pet dealers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 405. Inspection of pet dealers. 1. The commissioner or his or her\nauthorized agents shall, at a minimum, make yearly inspections of pet\ndealers' facilities to ensure compliance with the provisions of this\narticle and with the provisions of article thirty-five-D of the general\nbusiness law, except for those pet dealers who engage in the sale of\nless than twenty-five animals in a year, in which case inspections shall\nbe made whenever in the discretion of the commissioner or his or her\nauthorized agents, a complaint warrants such investigation.\n  2. The commissioner may, pursuant to an agreement entered into with a\ncounty or city delegate the authority to conduct inspections of pet\ndealers and to respond to complaints concerning pet dealers to such\ncounty or city where the pet dealer is located; provided however such\ndelegation of inspection authority shall only be permitted where the\ncommissioner has delegated his or her authority to issue licenses\npursuant to section four hundred three of this article.\n  3. Any person conducting an inspection of a pet dealer or responding\nto a complaint concerning a pet dealer shall be specifically trained in\nthe proper care of cats and dogs and in the investigation and\nidentification of cruelty to animals.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>