<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-427"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-427"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="427"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-427/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-427/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-427/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-427/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_427">
        <num>427</num>
        <heading>Shelter management protocols</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 427. Shelter management protocols. 1. Each animal shelter shall have\na clear, written, management structure that defines staff authority,\nreporting structure and responsibilities, and is readily accessible to\nall staff and volunteers.\n  2. Staffing shall be sufficient to allow adequate time, per animal,\nfor cleaning and daily feeding, and to meet the minimum requirements for\nsocialization and exercise of animals as prescribed in section four\nhundred thirty of this article.\n  3. The total number of animals housed in an animal shelter facility or\nfoster home shall not exceed the number of housing units available at\nthe facility as required by section four hundred twenty-five of this\narticle; provided, however, that exceptions to the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall be permissible for periods not to exceed forty-five\ncontiguous days in the event of an animal seizure pursuant to article\ntwenty-six of this chapter or a natural disaster where an official\ndeclaration of the disaster or emergency has been made.\n  4. All animals shall be observed daily by a manager or designee to\nidentify each animal's needs for care, housing and service and to ensure\nthat each animal has a plan to advance efficiently through the shelter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>