<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-428"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-428"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="428"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-428/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-428/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-428/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-428/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_428">
        <num>428</num>
        <heading>Animal husbandry</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each animal shelter shall provide each\nanimal under its care with fresh, potable water at all times unless\notherwise directed by a duly licensed veterinarian.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each animal shelter shall feed each animal under its care a\ncomplete and nutritionally balanced, species-specific and\nlife-stage-appropriate diet as indicated by the animal's age, weight,\nand medical health, or as directed by a duly licensed veterinarian in\naccordance with the written protocols required by section four hundred\ntwenty-three of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Food shall be provided at least once daily for adult animals, at\nleast twice daily for animals less than six months of age, and at least\nthree times daily for animals less than two months of age.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Perishable animal food shall be refrigerated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Animal food and water containers shall be present in sufficient\nnumber and location to safely enable each animal in the enclosure to\naccess an adequate supply of food and water. Food and water bowls shall\nbe of the type that can be easily sanitized, be kept clean and shall be\ncleaned and disinfected prior to use by a different animal, unless\ndisposable bowls are used and replaced between animals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each animal shall be observed during or following each feeding\ntime to ensure daily food intake, or at least once every twenty-four\nhours for animals continually offered food. Such observations shall be\nrecorded.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Humane and safe physical restraint to limit some or all normal\nvoluntary movement of any animal in each animal shelter's care shall\nminimize fear, pain, stress and suffering for the animal, protect both\nthe animal and personnel from harm, and be of the least intensity and\nduration required to allow the specific procedure or procedures to be\nperformed properly.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Frightened or fractious animals may be appropriately\ntranquilized, under the orders and supervision of a duly licensed\nveterinarian, if they cannot be restrained safely and humanely.\n  (ii) No physical force shall be used as punishment or in anger.\n  (iii) Handling methods shall minimize the chance of escape and ensure\nthe safety of both humans and animals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Restraint devices and handling techniques employed by each animal\nshelter shall be used in a manner that minimizes animal stress and risk\nof injury to both animals and personnel, in the event such devices and\ntechniques are necessary for the safe handling of the animal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_428__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All equipment shall be maintained in good working order.\n  (ii) Cats shall not be restrained with control poles. Humane traps,\ncat boxes, nets, towels, or other equipment appropriate for handling\nfractious animals may be used. Squeeze cages, feral cat boxes, or humane\ntraps with dividers shall be used for restraining cats and administering\ntranquilizers prior to handling.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>