<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-43"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-43"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="43"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-43/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-43/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-43/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-43/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43">
        <num>43</num>
        <heading>Evidence</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 43. Evidence.  The doing of anything prohibited by this chapter\nshall be evidence of the violation of the provisions of this chapter\nrelating to the thing so prohibited, and the omission to do anything\ndirected to be done shall be evidence of a violation of the provisions\nof the chapter relative to the thing so directed to be done. The intent\nof any person doing or omitting to do any such act is immaterial in any\nprosecution for a violation of the provisions of this chapter.  Any\nperson who suffers, permits or allows any violation of the provisions of\nthis chapter in any room or building occupied or controlled by him,\nshall be guilty of such violation and liable accordingly. Any person who\nshall keep, store or display any article or product, the manufacture or\nsale of which is prohibited or regulated by this chapter, with other\nmerchandise or stock in his place of business, shall be deemed to have\nthe same in his possession for sale.\n  Every certificate, duly signed and acknowledged, of a chemist, analyst\nor other expert employed by the commissioner or any analysis,\nexamination or investigation made by such analyst, chemist or expert\nwith respect to any matter or product which the commissioner has\nauthority to examine or cause to be examined, shall be presumptive\nevidence of the facts therein stated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>