<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-432"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-432"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="432"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-432/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-432/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-432/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-432/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_432">
        <num>432</num>
        <heading>Foster care provider requirements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 432. Foster care provider requirements. 1. No person may operate as\na foster care provider in this state without first having signed a\nwritten agreement with an animal shelter licensed pursuant to this\narticle stating that such person may operate as a foster care provider\nwith the approval and under the responsibility of such animal shelter.\nSuch agreement shall be renewed not less than once every two years, and\na copy of such agreement shall be kept by both the animal shelter and\nfoster care provider and made available for inspection by the\ncommissioner upon request. It shall be the responsibility of the animal\nshelter entering into such agreement with any foster care provider\npursuant to this article to ensure that such foster care provider is\nable to responsibly harbor and provide necessary sustenance for any\nanimal placed in their care by such animal shelter in a manner that\npromotes the good health, safety and welfare of such animals. No animal\nshelter shall knowingly enter into any agreement pursuant to this\nsubdivision with any person who has been previously convicted of a\nviolation of any provision of article twenty-six of this chapter or\nregulations promulgated thereunder pertaining to humane treatment of\nanimals, cruelty to animals, endangering the life or health of an\nanimal, or violation of any federal, state, or local law pertaining to\nthe care, treatment, sale, possession, or handling of animals or any\nregulation or rule relating to the endangerment of the life or health of\nan animal.\n  2. Foster care providers may harbor animals owned by a licensed animal\nshelter but shall not own such animals and shall keep a copy of the\ncurrent record of each animal harbored under any agreement established\npursuant to subdivision one of this section. Such record shall be\nmaintained at the physical premises where such foster care providers\nharbor such animals. Animal shelters may, if appropriate to protect the\nidentity of the source of any animal, provide their foster care\nproviders with a partial animal record that excludes the name and\naddress of the organization or individual from whom such animal was\nobtained and the date of receipt, so long as such animal shelters keep a\ncopy of the complete record at the location where it maintains such\nrecords pursuant to section four hundred twenty-three of this article.\nIt is the responsibility of the animal shelter with which such foster\ncare provider has established an agreement pursuant to subdivision one\nof this section to ensure compliance with this subdivision.\n  3. Any animal harbored by a foster care provider pursuant to this\nsection that is affected by an infectious or contagious disease shall be\nhandled in a manner that prevents the spread of such disease in\naccordance with subdivision nine of section four hundred twenty-four of\nthis article. It shall be the responsibility of the animal shelter with\nwhich such foster care provider has established an agreement pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section to ensure compliance with this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>