<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-433"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-433"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="433"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-433/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-433/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-433/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-433/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_433">
        <num>433</num>
        <heading>Violations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_433__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection eighty-three hundred three of the civil practice law and rules,\nand direct restitution. Whenever the court shall determine that a\nviolation of this article has occurred, the court may impose a civil\npenalty of not less than one hundred dollars and not more than one\nthousand dollars. In connection with any such proposed application, the\nattorney general is authorized to take proof and make a determination of\nthe relevant facts and to issue subpoenas in accordance with the civil\npractice law and rules.\n  3. Any animal shelter that violates any provisions of this article\nshall correct such violations to the satisfaction of the commissioner\nwithin a period not to exceed ten days; provided, however, that where\nsuch violation poses a severe or immediate threat to public health or\nanimal safety or well-being, such violation shall be corrected to the\nsatisfaction of the commissioner within a period not to exceed\nseventy-two hours.\n  4. Nothing in this section shall preclude the commissioner from taking\nadditional actions to address violations related to the immediate threat\nto animal safety or well-being, including but not limited to, suspension\nof animal shelter operations until such violations are corrected to the\nsatisfaction of the commissioner.\n  5. Upon identification of one of more violations, the commissioner\nshall provide the animal shelter with a written description of all\nviolations issued and the steps necessary to correct such deficiencies.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>