<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-45-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-45-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="45-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-45-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-45-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-45-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-45-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_B">
        <num>45-B</num>
        <heading>Unauthorized possession, sale, or exchange of food order stamps issued under food stamp plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 45-b. Unauthorized possession, sale, or exchange of food order\nstamps issued under food stamp plan.  Any person, other than a person\nauthorized by the regulations and conditions prescribed by the secretary\nof agriculture of the United States governing the food stamp plan, who\nshall have in his possession, or who shall purchase sell or exchange any\nfood stamps, books, book covers or any other instruments or documents\nrelating to food stamps, for money or for any article or articles other\nthan those foods authorized by the regulations and conditions prescribed\nby the secretary of agriculture of the United States governing the food\nstamp plan, or for food the value of which is less than the face amount\nof such food stamps, or in any other manner in violation of the\nregulations and conditions prescribed by the secretary of agriculture of\nthe United States governing the food stamp plan, shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor. As used herein, the word "person" shall mean any\nindividual, partnership, corporation, or association, whether or not\nsuch individual, partnership, corporation or association is eligible to\nparticipate or is participating in the food stamp plan.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>