<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-46-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-46-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="46-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-46-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-46-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-46-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-46-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_46_A">
        <num>46-A</num>
        <heading>Regulations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 46-a. Regulations. The commissioner shall, after public hearing,\npromulgate definitions and standards for milk and milk products, and for\nproducts other than milk and milk products, which products are similar\nin appearance, odor or taste to milk and milk products, together with\nrules and regulations for the packaging and labeling of all such\nproducts, and other conditions relating to the manufacture, processing,\npackaging, distribution and sale of all such products including\nsanitation pertaining to manufacture, processing, handling,\ndistribution, surroundings, grounds, equipment, personnel and\npasteurization of such products. Such regulations shall apply to all\nsources including farms where such milk is produced. A copy of all such\nrules and regulations governing sanitation shall be provided to the\nstate commissioner of health fifteen days prior to the public hearing.\nThe commissioner is further empowered to promulgate rules and\nregulations by which milk may be standardized, including the plants at\nwhich such standardization may be done and may provide that\nstandardization may be done only at plants which are duly licensed and\nspecifically approved by the commissioner to perform such\nstandardization. The commissioner may provide in such rules and\nregulations for different standards and labeling for products\nmanufactured within the state and sold out of state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>