<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5">
        <num>5</num>
        <heading>Commissioner of agriculture and markets</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5. Commissioner of agriculture and markets.  The head of the\ndepartment of agriculture and markets shall be the commissioner of\nagriculture and markets, who shall be appointed by the governor, by and\nwith the advice and consent of the senate, and hold office until the end\nof the term of the governor by whom he was appointed, and until his\nsuccessor is appointed and has qualified.  He shall be a person\nqualified by training and experience for the duties of his office.\nSubject to removal by the governor, the commissioner of agriculture and\nmarkets in office at the time this section takes effect shall be the\nhead of the department of agriculture and markets and shall hold such\noffice until his successor is appointed and has qualified. In addition\nto the powers and duties specifically prescribed by this chapter, the\ncommissioner shall have supervision over and direction of all officers\nand employees and of the affairs of the department. He shall be\nresponsible for the enforcement and carrying into effect of the laws,\nrules and orders pertaining to matters as to which the department has\nfunctions, powers and duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>