<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_G">
        <num>50-G</num>
        <heading>Licenses to manufacturers of melloream</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-g. Licenses to manufacturers of melloream. 1. No person shall\nengage in the manufacture or production of melloream in the state of New\nYork or for sale or distribution in the state of New York unless duly\nlicensed as provided in this article or unless licensed as a milk dealer\npursuant to article twenty-one of the agriculture and markets law.\n  2. Application for a license shall be made upon a form prescribed by\nthe commissioner and shall include such facts concerning the applicant's\nstatus and operations as are deemed necessary by the commissioner for\nadministration of this article. A license shall be for a period not to\nexceed two years and a renewal of license must be duly made at least\nthirty days in advance of the expiration date. The license fee pursuant\nto this article for the license period for a person who is not otherwise\nlicensed as a milk dealer pursuant to article twenty-one of the\nagriculture and markets law shall be fifty dollars for each manufactory,\nplant or place where melloream is manufactured or produced.\n  3. No license issued pursuant to this article to a manufacturer of\nmelloream shall be denied or revoked unless the commissioner finds by a\npreponderance of evidence, after due notice and opportunity of a hearing\nto the applicant or licensee, that such person is not in compliance with\nor is in violation of any of the provisions of this article or\nregulations of the commissioner governing the manufacture and labeling\nof melloream.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>