<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_H">
        <num>50-H</num>
        <heading>Entry, inspection and investigation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-h. Entry, inspection and investigation. Any person designated for\nthe purpose shall have access to and may enter at all reasonable hours\nall places where melloream is being manufactured, packaged or stored for\nsale or distribution in the state of New York, where melloream is\notherwise being handled or sold in the state of New York, or where the\nbooks, papers, records or documents relating to such transactions are\nkept, and shall have power to inspect and copy the same, and may\nadminister oaths and take testimony for the purpose of ascertaining\nfacts which in the judgment of the commissioner are necessary to\nadminister this article. The commissioner may inspect a plant beyond the\nboundary of the state, and when he does, the applicant or licensee\nshall, prior to such inspection, agree to pay, in addition to the\nlicense fee provided pursuant to subdivision two of section fifty-g of\nthis article, fees for the inspection of the plant by the commissioner\nor his representatives. Such fees shall be twenty-five dollars for each\nday consisting of seven hours or part thereof during which an employee\nof the commissioner spends traveling to and from and inspecting the\nplant. In addition the applicant or licensee shall agree to pay all\nnecessary expenses including but not limited to expenses for traveling,\nlodging and meals. The commissioner may, if satisfied with the adequacy\nof inspection by some other regulatory agency, and if satisfied that\nthere is substantial compliance with the regulations of the\ncommissioner, forego actual inspection of such out-of-state plant or\nplants.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>