<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-50-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_I">
        <num>50-I</num>
        <heading>Labeling of melloream and vegetable oil blends</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-i. Labeling of melloream and vegetable oil blends. Whenever the\nbrand name of melloream or a vegetable oil blend, as defined in section\nfifty-f, appears on the container so conspicuously as to be seen under\ncustomary conditions of purchase, there shall immediately and\nconspicuously precede or follow the brand name or product designation\nwithout intervening written, printed or graphic matter in letters at\nleast one-third of the size of the brand name and on a contrasting\nbackground, any one of the following statements: "melloream," "a\nvegetable blend," "a vegetable oil product," "not a dairy product," and\nthe words "milk," "cream," "half and half," or "a mixture of milk and\ncream" shall not be used on the package label of melloream or vegetable\noil blends except to the extent that there shall also appear on the\nlabel an accurate list of ingredients. In the event that a product under\nthis section shall contain an ingredient which has been derived from\nmilk or a milk by-product or during its formation has used milk or a\nmilk by-product, the ingredient labeling shall after specifying the name\nof the ingredient, place in parentheses the words "milk derived".\n  Persons or corporations offering such products for sale shall upon\nrequest by the commissioner submit to him evidence in support of any\nnutritional claims made for such products through advertising, labeling\nor public announcement, and failure to submit such evidence or to revise\nsuch claims in the manner suggested by the commissioner shall be\npresumed to be a misbranding of said products within the meaning of\nsection two hundred one of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>