<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-10-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="500-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_500_C">
        <num>500-C</num>
        <heading>Granting, suspending or revoking licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 500-c. Granting, suspending or revoking licenses. The commissioner\nmay decline to grant a new license, may decline to renew a license, may\nsuspend or revoke a license already granted after due notice and\nopportunity for hearing whenever such commissioner finds that:\n  1. Any statement contained in an application for license is or was\nfalse or misleading;\n  2. The establishment does not have facilities or equipment sufficient\nto maintain adequate sanitation for the activities conducted;\n  3. The establishment is not maintained in a clean and sanitary\ncondition or is not operated in a sanitary or proper manner;\n  4. The maintenance and operation of the establishment is such that the\nproduct offered for sale or stored therein is or may be adulterated;\n  5. The establishment has failed or refused to produce any records or\nprovide any information demanded by the commissioner reasonably related\nto the administration and enforcement of this article;\n  6. The applicant or licensee, or an officer, director, partner, holder\nof ten percent of the voting stock, or any other person exercising any\nposition of management or control has failed to comply with any of the\nprovisions of this chapter or rules and regulations promulgated pursuant\nthereto; or\n  7. Any person including the applicant or licensee, or an officer,\ndirector, partner or any stockholder, exercising any position of\nmanagement or control has been convicted of a felony in any court of the\nUnited States or any state or territory.\n  * NB Effective February 13, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>