<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-10-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="500-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-500-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_500_F">
        <num>500-F</num>
        <heading>Sanitary inspections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 500-f. Sanitary inspections. 1. The department shall assign at\nleast one retail food specialist to each inspection zone. Such\nspecialists shall assist retail food stores, food service\nestablishments, and food warehouses in remedying chronic deficiencies\nand shall ensure that effective pest control and other sanitary measures\nare properly implemented.\n  2. Such specialists shall be given additional training to that\nnormally provided to sanitary inspectors to qualify them for their\nduties under this section, with particular emphasis on the problems\nunique to retail food stores, food service establishments, and food\nwarehouses and pest control measures.\n  3. The department shall inspect each retail food store at least once\nin every twelve-month period. Any store that fails two consecutive\ninspections shall be inspected at least once in every six-month period\nuntil it has passed two consecutive inspections.\n  4. In addition to any and all remedies provided in this article, in\nthe event that a retail food store fails three consecutive inspections,\nthe department may, in its discretion, order such establishment to cease\nall retail or wholesale operation until it passes inspection or suspend\nor revoke any license issued to such establishment.\n  5. Each retail food store and food service establishment shall post a\ncopy of the date and results of its most recent sanitary inspection by\nthe department in a conspicuous location near each public entrance, as\nprescribed by the commissioner. Such copies shall also be made available\nto the public upon request.\n  * NB Effective February 13, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>