<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-513"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-513"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-03-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="513"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_513">
        <num>513</num>
        <heading>Access to criminal history information through the division of criminal justice services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 513. Access to criminal history information through the division of\ncriminal justice services. In connection with the administration of this\narticle, the commissioner is authorized to request, receive and review\ncriminal history information through the division of criminal justice\nservices, referred to as "the division" for the purposes of this\nsection, with respect to any person seeking authorization under this\narticle to undertake a hemp pilot project or a hemp license; and/or each\nindividual who has substantial management responsibility for the\nauthorized or licensed activity or those in control of the entity,\nincluding principals, officers, or other such persons. Those persons for\nwhom criminal history information is sought shall promptly submit to the\ndivision his or her fingerprints in such form and in such manner as\nspecified by the division, for the purpose of conducting a search\nidentifying criminal convictions and pending criminal charges and\nreturning a report thereon in accordance with the procedures and\nrequirements established by the division pursuant to the provisions of\narticle thirty-five of the executive law, which shall include the\npayment of the specified processing fees for the cost of the division's\nfull search and retain procedures and a national criminal history record\ncheck for such information. The commissioner, or his or her designee,\nshall submit such fingerprints and the processing fee to the division.\nThe division shall forward to the commissioner a report with respect to\nthe person's previous criminal convictions and pending criminal charges,\nif any, or a statement that the person has no such previous criminal\nhistory according to its files. Fingerprints submitted to the division\npursuant to this section may also be submitted to the federal bureau of\ninvestigation for a national criminal history record check as described\nin this section. If additional copies of fingerprints are required, the\nperson to be fingerprinted shall furnish them upon request.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>