<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-520"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-520"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-02-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="520"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_520">
        <num>520</num>
        <heading>Hemp data collection and best farming practices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 520. Hemp data collection and best farming practices. 1. The\ncommissioner shall have the power to collect and publish data and\nresearch concerning, among other things, the growth, cultivation,\nproduction and processing methods of hemp and products derived from hemp\nand work with the New York state college of agriculture and life\nsciences at Cornell pursuant to section fifty-seven hundred twelve of\nthe education law and Cornell cooperative extension pursuant to section\ntwo hundred twenty-four of the county law to promote best farming\npractices for hemp which are compatible with state water quality and\nother environmental objectives.\n  2. The department, in conjunction with the department of environmental\nconservation, shall promulgate all necessary rules and regulations, as\nwell as a process for approval, governing the safe production of hemp,\nincluding, but not limited to, environmental and energy standards and\nrestrictions on the use of pesticides.\n  3. The department shall, to the extent practicable, share data and\ndocumentation related to an agricultural research pilot program with the\noffice of cannabis management.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>