<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-57-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-57-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="57-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-57-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-57-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-57-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-57-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_57_A">
        <num>57-A</num>
        <heading>Licensing of persons making bacterial counts of milk and/or cream or making tests of milk and/or cream to detect certain abnormalities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 57-a. Licensing of persons making bacterial counts of milk and/or\ncream or making tests of milk and/or cream to detect certain\nabnormalities. No person shall test milk and/or cream in order to\ndetermine the bacterial or leucocyte count or make other tests to\ndetermine the presence or absence of abnormal milk, where the results of\nsuch test affects the rate of payment to the producer for such milk\nand/or cream, the classification of milk and/or cream as received from\nthe producer, or the acceptance or rejection of such milk and/or cream\nby the operator of a milk-receiving or manufacturing plant, unless\nlicensed by the commissioner. Application for such license shall be made\nupon a form prescribed by the commissioner. The applicant shall furnish\nsatisfactory evidence of good moral character, and shall demonstrate his\nability to make such tests by an examination under the direction of the\ncommissioner. A license shall be for a period not exceeding five years.\nA license may be renewed in the discretion of the commissioner, without\nan examination, for successive periods of not exceeding five years each.\n  Each license shall be kept at the place where the licensee is engaged\nin testing milk and/or cream and shall be open to inspection.\n  A license may be revoked by the commissioner, after a hearing upon due\nnotice to the licensee, for dishonesty, incompetency, inaccuracy or a\nviolation of the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>