<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-61"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-61"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="61"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-61/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-61/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-61/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-61/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_61">
        <num>61</num>
        <heading>Manufacture, sale, and use of oleomargarine</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_61__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Person" means any person, firm, corporation, copartnership,\nassociation, co-operative corporation, or unincorporated co-operative\nassociation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Oleomargarine" or "margarine" means any oleaginous substance,\nsold or exposed for sale, as a substitute for, or to take the place of,\nor used for the same purpose or purposes as butter, or having the\nappearance, odor, or taste which is similar to butter, and which is not\nmade exclusively of milk or cream, or any substance into which any oil\nor fat other than that obtained from milk or cream has been introduced\nto take the place of butterfat. The terms include oleomargarine of any\nshade or color.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Public eating place" means any hotel, boarding house, restaurant,\nsaloon, lunch counter, place of public entertainment or any other place\nwhere prepared or cooked food is offered for sale to the public for\nconsumption on the premises. When a hotel or other establishment\noperates more than one public eating place, each such place shall be\ndeemed to be a separate public eating place. It shall be deemed to\ninclude camps, dude ranches, and other similar establishments operated\nfor profit even though restricted to a certain age, or other distinctive\ngroup, but shall not be deemed to include religious, charitable or\nprivate camps.\n  2. Fat standard. Oleomargarine manufactured, sold, offered or exposed\nfor sale shall contain not less than eighty per centum of fat.\n  3. Notice to consumers. Consumers shall be given notice of the use of\noleomargarine in public eating places under the following conditions and\nin the following manners.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If oleomargarine is served directly to the customer or is placed\non the table or counter where the customer is served notice of such\nserving shall be given.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If oleomargarine is served in such a manner that the customer\ncannot identify it, notice of such serving shall be given, provided,\nhowever, that use of oleomargarine in preparation of cooked or other\nfoods, in which the identity of the oleomargarine is lost, shall not\nrequire notice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Form of notice. Notice shall be given in such a manner that it is\nlikely to be seen and understood by each person being served. If the\npublic eating place is such that a single sign can be readily seen by\neach person being served, such sign shall be sufficient; otherwise\nnotice shall be given by signs so located that one can be seen by each\ncustomer, or by notice on menus given to each customer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Wording of notice. If oleomargarine is served on the tables or\ncounters where customers are served, the notice shall read as,\n"Oleomargarine served here" or "margarine served here", provided,\nhowever, that if the oleomargarine is not served or used in any other\nmanner notice may be given by a label on or accompanying the\noleomargarine and identifying it as such. If oleomargarine is served in\nother ways, the notice shall be the same as hereinabove provided, or may\nspecify the food or foods with which the oleomargarine is served.\n  4. Rules and regulations. The commissioner is authorized, after due\nnotice and hearing, to issue such rules and regulations as are necessary\nto carry out the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>