<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-63"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-63"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="63"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-63/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-63/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-63/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-63/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_63">
        <num>63</num>
        <heading>Labeling of imitation cheese; imitation cheese food and products containing imitation cheese</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 63. Labeling of imitation cheese; imitation cheese food and products\ncontaining imitation cheese. 1. Whenever the brand name or product\ndesignation of imitation cheese or imitation cheese food appears on a\npackage, the brand name or product designation, whichever is larger,\nshall be immediately preceded, without intervening printed or graphic\nmaterial by the word imitation and the name of the food imitated, in\nletters of the same color and on the same contrasting background and of\nequal size as the brand name or product designation, whichever is\nlarger.\n  2. On the label of any product containing imitation cheese or\nimitation cheese food, the product designation shall be immediately\npreceded or followed by the words "contains imitation cheese" or\n"contains imitation cheese food" whichever is appropriate, in letters of\nthe same color and on the same contrasting background and of equal size\nas the product designation.\n  3. Whenever imitation cheese or imitation cheese food is used in a\nproduct which is offered for sale for carry out or on premises\nconsumption, a sign shall be prominently posted at the place of sale\nwhich states the product designation of the food followed immediately by\nthe words "contains imitation cheese" or "contains imitation cheese\nfood," whichever is appropriate. The letters on such sign shall be in\nblock letters at least three inches in height and on a contrasting\nbackground which can be easily read by consumers under normal conditions\nof purchase.\n  4. Whenever any product which contains imitation cheese or imitation\ncheese food product is offered for sale on the menu of any service food\nestablishment, the product designation on such menu shall be immediately\nfollowed by the words "contains imitation cheese" or "contains imitation\ncheese food", whichever is appropriate, in letters of equal size and on\na contrasting background.\n  5. Whenever any imitation cheese or imitation cheese food product is\nplaced on the tables or otherwise made available for use by customers in\nany service food establishment, the container of such product shall be\nconspicuously labeled "imitation cheese", or "imitation cheese food\nproduct".\n  6. The commissioner shall promulgate such rules and regulations as are\nnecessary and appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section,\nincluding specific identification of imitation cheese and imitation\ncheese food.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>