<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_A">
        <num>71-A</num>
        <heading>Declaration of policy</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall, after public\nhearing, promulgate definitions and standards for frozen desserts\nincluding those made with dairy products, those not made with dairy\nproducts and those which are similar in appearance, odor or taste to\nsuch products or are prepared or frozen as frozen desserts are\ncustomarily prepared or frozen, together with rules and regulations for\nthe packaging and all labeling requirements for all such products, and\nother conditions relating to the wholesale manufacture, processing,\npackaging, distribution and sale at wholesale of all such products;\nincluding, but not limited to, sanitization pertaining to manufacture,\nprocessing, handling, distribution, buildings, grounds, equipment,\npersonnel and pasteurization or heat treatment of frozen desserts or\ningredients. No municipality or county may impose any regulation or\nstandard for frozen desserts different from those provided herein or by\nregulations promulgated hereunder. No municipality or county may require\nthe inspection of frozen dessert plants beyond its borders and shall\naccept the certification of the commissioner that such plants conform to\nthis act and the rules and regulations promulgated hereunder, unless\nthere is substantial reason to believe that a manufacturer of frozen\ndesserts, offered for sale in such county or municipality, is not in\nsubstantial compliance with the requirements of this article or the\nregulations promulgated pursuant thereto.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Following any hearing to consider definitions and standards or\nrules and regulations, pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subsection, the\ncommissioner shall issue a recommended decision and shall afford\ninterested parties an opportunity to file exceptions to such recommended\ndecision based upon the facts in the hearing record. After full\nconsideration has been given to such exceptions, a final decision shall\nbe made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall manufacture, distribute or sell in this state a\nfrozen dessert for which a definition and standard has not been\npromulgated pursuant to this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who desires to manufacture, distribute or sell in this\nstate, any frozen dessert for which a definition and standard has not\nbeen promulgated by the commissioner pursuant to this section, shall\nfirst make application to the commissioner for the promulgation of a\ndefinition and standard for such proposed frozen dessert. Such\napplication shall include the essential details of such proposed\ndefinition and standard. Upon the receipt of such an application, the\ncommissioner shall call a public hearing for the purpose of considering\nsuch proposed definition and standard. In determining whether or not\nsuch proposed definition and standard shall be promulgated, the\ncommissioner shall consider, among other things, the following:\n  1. Is the proposed product a frozen dessert as provided pursuant to\nthe provisions of subdivision two of this section?\n  2. Is the proposed frozen dessert substantially different from other\nfrozen desserts for which definitions and standards have already been\npromulgated by the commissioner?\n  3. Is it in the public interest to promulgate such proposed definition\nand standard?\n  4. Will the promulgation of such proposed definition and standard be\nadvantageous to consumers and not result in a lowering of health\nstandards or promote fraud and deception?\nFollowing the hearing to consider any such proposed definition and\nstandard, the commissioner shall issue a recommended decision as\nprovided pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of this section,\neither adopting, modifying, or denying the proposed definition and\nstandard, giving interested parties an opportunity to file exceptions,\nwithin thirty days, to such recommended decision based upon the facts in\nthe hearing record, and after full consideration has been given to any\nsuch exceptions, a final decision shall be made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>