<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_B">
        <num>71-B</num>
        <heading>Application for license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 71-b. Application for license. 1. Every wholesale manufacturer of\nfrozen desserts produced for sale, and every person who sells, offers or\nexposes for sale, or has or possesses for sale other than exclusively at\nretail, any frozen dessert, shall, not later than the first day of\nFebruary of every other year, file with the commissioner an application\nfor a license upon a form prescribed by the commissioner, which\napplication shall state such facts concerning the applicant's\ncircumstances and the nature of business to be conducted as in the\nopinion of the commissioner are necessary for the administration of this\narticle. The license period shall be for twenty-four months, beginning\nMarch first following.\n  2. The application of a manufacturer must show that the frozen\ndesserts to be manufactured by the applicant are to be composed of pure\nand wholesome ingredients and are to be produced under sanitary\nconditions.  The application shall also show the location of each plant\nat which frozen desserts are to be manufactured, and the name of the\nbrand or brands, if any, under which the same are to be sold.\n  3. This section shall not apply to any boarding house in respect to\nfrozen desserts manufactured by such boarding house and served to the\npatrons thereof for consumption on the premises where manufactured, nor\nto a person, other than a manufacturer, who sells, offers or exposes for\nsale, or has on hand with intent to sell exclusively at retail, any\nfrozen dessert.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>