<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-71-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_D">
        <num>71-D</num>
        <heading>Issuance of License</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 71-d. Issuance of License. No license shall be granted unless the\ncommissioner is satisfied that the applicant is qualified by character\nand experience, and is equipped to conduct the proposed business\nproperly. Prior to the issuance of a license to manufacture frozen\ndesserts, to satisfy himself that the applicant is equipped to conduct\nthe proposed business properly, as required in this section, and at any\nother time when, in his discretion, he shall deem such action necessary,\nthe commissioner may inspect the plant and equipment of the applicant.\nThe commissioner may enter into and effectuate reciprocal agreements\nwith other states, covering regulation and inspection of frozen dessert\nplants, as will insure inhabitants of this state frozen desserts\nsubstantially complying with the requirements herein enacted or\npromulgated in rules and regulations hereunder and as part of such\nagreements may approve or accept inspections and regulation of other\nstates covering frozen desserts plants. The commissioner may inspect a\nplant beyond the boundary of the state, and when he does, the applicant\nshall, prior to such inspection, pay by certified check, bank check,\ndomestic or international money order in funds of the United States, in\naddition to the license fee set forth in section seventy-one-c of this\narticle, fees for inspection of the plant by the department. Such fees\nshall include expenses for all time during which an employee of the\ndepartment spends traveling to and from and inspecting the plant. In\naddition, the applicant shall pay all necessary and reasonable expenses\nincurred in making such inspection, including, but not limited to,\nexpenses for traveling, lodging and meals and the inspector's salary,\nincluding fringe benefits, and overtime if applicable. The commissioner,\nif satisfied with the qualifications of the applicant as stated in this\nsection and if satisfied that the equipment, the vehicles used for\ntransporting frozen desserts and the premises named in the application\nand used by the applicant for the manufacture, storage or sale of frozen\ndesserts are maintained in accordance with the standards of sanitation\nprescribed in the rules and regulations promulgated under the authority\nof this article, shall issue a license for the handling of frozen\ndesserts. No license shall be issued if any statement in the application\nis false or misleading, or if the brand name or any label or\nadvertisement of the frozen dessert involved in the application gives a\nfalse indication of origin, character, composition or place of\nmanufacture, or is otherwise false or misleading in any particular.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>