<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-72-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-72-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-72-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-72-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-72-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-72-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_A">
        <num>72-A</num>
        <heading>Feeding of garbage, offal or carcasses to cattle, swine or poultry prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 72-a. Feeding of garbage, offal or carcasses to cattle, swine or\npoultry prohibited.  1. Garbage fed to cattle, swine or poultry\ncontributes to the spread of vesicular exanthema, cholera, erysipelas,\nfoot and mouth disease, trichinosis and other infectious animal\ndiseases. Meat from animals so afflicted, when consumed by human beings,\nis a primary source of trichinosis and other human sickness. It is\ntherefore declared to be the public policy of this state to prohibit the\nfeeding of garbage, offal or carcasses to cattle, swine or poultry to\nassist in the eradication of animal diseases and for the protection of\nthe public health and public welfare.\n  2. Definitions. When used in this section:\n  a. "Garbage" means putrescible animal and poultry wastes from the\nhandling, processing, preparation, cooking and consumption of foods.\n  b. "Offal" means the waste parts of butchered animals or poultry.\n  c. "Carcasses" means the dead bodies of animals or poultry.\n  d. "Person" means any individual, firm, partnership, public or private\ncorporation, public or private institution, public authority, municipal\ncorporation and the state.\n  e. Notwithstanding anything in the preceding paragraphs of this\nsubdivision to the contrary, animal feeds which have been heat rendered\nby a rendering plant at a temperature sufficient to make the product\ncommercially sterile shall not be considered garbage, offal or carcasses\nwithin the meaning of this section.\n  3. a. It shall be unlawful for any person to feed garbage, offal, or\ncarcasses, whether cooked or uncooked, to cattle, swine or poultry.\n  b. This section shall not apply to any individual who feeds garbage\nfrom his own household only, to cattle, swine or poultry on his own\npremises.\n  c. Violation of this section shall constitute a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>