<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-74"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-74"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="74"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-74/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-74/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-74/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-74/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_74">
        <num>74</num>
        <heading>Regulations relating to importation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 74. Regulations relating to importation.  The following regulations\nshall apply to the importation of domestic or feral animals:\n  1. No person shall knowingly bring into this state any domestic or\nferal animal which has an infectious or communicable disease, except in\nthe case of pure bred registered bovine animals which have been removed\nfrom this state and have reacted to the tuberculin or other recognized\ntest subsequent to such removal, may be returned to this state upon\nwritten permission from the commissioner subject to such rules as he may\nprescribe in relation thereto.\n  2. Any person bringing into this state domestic or feral animals for\nany purpose other than immediate slaughter without taking precaution to\nascertain whether such animals have an infectious or communicable\ndisease shall be presumed to have brought them in knowingly in violation\nof this section, if they are found to have such disease.\n  3. Animals received from outside the state under the supervision of\nthe United States department of agriculture or the department of\nagriculture and markets of the state of New York, or for which a permit\nor certificate shall have been issued by either of such departments,\nshall be deemed to have been handled with due precaution.\n  4. Any person importing or bringing into this state meat cattle for\ndairy or breeding purposes shall report immediately upon bringing such\ncattle into the state to the department, in writing, stating the number\nof cattle thus brought in, the places where they were procured, the\nlines over which they were brought, their destination within the state\nand when they arrive thereat; and if there be filed with the department\nat the time of filing such report or within ten days thereafter, a\ncertificate by a duly authorized veterinary practitioner approved by the\nauthorities of the state in which he resides or by an authorized\nveterinary inspector of the United States bureau of animal industry to\nthe effect that he has duly examined such animals and that they are free\nfrom any infectious or communicable disease, the commissioner may issue\na permit to such person to remove such cattle immediately. Otherwise\nsuch person shall detain such animals at the point of destination for at\nleast twenty days for inspection or examination by the commissioner or\nhis duly authorized agent. The provisions of this subdivision relating\nto advance reports to the department shall not apply to cattle imported\ninto this state at a point where there is federal inspection.\n  5. Persons bringing into this state or receiving domestic or feral\nanimals from without the state shall give such other information to the\ndepartment as it may from time to time request relating to such animals.\n  6. The commissioner may order all or any animals coming into the state\nto be detained at any place or places for inspection and examination,\nand if any of them after due examintion be found affected with any\ninfectious or communicable disease, such animals shall be condemned and\nslaughtered or held in strict quarantine.\n  7. Each animal brought into the state in violation of any of the\nprovisions of this article shall constitute a separate and distinct\nviolation.\n  8. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to prevent or\nmake unlawful the transportation of domestic or feral animals through\nthis state on railroads or boats.\n  9. The commissioner is hereby authorized, after public hearing, to\nadopt and promulgate rules and regulations to implement and give full\neffect to the provisions of this section, including rules and\nregulations requiring a permit for the importation of domestic or feral\nanimals into the state.\n  10. For the purposes of this section, a feral animal shall mean an\nundomesticated or wild animal.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>