<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-75"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-75"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-75/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-75/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-75/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-75/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75">
        <num>75</num>
        <heading>Sanitary regulations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 75. Sanitary regulations.  The commissioner may adopt and enforce\nrules regulating the sanitation and physical requirements of stables,\nlivestock auction buildings or other buildings used for the housing of\ndomestic animals for the purpose of preventing the spread of infection\nand contagion among such animals and may provide for the inspection and\nexamination of such stables and buildings. The commissioner may adopt\nand enforce rules concerning the equipment for and the method of the\nsanitary production of milk and may provide for the examination and\nscoring of dairies in accordance with such rules. He may also prescribe\nsuch rules as may be necessary for disinfecting and cleaning premises,\nbuildings, railway cars, boats and other objects, from or by means of\nwhich infection or contagion of animals may be spread or conveyed.\nVehicles used for the transportation of livestock shall be cleaned and\ndisinfected at least weekly, or as otherwise directed by the\ncommissioner, with a disinfectant approved by the commissioner.\nVehicles used by a farmer in transporting his own livestock need not be\ncleaned and disinfected as prescribed by the preceding sentence unless\ndirected by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>