<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-79"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-79"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="79"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-79/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-79/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-79/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-79/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_79">
        <num>79</num>
        <heading>Examination at request of owner; segregation; grading of herds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 79. Examination at request of owner; segregation; grading of herds.\nThe owner of a herd of cattle kept for dairy or breeding purposes within\nthe state may apply to the commissioner for examination of his herd by\nthe tuberculin, or other approved tests, subject to the following\nregulations:\n  1. The application therefor shall be upon a blank form provided by the\ncommissioner and shall include an agreement on the part of the owner of\nthe herd to improve faulty sanitary conditions, to disinfect his\npremises if diseased cattle be found, and to follow directions of the\ncommissioner designed to prevent the reinfection of the herd and to\nsuppress the disease and prevent the spread thereof.\n  2. The commissioner shall cause such cattle to be examined\naccordingly, subject to the provisions of this article, and if any\nanimal responds to such test, he may cause it to be slaughtered or held\nin strict quarantine.\n  3. If after examination an animal be found to be suffering from\ntuberculosis such animal shall be slaughtered under the provisions of\nthis article, or the commissioner may enter into a written agreement\nwith the owner for keeping such animal in segregation or the\ncommissioner may, if the condition of such animal warrants it, consign\nsuch animal to any one of the experiment stations or farms owned or\ncontrolled by the state, or by any county of the state, or to the farms\nof such public institutions in the state as the commissioner shall\napprove, or to hospitals, sanitariums or other institutions existing in\nwhole or in part for the purpose of suppressing tuberculosis, there to\nbe kept and used for breeding, dairy or experimental purposes under\nregulations to be prescribed by the commissioner.\n  4. Subject to the rules of the commissioner, an animal found to be\ndiseased after such examination may continue to be used for breeding\npurposes, but the milk from such animal shall not be used for any\npurpose until pasteurized at such temperature and for such period as the\ncommissioner may prescribe.\n  5. The young of any such diseased animal shall immediately be\nseparated from its mother and shall not be permitted to receive or be\nfed the milk from such affected animal until such milk has been\npasteurized as provided in subdivision four of this section.\n  6. The commissioner may make rules for classifying herds tested under\nthis section and for the purpose of giving recognition to herds which\nare in a healthy condition, he is hereby authorized to issue such\ncertification as he may deem proper in relation to such herds.  If such\nrules and such certification provide for periodical retests of\naccredited herds, or other herds not yet accredited, the cost of such\nretests, after January first, nineteen hundred and thirty, shall be\nborne by the state and there shall be appropriated annually to the\ndepartment a sum sufficient to defray the expense of the veterinary\nservice for such required retests.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>