<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8">
        <num>8</num>
        <heading>Counsel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8. Counsel.  There shall be a counsel of the department to be\nappointed by the commissioner and who shall serve during the pleasure of\nthe commissioner. The counsel of the department shall represent and\nappear for the department in all actions and proceedings involving any\nquestion under this chapter or within the jurisdiction of the department\nunder any general or special law or under or in reference to any act,\norder or proceeding of or before the commissioner, and shall, when\ndirected, intervene, if possible, in behalf of the department in any\naction or proceeding involving or relating to any matter within the\njurisdiction or powers of the department as herein prescribed, except\nthat the attorney-general of the state shall continue to have direct\ncharge of and bring such actions as he may deem necessary for any and\nall violations of this chapter.  The said counsel shall, also, act as\ncounsel for any officer of the department in the conduct of a hearing,\ninvestigation or inquiry instituted under authority of the department or\nas provided in this chapter. He shall advise the commissioner or any\nofficer of the department, when so requested, in regard to all matters\nin connection with their powers and duties, and perform generally all\nduties and services as counsel of the department which may reasonably be\nrequired of him.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>