<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-83"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-83"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="83"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-83/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-83/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-83/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-83/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_83">
        <num>83</num>
        <heading>Appraisal of diseased animals</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 83. Appraisal of diseased animals.  Each animal directed to be\nslaughtered shall be appraised at its market value. The appraiser shall\nmake and transmit to the commissioner a certificate of appraisal and\nshall deliver to the owner a copy of such appraisal certificate. If the\nowner is dissatisfied with the amount of the appraisal he may, within\nten days after the delivery of the copy of appraisal certificate, make\nwritten application to the commissioner for a review of the appraisal.\nUpon receipt of such application, the commissioner shall cause an\ninvestigation to be made as to the market value of the animals referred\nto in the application for a review.  Upon completion of such\ninvestigation, the commissioner shall render a decision either\nconfirming the appraisal or modifying it by an increase or a decrease of\nthe amount of the appraisal as justice may require, and shall state in\nhis decision the reasons therefor and shall transmit a copy of the\ndecision to the owner. The decision of the commissioner may be reviewed\nby a proceeding under article eight of the civil practice law and rules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>