<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-87"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-87"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="87"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-87/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-87/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-87/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-87/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_87">
        <num>87</num>
        <heading>Payments for animals killed</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 87. Payments for animals killed.  The commissioner shall determine\nall claims which may be presented to him for indemnity to owners of\nanimals killed by the state under the provisions of this article, and\nshall file in his office a certificate of his determination and,\nprovided the claim is determined complete, shall within five days of\nhaving received the claim, issue his order for the amount due to the\ncomptroller for payment. All claims allowed shall bear interest computed\nas provided in section one hundred seventy-nine-g of the state finance\nlaw. A claim shall be considered an invoice within the meaning of the\nprovisions of article eleven-A of the state finance law. Anyone having a\nright of reimbursement pursuant to the provisions of this article shall\nbe deemed to be a "contractor" having a "contract" with a "state agency"\nas such terms are defined in section one hundred seventy-nine-e of the\nstate finance law. The commissioner shall issue his order for the amount\ndue as determined by the certificate, which amount shall be paid from\nthe treasury, on the warrant of the comptroller, out of moneys\nappropriated therefor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>