<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-08-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="90-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_90_B">
        <num>90-B</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 90-b. Definitions. As used in this article unless otherwise\nexpressly stated:\n  1. The term "auctioneer" means a person who sells, or makes a business\nof selling cattle, swine, sheep, goats, camelids or horses, at auction.\n  2. The term "auction" means a public sale of cattle, swine, sheep,\ngoats, camelids or horses.\n  3. The term "cattle" means the entire family of bovidae.\n  4. The term "camelid" means the entire family of camelidae.\n  5. The term "cervid" means any member of the family of cervidae.\n  6. The term "dealer" means any person who buys and sells cattle,\nhorses, swine, cervids, camelids, poultry, goats, or sheep as a business\nenterprise. The term shall not include persons who buy and sell such\nanimals as part of a bona fide breeding, feeding or farming operation,\nor receive such animals exclusively for slaughter on their own premises,\nor purchase or sell horses either as part of a bona fide riding or\nracing operation or for their own personal use.\n  7. The term "goat" means any member of the genus capra.\n  8. The term "horse" means the entire family of equidae.\n  9. The term "live poultry market" means any premises where poultry are\nassembled and held for sale and slaughter. It does not include livestock\nauction buildings.\n  10. The term "official backtag" means a unique, tamper-resistant\ndevice approved by the United States department of agriculture, which,\nwhen affixed to cattle, cervid, swine or camelid, identifies and\ndistinguishes animals that shall be moved directly to slaughter.\n  11. The term "official ear tag" means a unique, tamper-resistant\ndevice approved by the United States department of agriculture, which,\nwhen affixed to the ears of cattle, cervid, swine, sheep, goat, or\ncamelid, identifies and distinguishes such animals.\n  12. The term "poultry" means a domesticated fowl including chickens,\nturkeys, waterfowl, guinea fowl and game birds commonly used for the\nproduction of meat and eggs. It does not include pigeons.\n  13. The term "poultry transporter" or "transporter of poultry" means\nany person who transports poultry or otherwise moves poultry to a live\nmarket.\n  14. The term "registration number" means the number assigned to and\nthat identifies a particular domestic animal, where such number and the\nidentifying characteristics of such domestic animal are set forth in a\nregistry maintained by a breed association recognized by the department.\n  15. The term "rescue" means the action by a person that accepts\ncattle, swine, horses, sheep, goats, cervids, or camelids from any\nsource and attempts to find permanent homes through adoption, transfer,\nsale, lease, sponsorship, or gift of such livestock.\n  16. The term "sheep" means any member of the genus ovis.\n  17. The term "swine" means the entire super family of suidoidae.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>