<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-08-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="90-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-90-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_90_E">
        <num>90-E</num>
        <heading>Refusing and revoking permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 90-e. Refusing and revoking permits. The commissioner, after due\nnotice and opportunity of hearing to the applicant or permittee, may\ndeny an application for or revoke or refuse to renew a permit when the\ncommissioner is satisfied that the applicant or permittee has:\n  1. violated the statutes of the state of New York or of the United\nStates or the official regulations of the commissioner governing the\ninterstate or intrastate movement, shipment or transportation of cattle\nor horses, swine, camelids, cervids, sheep, goats or poultry;\n  2. made false or misleading statements in their application for an\nanimal health permit or has made false or misleading statements as to\nthe health or physical condition of cattle, horses, swine, camelids,\ncervids, sheep, goats or poultry; regarding official tests;\n  3. knowingly sold for purposes other than slaughter cattle, horses,\nswine, camelids, cervids, sheep, goats or poultry which were affected\nwith a communicable disease;\n  4. failed to observe sanitary measures in barning, stabling premises\nor vehicles used for the stabling, holding or transportation of cattle,\nhorses, swine, camelids, cervids, sheep, goats or poultry;\n  5. engaged in a course of dealing of such a nature as to satisfy the\ncommissioner of their inability or unwillingness properly to conduct the\nbusiness for which an animal health permit has been issued;\n  6. been convicted of a felony;\n  7. had their animal health permit terminated or revoked;\n  8. ceased to operate the business for which the animal health permit\nwas issued; or\n  9. failed to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter or the\nrules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>