<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-91"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-91"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="91"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-91/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-91/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-91/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-91/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_91">
        <num>91</num>
        <heading>Hog cholera and pseudorabies control; indemnity</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 91. Hog cholera and pseudorabies control; indemnity.  1. The\ncommissioner, to control, suppress or eradicate hog cholera and\npseudorabies, may cause to be made appropriate examinations or tests for\nascertaining the presence or absence of such diseases in swine.  If,\nfrom such examinations or tests, any swine be found to be infected with\nor exposed to hog cholera or pseudorabies and such condition be such as\nto cause the swine to be a menace to the health of other animals the\ncommissioner may order such swine to be immediately slaughtered or\notherwise disposed of as he may prescribe.\n  2. No swine infected with or exposed to hog cholera or pseudorabies\nshall be sold or removed from the premises where examined, or from any\nother premises, except upon written permission of the commissioner.  No\nswine so infected or exposed shall be slaughtered or killed except under\nthe supervision of the commissioner.\n  3. The commissioner, within the appropriation for such purpose, may\ncause blood samples of swine to be taken and tested.\n  4. Swine killed on account of hog cholera or pseudorabies shall be\nappraised and indemnity shall be paid to the owner as provided in this\narticle, except as otherwise specifically limited by this section. The\nowner shall be entitled to receive the net proceeds, if any, of the sale\nof the swine, and in addition thereto, within the appropriation for such\npurpose, shall be paid indemnity in a sum not exceeding one hundred\ndollars for a registered purebred, inbred or hybrid swine, and not\nexceeding forty dollars for any other swine. A purebred swine is any\nbreeding swine upon which a certificate of pure breeding has been issued\nby a purebred swine association; an inbred or hybrid swine is any\nbreeding swine upon which a certificate or registration has been issued\nby a recognized inbred or hybrid registry association. Certificates of\npure breeding or registration for inbred or hybrid swine shall be\npresented at the time of appraisal or such swine will be appraised as\ngrades, provided, however, that in the absence of such certificates or\nregistrations the commissioner may grant a reasonable time for the\npresentation of such certificates or registrations to the appraiser.\nThe total amount receivable by the owner from the net proceeds of the\nsale of the swine and indemnity from the federal government and\nindemnity from the state shall, in every case, except as otherwise\nspecifically limited by this section, equal but not exceed the full\nappraised value of the swine.\n  5. The commissioner may adopt and enforce rules and regulations, and\nmay cooperate with the authorities of the United States government and\nwith local officials, to implement the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>