<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="96-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_E">
        <num>96-E</num>
        <heading>Unlawful acts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 96-e. Unlawful acts. 1. It shall be unlawful for any person, firm,\npartnership or corporation to operate any slaughterhouse, abattoir or\nother place or establishment where animals or fowl are slaughtered or\nwhere meat or meat food products are prepared or processed for food\nunless such place or establishment is maintained and operated in a clean\nand sanitary manner, and conducted in accordance with the provisions of\nthis article and with the regulations of the commissioner.\n  2. It shall be unlawful to expose any meat, fowl or meat food product\nin any slaughterhouse, abattoir or other place or establishment to\ninsects, live animals or injurious contamination; or to slaughter,\npossess or sell unwholesome meat. Meat shall be unwholesome within the\nmeaning of this article if it be from a diseased animal or one which\nshall have died other than by slaughter, or if such meat shall be\ncontaminated with filth or shall have been slaughtered, processed or\nhandled under insanitary conditions.\n  3. It shall be unlawful to feed hogs uncooked offal from a\nslaughterhouse.\n  4. It shall be unlawful for any slaughterhouse, abattoir or other\nplace or establishment, or for any person, to slaughter or butcher\ndomesticated dog (canis familiaris) or domesticated cat (felis catus or\ndomesticus) to create food, meat or meat products for human or animal\nconsumption. A violation of this subdivision shall subject the offender\nto a civil penalty of up to one thousand dollars for an individual and\nup to five thousand dollars for a corporation for the first violation.\nAny subsequent violation shall be subject to a civil penalty of up to\ntwenty-five thousand dollars. Any civil penalties collected pursuant to\nthis subdivision shall be paid to the animal population control fund\nestablished by section ninety-seven-xx of the state finance law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>