<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-P-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-P-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="96-P-2"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-P-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-P-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-P-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-P-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_P_2">
        <num>96-P-2</num>
        <heading>Mishandling and improper transportation of meat, meat by-products and meat food products</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 96-p-2. Mishandling and improper transportation of meat, meat\nby-products and meat food products. (1) No person, firm, association,\npartnership or corporation engaged in carrying or transporting meat,\nmeat by-products or meat food products shall transport such products\nexcept in an enclosed vehicle in such a manner as to assure delivery of\nthe aforesaid products so that frozen products remain frozen and such\nother products do not rise above forty degrees Fahrenheit, provided,\nhowever, that this section shall not apply to establishments engaging in\nmeat handling operations at retail stores and restaurants, when\nconducted at any retail store or restaurant or similar retail-type\nestablishment for sale in normal retail quantities or service of such\narticles to consumers at such establishments, nor to household\nconsumers. This section shall not apply to meat food products which\nbecause of their method of manufacture, processing, and packaging,\nrequire no special handling temperatures to prevent adulteration or\nunwholesomeness including, but not limited to, commercially sterile meat\nfood products in hermetically sealed containers.\n  (2) The commissioner may promulgate rules and regulations to further\ndefine standards for the transportation of meat, meat by-products or\nmeat food products to further ensure that they are delivered in an\nunadulterated and wholesome condition.\n  (3) A violation of the provisions of this section shall be a violation\nas defined in subdivision three of section 10.00 of the penal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>