<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="AGM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-X"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-X"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="96-X"/>
          <FRBRname value="AGM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/agm/section-96-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_X">
        <num>96-X</num>
        <heading>Declaration of policy and purposes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 96-x. Declaration of policy and purposes.  The use as food of meat\nor meat products derived from dead, dying, disabled, diseased or\ncondemned animals endangers the health and welfare of the people of the\nstate. The powers of seizure, quarantine and condemnation held and\nexercised by the department tend to suppress but do not constitute\nadequate controls to prevent such adulterated and unfit meat and meat\nproducts from being sold for consumption. It is hereby declared to be a\nmatter of legislative determination that regulation and supervision of\nthose who deal in, handle, transport, process or dispose of such animals\nand the products therefrom are needed in the public interest, and that\nin the exercise of the police power such persons be required to be\nlicensed before engaging in such activities and that such activities be\nregulated and supervised. The general purpose of this article is to\nprotect the public health, safety and welfare by controlling the use,\nmovement and disposition of dead, dying, disabled, diseased, or\ncondemned animals, and the meat and meat products derived therefrom.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>