<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1002"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1002"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-09-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1002"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1002">
        <num>1002</num>
        <heading>Combative sports prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1002. Combative sports prohibited. 1. The conduct of combative\nsports outside the supervision of the commission or an authorized\nsanctioning entity is prohibited.\n  2. A person advances a prohibited combative sport when, acting other\nthan as a spectator, he or she engages in conduct which materially aids\nany unauthorized combative sport. Such conduct includes but is not\nlimited to conduct directed toward the creation, establishment or\nperformance of a prohibited combative sport, toward the acquisition or\nmaintenance of premises, paraphernalia, equipment or apparatus therefor,\ntoward the solicitation or inducement of persons to attend or\nparticipate therein, toward the actual conduct of the performance\nthereof, toward the arrangement of any of its financial or promotional\nphases, or toward any other phase of a prohibited combative sport. One\nadvances a prohibited combative sport when, having substantial\nproprietary or other authoritative control over premises being used with\nhis or her knowledge for purposes of a prohibited combative sport, he or\nshe permits such to occur or continue or makes no effort to prevent its\noccurrence or continuation.\n  3. A person profits from a prohibited combative sport when he or she\naccepts or receives money or other property with intent to participate\nin the proceeds of a prohibited combative sport, or pursuant to an\nagreement or understanding with any person whereby he or she\nparticipates or is to participate in the proceeds of a prohibited\ncombative sport.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>