<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1003"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1003"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1003"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1003">
        <num>1003</num>
        <heading>State athletic commission</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1003. State athletic commission. 1. The state athletic commission,\nas named by chapter nine hundred twelve of the laws of nineteen hundred\ntwenty, as amended by chapter six hundred three of the laws of nineteen\nhundred eighty-one, is continued as a division of the department of\nstate. The commission shall act in the best interests of combative\nsports. The commission is enacted to protect the health, safety and\ngeneral welfare of all participants in combative sports and spectators\nthereof, to preserve the integrity of combative sports through the means\nof licensing, oversight, enforcement and the authorization of\nsanctioning entities, and to facilitate the development and responsible\nconduct of combative sports throughout the entire state. The commission\nshall consist of five members who shall be appointed by the governor by\nand with the advice and consent of the senate. The governor shall\ndesignate one of the members as chairperson of the commission. The\nmembers of the commission shall be appointed for terms of three years.\nAny vacancy in the membership of the commission caused otherwise than by\nexpiration of term shall be filled only for the balance of the term of\nthe member in whose position the vacancy occurs.\n  2. The commissioners shall be paid their actual and necessary\ntraveling and other expenses incurred by them in the performance of\ntheir official duties. The members of the commission shall adopt a seal\nfor the commission, and make such rules for the administration of their\noffice, not inconsistent herewith, as they may deem expedient; and they\nmay amend or abrogate such rules. Three of the members of the commission\nshall constitute a quorum to do business; and the concurrence of a\nmajority of the commissioners present shall be necessary to render a\ndetermination by the commission. The commission is vested with the\nauthority to adopt such rules and regulations as necessary to effectuate\nthe provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>