<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1008"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1008"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-09-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1008"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1008/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1008/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1008/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1008/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1008">
        <num>1008</num>
        <heading>Licenses; judges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1008. Licenses; judges. 1. Except as otherwise provided in sections\none thousand six and one thousand seventeen of this article, only a\nperson licensed by the commission, as a combative sports judge, may\njudge an authorized professional combative sport within the state.\nJudges for any authorized professional combative sport under the\njurisdiction of the commission shall be selected by the commission from\na list of qualified licensed judges maintained by the commission.\n  2. Any participant in a professional combative sport or his or her\nmanager may protest the assignment of a judge to a contest and the\nparticipant or manager may be heard by the commission or its designee if\nsuch protest is timely. If the protest is untimely it shall be summarily\nrejected.\n  3. Each person seeking to be licensed as a judge by the commission\nshall be required to submit to or provide proof of an eye examination\nand annually thereafter on the anniversary of the issuance of the\nlicense.  The commission shall establish continuing education programs\nand requirements to be completed by licensed judges. Each judge must be\ncertified as having completed a training program as approved by the\ncommission and shall pass an examination approved by the commission.\n  4. Each person seeking a license to judge authorized professional\ncombative sports in the state shall be required to fill out a financial\nquestionnaire certifying under penalty of perjury full disclosure of the\njudge's financial situation on a questionnaire to be promulgated by the\ncommission. Such questionnaire shall be in a form and manner approved by\nthe commission and shall provide information as to areas of actual or\npotential conflict of interest as well as appearances of such conflicts,\nincluding financial responsibility. Within forty-eight hours of any\nmatch, each judge of a professional combative sport shall file with the\ncommission a financial disclosure statement in such form and manner as\nshall be acceptable to the commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>