<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1010"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1010"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-09-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1010"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1010/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1010/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1010/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1010/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1010">
        <num>1010</num>
        <heading>Licenses; professionals</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1010. Licenses; professionals. 1. Except as otherwise provided in\nsections one thousand six, one thousand eleven and one thousand\nseventeen of this article, only persons licensed by the commission shall\ncompete in authorized professional combative sports.\n  2. Any professional applying for a license or renewal of a license to\nparticipate in combative sports under this article shall undergo a\ncomprehensive physical examination including clinical neurological\nexaminations by a physician approved by the commission. If, at the time\nof such examination, there is any indication of brain injury, or for any\nother reason the physician deems it appropriate, the professional shall\nbe required to undergo further neurological examinations by a\nneurologist including magnetic resonance imaging or other medically\nequivalent procedures. The commission shall not issue a license to a\nprofessional until such examinations are completed and reviewed by the\ncommission. The results of all such examinations herein required shall\nbecome a part of the professional's permanent medical record as\nmaintained by the commission. The costs of all such examinations shall\nbe assumed by the applicant or promoter with which the professional is\naffiliated, regardless of provider.\n  3. Any professional licensed under this article shall, as a condition\nof licensure, waive right of confidentiality of medical records relating\nto treatment of any physical condition which relates to his or her\nability to fight. All medical reports submitted to, and all medical\nrecords of the medical advisory board or the commission relative to the\nphysical examination or condition of professionals shall be considered\nconfidential, and shall be open to examination only to the commission or\nits authorized representative, to the licensed professional or manager\nupon written application to examine said records, or upon the order of a\ncourt of competent jurisdiction in an appropriate case.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>