<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1018"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1018"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-09-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1018"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1018/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1018/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1018/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1018/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1018">
        <num>1018</num>
        <heading>Prohibited conduct</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1018. Prohibited conduct. 1. No corporation or person shall have,\neither directly or indirectly, any financial interest in a professional\nboxer competing on premises owned or leased by the corporation or\nperson, or in which such corporation or person is otherwise interested\nexcept pursuant to the specific written authorization of the commission.\n  2. No contestant in a boxing or sparring match or exhibition shall be\npaid for services before the contest, and should it be determined by the\ncommission that such contestant did not give an honest exhibition of his\nor her skill, such services shall not be paid for.\n  3. Any person, including any corporation and the officers thereof, any\nphysician, referee, judge, timekeeper, professional, manager, trainer or\nsecond, who shall promote, conduct, give or participate in any sham or\ncollusive authorized professional combative sports, shall be deprived of\nhis or her license by the commission and any other appropriate legal\nremedies.\n  4. No licensed promoter or matchmaker shall knowingly engage in a\ncourse of conduct in which fights are arranged where one professional\nhas skills or experience significantly in excess of the other\nprofessional so that a mismatch results with the potential of physical\nharm to the professional.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>