<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1021"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1021"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-09-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1021"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1021/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1021/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1021/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-1021/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1021">
        <num>1021</num>
        <heading>Exceptions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1021. Exceptions. The provisions of this article except as provided\nin subdivision twelve of section one thousand fifteen of this article\nshall not be construed to apply to any sparring or boxing contest or\nexhibition conducted under the supervision or the control of the New\nYork state national guard or naval militia where all of the contestants\nare members of the active militia; nor to any such contest or exhibition\nwhere the contestants are all amateurs, sponsored by and under the\nsupervision of any university, college, school or other institution of\nlearning, recognized by the regents of the state of New York; nor to any\nbusiness entity incorporated for the purposes of providing instruction\nand evaluation in a combative sport to customers for the purposes of\nhealth and fitness, personal development, self-defense or participation\nin amateur events conducted by an authorized sanctioning entity; nor to\nany such contest or exhibitions where the contestants are all amateurs\nsponsored by and under the supervision of the American Olympic\nAssociation or, in the case of boxing, the U.S. Amateur Boxing\nFederation or its local affiliates or the American Olympic Association;\nnor except as to the extent provided otherwise in this article, to any\nprofessional wrestling contest or exhibition as defined in this article.\nAny individual, association, corporation or club, except elementary or\nhigh schools or equivalent institutions of learning recognized by the\nregents of the state of New York, who or which conducts an amateur\ncontest pursuant to this section must register with the U. S. Amateur\nBoxing Federation or its local affiliates and abide by its rules and\nregulations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>