<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-116"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-116"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="116"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_116">
        <num>116</num>
        <heading>Redemption of unused passage tickets</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 116. Redemption of unused passage tickets.  Every person who shall\nhave purchased a passage ticket from an authorized agent of a railroad\ncompany, which shall not have been used, or shall have been used only in\npart, may, within thirty days after the date of the sale of said ticket,\npresent the same, unused or partly used, for redemption, at the general\noffice of the railroad company which issued said ticket, or at the\nticket office where said ticket was sold, or at the ticket office at the\npoint to which the ticket has been used.  If said ticket wholly unused,\nshall be presented for redemption at the ticket office where sold, the\nsame shall be then and there redeemed by the agent in charge of said\nticket office at the price paid for said ticket. If said ticket, partly\nused, shall be presented for redemption at the ticket office where sold,\nor at the ticket office at the point to which used, the ticket agent at\neither of said offices, upon delivery of said ticket, shall issue to the\nholder thereof a receipt, properly describing said ticket and setting\nforth the date of the receipt of said ticket, and the name of the person\nfrom whom received, and shall thereupon forthwith transmit said ticket\nfor redemption to the general office. It shall be the duty of every\nrailroad company to redeem tickets presented for redemption, as in this\nsection provided for promptly and within not to exceed thirty days from\nthe date of presentation at the general office or from the date of the\naforesaid receipt. A wholly unused ticket shall be redeemed at the price\npaid therefor. A partly used ticket shall be redeemed at a rate which\nshall be equal to the difference between the price paid for the whole\nticket and the cost of a ticket of the same class between the points for\nwhich said ticket was actually used. Mileage books shall be redeemed\nwithin thirty days after the date of the expiration thereof in the same\nmanner. Provided, however, that nothing herein contained shall be deemed\nto prohibit the requirement by tariff of advance notice of cancellation\nas a condition to the redemption or use of passage tickets in connection\nwith which reserve accommodations have been obtained; provided, further,\nthat nothing herein contained shall be deemed to prohibit the\nestablishment by tariff of a service charge for the redemption of wholly\nunused or partly used tickets. Every railroad company which shall\nwrongfully refuse redemption, as in this section provided for, shall\nforfeit to the aggrieved party fifty dollars, which sum may be\nrecovered, together with the amount of redemption money to which the\nparty is entitled, in an action in any court of competent jurisdiction,\ntogether with costs; but no such action can be maintained unless\ncommenced within one year after the cause of action accrued.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>