<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-131"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-131"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131">
        <num>131</num>
        <heading>Ownership of merchandise establishments and services to be publicly revealed and displayed</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131. Ownership of merchandise establishments and services to be\npublicly revealed and displayed.  Every person, partnership, association\nor corporation owning or conducting any shop, store or other\nestablishment or service wherein the sale of merchandise at retail or\nwholesale is carried on or transacted or a service is performed as a\nbusiness shall cause the true, full name, including the full first name\nor legally registered trade name or names of the proprietor or owner or\nproprietors or owners of such shop, store or other establishment or\nservice to be publicly revealed and prominently and legibly displayed in\nthe English language either upon a window of such shop, store or other\nestablishment or place where a service is performed or upon a sign\nconspicuously placed upon the exterior of the building containing the\nsame. The foregoing provisions shall not apply to a person, partnership,\nassociation or corporation operating under a lease, a department in a\nshop, store or other establishment or service as aforesaid where the\nlessor of such shop, store or other establishment or service is liable\nto customers for merchandise sold by and the operations of such leased\ndepartment. Failure to comply with the provisions of this section shall\nconstitute a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>