<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-138"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-138"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="138"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-138/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-138/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-138/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-138/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_138">
        <num>138</num>
        <heading>Use of certain governmental, military or naval names</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 138. Use of certain governmental, military or naval names. 1. It\nshall be unlawful and is prohibited for any person, firm, corporation or\nassociation, not an agency or instrumentality of the United States\ngovernment, selling or offering for sale goods, wares or merchandise, to\nuse or cause or permit to be used in the corporate or trade name or\ndescription of the seller or of the place where the goods, wares or\nmerchandise are offered for sale, any of the following words or\nexpressions, viz., "army," "navy," "marine corps," "marines," "coast\nguard," "government," "post exchange," "P. X.," or "G. I.," unless there\nis displayed in conjunction therewith, in letters of at least the same\nsize as such words or expressions, the words, "we sell articles acquired\nfrom the United States government only," or "we sell both articles\nacquired from the United States government and non-government articles,"\nas the case may be.\n  2. No person, firm, corporation or association selling or offering for\nsale any article of merchandise, shall in any manner represent, contrary\nto fact, that the article was made for, or acquired directly or\nindirectly from, the United States government or its military or naval\nforces or any agency of the United States government, or that the\narticle conforms to government specifications or requirements, or that\nit has been disposed of by the United States government.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>