<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-14"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-14"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14">
        <num>14</num>
        <heading>Processions and parades on Sunday</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14. Processions and parades on Sunday. 1. All processions and\nparades on Sunday in any city, excepting only funeral processions for\nthe actual burial of the dead, and processions to and from a place of\nworship in connection with a religious service there celebrated, are\nforbidden; and in such excepted cases there shall be no music,\nfireworks, discharge of cannon or firearms, or other disturbing noise.\nAt a military funeral, or at the funeral of a United States soldier,\nsailor or marine, or of a national guardsman, or of a deceased member of\nan association of veteran soldiers, sailors or marines, or of a\ndisbanded militia regiment, or of a secret fraternal society, or of an\nassociation of employees of the national, state, or municipal\ngovernments, music may be played while escorting the body; also in\npatriotic military processions on Sunday previous to Decoration day,\nknown as memorial Sunday, to cemeteries or other places where memorial\nservices are held, and also by organizations of the national guard or\nnaval militia or of an association of employees of the national, state,\nor municipal governments, attending religious service on Sunday; but in\nno case within one block of a place of worship where service is then\nbeing celebrated. Music may also be played in any procession conducted\nby a religious organization or society in connection with a religious\nservice or religious rally after one o'clock noon on Sunday.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, it shall be lawful\nto conduct, witness, participate or engage in processions or parades and\nto play music in any such procession or parade on Sunday after two\no'clock in the afternoon, in a city, town or village, as shall be\npermitted by a local law or ordinance heretofore or hereafter adopted by\nthe common council or other legislative body of a city, town or village\npermitting such processions and parades on such day and after such hour.\n  3. This section shall not apply to a city with a population of one\nmillion or more; provided, however, that if a parade or procession is\nheld in such city on Sunday before two o'clock in the afternoon there\nshall be no music, fireworks, discharge of cannon or firearms, or other\ndisturbing noise in relation thereto within one hundred and fifty feet\nof a place of worship.\n  4. A person wilfully violating any provision of this section is\npunishable by a fine not exceeding twenty dollars or imprisonment not\nexceeding ten days, or by both.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>