<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-141"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-141"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="141"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-141/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-141/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-141/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-141/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_141">
        <num>141</num>
        <heading>Unlawful use of the name United Nations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 141. Unlawful use of the name United Nations. No person, firm or\ncorporation shall, without express authority from the secretary general\nof the United Nations, assume, adopt or use as, or as a part of a\ncorporate, assumed or trade name, for advertising purposes, or for the\npurposes of trade, or for any other purpose, the name United Nations, or\nabbreviation thereof; or any official emblem or other official insignia\nthereof; nor shall any person, firm or corporation, with intent to\ndeceive or mislead the public, for any of such purposes, assume, adopt\nor use any name, designation or style, or simulation thereof, or\ndesignation or style, or simulation thereof, which may deceive or\nmislead the public as to the true identity of such person, firm or\ncorporation or as to the official connection of such person, firm or\ncorporation with the United Nations.  A violation of this section shall\nbe a misdemeanor. Whenever there shall be an actual or threatened\nviolation of this section, an application may be made to a court or\njustice having jurisdiction to issue an injunction, upon notice to the\ndefendant of not less than five days, to enjoin and restrain such actual\nor threatened violation; and if it shall appear to the satisfaction of\nthe court or justice that the defendant is in fact, assuming, adopting\nor using such name, or is about to assume, adopt or use such name, and\nthat the assumption, adoption or use of such name was not expressly\nauthorized by the secretary general of the United Nations, and may\ndeceive or mislead the public, an injunction may be issued by such court\nor justice, enjoining and restraining such actual or threatened\nviolation without requiring proof that any person has in fact been\ndeceived or mislead thereby. This section shall not prevent the\ncontinued use of a corporate name or trade name heretofore lawfully\nused.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>