<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-143"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-143"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="143"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-143/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-143/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-143/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-143/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_143">
        <num>143</num>
        <heading>False identification documents</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 143. False identification documents. 1. As used in this section,\n"false identification document" means any document, including a personal\nidentification card, which is of a type intended or commonly used or\naccepted for the purpose of identification of individuals and which is\nnot issued by or under the lawful authority of the named or indicated\nissuer. "False identification document" shall also include a personal\nidentification document intended or commonly used or accepted for the\npurpose of identification which resembles or is intended to resemble one\nissued by the named or indicated issuer even though that issuer may be\nfictitious.\n  2. No person, firm or corporation shall produce, advertise, offer for\nsale, sell, distribute or otherwise transfer in this state any false\npersonal identification document unless such document bears the word\n"NOVELTY" diagonally printed clearly and indelibly on both the front and\nback of such document in capital letters in not less than twelve point\ntype.\n  3. Whenever there shall be a violation of this section, an application\nmay be made by the attorney general in the name of the people of the\nstate of New York or by the corporation counsel for any city or by an\nattorney properly designated by the governing body to represent any\nother political subdivision, to a court or justice having jurisdiction\nby a special proceeding to issue an injunction, and upon notice to the\nrespondent of not less than five days, to enjoin and restrain the\ncontinuance of such violations; and if it shall appear to the\nsatisfaction of the court or justice that the respondent has, in fact,\nviolated this section, an injunction may be issued by such court or\njustice, enjoining and restraining any further violation, without\nrequiring proof that any person has, in fact, been injured or damaged\nthereby.  Whenever the court shall determine that a violation of this\nsection has occurred, the court may impose a civil penalty of not more\nthan five hundred dollars for each violation. In connection with any\nsuch proposed application, the attorney general, corporation counsel or\nother properly designated attorney, as the case may be, is authorized to\ntake proof and make a determination of the relevant facts and to issue\nsubpoenas in accordance with the civil practice law and rules. Each sale\nof a false identification document shall constitute a separate and\ndistinct violation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>