<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-158"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-158"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="158"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-158/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-158/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-158/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-158/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_158">
        <num>158</num>
        <heading>Prohibited practices by travel consultants</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 158. Prohibited practices by travel consultants. It shall be illegal\nfor any travel consultant and, if such travel consultant is a\ncorporation, any officer or director thereof, to engage in any or all of\nthe following enumerated practices:\n  1. Knowingly misrepresent the quality or kind of service, type or size\nof aircraft, vehicle, ship or train, time of departure or arrival,\npoints served, route to be traveled, stops to be made, or total\ntrip-time from point of departure to destination or other services\navailable, reserved or contracted for in connection with any trip or\ntour.\n  2. Knowingly misrepresent the fares and charges for transportation or\nservices in connection therewith.\n  3. Knowingly advertise or otherwise offer for sale or sell\ntransportation or services in connection therewith at less than the\nrates, fares and charges specified in the currently effective tariffs of\nthe carrier, who is engaged to provide such transportation or services,\nor knowingly offer or give rebates or other concessions thereon, or\nknowingly assist or permit a person or persons to obtain such\ntransportation or services at less than such lawful rates, fares and\ncharges.\n  4. Knowingly misrepresent that special priorities for reservations are\navailable when such special considerations are not in fact granted to\nmembers of the public generally.\n  5. Knowingly sell transportation to a person or persons on a\nreservation or charter basis for specified space, flight or time or\nknowingly represent that such definite reservation or charter is or will\nbe available or has been arranged, without a binding commitment with a\ncarrier for the furnishing of such definite reservation or charter as\nrepresented or sold.\n  6. Knowingly sell or issue tickets or other documents to passengers to\nbe exchanged or used for transportation if such tickets or other\ndocuments will not be or cannot be legally honored by carriers for\ntransportation.\n  7. Knowingly misrepresent the requirements that must be met by a\nperson or persons in order to qualify for charter or group fare rates.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>