<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-176"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-176"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="176"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_176">
        <num>176</num>
        <heading>Assignment or transfer of license; change of location; additional locations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 176. Assignment or transfer of license; change of location;\nadditional locations. A license granted as provided in this article\nshall not be valid for any person other than the person to whom it is\nissued or any place other than that designated in the license and shall\nnot be assigned or transferred without the consent of the commissioner.\nApplications for such consent shall be made in the same manner as an\napplication for a license, and all the provisions of sections one\nhundred seventy-three and one hundred seventy-four shall apply to\napplications for such consent. The location of an employment agency\nshall not be changed without the consent of the commissioner, and such\nchange of location shall be indorsed upon the license. A person who has\nobtained an employment agency license in accordance with the provisions\nof this article, may apply for an additional license to conduct an\nadditional employment agency, in accordance with the provisions of\nsection one hundred seventy-three. The manner of application, and the\nconditions and terms applicable to the issuance of such license shall be\nthe same as for an initial or original license except that the said\nlicense shall not extend beyond the termination date of the original\nlicense.  An additional bond shall be furnished to the commissioner\nissuing the additional license, and the terms of said bond shall be such\nas to make it payable as well to the people of the state of New York or\nof the city of New York, as the case may be.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>