<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-179"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-179"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="179"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_179">
        <num>179</num>
        <heading>Registers and other records to be kept</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 179. Registers and other records to be kept. It shall be the duty of\nevery licensed person to keep a register, approved by the commissioner,\nin which shall be entered, in the English language, the date of the\napplication for employment, the date the applicant started work and the\nname and address of every applicant from whom a fee or deposit is\ncharged, the amount of the fee or deposit and the service for which it\nis received or charged. Such licensed person shall also enter in the\nsame or in a separate register, approved by the commissioner, in the\nEnglish language, the name and address of every employer from whom a fee\nis received or charged or to whom the licensed person refers an\napplicant who has paid or is charged a fee, the date of such employer's\nrequest or assent that applicants be furnished, the kind of position for\nwhich applicants are requested, the names of the applicants sent from\nwhom a fee or deposit is received or charged with the designation of the\none employed, the amount of the fee or deposit charged, and the rate of\nsalary or wages agreed upon. It shall also be the duty of every licensed\nperson to keep complete and accurate written records in the English\nlanguage of all receipts and income received or derived directly from\nthe operation of his employment agency, and to keep records concerning\njob orders. No such licensed person, his agent or employees, shall make\nany false entry in such records. It shall be the duty of every licensed\nperson to communicate orally or in writing with at least one of the\npersons mentioned as references for every applicant for work in private\nfamilies, or employed in a fiduciary capacity, and the result of such\ninvestigation shall be kept on file in such agency for a period of at\nleast three years. Every register and all records kept pursuant to the\nrequirements of this article shall be retained on the premises of the\nagency concerned for three years following the date on which the last\nentry thereon was made.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>