<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-182"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-182"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="182"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-182/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-182/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-182/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-182/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_182">
        <num>182</num>
        <heading>Cards to be furnished nurses; registry records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 182. Cards to be furnished nurses; registry records. A nurses'\nregistry shall send out to practice nursing only persons duly licensed\npursuant to article one hundred thirty-nine of the education law as a\nregistered professional nurse or licensed practical nurse. Every nurses'\nregistry, before sending a person out to practice nursing, shall\ninvestigate such person's educational qualifications and verify such\nperson's licensure and current registration. At least two current\nwritten references shall be required of such person.  The record of such\ninvestigation and verification shall be kept on file in the registry.\n  Every nurses' registry that sends out any such person shall at such\ntime give to such person and send to the employer of such person a card\nstating (1) such person's name, address and salary, (2) whether such\nperson is a registered professional nurse or licensed practical nurse,\n(3) the number of the current registration certificate issued to such\nperson by the education department, and (4) a statement that the record\nof such person's educational qualifications and experience in the\npractice of nursing is on file in such registry and that a copy thereof\nwill be sent to such employer on request. A copy of such card shall be\nkept on file in the registry.\n  The record of investigation and verification and the card-copy\nrequired by this section to be kept on file shall be open to inspection\nby any duly authorized agent of the university of the state of New York,\nand every nurses' registry shall furnish a complete list of its\nregistrants on request of such agent.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>