<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-184-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-184-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="184-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-184-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-184-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-184-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-184-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_184_A">
        <num>184-A</num>
        <heading>Recruitment of domestic or household employees from outside the continental United States</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has become\ndisabled and is unable to continue work as evidenced by a certificate\nfrom a doctor designated by the consulate of the country of his\nnationality; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is in financial distress and wishes to return to\nthe country from which he came, the agency shall provide return fare and\na reasonable allowance for meals while traveling.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the employee is hospitalized within ninety days after arrival,\nand the employee is in financial distress and unable to meet the cost of\nhospitalization, the agency shall be responsible for reasonable\nhospitalization costs incurred during such ninety-day period, provided,\nhowever, that this responsibility shall be deemed to be met if the\nagency provides a basic twenty-one day hospitalization insurance policy\napproved by the commissioner. This provision shall in no way prevent an\nagency from requiring the employer to agree to provide the same basic\ntwenty-one day hospitalization insurance policy for the employee, but\nthe employee may not be required to pay the premium for such policy\ncovering the first ninety days. Any person or organization damaged by\nthe failure of an agency to comply with this paragraph or with\nparagraphs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this subdivision may bring an action on the\nagency bond as provided in this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Comply with all of the applicable laws and regulations of the\ncountry from which the employee is recruited.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If prior to the arrival of the employee in the United States,\neither the employee or the employer cancels the employment agreement,\nthe agency shall notify in writing the central immigration office of the\nNew York state department of labor within ten days of receiving notice\nof the cancellation.\n  4. Fees and disbursements. a. Circumstances permitting fees. Such\nagency shall not charge or accept a fee or other consideration unless in\naccordance with the terms of a written contract, the form of which has\nbeen approved by the commissioner, and unless the agency has been\nresponsible for the employment of the employee.\n  b. Maximum fee.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The total maximum fee that such agency may charge\nfor any placement shall not exceed eleven percent of the employee's\nagreed or anticipated first full year's wages, and of this total maximum\nfee not more than twenty-five percent may be charged the employee.\nNothing herein shall be construed as prohibiting an agency from making\nan agreement with an employer under which the employer agrees to pay the\ntotal maximum fee provided by this subdivision, but in such event, no\nfee shall be charged the employee.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the agreement between the employer and employee provides for an\nadditional wage payment on completion of the contract of employment, and\nif such additional payment is payable to the employee on a monthly\npro-rata basis in the event that the employment terminates for any\nreason before the completion of the contract, such additional payment\nmay be considered part of the employee's first full year's wages.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an employee is provided meals or lodging, the value of such\nmeals or lodging shall not be included in determining the employee's\nfirst full year's wages.\n  c. Deposits or advance fee. An agency may require an employer to pay a\ndeposit or advance the fee before an employee is employed, and such\ndeposit or advance shall be offset against the fee charged the employer.\n  d. Employer's cancellation fee. The agency shall be entitled to a fee\nfrom the employer not exceeding twenty-five dollars if the employer\ncancels his job order before the acceptance of the job offer by the\nemployee. If the cancellation occurs after such acceptance and before\ncertification for noncitizen employment by the appropriate governmental\nagency, the fee shall not exceed fifty dollars. If the cancellation\noccurs after such acceptance and after such certification, the fee shall\nnot exceed seventy-five dollars. No cancellation fee, however, shall be\npayable if within a reasonable time after the employ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision\nof this section, if the employment terminates for any reason within\nninety days, the following fees may be charged the employer and may be\ncharged the employee:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fifty percent of the maximum fee provided by paragraph b of this\nsubdivision, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the employment terminates after thirty days, an additional fee\ncomputed by prorating the remaining fifty percent of the maximum fee on\nthe basis of the number of days worked during such sixty-day period.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If after termination, subsequent placements are made by the agency\nto such employer or of such employee, the total termination fees payable\nby such employer and such employee shall not exceed the maximum fees\nprovided by paragraph b of this subdivision for the initial placement.\n  g. Subsequent placement with another employer. If employment\nterminates within ninety days and the agency is responsible for the\nplacement of the employee with another employer within such ninety-day\nperiod, the maximum fee that the agency may charge for such subsequent\nplacement shall be the fee provided by paragraph b of this subdivision.\nIf such subsequent placement is made after such ninety-day period, the\nfee provisions of section one hundred eighty-five of this article shall\napply to such placement, notwithstanding subdivision two of this\nsection.\n  h. Employee's refusal of employment. Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of this section, if the employee after arrival in this\ncountry, refu...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the last home address and birth\ndate of all applicants for employment who were recruited by the agency;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name and address of the emigrant agent, if any, through whom\nsuch applicant was obtained;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the fee, if any, paid to the emigrant\nagent by the agency, job applicant or employer which shall be separately\nstated;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the charges or advances made to the job applicant for agency\nfee, transportation and visa fee, and such charges or advances shall be\nseparately listed and the total indicated; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the manner in which\nthe employee's age and references were confirmed.\n  7. Recordkeeping. Such agency shall retain for inspection:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>copies\nof all forms prepared or received on behalf of an employee and submitted\nto any governmental agency in connection with immigration requirements;\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_184_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>copies of executed contracts between the agency and the employer\nand between the agency and the employee. The copies shall be retained on\nthe premises of the agency for three years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>