<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-185"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-185"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="185"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-185/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-185/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-185/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-185/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_185">
        <num>185</num>
        <heading>Fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_185__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>after an agency has been responsible for\nreferring an artist to an employer or such employer to an artist and\nwhere as a result thereof such artist has been employed by such\nemployer; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_185__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>after an agency represents an artist in the negotiation\nor renegotiation of an original or pre-existing employment contract and\nwhere as a result thereof the artist enters into a negotiated or\nrenegotiated employment contract. For class "C" employment pursuant to\nthis paragraph, an employment agency shall provide an artist with a\nstatement setting forth in a clear and concise manner the provisions of\nthis section and section one hundred eighty-six of this article.\n  The maximum fees provided for herein for all types of placements or\nemployment may be charged to the job applicant and a similar fee may be\ncharged to the employer provided, however, that with regard to\nplacements in class "B" employment, a fee of up to one and one-half\ntimes the fee charged to the job applicant may be charged to the\nemployer. By agreement with an employment agency, the employer may\nvoluntarily assume payment of the job applicant's fee. The fees charged\nto employers by any licensed person conducting an employment agency for\nrendering services in connection with, or for providing employment in\nclasses "A", "A-1" and "B", as hereinafter defined in subdivision four\nof this section where the applicant is not charged a fee shall be\ndetermined by agreement between the employer and the employment agency.\nNo fee shall be charged or accepted for the registration of applicants\nfor employees or employment.\n  2. Size of fee; payment schedule. The gross fee charged to the job\napplicant and the gross fee charged to the employer each shall not\nexceed the amounts enumerated in the schedules set forth in this\nsection, for any single employment or engagement, except as hereinabove\nprovided; and such fees shall be subject to the provisions of section\none hundred eighty-six of this article. Except as otherwise provided\nherein, and except for class "C" employment, an employment agency shall\nnot require an applicant while employed in the continental United\nStates, and paid weekly ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_185__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for private nursing duty, five per cent of the salary or wages\nreceived each week through the first ten weeks of that engagement only,\nand such fee shall be due and payable at the end of each such week;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_185__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for any other nursing duty, the amount of the first week's salary\nor wages unless the first year's computed salary or wages to be derived\nfor at least one year's employment is twenty-five hundred dollars or\nmore, in which event the gross fee shall not exceed, in percentage of\nsuch salary or wages, the following:\n  where such first year's salary or wages is\nat least $2500 but less than $3000 ............................. 2 1/2 %\nat least $3000 but less than $3500 ............................. 3     %\nat least $3500 but less than $4000 ............................. 3 1/2 %\nat least $4000 but less than $4500 ............................. 4     %\nat least $4500 but less than $5000 ............................. 4 1/2 %\n$5000 or more .................................................. 5     %\n  10. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, no fee\nmay be charged or collected for services rendered by an employment\nagency not licensed pursuant to section one hundr...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>