<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-198-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-198-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="198-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-198-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-198-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-198-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-198-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_198_B">
        <num>198-B</num>
        <heading>Sale or lease of used motor vehicles</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bank or financial institution except in the case of a lease of a\nused motor vehicle,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a business selling a used vehicle to an employee of that business,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a regulated public utility which sells at public auction vehicles\nused in the ordinary course of its operations, provided that any\nadvertisements of such sales conspicuously disclose the "as is" nature\nof the sale,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the sale of a leased vehicle to that vehicle's lessee, a family\nmember of the lessee, or an employee of the lessee, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state, its agencies, bureaus, boards, commissions and\nauthorities, and all of the political subdivisions of the state,\nincluding the agencies and authorities of such subdivisions;\n  4. "Warranty" means any undertaking in connection with the sale or\nlease by a dealer of a used motor vehicle to refund, repair, replace,\nmaintain or take other action with respect to such used motor vehicle\nand provided at no extra charge beyond the price of the used motor\nvehicle;\n  5. "Service contract" means a contract in writing for any period of\ntime or any specific mileage to refund, repair, replace, maintain or\ntake other action with respect to a used motor vehicle and provided at\nan extra charge beyond the price of the used motor vehicle or of the\nlease contract for the used motor vehicle;\n  6. "Repair insurance" means a contract in writing for any period of\ntime or any specific mileage to refund, repair, replace, maintain or\ntake other action with respect to a used motor vehicle and which is\nregulated by the department of financial services.\n  b. Written warranty required; terms. 1. No dealer shall sell or lease\na used motor vehicle to a consumer without giving the consumer a written\nwarranty which shall at minimum apply for the following terms:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the used motor vehicle has thirty-six thousand miles or less,\nthe warranty shall be at minimum ninety days or four thousand miles,\nwhichever comes first.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the used motor vehicle has more than thirty-six thousand miles,\nbut less than eighty thousand miles, the warranty shall be at minimum\nsixty days or three thousand miles, whichever comes first.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the used motor vehicle has eighty thousand miles or more but no\nmore than one hundred thousand miles, the warranty shall be at a minimum\nthirty days or one thousand miles, whichever comes first.\n  2. The written warranty shall require the dealer or his agent to\nrepair or, at the election of the dealer, reimburse the consumer for the\nreasonable cost of repairing the failure of a covered part. Covered\nparts shall at least include the following items:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Engine. All lubricated parts, water pump, fuel pump, manifolds,\nengine block, cylinder head, rotary engine housings and flywheel.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Transmission. The transmission case, internal parts, and the\ntorque converter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Drive axle. Front and rear drive axle housings and internal parts,\naxle shafts, propeller shafts and universal joints.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Brakes. Master cylinder, vacuum assist booster, wheel cylinders,\nhydraulic lines and fittings and disc brake calipers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Radiator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Steering. The steering gear housing and all internal parts, power\nsteering pump, valve body, piston and rack.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Alternator, generator, starter, ignition system excluding the\nbattery.\n  3. Such repair or reimbursement shall be made by the dealer\nnotwithstanding the fact that the warranty period has expired, provided\nthe consumer notifies the dealer of the failure of a covered part within\nthe specified warranty period.\n  4. The written warranty may contain additional language excluding\ncoverage:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for a failure of a covered part caused by a lack of customary\nmaintenance;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for a failure of a covered part caused by collision, abuse,\nnegligence, theft, vandalism, fire or other casualty and damage from the\nenvironment (windstorm, lightning, road hazards, etc.);\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the odometer has been stopped or altered such that the\nvehicle's actual mileage cannot be readily determined or if any covered\npart has been altered such that a covered part was thereby caused to\nfail;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for maintenance services and the parts used in connection with\nsuch services such as seals, gaskets, oil or grease unless required in\nconnection with the repair of a covered part;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for a motor tuneup;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for a failure resulting from racing or other competition;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for a failure caused by towing a trailer or another vehicle unless\nthe used motor vehicle is equipped for this as recommended by the\nmanufacturer;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the used motor vehicle is used to carry passengers for hire;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the used motor vehicle is rented to someone other than the\nconsumer as defined in paragraph one of subdivision a of this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for repair of valves and/or rings to correct low compression\nand/or oil consumption which are considered normal wear;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the extent otherwise permitted by law, for property damage\narising or allegedly arising out of the failure of a covered part; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the extent otherwise permitted by law, for loss of the use of\nthe used motor vehicle, loss of time, inconvenience, commercial loss or\nconsequential damages.\n  c. Failure to honor warranty. 1. If the dealer or his agent fails to\ncorrect a malfunction or defect as required by the warranty specified in\nthis section which substantially impairs the value of the used motor\nvehicle to the consumer after a reasonable period of time, the dealer\nshall accept return of the used motor vehicle from the consumer and\nrefund to the consumer the full purchase price, or in the case of a\nlease contract all payments made under the contract, including sales or\ncompensating use tax, less a reasonable allowance for any damage not\nattributable to normal wear or usage, and adjustment for any\nmodifications which either increase or decrease the market value of the\nvehicle or of the lease contract, and in the case of a lease contract,\nshall cancel all further payments due from the consumer under the lease\ncontract. In determining the purchase price to be refunded or in\ndetermining all payments made under a lease contract to be refunded, the\npurchase price, or all payments made under a lease contract, shall be\ndeemed equal to the sum of the actual cash difference paid for the used\nmotor vehicle, or for the lease contract, plus, if the dealer elects to\nnot return any vehicles traded-in by the consumer, the wholesale value\nof any such traded-in vehicles as listed in the National Auto Dealers\nAssociation Used Car Guide, or such other guide as may be specified in\nregulations promulgated by the commissioner of motor vehicles, as\nadjusted for mileage, improvements, and any major physical or mechanical\ndefects in the traded-in vehicle at the time of trade-in. The dealer\nselling or leasing the used motor vehicle shall deliver to the consumer\na written notice including conspicuous language indicating that if the\nconsumer should be entitled to a refund pursuant to this sect...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The malfunction or defect does not substantially impair such\nvalue; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The malfunction or defect is the result of abuse, neglect or\nunreasonable modifications or alterations of the used motor vehicle.\n  2. It shall be presumed that a dealer has had a reasonable opportunity\nto correct a malfunction or defect in a used motor vehicle, if:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The same malfunction or defect has been subject to repair three or\nmore times by the selling or leasing dealer or his agent within the\nwarranty period, but such malfunction or defect continues to exist; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The vehicle is out of service by reason of repair or malfunction\nor defect for a cumulative total of fifteen or more days during the\nwarranty period. Said period shall not include days when the dealer is\nunable to complete the repair because of the unavailability of necessary\nrepair parts. The dealer shall be required to exercise due diligence in\nattempting to obtain necessary repair parts. Provided, however, that if\na vehicle has been out of service for a cumulative total of forty-five\ndays, even if a portion of that time is attributable to the\nunavailability of replacement parts, the consumer shall be entitled to\nthe replacement or refund remedies provided in this section.\n  3. The term of any warranty, service contract or repair insurance\nshall be extended by any time period during which the used motor vehicle\nis in the possession of the dealer or his duly authorized agent for the\npurpose of repairing the used motor vehicle under the terms and\nobligations of said warranty, service contract or repair insurance.\n  4. The term of any warranty, service contract or repair insurance, and\nthe fifteen day out-of-service period, shall be extended by any time\nduring which repair services are not available to the consumer because\nof a war, invasion or strike, fire, flood or other natural disaster.\n  d. Waiver void. 1. Any agreement entered into by a consumer for the\npurchase or lease of a used motor vehicle which waives, limits or\ndisclaims the rights set forth in this article shall be void as contrary\nto public policy. Further, if a dealer fails to give the written\nwarranty required by this article, the dealer nevertheless shall be\ndeemed to have given said warranty as a matter of law.\n  2. Nothing in this section shall in any way limit the rights or\nremedies which are otherwise available to a consumer under any other\nlaw.\n  3. Notwithstanding paragraph one of this subdivision, this article\nshall not apply to used motor vehicles sold for, or in...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If your used car has more than 18,000 miles and up to and\nincluding 36,000 miles, a warranty must be provided for at least 90 days\nor 4,000 miles, whichever comes first.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If your used car has more than 36,000 miles but less than 80,000\nmiles, a warranty must be provided for at least 60 days or 3,000 miles,\nwhichever comes first.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If your used car has 80,000 miles or more but no more than 100,000\nmiles, a warranty must be provided for at least 30 days or 1,000 miles,\nwhichever comes first. Cars with over 100,000 miles are not covered.\n  4. If your engine, transmission, drive axle, brakes, radiator,\nsteering, alternator, generator, starter, or ignition system (excluding\nthe battery) are defective, the dealer or his agent must repair or, if\nhe so chooses, reimburse you for the reasonable cost of repair.\n  5. If the same problem cannot be repaired after three or more\nattempts, you are entitled to return the car and receive a refund of\nyour purchase price or of all payments made under your lease contract,\nand of sales tax and fees, minus a reasonable allowance for any damage\nnot attributable to normal usage or wear, and, in the case of a lease\ncontract, a cancellation of all further payments you are otherwise\nrequired to make under the lease contract.\n  6. If your car is out of service to repair a problem for a total of\nfifteen days or more during the warranty period you are entitled to\nreturn the car and receive a refund of your purchase price or of all\npayments made under your lease contract, and of sales tax and fees,\nminus a reasonable allowance for any damage not attributable to normal\nusage or wear, and, in the case of a lease contract, a cancellation of\nall further payments you are otherwise required to make under the lease\ncontract.\n  7. A dealer may put into the written warranty certain provisions which\nwill prohibit your recovery under certain conditions; however, the\ndealer may not cause you to waive any rights under this law.\n  8. A dealer may refuse to refund your purchase price, or the payments\nmade under your lease contract, if the problem does not substantially\nimpair the value of your car, or if the problem is caused by abuse,\nneglect, or unreasonable modification.\n  9. If a dealer has established an arbitration procedure, the dealer\nmay refuse to re...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>