<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="206-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_206_C">
        <num>206-C</num>
        <heading>Frauds on guests of hotels, boarding houses, rooming-houses and lodging houses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 206-c. Frauds on guests of hotels, boarding houses, rooming-houses\nand lodging houses. A person who for purposes of gain and by means of\nany false statement or representation regarding a hotel, boarding house,\nrooming-house or lodging house, shall divert or attempt to divert any\ntraveler or any other person to another hotel, boarding house,\nrooming-house or lodging house, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n  The making of a false statement regarding a hotel, boarding house,\nrooming-house or lodging house, coupled with a suggestion or\nrecommendation to patronize another hotel, boarding house, rooming-house\nor lodging house shall be presumptive evidence that the act of the\ndefendant was committed for the purpose of gain.\n  Any person who shall pay, or offer to pay any money or other reward to\nanother for diverting patrons from one hotel, boarding house,\nrooming-house or lodging house to another, knowing that such diversion\nwas effected in the manner herein prohibited, shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor.\n  In any prosecution of a person for payment or offer of payment of\nmoney or other reward in violation of this section, proof of prior\nnotice to the defendant that the person to whom payment was made or\noffered has at any time diverted patronage from one hotel, boarding\nhouse, rooming-house or lodging house to another by means of false\nrepresentation, shall be presumptive evidence that such defendant knew\nthat the diversion complained of was effected by false statements or\nrepresentations in violation of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>