<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="206-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-206-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_206_B">
        <num>206-B</num>
        <heading>Posting of rates for motels and motor courts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 206-b. Posting of rates for motels and motor courts. Every person,\nfirm or corporation engaged in the business of furnishing public lodging\naccommodations in motels and motor courts shall:\n  Post in a conspicuous place or manner in each and every rental unit, a\nprinted copy of this section and section two hundred six-a and a\nstatement of the rental unit charge or rate charged by the day for the\nrental unit. No charge or sum shall be collected or received by any\nmotel or motor court keeper for any service not actually rendered or for\na longer time than the person so charged actually remained at such motel\nor motor court, nor for a higher rate of charge for the use of said\nrental unit than is specified in the list of charges required to be\nposted by the last preceding sentence of this paragraph, nor for a\nhigher rate of charge for the use of said rental unit than the maximum\nrate posted or maintained on any outdoor or outside advertising sign\npertaining to such establishment, provided such guest shall have given\nsuch motel or motor court keeper notice at the office of his departure.\nFor any violation of this section, the offender shall forfeit to the\ninjured party, three times the amount so charged, and shall not be\nentitled to receive any money for services or time charged.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>