<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-209-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-209-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-209-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-209-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-209-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-209-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_A">
        <num>209-A</num>
        <heading>Registration of hotel and motel names</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-a. Registration of hotel and motel names. Any person or\ncorporation now owning or now engaged in and conducting the business of\nan hotel or motel in the state of New York may register the name by\nwhich said hotel or motel is known and designated by filing in the\noffice of the secretary of state a petition subscribed by the petitioner\nand affirmed by him as true under the penalties of perjury, containing\nthe facsimile of such name or designation and specifically describing\nthe location of the hotel or motel to be known by such name or\ndesignation, together with the name and address of the person or\ncorporation owning or operating the hotel or motel in addition to such\nother recitals as the secretary of state may require. A duplicate\noriginal or a certified copy of such petition shall also be filed in the\noffice of the clerk of the county in which said hotel or motel is\nsituated and a copy of said petition shall be printed once each week for\nthree consecutive weeks in a newspaper published in the county in which\nsaid hotel or motel is located, and such person or corporation shall\nthereupon have the right to the exclusive use of such name or\ndesignation for an hotel or motel in the state of New York. Where it\nappears that the required publication has been made and this article has\nbeen in all other respects complied with the secretary of state shall\ndeliver to such person or corporation so filing such petition a\ncertificate under his seal of the record of such filing and such\ncertificate shall be prima facie evidence of the right to the exclusive\nuse in the state of New York of such name or designation by the person\nor corporation therein named. Any person or corporation may so register\nthe name of an hotel or motel about to be erected, provided, however,\nthat in the event that such person or corporation shall not begin the\nconstruction of said hotel or motel within one year thereafter and\nprosecute the construction thereof with reasonable dispatch, said person\nor corporation shall be deemed to have abandoned the right to use such\nname or designation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>