<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-227"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-227"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="227"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_227">
        <num>227</num>
        <heading>Required posting of safety guidelines</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 227. Required posting of safety guidelines. 1. The owner and/or\noperator of a trampoline park shall conspicuously post a sign containing\nsafety and instructional rules and guidelines to be followed by\nparticipants while at the trampoline park or using a commercial\ntrampoline. Such sign shall include appropriate behavior and activities\nat the trampoline park to minimize potential risks to participants.\n  2. Such signs shall be conspicuously displayed near all entrances.\n  3. Such signs shall contain warnings that there are inherent risks in\nthe participation in or on the commercial trampoline, since it is\nrecognized that participation in or on the trampoline may be hazardous\nregardless of all feasible safety measures that can be undertaken by the\ndevice owner and/or operator; and that there is a duty for the\nparticipants, or parent or guardian in the case of a minor, to become\napprised of the warnings and the risks inherent in participation in or\non a commercial trampoline if the warnings are not obeyed.\n  4. Prior to participating in or on such commercial trampolines,\nparticipants and parents or guardians in the case of a minor, shall\nfamiliarize themselves with the posted safety warnings so that they may\nmake an informed decision of whether to participate in or on the\ntrampoline notwithstanding the risks.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>