<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-23"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-23"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23">
        <num>23</num>
        <heading>Automobile auctioneer</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in a written\ndisclosure made in not less than ten-point bold face type and appearing\non the front of the sales contract, receipt, invoice, or other document\nused in connection with the sale of the vehicle that shall set forth the\nseller's true legal name, complete street address and dealer facility\nidentification number and that shall be captioned "Identity of Vehicle's\nSeller"; and (ii) by affixing a conspicuous sign to the windshield of\neach vehicle offered for sale, sold or made available for inspection\nprior to auction that shall disclose the seller's true legal name,\ncomplete street address and dealer facility identification number.\n  b. No used motor vehicle subject to the provisions of section one\nhundred ninety-eight-b of this chapter shall be sold or offered for sale\nby an automobile auctioneer unless such auctioneer discloses the Used\nCar Lemon Law Bill of Rights. Such disclosure shall be made in writing,\nin not less than ten-point bold face type and appearing on the front of\nthe sales contract, receipt, invoice, or other document used in\nconnection with the sale of the vehicle, and shall be captioned "Used\nCar Lemon Law Bill of Rights".\n  c. No motor vehicle subject to the provisions of section one hundred\nninety-eight-a of this chapter shall be sold or offered for sale by an\nautomobile auctioneer unless such auctioneer discloses the New Car Lemon\nLaw Bill of Rights. Such disclosure shall be made in writing, in not\nless than ten-point bold face type and appearing on the front of the\nsales contract, receipt, invoice, or other document used in connection\nwith the sale of the vehicle, and shall be captioned "New Car Lemon Law\nBill of Rights".\n  d. No used motor vehicle shall be sold or offered for sale by an\nautomobile auctioneer unless such auctioneer provides the following\nnotice, in writing, in not less than ten-point bold face type and\nappearing on the front of the sales contract, receipt, invoice or other\ndocument used in c...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_23__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the title or proof of ownership conveyed shall be good, and its\ntransfer rightful; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_23__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the goods shall be delivered free from any security interest or\nother lien or encumbrance of which the buyer at the time of contracting\nhas no knowledge.\n  b. Any waiver of the warranty provided for in paragraph a of this\nsubdivision by a buyer shall be deemed contrary to public policy and\nshall be void and unenforceable. Any attempt by an automobile auctioneer\nto exclude or modify such warranties shall constitute a violation of\nthis section.\n  5. Documentation of transactions. In addition to the records required\nto be kept by auctioneers pursuant to section twenty-five of this\narticle, every sale by an automobile auctioneer shall be accompanied by\nan itemized receipt which shall contain the following information:\n  a. legal name, and trade name if different, of the automobile\nauctioneer;\n  b. address and telephone number of the automobile auctioneer;\n  c. name of the buyer;\n  d. make, year of manufacture, and identification number of said motor\nvehicle;\n  e. the amou...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eighty-three hundred three of the civil\npractice law and rules, and direct restitution.\n  b. Whenever the court shall determine that a violation of this section\nhas occurred, it may impose a civil penalty of not more than one\nthousand dollars for each violation. In connection with an application\nmade under this subdivision, the attorney general is authorized to take\nproof and to make a determination of the relevant facts and to issue\nsubpoenas in accordance with the civil practice law and rules.\n  10. Additional remedies. In addition to the right of action granted to\nthe attorney general pursuant to subdivision nine of this section, any\nbuyer injured by a violation of this section may bring an action in his\nown name to enjoin such unlawful practice, an action to recover his\nactual damages or five hundred dollars, whichever is greater, or both\nsuch actions. The court in its discretion may increase the award of\ndamages to an amount not to exceed three times the actual damages. The\ncourt may award costs and reasonable attorney's fees to a prevailing\nplaintiff.\n  11. Burden of proof. In any proceeding involving this section, the\nburden of proving an exception or inapplicability for the definition of\nautomobile auctioneer is upon the person claiming it.\n  12. Severability clause. If any provision of this section or if any\napplication thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the\nremainder of the section and the application of the provision to other\npersons and circumstances shall not be affected thereby.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>