<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-230"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-230"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="230"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-230/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-230/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-230/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-230/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_230">
        <num>230</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 230. Definitions.  In this article unless the context otherwise\nrequires: "Article" means any article of merchandise and includes any\nportion of such article, whether a distinct part thereof, or not\n(including every part thereof whether or not separable and also\nincluding material for manufacture).\n  Platinum, iridium, palladium, ruthenium, rhodium and/or osmium,\ninclude any alloy or alloys of any one or more of said metals.\n  "Mark" means any mark, sign, device, imprint, stamp, brand applied to\nany article, or to any tag, card, paper, label, box, carton, container,\nholder, package cover or wrapping attached to, used in conjunction with\nor enclosing such article or any bill, bill of sale, invoice, statement,\nletter, circular, advertisement, notice, memorandum, or other writing or\nprinting.\n  "Apply" and "applied" include any method or means of application or\nattachment to, or of use on, or in connection with, or in relation to,\nan article, whether such application, attachment or use is to, on, by,\nin or with\n  1. The article itself, or\n  2. Anything attached to the article, or\n  3. Anything to which the article is attached, or\n  4. Anything in or on which the article is, or\n  5. Anything so used or placed as to lead to a reasonable belief that\nthe mark on that thing is meant to be taken as a mark on the article\nitself.\n  "Quality mark" is any mark as herein defined indicating, describing,\nidentifying or referring to or appearing or seeming or purporting to\nindicate, describe, identify or refer to the partial or total presence\nor existence of or the quality of or the percentage of or the purity of\nor the number of parts of platinum, iridium, palladium, ruthenium,\nrhodium and/or osmium in any article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>