<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-243"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-243"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="243"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-243/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-243/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-243/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-243/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_243">
        <num>243</num>
        <heading>Aircraft; construction, design and airworthiness; federal registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 243. Aircraft; construction, design and airworthiness; federal\nregistration. The public safety requiring, and the advantages of uniform\nregulation making it desirable, in the interest of aeronautical\nprogress, that aircraft to be avigated within this state should conform,\nwith respect to design, construction and airworthiness, to standards\nprescribed by the United States government with respect to avigation of\naircraft subject to its jurisdiction, it shall be unlawful for any\nperson to avigate an aircraft within this state unless it is licensed\nand registered by the department of transportation of the United States\nin the manner prescribed by the lawful rules and regulations of the\nUnited States government then in force. The license for such aircraft\nmust be carried and conspicuously posted in the aircraft while in\nflight. Such license also shall be presented for inspection, on demand,\nto any peace officer, acting pursuant to his special duties, or police\nofficer, or to any official, manager or person in charge of an airport\nor landing place where the aircraft may be. The provisions of this\nsection shall not apply to aircraft used exclusively in the governmental\nservice of the United States, or used exclusively in the service of the\nnational guard or of one or more of the civil departments of this state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>