<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-246"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-246"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="246"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-246/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-246/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-246/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-246/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_246">
        <num>246</num>
        <heading>Penalties for violation of the foregoing provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 246. Penalties for violation of the foregoing provisions. A person\nwho violates any of the foregoing provisions of this article shall be\nguilty of a misdemeanor and punishable by a fine of not more than one\nhundred dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than ninety days, or\nboth. Failure by an operator to exhibit his pilot certificate upon\nproper demand or failure to show the aircraft registration certificate\nupon proper demand shall be presumptive evidence that the operator is\nnot duly licensed or that the aircraft is not duly registered under this\narticle. That an act or omission with respect to rules set forth in\nsubdivision six of section two hundred forty-five was done or made in\naccordance with regulations affecting aircraft subject to federal\naviation regulations, or that a landing or take-off from or on a public\nstreet or highway was done with consent of local authorities and\napproval of the administrator of the federal aviation agency, or that an\nact or omission which would otherwise be a violation of a prescribed\nrule was an authorized deviation under subdivision eleven of section two\nhundred forty-five, shall be matters of defense.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>