<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-279-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-279-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="279-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-279-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-279-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-279-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-279-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_279_G">
        <num>279-G</num>
        <heading>Search warrant to discover vessels, receptacles or utensils</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 279-g. Search warrant to discover vessels, receptacles or utensils.\nWhenever any person who has filed under this article, or his authorized\nagent, shall make oath before any magistrate or court of competent\njurisdiction that he has reason to believe, and does believe, that a\nviolation of this article is occurring with respect to one or some of\nhis vessels, receptacles or utensils having produced thereon a name,\nmark or device filed under this article, the said magistrate or court\nmust thereupon issue a search warrant to discover and obtain the same.\nThe said magistrate or court shall cause to be brought before him the\nperson in whose possession the said vessels, receptacles or utensils are\nfound and shall inquire into the circumstances of possession. If the\nsaid magistrate or court finds that such person is guilty of any of the\noffenses mentioned in this article, the punishment herein prescribed\nshall be imposed and possession of the said vessels, receptacles or\nutensils obtained upon the warrant shall be awarded to the owner\nthereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>