<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="304"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_304">
        <num>304</num>
        <heading>Standard and storage of illuminating oils</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 304. Standard and storage of illuminating oils. No person shall\nmanufacture or have in his possession or sell or give away for\nilluminating or heating purposes in lamps or stoves within this state,\nany oil or burning fluid wholly or partly composed of naphtha, coal oil,\npetroleum or products thereof, or of other substances or materials\nemitting an inflammable vapor which will flash at a temperature below\none hundred degrees Fahrenheit according to the tag closed tester\nprescribed and the method adopted by the American Society for Testing\nMaterials for flash point of volatile flammable liquids.\n  No such oil or fluid which will ignite at a temperature below two\nhundred and ninety-five degrees Fahrenheit as determined by the standard\nmethod of test for flash and fire points by means of open cup of the\nAmerican Society for Testing Materials shall be burned or be carried as\nfreight in any passenger or baggage car or passenger boat moved by steam\nor electric power in this state, or in any stage or street car, however\npropelled, except that coal oil, petroleum and its products may be\ncarried, when securely packed in barrels or metallic packages, in\npassenger boats propelled by steam when there are no other public means\nof transportation.\n  Naphtha and other illuminating products of petroleum which will not\nstand the flash test required by this section, may be used for\nilluminating or heating purposes only in the following cases:\n  1. In street lamps and open air receptacles apart from any building,\nfactory or inhabited house in which the vapor is burned.\n  2. In dwellings, factories or other places of business when vaporized\nin secure tanks or metallic generators made for that purpose, in which\nthe vapor so generated is used for lighting or heating.\n  3. For use in the manufacture of illuminating gas in gas manufactories\nsituated apart from dwellings and other buildings.\n  Any person violating any provision of this section shall forfeit to\nthe city or village, or if not in a city or village to the town in which\nthe violation occurs, the sum of one hundred dollars for every such\nviolation, and for every day or part of a day that such violation\noccurs.\n  This section shall not apply to the city of New York, and shall not\nsupersede but shall be in addition to the ordinances or regulations of\nany city or village made pursuant to law for the inspection or control\nof combustible materials therein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>