<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="306"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_306">
        <num>306</num>
        <heading>Fire and light within one hundred and fifty feet of warehouses in the counties of New York, Kings, Queens and Nassau prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 306. Fire and light within one hundred and fifty feet of warehouses\nin the counties of New York, Kings, Queens and Nassau prohibited. No\nperson shall bring, have, keep or use or suffer or permit to be brought,\nkept, had or used on board of any ship, vessel, canal boat, barge,\nlighter, boat or other craft lying at or within the distance of one\nhundred and fifty feet of any warehouse, yard, shed, dock, pier,\nbulkhead, wharf or other place within the counties of New York, Kings,\nQueens or Nassau at, in or upon which petroleum oil or any of its\nproducts is stored or is kept for export or in quantities exceeding ten\nthousand gallons, or at, in or upon any such warehouse, shed, yard,\ndock, pier, bulkhead or other place, any lighted match or lighted cigar,\ncigarette or pipe, or any fire or light of any kind, except in strict\nconformity to the written permission of the owner, lessee or\nsuperintendent of such warehouse, yard, shed, dock, pier, bulkhead,\nwharf or other place, specifying the fire or light to be kept, had or\nused, the particular purpose for and the place or spot at which the same\nmay be so kept, had or used and the particular manner of keeping, having\nand using the same.\n  This section shall not apply to steam tugs while transacting their\nordinary business nor to steam fire engines engaged in extinguishing\nfires.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>