<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="307"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_307">
        <num>307</num>
        <heading>Penalties and the enforcement thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 307. Penalties and the enforcement thereof. Every person violating\nthe provisions of this article, relating to the test for refined\npetroleum and oil, shall forfeit to the people of the state the sum of\nfive hundred dollars for each violation.\n  Every person violating any provision of this article, relating to the\nstorage or keeping for sale of any article, substance or product herein\nspecified, shall forfeit to the people of the state, the sum of two\nhundred and fifty dollars for each day and part of a day that such\nviolation continues.\n  Every person violating any provisions of this article, relating to the\nincumbering of any sidewalk or street, shall forfeit the sum of\ntwenty-five dollars for each day and part of a day that such violation\ncontinues, to be paid, if in a city or village, to such city or village,\nand elsewhere, to the town in which such violation occurs.\n  The mayor and common council of every city or other proper authorities\nthereof, shall, by ordinance or resolution, provide for the proper\nenforcement of the provisions of the preceding sections of this article,\nand in every such city, the moneys collected by the city as penalties\nfor the violation of any such ordinance or resolution or of any of such\nprovisions, shall be applied to the support of the poor therein, except\nin Brooklyn, where they shall be paid into the widows and orphans' fund\nof the fire department, and except in Buffalo, where they shall be paid\nto the treasurer of the firemen's benevolent association of the city for\nits use and benefit.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>