<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-32"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-32"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="32"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_32">
        <num>32</num>
        <heading>Licenses to veterans of the armed forces of the United States</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_32__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>was\nhonorably discharged from such service, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_32__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has a qualifying\ncondition, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law, and\nhas received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from\nsuch service, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_32__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is a discharged LGBT veteran, as defined in section\none of the veterans' services law, and has received a discharge other\nthan bad conduct or dishonorable from such service, and who is a\nresident of this state and a veteran of any war, or who shall have\nserved in the armed forces of the United States overseas, and the\nsurviving spouse of any such veteran, if a resident of the state, shall\nhave the right to hawk, peddle, vend and sell goods, wares or\nmerchandise or solicit trade upon the streets and highways within the\ncounty of his or her residence, as the case may be, or if such county is\nembraced wholly by a city, within such city, by procuring a license for\nthat purpose to be issued as herein provided. No part of the lands or\npremises under the jurisdiction of the division of the state fair in the\ndepartment of agriculture and markets, shall be deemed a street or\nhighway within the meaning of this section.\n  2. Any such former member of the armed forces of the United States may\npresent to the clerk of any county in which he has resided for a period\nof at least six months, his original certificate of release or discharge\nfrom active duty, or a copy thereof duly certified by the recording\nofficer or a certificate in lieu of lost discharge issued by a\ndepartment of the armed forces of the United States which shall show\nthat the person presenting it is a veteran of any war, or that he has\nserved overseas in the armed forces of the United States. He shall also\nfill out a blank which shall when filled out state his name, residence\nat the time of application, nature of goods to be sold, and if the\napplicant is working on commission or percentage for any person, firm or\ncorporation, the name and business address of such person, firm or\ncorporation. This statement shall be signed by the applicant in the\npresence of the county clerk, or a deputy designated by him, and the\nname on this application and on the original certificate of release or\ndi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>