<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-330"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-330"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="330"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_330">
        <num>330</num>
        <heading>Publication of owner's name</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 330. Publication of owner's name. 1. Every newspaper, magazine or\nother periodically printed publication published in this state, shall\npublish in every copy of every issue, upon the editorial page or in one\nof the first four pages of the publication, the full name and address of\nthe owner, owners, proprietor or proprietors of such publication; and if\nsaid publication shall be owned or published by a corporation, then the\nname of the corporation and the address of its principal place of\nbusiness shall be published, together with the full names and addresses\nof the president, secretary and treasurer thereof; and if the said\npublication shall be owned or published by a partnership, limited\npartnership, or an unincorporated joint stock association, then the full\nnames and addresses of the partners, or officers and managers of said\npartnership, limited partnership or unincorporated joint-stock\nassociation shall be published in like manner. The representative\ncapacities of those named shall be indicated in like manner.\n  2. Every publication printed or reprinted after September first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-three which is so composed or illustrated as a\nwhole as to be devoted to the description or portrayal of bondage,\nsadism, masochism or other sexual perversion or to the exploitation of\nsex or nudity and published in this state shall conspicuously have\nimprinted on the cover, title, or copyright page or at the end of the\npublication the true name and address of the publisher or printer.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>