<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="336-B*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_336_B*2">
        <num>336-B*2</num>
        <heading>Interactive information network service; disclosure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_B*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a telephone\ncorporation as that term is defined in section two of the public service\nlaw,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_B*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a provider of mobile service as defined in 47 U.S.C. ยง 153, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_B*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a cable television company as defined in section two hundred twelve\nof the public service law, or the affiliates of any of the foregoing.\n  6. For the purposes of this section any games or contests with or\nwithout prizes being offered shall be an entertainment service.\n  7. Whenever there shall be a violation of this section, an application\nmay be made by the attorney general in the name of the people of the\nstate of New York to a court or justice having jurisdiction to issue an\ninjunction to enjoin and restrain the continuance of such violation; and\nif it shall appear to the satisfaction of the court or justice that the\ndefendant has, in fact, violated this section, an injunction may be\nissued by such court or justice, enjoining and restraining any further\nviolation, without requiring proof that any person has, in fact, been\ninjured or damaged thereby. Whenever the court shall determine that a\nviolation of this section has occurred, the court may impose a civil\npenalty of not more than five hundred dollars for each violation. In\nconnection with any such proposed application the attorney general is\nauthorized to take proof and make a determination of the relevant facts\nand to issue subpoenas in accordance with the civil practice law and\nrules.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 336-b's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>