<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="336-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_336_A">
        <num>336-A</num>
        <heading>Telephone corporation; coin operated telephones implementation of system to call an operator without use of coins; rules and regulations ...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 336-a. Telephone corporation; coin operated telephones\nimplementation of system to call an operator without use of coins; rules\nand regulations of public service commission. 1. All telephone\ncorporations doing business in this state and providing coin pay\ntelephones shall implement a system whereby calls may be made to the\noperator without charge and without requiring the insertion of any coins\ninto such pay telephone pursuant to the rules and regulations\npromulgated by the public service commission in the manner provided for\nin subdivision two of this section.\n  2. The public service commission shall establish, by rule or\nregulation, the effective date for implementing the system mandated in\nsubdivision one of this section. Such rules and regulations shall\nfurther provide for the method and manner of implementing such system.\nSuch rules and regulations shall be promulgated not later than one year\nnext succeeding the effective date of this section. Notwithstanding the\nimmediately preceding sentence, the public service commission shall\nforward copies of the final draft of such rules and regulations to the\ngovernor and the legislature, at least forty-five days prior to the\nproposed effective date of such rules and regulations. In no event shall\nsuch forwarding be made later than the two hundred seventieth day next\nsucceeding the effective date of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>