<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-08-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="336-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-336-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_336_B">
        <num>336-B</num>
        <heading>Public pay telephone volume controls</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 336-b. Public pay telephone volume controls. 1. Each telephone\ncorporation doing business in this state which provides public pay\ntelephones, including those owners or providers of customer owned\ncurrency operated telephones (COCOT's), shall provide at least\ntwenty-five percent of its public pay telephones installed on or after\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred ninety-three with volume control\nequipment to enable deaf or hard of hearing persons to access and\nutilize telecommunications services. The telephones with volume control\nequipment shall be distributed evenly among the public pay telephones\nprovided by the corporation. Each public pay telephone with a volume\ncontrol shall have signage either on the telephone or in the immediate\nvicinity thereof, identifying that telephone as being equipped with a\ndeaf or hard of hearing volume control.\n  2. Whenever more than two public pay telephones are installed within\nfifty feet of each other then at least one such telephone shall be\nequipped with volume control equipment.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall be applicable to all buildings\nor facilities constructed for public use.\n  4. For the purposes of this section the following terms shall have the\nfollowing meanings:\n  a. "Building or facility" shall mean all or any portion of buildings,\nstructures, equipment, roads, walks, parking lots, parks, sites, or\nother real property or interest in such property;\n  b. "Public use" shall mean any interior and exterior rooms or spaces\nmade available to the general public. Public use may be provided at a\nbuilding or facility that is privately or publicly owned;\n  c. "Signage" shall mean the display of written, symbolic, tactile, or\npictorial information.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 336-b's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>