<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-34"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-34"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="34"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-34/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-34/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-34/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-34/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34">
        <num>34</num>
        <heading>Arrest and conviction of offender</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 34. Arrest and conviction of offender. The public welfare officials\nshall see that the provisions of this article are enforced in their\nrespective towns. Any citizen may arrest any person trading as a peddler\nwho neglects or refuses to produce his license on demand, and shall\nimmediately convey such person before some justice of the peace of the\ncounty. If the fact that the person so arrested has traded without a\nlicense be proved to the satisfaction of the justice, he shall convict\nsuch person of an offense against this article and on such conviction\nshall issue his warrant to some constable of the county, commanding such\nconstable to levy and collect from the personal property of the offender\nthe sum of twenty-five dollars, with the costs of the proceeding, not\nexceeding five dollars. The penalty collected on such warrant shall be\npaid by the justice to the public welfare official of the town where the\noffense was committed.\n  If it appears in said proceeding that the person arrested refused to\nproduce his license or to disclose his name when lawfully required, no\ncosts shall be allowed such defendant, nor shall he maintain an action\nfor false imprisonment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>