<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-347"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-347"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="347"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-347/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-347/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-347/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-347/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_347">
        <num>347</num>
        <heading>Criminal prosecution</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 347. Criminal prosecution. The attorney general may prosecute every\nperson charged with the commission of a criminal offense in violation of\nthe laws of this state, applicable to or in respect of the practices or\ntransactions referred to in this article. In any such prosecution by the\nattorney general or a district attorney hereunder, the provisions of\nsection three hundred ninety-nine, of the code of criminal procedure\nshall not be applicable. In all such proceedings, the attorney general\nmay appear in person or by his deputy before any court of record or any\ngrand jury and exercise all the powers and perform all the duties in\nrespect of such actions or proceedings which the district attorney would\notherwise be authorized or required to exercise or perform; or the\nattorney general may in his discretion transmit evidence, proof and\ninformation as to such offense to the district attorney of the county or\ncounties in which the alleged violation has occurred, and every district\nattorney to whom such evidence, proof and information is so transmitted\nshall forthwith proceed to prosecute any corporation, company,\nassociation, or officer, manager or agent thereof, or any firm or person\ncharged with such violation. A district attorney shall give reasonable\nnotice to the attorney general of intention to prosecute under this\narticle and the attorney general may appear in any criminal proceeding\nbrought under this article. In any such proceeding, wherein the attorney\ngeneral has appeared either in person or by deputy, the district\nattorney shall only exercise such powers and perform such duties as are\nrequired of him by the attorney general or the deputy attorney general\nso appearing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>