<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="349-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_349_B">
        <num>349-B</num>
        <heading>Residential telephone equipment advertising, sale and warranty requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Residential telephone equipment" shall mean customer premises\nequipment such as telephone handsets, designed for use on the\nresidential premises of a person, other than a carrier, to originate,\nroute or terminate telecommunications, and does not include equipment\nused to multiplex, maintain or terminate access lines;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"New residential telephone equipment" shall mean residential\ntelephone equipment that is neither rebuilt nor used;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Rebuilt residential telephone equipment" shall mean residential\ntelephone equipment which has been modified, rebuilt, improved or\nreconditioned, either with new components or with components which were\npreviously used in other equipment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Used residential telephone equipment" shall mean residential\ntelephone equipment previously used by another person and in proper\nworking order but not modified, rebuilt, improved or reconditioned;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Consumer" or "purchaser" shall mean a retail customer who\npurchases such equipment for personal use in a place of residence; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Seller" shall mean any retailer, distributor or manufacturer who\nsells or offers for sale new residential telephone equipment, rebuilt\nresidential telephone equipment or used residential telephone equipment\ndirectly to a consumer or purchaser or places in the chain of\ndistribution such equipment to be ultimately sold to a consumer or\npurchaser.\n  2. Any manufacturer of new residential telephone equipment, rebuilt\nresidential telephone equipment or used residential telephone equipment\nshall specify on or in the package in which such equipment is sold, and\nany seller shall specify in all advertisements and catalogues excepting\ntelevision, radio and cable television advertising whether such\nequipment employs pulse, tone, pulse-or-tone or another signalling\nmethod and a statement as to whether such equipment is capable of\naccessing tone-actuated computer systems.\n  3. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the\nprovisions of subdivision two of this section shall not apply to any of\nthe following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Advertising, point-of-sale advertising, catalogues for and sales\nof such equipment not intended for direct connection to a telephone\ncorporation's lines or a central switching office;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Advertising for such equipment located on a customer's premises\noffered for sale in place; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Catalogues and equipment packages for such equipment which are in\nprint or physical production on or before the effective date of this\nsection.\n  4. Any manufacturer of such equipment shall specify on the package and\nany retailer shall specify in conspicuous notice at the point-of-sale,\nexcepting sale in place:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether such equipment is rebuilt or used;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether such equipment requires a source of power or connection\nother than ordinary connections to the inside premises' telephone wiring\nof the customer.\n  5. Any manufacturer of such equipment, except equipment sold in place,\nshall specify on the package the period of warranty of such equipment.\nInformation regarding obtaining a copy of the warranty showing the name\nand address of the manufacturer or other person to whom service\nquestions or warranty claims should be addressed during the warranty\nduration shall be specified on or in the package.\n  6. Any seller of such equipment, except equipment sold in place, shall\nprovide written warranties of not less than one year for new residential\ntelephone equipment, not less than ninety days for rebuilt residential\ntelephone equipment and not less than sixty days for used residential\ntelephone equipment. All warranties shall guarantee that the equipment\nso warranted is fit for the use for which it is intended during the time\nperiod specified in this subdivision. The primary obligation to provide\nthe written warranty required by this section shall be the obligation of\nthe manufacturer or distributor of the residential telephone equipment.\nA retailer shall be deemed to have complied with this section if the\nresidential telephone equipment it sells is warranted in compliance with\nthe requirements of this section by the manufacturer or distributor. If\nthe equipment does not conform to the written warranty and the consumer\nor purchaser reports, during the effective period of the warranty, such\nnonconformity, defect or condition to the manufacturer, the distributor,\nor the retailer from whom the consumer or purchaser purchased the\nequipment, such equipment shall be replaced or repaired, free of charge\nby any such seller to whom the consumer or purchaser reports the\nnonconformity, defect or condition.\n  7. It shall be an affirmative defense to any claim under this section\nthat the nonconformity, defe...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>