<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="349-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-349-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_349_D">
        <num>349-D</num>
        <heading>Energy services company consumers bill of rights</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Energy services" shall mean electricity and/or natural gas;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Energy services company" or "ESCO" shall mean an entity eligible\nto sell energy services to end-use customers using the transmission or\ndistribution system of a utility;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Customer" shall mean any person who is sold or offered an energy\nservices contract by an ESCO</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for residential utility service, or\n(ii) through door-to-door sales; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Door-to-door sales" shall mean the sale of energy services in\nwhich the ESCO or the ESCO's representative personally solicits the\nsale, and the buyer's agreement or offer to purchase is made at a place\nother than the place of business of the seller; provided that such term\nshall not include any sale which is conducted and consummated entirely\nby mail, telephone or other electronic means, or during a scheduled\nappointment at the premises of a buyer of nonresidential utility\nservice, or through solicitations of commercial accounts at trade or\nbusiness shows, conventions or expositions.\n  2. Any person who sells or offers for sale any energy services to a\ncustomer for or on behalf of an ESCO shall</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>properly identify himself\nor herself and the energy services company or companies which he or she\nrepresents;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>explain that he or she does not represent a distribution\nutility;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>explain the purpose of the solicitation;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide each\nprospective customer with a copy of the "ESCO consumers bill of rights"\ndeveloped by the public service commission, in consultation with the\nLong Island power authority, the state consumer protection board and the\ndepartment of law; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide any written materials, including\ncontracts and the "ESCO consumers bill of rights", in the same language\nutilized to solicit the prospective customer.\n  3. No person who sells or offers for sale any energy services for, or\non behalf of, an ESCO shall engage in any deceptive acts or practices in\nthe marketing of energy services.\n  4. No contract for provision of energy services by an ESCO shall\nrequire any customer prepayment for energy services. However, an ESCO\nmay offer a customer an option of prepayment. Any contract providing for\nprepayment may be cancelled by the customer, without any penalty or\nobligation, within ninety calendar days. Any unused portion of the\nprepayment shall be returned to the customer by the ESCO within thirty\nbusiness days following receipt of notice of cancellation.\n  5. No contract for provision of energy services by an ESCO shall\nrequire the customer to pay any fee for termination or early\ncancellation of a contract in excess of either</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one hundred dollars\nfor any contract with a remaining term of less than twelve months;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ntwo hundred dollars for any contract with a remaining term of twelve\nmonths or more; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>twice the estimated bill for energy services for\nan average month. To charge a fee based on the estimated bill for energy\nservices for an average month, an ESCO must have provided the customer,\nat the time that the contract is offered, with an estimate of the\naverage monthly bill that customer would be charged for energy services\nand the fee that would be charged based on such estimate.\n  6. No material change shall be made in the terms or duration of any\ncontract for the provision of energy services by an ESCO without the\nexpress consent of the customer. A change in price or a change to or\nfrom fixed or variable pricing shall be deemed to be material. This\nshall not restrict an ESCO from renewing a contract by clearly informing\nthe customer in writing, not less than thirty days nor more than sixty\ndays prior to the renewal date, of the renewal terms and of his or her\noption not to accept the renewal offer; provided, however, that no fee\npursuant to subdivision five of this section shall be charged to a\ncustomer whose express consent has not been obtained to any change in\nmaterial terms and conditions, or who objects to such renewal not later\nthan three business days after receiving the first billing statement\nfrom the ESCO under the terms of the contract as renewed. The public\nservice commission and the Long Island power authority may adopt\nadditional guidelines, practices, rules or regulations governing the\nrenewal process.\n  7. In every contract for energy services and in all marketing\nmaterials provided to prospective purchasers of such contracts, all\nvariable charges shall be clearly and conspicuously identified. In any\nnotice regarding contract renewability, the provider shall disclose the\nfollowing information as it exists at the time of such notice:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nprice charged for energy services; (ii) the price it proposes to charge\nupon renewal; (iii) the price that is charged by the customer's\ndistribution utility; and (iv) information notifying the customer how\nthey may compare past bills with what they would have been charged had\nthey received energy services from their respective distribution\nutility, including, the internet address of any bill calculator offered\nby such customer's distribution utility's website.\n  8. Any contract for energy services which does not comply with the\napplicable provisions of this section shall be void and unenforceable as\ncontrary to public policy. Any waiver by a buyer of energy services of\nthe provisions of this section shall be deemed void and unenforceable by\nthe ESCO as contrary to public policy.\n  * 9. The attorney general, upon his or her own motion or upon referral\nfrom the public service commission, the Long Island power authority or\nthe department of state, may bring a civil action against any energy\nservices company that violates any provision of this section and may\nrecover</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a civil penalty not to exceed one thousand dollars per\nviolation; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>costs and reasonable attorney's fees. In any such\nproceeding the court may direct restitution.\n  * NB Effective until June 17, 2026\n  * 9. The first page of each billing statement from an ESCO delivered\nto the customer, either by the ESCO directly or by a utility\ncorporation, by a municipality or by any other method, shall include a\nside-by-side comparison showing both the price charged by the ESCO for\ncommodity and delivery service during the prior billing period, and the\nprice the customer would have paid had they taken commodity and delivery\nservice from their local utility corporation or municipality, as\napplicable.  Such statement shall also include, separately and apart\nfrom the price charged by the ESCO for commodity and delivery service,\nan itemized list of prices charged by the ESCO for any energy-related\nvalue-added products provided by the ESCO during the prior billing\nperiod.\n  * NB Effective June 17, 2026\n  * 10. In addition to the right of action granted to the attorney\ngeneral pursuant to this section, any person who has been injured by\nreason of any violation of this section may bring an action in his or\nher own name to enjoin such unlawful act or practice, an action to\nrecover his or her actual damages or five hundred dollars, whichever is\ngreater, or both such actions. The court may, in its discretion,\nincrease the award of damages to an amount not to exceed three times the\nactual damages up to ten thousand dollars, if the court finds the\ndefendant willfully or knowingly violated this section. The court may\naward reasonable attorney's fees to a prevailing plaintiff.\n  * NB Effective until June 17, 2026\n  * 10. Every twelve months, an ESCO shall provide each of its customers\nwith a statement comparing the price charged by the ESCO for commodity\nand delivery services and other energy-related value-added products over\nthe prior twelve-month period with the price such customer would have\npaid had they taken commodity and ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a civil penalty not to exceed one thousand dollars per\nviolation; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>costs and reasonable attorney's fees. In any such\nproceeding the court may direct restitution.\n  * NB Effective June 17, 2026\n  * 12. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to limit any authority\nof the public service commission or the Long Island power authority,\nwhich existed before the effective date of this section, to adopt\nadditional guidelines, practices, policies, rules or regulations\nrelating to the marketing practices of energy services companies to\nresidential and commercial customers, whether in person (including door\nto door), or by mail, telephone or other electronic means, that are not\ninconsistent with the provisions of this section.\n  * NB Effective until June 17, 2026\n  * 12. In addition to the right of action granted to the attorney\ngeneral pursuant to this section, any person who has been injured by\nreason of any violation of this section may bring an action in their own\nname to enjoin such unlawful act or practice, an action to recover their\nactual damages or five hundred dollars, whichever is greater, or both\nsuch actions. The court may, in its discretion, increase the award of\ndamages to an amount not to exceed three times the actual damages up to\nten thousand dollars, if the court finds the defendant willfully or\nknowingly violated this section. The court may award reasonable\nattorney's fees to a prevailing plaintiff.\n  * NB Effective June 17, 2026\n  * 13. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to limit any authority\nof the public service commission or the Long Island power authority,\nwhich existed before the effective date of this section, to limit,\nsuspend or revoke the eligibility of an energy services company to sell\nor offer for sale any energy services for violation of any provision of\nlaw, rule, regulation or policy enforceable by such commission or\nauthority.\n  * NB Effective June 17, 2026\n  * 14. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to limit any authority\nof the public service commission or the Lo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>