<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-355"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-355"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="355"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-355/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-355/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-355/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-355/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_355">
        <num>355</num>
        <heading>Procedure on hearing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 355. Procedure on hearing. The order for such examination must be\nsigned by the justice making it and service of a copy thereof with an\nendorsement by the attorney-general signed by him or his deputy, to the\neffect that the person named therein is required to appear and be\nexamined at the time and place and before the justice or referee\nspecified in such endorsement, shall be sufficient notice for the\nattendance of witnesses. Such endorsement may contain a clause requiring\nsuch person to produce at such examination all books, papers and\ndocuments in his possession or under his control relating to the subject\nof such examination. The order shall be served upon the person named in\nthe endorsement aforesaid by delivering to and leaving with him a\ncertified copy thereof, endorsed as above provided, subject to the\npayment of witness fees and mileage as and when provided to be paid by\nsection three hundred fifty-two, subdivision three of this article in\nconnection with attendance pursuant to subpoenas authorized to be issued\nunder said action. Service of an order pursuant to section three hundred\nfifty-four of this article may be made under section three hundred\nfifty-two-b of this article in cases falling thereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>