<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-359-EE"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-359-EE"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="359-EE"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-359-EE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-359-EE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-359-EE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-359-EE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_359_EE">
        <num>359-EE</num>
        <heading>Report of existence</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_359_EE__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The name of the dealer, and if it was changed,\nthe name under which last registered.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_359_EE__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The date of the last filing of\nthe dealer's statement in the department of law.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_359_EE__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That its existence\nis hereby continued.  Such certificate shall be signed and certified by\nthe dealer or any principal officer thereof.\n  2. On or before January first, nineteen hundred fifty-nine, notice of\nthe enactment of this section shall be given by the attorney-general to\neach dealer to which this section applies by mailing a copy of such\nnotice to said dealer directed to said dealer at the address stated in\nthe "dealer's statement" filed by said dealer in the department of law\nand then on file there. A copy of this section shall be endorsed or\nannexed to each such notice.\n  3. On March fifteenth, nineteen hundred fifty-nine, the\nattorney-general shall make a list containing the names of all such\ndealers, who have not filed the certificate of report of existence\nrequired by subdivision one of this section.\n  4. The attorney-general shall make a proclamation under his hand and\nseal of office as to the dealers whose names are included in such list,\ndeclaring the "dealers' statements" theretofore filed by such dealers as\nvoid pursuant to the provisions of this section. He shall file the\noriginal proclamation in his office and shall publish a copy thereof in\nthe April or May issue of the state bulletin in the year nineteen\nhundred fifty-nine.\n  5. Upon the publication of such proclamation in the manner aforesaid,\nthe "dealer's statement" of each dealer named therein shall be deemed\nvoid as of May thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-nine, without\nfurther proceedings, except as otherwise provided in subdivision six of\nthis section.\n  6. After this section takes effect, no dealer whose statement has been\nvoided by subdivision five of this section shall sell or offer for sale\nto the public within this state, as principal, broker or agent, or\notherwise, any securities issued or to be issued, unless and until such\ndealer shall have caused to be filed in the department of law a new\n"dealer's statement" as required by section three hundred...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>