<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-360-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-360-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="360-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-360-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-360-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-360-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-360-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_360_E">
        <num>360-E</num>
        <heading>Duration and renewal</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 360-e. Duration and renewal. A registration of mark hereunder shall\nbe effective for a term of ten years from the date of registration and,\nupon application filed within six months prior to the expiration of such\nterm, in a manner complying with the requirements of the secretary, the\nregistration may be renewed for a like term from the end of the expiring\nterm. A renewal fee, payable to the secretary, shall accompany the\napplication for renewal of the registration. A registration may be\nrenewed for successive periods of ten years in like manner. Any\nregistration in force on the date on which this article shall become\neffective shall continue in full force and effect for the unexpired term\nthereof and may be renewed by filing an application for renewal with the\nsecretary complying with the requirements of the secretary and paying\nthe aforementioned renewal fee therefor within six months prior to the\nexpiration of the registration.  All applications for renewal under this\narticle, whether of registrations made under this article or of\nregistrations effected under any prior law, shall include a verified\nstatement that the mark has been and is still in use and include a\nspecimen showing actual use of the mark on or in connection with the\ngoods or services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>