<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-390-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-390-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="390-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-390-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-390-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-390-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-390-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_390_E">
        <num>390-E</num>
        <heading>Unauthorized installation of certain security devices prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 390-e. Unauthorized installation of certain security devices\nprohibited. No person, firm, partnership, association or corporation\nshall install any keyless security device used to control and secure\naccess to the common areas of any residential building without the\nexpress written consent of the owner, board of managers, board of\ndirectors, or authorized party of such property. Where a keyless\nsecurity device has been authorized, any installation of such device\nshall be performed by, or with the consent of, the owner, property\nmanager, board of managers, board of directors, or authorized party in\nplace in such building. The owner, board of managers, board of\ndirectors, or authorized party of such property consenting to the\ninstallation of a keyless security device shall provide written notice\nto occupants of the residential building no less than thirty days prior\nto installation of the keyless security device, which may be made by\ndelivering a notice to each unit, either via physical or electronic\nmeans, or by posting the notice in a conspicuous location in each common\narea accessible to residents for a thirty-day period. Where notice is\nprescribed by the certificate of incorporation or the by-laws of a\ncooperative or condominium, the owner, board of managers, board of\ndirectors or other authorized party may instead comply with the\ncertificate of incorporation or by-laws. In no event shall the\ninstallation of such a system be considered a service nor be considered\na reason, for any purpose, to increase rent. In no event shall the\ninstallation of such a system obstruct or adversely impact the manner in\nwhich residents of the residential building access such building.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 390-e's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>