<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="391-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_391_L">
        <num>391-L</num>
        <heading>Personal emergency response service agreements; required cancellation provisions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the provision and maintenance\nof electronic communication equipment in the home of an individual which\nsignals a monitoring agency for help when activated by the individual,\nor after a period of time if a timer mechanism has not been reset;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe continuous monitoring of such signals by a trained operator and, in\ncase of receipt of such signal, the immediate notification of such\nemergency response organizations or persons, if necessary, as the\nindividual has previously specified.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any right otherwise to revoke an offer, the\npurchaser or other person obligated for any part of the purchase price\nor price for service for obtaining a personal emergency response service\nmay cancel the sale or purchase thereof with or without cause at any\ntime until midnight of the seventh business day after the day on which\nthe purchaser has signed an agreement or offer to purchase relating to\nsuch sale or purchase, without any penalty or obligation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the cancellation right created by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, the agreement providing for obtaining such service may\nbe cancelled by the purchaser or other person obligated for any part of\nthe purchase price or price for such service, upon thirty days prior\nwritten notice to the seller or supplier of such service, that the\npurchaser of such service has legally obligated himself or herself to\ncommence residence in a nursing home or other health-related facility\nwithin such thirty-day period for what is expected to be a permanent\nstay or an extended stay of at least two months duration, or that\nresidence therein with such expectation has already commenced.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cancellation under the terms of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\ntwo of this section occurs when written notice of cancellation is given\nto the seller or provider of such service. Cancellation under the terms\nof such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall be governed by the requirements of the\n"door-to-door sales protection act" contained in article ten-A of the\npersonal property law, whether or not such sale is a "door-to-door sale"\nas defined therein, except where such requirements are inconsistent with\nthe provisions of this section, in which case the provisions of this\nsection shall prevail, and except that the transactional exclusions from\nthe definition of "door-to-door sale" contained in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthrough</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section four hundred twenty-six of the\npersonal property law shall not apply to the sale or purchase of a\npersonal emergency response service as defined herein.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cancellation under the terms of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two\nof this section occurs upon the thirtieth day after written notice of\ncancellation is given to the seller or provider of such service. Upon\nthe occurrence of cancellation under such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, the purchaser\nor other person obligated for the purchaser shall remain obligated under\nsuch agreement to pay for the use of such service only for the period of\ntime during which the service was provided prior to the occurrence of\ncancellation thereunder. For this purpose, under such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nprice agreed to for the entire term of such agreement shall be prorated\nby multiplying such price by a fraction, the numerator of which is the\nperiod of time during which such service was provided prior to the\noccurrence of cancellation, and the denominator of which is the entire\nterm of such agreement. Any overpayment made in advance for the\nprovision of such service, the amount of which is determined by such\nproration shall be refunded to the purchaser or other person obligated\nfor the purchaser, as the case may be, within ten business days from the\ndate of the occurrence of cancellation under such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>. Such\ncancellation shall be without penalty to or other obligation on the part\nof, the purchaser or other person obligated for the purchaser.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Written notice of cancellation, if given by first-class mail,\nshall be deemed given when deposited in a mailbox properly addressed and\nadequate postage prepaid. Such written notice under the terms of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section shall be effective\nirrespective of the form of such written notice if it indicates the\nintention of the purchaser or other person obligated not to be bound.\nWritten notice of cancellation under the terms of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision two of this section, to be effective irrespective of the\nform of such written notice shall, in addition to indicating an\nintention not to be bound, state the date of expected commencement or\ncommencement of residence in such nursing home or other health-related\nfacility, the expected duration of such residence, and the name and\naddress of such home or facility, and include with such notice a signed\nnote from such person's physician or from the home or facility, or a\ncopy of such person's agreement with such home or other facility,\nverifying that the terms of such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for cancellation have\nbeen satisfied.\n  4. In a sale or purchase of a personal emergency response service, the\nseller shall furnish to the purchaser:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a fully completed receipt or copy of any agreement pertaining to\nsuch sale at the time of its execution, which is in the same language,\ne.g. Spanish, as that principally used in any oral sales presentation\nand which shows the date of the transaction and contains the name and\naddress of the seller, and in immediate proximity to the space reserved\nin the contract for the signature of the purchaser or on the front page\nof the receipt if an agreement is not used and in not less than\nten-point boldface type, statements in substantially the following form:\n  "I. YOU, THE PURCHASER, MAY CANCEL THIS TRANSACTION WITH OR WITHOUT\nCAUSE AT ANY TIME PRIOR TO MIDNIGHT OF THE SEVENTH BUSINESS DAY AFTER\nTHE DATE OF THIS TRANSACTION."\n  "II. ON AND AFTER MIDNIGHT OF SUCH SEVENTH DAY, YOU, THE PURCHASER,\nMAY CANCEL YOUR AGREEMENT WITH THE SELLER FOR YOU TO RECEIVE PERSONAL\nEMERGENCY RESPONSE SERVICE MORE THAN 30 DAYS AFTER YOUR NOTIFYING THE\nSELLER IN WRITING OF YOUR CANCELLING SUCH AGREEMENT, PROVIDED THAT YOU\nHAVE LEGALLY OBLIGATED YOURSELF TO BEGIN LIVING IN A NURSING HOME OR\nOTHER HEALTH-RELATED FACILITY WITHIN SUCH 30-DAY PERIOD FOR WHAT IS\nEXPECTED TO BE A PERMANENT STAY OR AN EXTENDED STAY FOR AT LEAST 2\nMONTHS, OR THAT YOU HAVE ALREADY BEGUN LIVING THEREIN EXPECTING YOUR\nSTAY TO BE PERMANENT OR FOR AT LEAST 2 MONTHS, AND PROVIDED THAT THESE\nFACTS ARE VERIFIED BY YOUR DOCTOR OR BY THE NURSING HOME OR OTHER\nHEALTH-RELATED FACILITY."\n  "SEE THE ATTACHED NOTICE OF CANCELLATION FORM FOR AN EXPLANATION OF\nTHESE RIGHTS."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at the time the purchaser signs the contract to obtain the\npersonal emergency response service or otherwise agrees to purchase such\nservice from the seller, a completed form in duplicate, captioned\n"NOTICE OF CANCELLATION", which shall be attached to the contract or\nreceipt and easily detachable, and which shall contain in not less than\nten-point boldface type the following information and statements in the\nsame language, e.g. Spanish, as that used in the contract:\n                          NOTICE OF CANCELLATION\n             _______________________________________________\n                    (enter date of transaction here)\n  I. YOU MAY CANCEL THIS TRANSACTION, WITHOUT ANY PENALTY OR OBLIGATION,\nWITHIN SEVEN</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>BUSINESS DAYS FROM THE ABOVE DATE.\n  IF YOU CANCEL UNDER THIS FIRST RIGHT TO CANCEL, ANY PROPERTY TRADED\nIN, ANY PAYMENTS MADE BY YOU UNDER THE CONTRACT OR SALE, AND ANY\nNEGOTIABLE INSTRUMENT EXECUTED BY YOU WILL BE RETURNED WITHIN TEN</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_391_L__subsec_b__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nBUSINESS DAYS FOLLOWING RECEIPT BY THE SELLER OF YOUR CANCELLATION\nNOTICE, AND ANY SECURITY INTEREST ARISING OUT OF THE TRANSACTION WILL BE\nCANCELLED.\n  II. IN ADDITION TO THE ABOVE RIGHT TO CANCEL THE TRANSACTION, YOU OR\nANOTHER PERSON OBLIGATED FOR ANY PART OF THE PURCHASE PRICE OR PRICE FOR\nSUCH SERVICE MAY ALSO CANCEL YOUR AGREEMENT WITH THE SELLER PROVIDING\nFOR YOUR OBTAINING OF SUCH SERVICE EFFECTIVE UPON THE 30TH DAY AFTER\nGIVING WRITTEN NOTICE TO SUCH SELLER OR SUPPLIER OF THE SERVICE, THAT\nYOU HAVE LEGALLY OBLIGATED YOURSELF TO COMMENCE RESIDENCE IN A NURSING\nHOME OR OTHER HEALTH-RELATED FACILITY WITHIN THE NEXT 30 DAYS FOR WHAT\nIS EXPECTED TO BE A PERMANENT STAY OR AN EXTENDED STAY OF AT LEAST 2\nMONTHS DURATION, OR THAT YOUR RESIDENCE THEREIN WITH SUCH EXPECTATION\nHAS ALREADY COMMENCED.\n  YOU MAY DO SO PROVIDED THAT IN SUCH WRITTEN NOTICE OF CANCELLATION YOU\nINDICATE AN INTENTION NOT TO BE BOUND, STATE THE DATE OF EXPECTED\nCOMMENCEMENT OR DATE OF ACTUAL COMME...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>