<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="391-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_391_CC">
        <num>391-CC</num>
        <heading>Sale of bicycles with electric assist and micromobility devices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 391-cc. Sale of bicycles with electric assist and micromobility\ndevices. 1. As used in this section, "micromobility device" shall mean\nan electric scooter as defined in section one hundred fourteen-e of the\nvehicle and traffic law, an electrical personal assistive mobility\ndevice as defined in section one hundred fourteen-d of the vehicle and\ntraffic law, or other personal mobility device that has an electric\nmotor. The term micromobility device shall not include bicycles with\nelectric assist as defined by section one hundred two-c of the vehicle\nand traffic law, limited use motorcycles as defined in section one\nhundred twenty-one-b of the vehicle and traffic law, wheelchairs or\nother electrically driven mobility assistance devices as defined in\nsection one hundred thirty-a of the vehicle and traffic law, or any\nvehicle that is capable of being registered with the department of motor\nvehicles.\n  2. No person, firm, partnership, association, or corporation shall\nsell or offer for sale at retail any bicycle with electric assist as\ndefined by section one hundred two-c of the vehicle and traffic law or\nmicromobility device to any person, firm, partnership, association, or\ncorporation, without supplying a notice to be affixed to such bicycle\nwith electric assist or micromobility device by the person, firm,\npartnership, association, or corporation. Such notice shall have an\nadhesive backing, be made from common materials used to affix other\ncomparable notices or stickers to vehicles and be printed in English and\nthe two most common non-English languages spoken in the state, based on\nthe data in the most recent American Community Survey published by the\nUnited States Census Bureau. Such notice shall read:\n  "NOTICE: Always yield to pedestrians and follow traffic laws. Riding\non the sidewalk may be illegal; consult local laws."\n  3. The department of state, in consultation with appropriate state\nagencies, shall promulgate rules and regulations necessary to implement\nthe provisions of this section.\n  4. Violation of this section by the retail entity pursuant to\nsubdivision two of this section shall be punishable by a fine of not\nmore than two hundred fifty dollars per stocking unit for the first\noffense and not more than one thousand dollars per stocking unit for\neach subsequent offense.\n  5. This section shall not annul, alter, affect, or exempt any person,\nfirm, partnership, corporation, or association, subject to the\nprovisions of this section from complying with the laws, ordinances,\nrules, or regulations of any locality, relating to the affixing,\nlabeling, or provision of identification, safety, informational, or\nother materials.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>