<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="391-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_391_I">
        <num>391-I</num>
        <heading>Sale of urea-formaldehyde foam insulation; notice</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 391-i. Sale of urea-formaldehyde foam insulation; notice. 1.  As\nused in this section, the term "urea-formaldehyde foam insulation" shall\nmean urea-formaldehyde based, foamed-in-place insulation.\n  2. Any person, firm or corporation which sells or installs\nurea-formaldehyde foam insulation shall give written notice to the\npurchaser of such insulation or the owner of the building wherein such\ninsulation is installed, stating as follows:\n  "This insulation is urea-formaldehyde based and may emit formaldehyde.\nAfter installation of this product, some people have experienced adverse\nphysical effects from formaldehyde emissions, including unpleasant odor,\nwatery eyes, and nose and throat irritations. These conditions may be\nalleviated by introducing fresh air into the building. Exposure to\nurea-formaldehyde foam insulation is not recommended for persons who\nhave been previously sensitized to formaldehyde, or who have a history\nof respiratory problems.  Urea-formaldehyde foam insulation is not\nrecommended for use in attics, below grade or wall cavities deeper than\nsix inches.  Urea-formaldehyde foam is not recommended unless the\noutside vertical walls have an air source.\n                YOU MAY CANCEL THIS SALE WITHIN THREE DAYS\nTo cancel the sale, you must notify the company in writing anytime\nbefore midnight of the third business day after the contract date.  No\nexplanation is necessary for cancellation."\n  3. Such notice shall be printed or written in a size equal to at least\nten point type and be placed at the beginning of any sales contract.\n  4.  Violation of this section shall be punishable by a civil penalty\nof not more than two hundred fifty dollars for the first offense and not\nmore than one thousand dollars for each subsequent offense.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>