<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="391-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-391-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_391_J">
        <num>391-J</num>
        <heading>Sale of fire extinguishers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 391-j. Sale of fire extinguishers. 1. It shall be unlawful for any\nperson, firm or corporation to sell or offer for sale fire extinguishers\nunless the fire extinguishers offered for sale:\n  a. Meet the current National Fire Protection Association standards for\nfire extinguishers of the model offered for sale and are labelled as\nhaving met such standards;\n  b. Have been tested and approved by the Underwriters Laboratory,\nFactory Mutual or other nationally accredited or accepted testing\nlaboratory and are labelled as having been tested and approved;\n  c. Have labelling securely affixed containing the following\ninformation:\n  (1) Operating instructions.\n  (2) The class or rating identifying kinds of fires which the\nparticular extinguisher is suitable to use. This information shall be\npresented by use of the appropriate letter rating and pictorial marking\nrepresentations.\n  d. Are accompanied with an instructional manual that has information\ndetailing operational use, basic fire safety information, information on\nhow and where to have the extinguisher serviced or recharged by an\nauthorized dealer or refer the customer to his local fire department and\nany information pertaining to checking the extinguisher's contents for\noperational use by the owner.\n  2. A knowing violation of this section shall be punishable by a civil\npenalty not to exceed five hundred dollars for a first violation and ten\nthousand dollars for each succeeding violation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>