<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="392-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_392_E">
        <num>392-E</num>
        <heading>Using false statements or altering mileage registering devices</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_392_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person, firm, partnership, or corporation shall, prior to\nthe transfer of ownership of a motor vehicle, misrepresent by any\nstatement, express or implied and which in fact is false, the mileage\nsaid motor vehicle purports to have been operated as the same appears on\nthe odometer in such motor vehicle. Nothing contained herein shall be\ndeemed to supercede the provisions of any other subdivision of this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_392_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A violation of this subdivision shall be subject to a fine not to\nexceed five hundred dollars for each violation; provided, however, that\na knowing or willful violation of this subdivision shall be subject to a\nfine not to exceed one thousand five hundred dollars for each such\nviolation. No person, firm, partnership, or corporation shall be deemed\nto have violated this subdivision where the vehicle is sold, offered for\nsale, or advertised for sale in reliance on the required statement of\nthe prior owner and pursuant to the provisions of subdivisions one, two,\nthree and four of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_392_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless the misrepresentation was made with an intent to defraud,\nthe provisions of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_392_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_392_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall not\napply to a statement made regarding a vehicle the most current ownership\ndocument for which is a salvage certificate or like document issued by a\nstate or jurisdiction or regarding a vehicle sold by a salvage pool\nregistered under section four hundred fifteen-a of the vehicle and\ntraffic law.\n  3. Nothing herein contained shall prevent the service, repair or\nreplacement of a mileage registering device, provided the mileage\nindicated thereon remains the same as before the service, repair or\nreplacement; or provided the mileage registering device reads zero and a\nnotice in writing is attached to the left front door frame of the\nvehicle by the owner or his agent, indicating the mileage prior to\nreplacement and the date on which it was replaced. Any unauthorized\nremoval of such notice so affixed shall constitute a violation of\nsubdivision two of section three hundred ninety-two-e.\n  4. This section shall not apply to new motor vehicles. A new motor\nvehicle is one sold or transferred by a manufacturer, distributor or\ndealer and which has not been placed in consumer use or has not been\nused as a demonstrator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>