<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="392-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-392-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_392_B">
        <num>392-B</num>
        <heading>False labels and misrepresentations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 392-b. False labels and misrepresentations. A person, who with\nintent to defraud:\n  1. Puts upon an article of merchandise, or upon a cask, bottle,\nstopper, vessel, case, cover, wrapper, package, band, ticket, label or\nother thing, containing or covering such an article, or with which such\nan article is intended to be sold, or is sold, any false description or\nother indication of or respecting the kind, number, quantity, weight or\nmeasure of such article, or any part thereof, or the place or country\nwhere it was manufactured or produced or the quality or grade of any\nsuch article, if the quality or grade thereof is required by law to be\nmarked, branded or otherwise indicated on or with such article; or\n  2. Sells or offers for sale an article, which to his knowledge is\nfalsely described or indicated upon any such package, or vessel\ncontaining the same, or label thereupon, in any of the particulars\nspecified; or\n  3. Sells or exposes for sale any goods in bulk to which no name or\ntrademark shall be attached, and orally or otherwise represents that\nsuch goods are the manufacture or production of some other than the\nactual manufacturer or producer, in a case where the punishment for such\noffense is not specially provided for otherwise by statute, is guilty of\na misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>