<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-06-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="393-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_393_F">
        <num>393-F</num>
        <heading>Voluntary third-party notification</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 393-f. Voluntary third-party notification. 1. Every telegraph or\ntelephone corporation, cable television corporation, or municipality\nshall permit a residential customer to designate a third party to\nreceive notice of the total amount due or past due on all bills, the\namounts of any payments paid by or on behalf of such residential\ncustomer, and copies of all notices relating to termination of service\nand notices relating to collection of amounts due sent to such\nresidential customer, provided that the designated third party indicates\nin writing a willingness to receive such notices, and provided further,\nwhere a residential customer opts for third-party notifications, such\nresidential customer may opt to continue to receive such notices.\n  2. Every cellular phone company, upon request by a customer, shall\npermit such customer to designate a third party to receive notice in\naccordance with subdivision one of this section. Such notice shall\ncomply with all requirements related to the protection of customer\nproprietary network information contained in the federal communications\nact of 1934 (47 U.S.C. 222) and any federal regulations adopted under\nthat authority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>