<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="393"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-393/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_393">
        <num>393</num>
        <heading>Lime; standard barrels</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 393. Lime; standard barrels. There is hereby established a large and\na small barrel of lime, the large barrel to consist of two hundred and\neighty pounds and the small barrel to consist of one hundred and eighty\npounds, net weight. It shall be unlawful for any person to sell or offer\nfor sale lime, unless there shall be stencilled or otherwise clearly\nmarked on one or both heads of the small barrel the figures "180 lbs.\nnet" and of the large barrel the figures "280 lbs. net," and on either\nbarrel in addition the name of the manufacturer of the lime and where\nmanufactured. When lime is sold in containers of less capacity than the\nstandard small barrel, it shall be sold in fractional parts of said\nstandard small barrel, and the net weight of lime contained in such\ncontainer shall by stencil or otherwise be clearly marked thereon,\ntogether with the name of the manufacturer thereof, and the name of the\nbrand, if any, under which it is sold. It shall be unlawful to pack,\nsell, or offer for sale any barrels or other containers of lime which\nare not marked as provided in this act, or to sell, charge for, or\npurport to deliver as a large or small barrel or a fractional part of\nsaid small barrel of lime, any less weight of lime than is established\nby the provisions of this section. Any person violating any of the\nprovisions of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>