<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-394-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-394-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="394-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-394-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-394-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-394-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-394-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_394_E">
        <num>394-E</num>
        <heading>Report on request for abortional services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_394_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a law enforcement agency, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_394_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state department of health or\nthe department of health of the city of New York, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_394_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>authorized in\nwriting by the subject of such report, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_394_E__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>unless such person, firm\nor corporation shall have been ordered to furnish such report by a duly\nconstituted court having jurisdiction to issue such an order. Every\nrequest for such a report shall be in writing and identify the name and\naddress of the requestor. A request by a law enforcement agency shall\ninclude a sworn statement that the agency is requesting the report\nsolely for law enforcement purposes.\n  2. A person may bring a civil action for damages or to restrain a\nperson, firm or corporation from violating this act or both and, in such\ncase, if it is found that such person, firm or corporation has wilfully\nviolated this act the violator shall, in addition to any liability for\nactual damages as may be shown, be liable for exemplary damages of not\nless than one hundred dollars and not more than ten thousand dollars for\neach violation together with costs and reasonable attorney's fees and\ndisbursements incurred by the person bringing the action.\n  3. Except as provided in this section, no person, firm or corporation\nshall be entitled to claim any privilege, absolute or qualified as a\ndefense in any civil action brought by a person aggrieved by the\npublication or dissemination of information relating to referral for\nabortional services or an inquiry or request therefor.\n  4. Any person who requests or obtains a report of a referral for\nabortional services or an inquiry or request therefor from any person,\nfirm or corporation under false pretenses or furnishes a report to any\nperson except in accordance with this section shall be guilty of a class\nA misdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>