<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-395-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-395-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="395-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-395-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-395-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-395-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-395-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_395_B">
        <num>395-B</num>
        <heading>Unlawfully installing or maintaining a two-way mirror or other viewing device</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_395_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>public correctional or custodial facility, or public or private\nmedical facility which is used for the treatment of persons pursuant to\nmedical directive, or\n  (ii) public or private treatment facility which is used for the\ntreatment of persons who are committed or are voluntarily confined to\nsuch facility or are voluntarily receiving treatment thereat, or\n  (iii) facility operated by any federal, state or local law enforcement\nagency, or\n  (iv) private dwelling.\n  b. The provisions of this section shall further not apply with respect\nto any fitting room, otherwise subject to the provisions of this\nsection, wherein the person who is the owner or manager of such premises\nhas caused written notice to be conspicuously posted at the entrance to\nthe fitting room stating that a two-way mirror or other viewing device\nhas been installed for the purpose of observing the interior of such\nroom. In cities with a population of one million or more, the written\nnotice shall be in both English and Spanish.\n  4. Whenever there shall be a violation of this section, an application\nmay also be made by the attorney general in the name of the people of\nthe state of New York or by the corporation counsel for any city or by\nthe appropriate attorney of any other political subdivision as shall be\ndesignated by the governing body of such political subdivision to a\ncourt or justice having jurisdiction to issue an injunction, and upon\nnotice to the defendant of not less than five days, to enjoin and\nrestrain the continuance of such violation; and if it shall appear to\nthe satisfaction of the court or justice that the defendant has, in\nfact, violated this section, an injunction may be issued by such court\nor justice, enjoining and restraining any further violation, without\nrequiring proof that any person has, in fact, been injured or damaged\nthereby. In connection with any such proposed application, the attorney\ngeneral, corporation counsel or other appropriate atto...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>