<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="396-K*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_396_K*2">
        <num>396-K*2</num>
        <heading>Sale of certain motor vehicles damaged by the ravages of natural disaster</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 396-k. Sale of certain motor vehicles damaged by the ravages of\nnatural disaster. No person, firm or corporation shall knowingly sell in\nthis state any motor vehicle the mechanical or electrical system of\nwhich has been previously damaged by the ravages of a natural disaster\nsuch as fire, flood, hurricane, landslide, earthquake, windstorm or\nother storm, to an extent which rendered the vehicle inoperable for any\nperiod of time, unless notice, in writing, of the fact of such damage,\nthe nature and extent thereof and the date and location in which it\noccurred is first given to each buyer of such motor vehicle. For the\npurposes of this section, a vehicle shall be deemed to have been\nrendered inoperable if, as a result of the damage caused by the natural\ndisaster, it would be necessary for such vehicle to undergo repair in\norder to pass inspection in the manner provided in article five of the\nvehicle and traffic law.\n  A violation of this section shall constitute a class B misdemeanor.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 396-k's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>