<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-BB"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-BB"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="396-BB"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_396_BB">
        <num>396-BB</num>
        <heading>Sale of motor fuels to disabled persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 396-bb. Sale of motor fuels to disabled persons.  1. Any person,\nfirm or corporation owning or operating a premises or facility for the\nretail sale of motor fuels for use in motor vehicles and offering self\nservice and full service at the same time, shall, between the hours of\nseven o'clock in the morning and seven o'clock in the evening, provide\nfull service of such motor fuels to disabled persons with a valid New\nYork state disabled person license plate or a valid parking permit for\nhandicapped persons issued pursuant to section twelve hundred three-a of\nthe vehicle and traffic law at the same price charged for such motor\nfuels at the self service islands and shall post a notice in a manner\nand in at least one location which is conspicuous to a person seeking\nrefueling service, including a depiction of the international symbol of\naccess and stating as follows:\n               Full service at self service prices\n               7 a.m. to 7 p.m.\n        Such notice may also further state,\n               For persons with a valid New York state disabled license\n               plate or a valid parking permit for handicapped persons.\n  2. For purposes of this section "disabled person" shall mean a\nregistered owner or authorized operator of a motor vehicle who has been\nissued special license tags by the state or a valid parking permit for\nhandicapped persons issued pursuant to section twelve hundred three-a of\nthe vehicle and traffic law.\n  3. Any violation of this section shall result in a civil fine of not\nmore than one hundred dollars to be collected by the corporation counsel\nfor any city or by the appropriate attorney of any political subdivision\nas shall be designated by the governing body of such political\nsubdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>