<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="396-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_396_K">
        <num>396-K</num>
        <heading>Hazardous toys and other articles intended primarily for use by children; prohibition and enforcement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Child" means any person less than fourteen years of age;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A toy or other article presents an electrical hazard if, in normal\nuse or when subjected to reasonably foreseeable damage or abuse, its\ndesign or manufacture may cause personal injury or illness by electrical\nshock or electrocution;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A toy or other article presents a mechanical hazard if, in normal\nuse or when subjected to reasonably foreseeable damage or abuse, its\ndesign or manufacture presents an unreasonable risk of personal injury\nor illness:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>from fracture, fragmentation or disassembly of the article;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>from propulsion of the article or any part or accessory thereof;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>from points or other protrusions, surfaces, edges, openings or\nclosures;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>from moving parts;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>from lack or insufficiency of controls to reduce or stop motion;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>as a result of self-adhering characteristics of the article;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>because the article or any part or accessory thereof may be\naspirated or ingested;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>because of instability;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>from stuffing material which is not free of dangerous or harmful\nsubstances; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_K__subsec_c__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>because of any other aspect of the article's design or\nmanufacture.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_K__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A toy or other article presents a thermal hazard if, in normal use\nor when subjected to reasonably foreseeable damage or abuse, its design\nor manufacture presents an unreasonable risk to personal injury or\nillness because of heat as from heated parts, substances or surfaces.\n  2. Whenever the attorney general shall believe from evidence\nsatisfactory to him that any person, firm, corporation or association or\nagent or employee thereof has violated any provision of this section, he\nmay bring an action in the supreme court of the state of New York for a\njudgment enjoining the continuance of such violation and for a civil\npenalty of not more than one thousand dollars for each violation, except\nthat the court may impose a civil penalty of not more than four thousand\ndollars if the violation is knowing and willful. If it shall appear to\nthe satisfaction of the court or justice that the defendant has violated\nany provision of this section, no proof shall be required that any\nperson has been injured thereby nor that the defendant knowingly or\nintentionally violated such provision. In such action preliminary relief\nmay be granted under article sixty-three of the civil practice law and\nrules.\n  3. Before any violation of this section is sought to be enjoined, the\nattorney general shall be required to give the person against whom such\nproceeding is contemplated notice by certified mail and an opportunity\nto show in writing within five business days after receipt of notice why\nproceedings should not be instituted against him, unless the attorney\ngeneral shall find, in any case in which he seeks preliminary relief,\nthat to give such notice and opportunity is not in the public interest.\n  4. In any such action it shall be a complete defense that the toy or\nother article sought to be enjoined either complies with, or is exempt\nunder, the federal "Child Protection and Toy Safety Act of 1969", as\namended, or the federal "Consumer Product Safety Act", as a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>