<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="396-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_396_CC">
        <num>396-CC</num>
        <heading>Notification of enclosure requirements for swimming pools</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"New York state uniform fire prevention and building code" means\nthe uniform fire prevention and building code promulgated under section\nthree hundred seventy-seven of the executive law.\n  (ii) "building code of the city of New York" shall mean the building\ncode of the city of New York as defined in titles twenty-seven and\ntwenty-eight of the administrative code of the city of New York.\n  2. Any person, firm, association or corporation who or which violates\nthe provisions of subdivision one of this section shall be subject to a\ncivil penalty of not more than one thousand dollars for each such\nviolation.\n  3. a. Upon any violation of the provisions of subdivision one of this\nsection, an application may be made by the attorney general in the name\nof the people of the state of New York to a court or justice having\njurisdiction to issue an injunction, and upon notice to the defendant of\nnot less than five days, to enjoin and restrain the continuance of the\nviolation. If it shall appear to the satisfaction of the court or\njustice that the defendant has violated subdivision one of this section,\nan injunction may be issued by the court or justice, enjoining and\nrestraining any further violation, without requiring proof that any\nperson has, in fact, been injured or damaged thereby. In any such\nproceeding, the court may make allowances to the attorney general as\nprovided in paragraph six of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eight thousand\nthree hundred three of the civil practice law and rules, and direct\nrestitution.\n  b. In connection with an application made under paragraph a of this\nsubdivision, the attorney general is authorized to take proof and to\nmake a determination of the relevant facts and to issue subpoenas in\naccordance with the civil practice law and rules.\n  4. The provisions of subdivision one of this section may be enforced\nconcurrently by the director of a municipal consumer affairs office, or\nby the town attorney, city corporation counsel, or other lawful designee\nof a municipality or local government, and all moneys collected\nthereunder shall be retained by such municipality or local government.\n  5. Nothing in this section shall be construed to expand, limit, or\notherwise affect the authority of municipalities to adopt more\nrestrictive standards for the construction or installation of swimming\npools pursuant to section three hundred seventy-nine of the executive\nlaw.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 396-cc's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>