<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="396-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_396_F">
        <num>396-F</num>
        <heading>Sale of blind made products</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Blind" shall mean a person having central visual acuity not to\nexceed 20/200 in the better eye, with correcting lenses, or visual\nacuity greater than 20/200, but with a limitation in the field of\nvision, such that the widest diameter of the visual field subtends an\nangle no greater than twenty degrees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Blind made products" shall mean the goods, wares and merchandise\nin the manufacture of which not less than seventy-five per cent of the\ntotal hours of direct labor is performed by a blind person or persons.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_F__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Manufacture" shall mean the preparation, processing and\nassemblying of goods, wares or merchandise intended for resale and shall\ninclude the manufacture of component materials.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_F__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Direct labor" shall mean all work required for the manufacture of\nblind made products, but shall not include time spent in the\nsupervision, administration, inspection and shipping of such product,\nnor shall it include work by blind persons consisting solely of the\npackaging of goods, wares and merchandise not manufactured by blind\npersons. However, nothing in this section shall preclude preferred bid\nstatus for the value added portion of any product that has been in part\nor solely packaged or assembled by blind or other severely handicapped\npersons.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_F__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Commission" shall mean the New York State commission for the\nvisually handicapped.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_F__subsec_e__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Registration requirement. Any person engaged in the manufacture or\ndistribution of blind made products shall apply to the commission on\nforms provided by it for a registration and authorization to use an\nofficial imprint, stamp, symbol or label, designed or approved by the\ncommission, to identify goods and articles as being blind made products.\nThe commission shall investigate each application, to assure that such\nperson is actually engaged in the manufacture or distribution of blind\nmade products. The commission may register, without investigation,\nnonresident persons upon proof that they are recognized and approved by\nthe state of their residence or organization pursuant to a law of such\nstate imposing requirements substantially similar to those prescribed\npursuant to this section.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_F__subsec_e__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Identification of blind made products. No goods or articles made\nin this or any other state shall be displayed, advertised, offered for\nsale or sold in this state upon a representation that the same are blind\nmade products unless the same are identified as such by label, imprint,\nstamp or symbol designed or approved by the commission.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_396_F__subsec_e__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Violations. Any person who shall willfully either:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>use or employ an imprint, stamp, symbol or label designed or\napproved by the commission or an imitation thereof without having\nregistered with the commission or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>who shall directly or indirectly by any means represent that the\ngoods, wares or merchandise are blind made products when in fact such is\nnot the case, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>