<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-Y"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-Y"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="396-Y"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_396_Y">
        <num>396-Y</num>
        <heading>Sale of certain personal property; incentives; disclosure of value</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_396_Y__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eighty-three\nhundred three of the civil practice law and rules, and direct\nrestitution. Whenever the court shall determine that a violation of this\nsection has occurred, the court may impose a civil penalty of not more\nthan five hundred dollars for each violation. In connection with any\nsuch proposed application the attorney general is authorized to take\nproof and make a determination of the relevant facts and to issue\nsubpoenas in accordance with the civil practice law and rules.\n  d. Nothing in this section shall be construed so as to nullify or\nimpair any right or rights which a consumer may have against a merchant\nat common law, by statute, or otherwise, nor to impair the ability of\nthe attorney general to institute investigations and proceedings, where\nappropriate, as provided in article twenty-three-A of this chapter, nor\nto eliminate the requirements that may be imposed upon a merchant under\nsuch article.\n  e. An action shall not be brought under this section more than six\nyears after the occurrence of the act, method or practice which is the\nsubject of the action or more than one year after the last payment in a\ntransaction involving the method, act or practice which is the subject\nof the action, whichever is later.\n  f. Any covenant, promise, agreement or understanding in, or in\nconnection with or collateral to a sale or offering for sale of consumer\ngoods, subject to the provisions of this section, purporting to\nacknowledge that a gift, bonus or other inducement received by a\nconsumer in connection with a sale or offering for sale of consumer\ngoods was not an incentive as defined herein, or otherwise purporting to\ndirectly or indirectly waive the provisions of this section, is against\npublic policy and is void and unenforceable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>