<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-EE"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-EE"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="396-EE"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-EE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-EE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-EE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-396-EE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_396_EE">
        <num>396-EE</num>
        <heading>Sale of certain weapons; locking devices therefor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 396-ee. Sale of certain weapons; locking devices therefor. (1) No\nperson, firm or corporation engaged in the retail business of selling\nrifles, shotguns or firearms, as such terms are defined in section\n265.00 of the penal law, shall sell, deliver or transfer any such rifle,\nshotgun or firearm to another person unless the transferee is provided\nat the time of sale, delivery or transfer with a gun locking device and\na label containing the quoted language specified in subdivision two of\nthis section is either affixed to such rifle, shotgun or firearm or\nplaced in the container in which such rifle, shotgun or firearm is sold,\ndelivered or transferred. For the purposes of this section, the term\n"gun locking device" shall mean an integrated design feature or an\nattachable accessory that is resistant to tampering and is effective in\npreventing the discharge of such rifle, shotgun or firearm by a person\nwho does not have access to the key, combination or other mechanism used\nto disengage the device. The division of state police shall develop and\npromulgate rules and regulations setting forth the specific devices or\nthe minimum standards and criteria therefor which constitute an\neffective gun locking device.\n  (2) Every person, firm or corporation engaged in the retail business\nof selling rifles, shotguns or firearms, as such terms are defined in\nsection 265.00 of the penal law, shall, in the place where such rifles,\nshotguns or firearms are displayed or transferred to the purchaser, post\na notice conspicuously stating in bold print that: "RESPONSIBLE FIREARM\nSTORAGE IS THE LAW IN NEW YORK STATE. RIFLES, SHOTGUNS AND FIREARMS MUST\nEITHER BE STORED WITH A GUN LOCKING DEVICE OR IN A SAFE STORAGE\nDEPOSITORY OR NOT BE LEFT OUTSIDE THE IMMEDIATE POSSESSION AND CONTROL\nOF THE OWNER OR OTHER LAWFUL POSSESSOR IF A CHILD RESIDES IN THE HOME OR\nIS PRESENT, OR IF THE OWNER OR POSSESSOR RESIDES WITH A PERSON\nPROHIBITED FROM POSSESSING A RIFLE, SHOTGUN OR FIREARM UNDER STATE OR\nFEDERAL LAW. RIFLES, SHOTGUNS AND FIREARMS SHOULD BE STORED UNLOADED AND\nLOCKED IN A LOCATION SEPARATE FROM AMMUNITION. LEAVING RIFLES, SHOTGUNS\nOR FIREARMS ACCESSIBLE TO A CHILD OR OTHER PROHIBITED PERSON MAY SUBJECT\nYOU TO IMPRISONMENT, FINE, OR BOTH." Nothing in this subdivision shall\nbe deemed to affect, impair or supersede any special or local law\nrelating to the posting of notice regarding the safe storage of rifles,\nshotguns or firearms.\n  (3) Any person, firm or corporation who fails to comply with the\nprovisions of this section shall be guilty of a violation punishable as\nprovided in the penal law. Any person, firm, or corporation who fails to\ncomply with the provisions of this section after having been previously\nconvicted of a violation of this section shall be guilty of a class A\nmisdemeanor, punishable as provided in the penal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>