<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="398-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_398_F">
        <num>398-F</num>
        <heading>Children's non-regulated camp</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this\nsection, a "children's non-regulated camp" shall mean property\nconsisting of a tract of land and any tents, vehicles, buildings or\nother structures that may be pertinent to its use, any part of which may\nbe occupied on a scheduled basis any time between June first and\nSeptember fifteenth in any year by ten or more persons under sixteen\nyears of age under general supervision for the purpose of indoor or\noutdoor organized group activities, involving passive and nonpassive\nrecreational activities, which is not subject to the provisions of\narticle thirteen-B of the public health law and is:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_F__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a day program operating three hours or more at least five or more\ndays in any two-week period; or\n  (ii) an overnight program operated within New York state for less than\nseventy-two consecutive hours on more than one occasion.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This section shall not include activities operated by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_F__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a public\nschool district and clubs which also occur during the traditional school\nyear; (ii) school districts, boards of cooperative educational services\nor nonpublic schools providing instruction to satisfy, enrich,\naccelerate, or improve skills in accordance with education law\nrequirements; (iii) child care programs and family shelter-based\ndrop-off child supervision programs permitted pursuant to article\nforty-seven of the New York city health code; (iv) activities subject to\nlicensure or registration by the office of children and family services;\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_F__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>properties where children are under the supervision of family\nand/or family friends.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person, firm, corporation or association shall enroll or\nallow participation of a child in a children's non-regulated camp unless\nsuch non-regulated camp has registered with the department of health, in\na form and manner prescribed by the department of health, on an annual\nbasis and the parent or guardian of the child has been provided with the\nfollowing written notice on the application or enrollment form:\n  "This camp is registered with but not regulated or inspected by the\nNew York State Department of Health and is not required to obtain a\nDepartment of Health permit. This camp is not required to follow\nDepartment of Health regulations, including, maintaining minimum\nstaff-to-child ratios; hiring medical personnel; or reporting injuries\nor illnesses to the Department of Health."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a children's non-regulated camp maintains a website, this\nnotice must be placed on the website.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_F__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any notice required in this subdivision shall be prominently and\nconspicuously posted at the camp facilities in minimum size twelve font.\n  3. The operator of a children's non-regulated camp shall retain a copy\nof each notice required to be provided by subdivision two of this\nsection for a period of three years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>