<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="398-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_398_C">
        <num>398-C</num>
        <heading>Children attending roller skating rinks and indoor ice skating rinks under certain conditions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 398-c. Children attending roller skating rinks and indoor ice\nskating rinks under certain conditions. Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of law, the owner, lessee, proprietor, operator, attendant or\nemployee of any roller skating rink or indoor ice skating rink loe may\nadmit or allow to remain in any such roller skating rink or indoor ice\nskating rink any child under the age of twelve years, unaccompanied by\nthe parent, guardian or other adult person authorized by the parent or\nguardian of such child, at any time other than while school classes of\nsuch child are in session, but not after six o'clock in the afternoon on\nany day preceding a day on which school classes will be in session,\nprovided that on the premises of such skating rink a qualified adult\nsupervisor shall be in attendance at all times. This section shall not\napply to any roller skating rink or indoor ice skating rink within\nwhich, or connected with any premises within which, the sale of any\nwine, spirituous or malt beverages or liquor is allowed, pool or\nbilliard tables are used or bowling alleys are maintained. Children of\nthe age of twelve years and less than sixteen years of age, however, may\nremain in such roller skating rink or indoor ice skating rink until\neleven o'clock in the evening, in pursuance of the provisions of this\nsection, of any day preceding a day on which school classes will be in\nsession. No time restriction is imposed on children of the age of\nsixteen or less, in pursuance of the provisions of this section, on any\nday preceding a day on which school classes will not be in session.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>