<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-11-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="398-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_398_E">
        <num>398-E</num>
        <heading>Indemnity provision in motor carrier transportation contracts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"motor carrier transportation contract" means a contract,\nagreement or understanding covering:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the transportation of property for compensation or hire by the\nmotor carrier;\n  (ii) entrance on property by the motor carrier for the purpose of\nloading, unloading or transporting property for compensation or hire; or\n  (iii) a service incidental to activity described in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nor (ii) of this paragraph, including, but not limited to, storage of\nproperty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_398_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"promisee" means the promisee and any agents, employees, servants\nor independent contractors who are directly responsible to the promisee\nexcept for motor carriers party to a motor carrier transportation\ncontract with the promisee and such motor carrier's agents, employees,\nservants or independent contractors directly responsible to such motor\ncarrier.\n  2. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a provision,\nclause or agreement contained in, collateral to or affecting a motor\ncarrier transportation contract that purports to indemnify, defend or\nhold harmless, or has the effect of indemnifying, defending or holding\nharmless, the promisee from or against any liability for loss or damage\nresulting from the negligence or intentional acts or omissions of the\npromisee is against the public policy of this state and is void and\nunenforceable.\n  3. "Motor carrier transportation contract," as defined in this\nsection, shall not include the Uniform Intermodal Interchange and\nFacilities Access Agreement administered by the Intermodal Association\nof North America or other agreements providing for the interchange, use\nor possession of intermodal chassis, containers or other intermodal\nequipment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>