<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="398-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-398-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_398_A">
        <num>398-A</num>
        <heading>Shipment of motor vehicles outside the continental United States</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 398-a. Shipment of motor vehicles outside the continental United\nStates. 1. No person whose business involves the preparation of the\nshipping order or dock receipt or bill of lading or other export papers\nfor the transportation by water of a motor vehicle outside the\ncontinental United States shall prepare such export papers unless he\nreceives from the person sending such motor vehicle outside the\ncontinental United States a photocopy or other facsimile of a transfer\nof registration or other proof of ownership for such motor vehicle\nindicating thereon the identification number of such vehicle.  Upon\nreceipt of such document, said person shall determine that the motor\nvehicle to be transported outside the continental United States is the\nsame vehicle described in such proof of ownership and shall certify such\nfact upon the copy of the shipping order, dock receipt, bill of lading\nor other export paper for such vehicle which he retains for his records.\nThe person who prepares such export papers for the transportation of a\nmotor vehicle outside the continental United States shall maintain on\nfile for a period of three years the photocopy or other facsimile of\nsuch transfer of registration or other proof of ownership together with\nthe appropriate shipping order, dock receipt, bill of lading or other\nexport paper.  This section shall not apply to a motor vehicle which the\nmanufacturer thereof or a duly authorized dealer has never sold to a\npurchaser for the purpose of use rather than of resale.\n  2. If a motor vehicle delivered for export does not correspond with\nthe proof of ownership presented for such vehicle, such facts shall be\nimmediately made known to the appropriate police department or other law\nenforcement agency.\n  3. The person who prepares such export papers for the transportation\nof a motor vehicle outside the continental United States shall, at least\nforty-eight hours prior to the time the motor vehicle is shipped,\nfurnish to the police department in whose jurisdiction the point of\nshipment lies and if there is no police department at that place to the\nsuperintendent of state police at Albany, a description and\nidentification of the motor vehicle listing its make, year manufactured,\nmodel, color and vehicle identification number or special vehicle\nidentification number designated by the commissioner of motor vehicles.\n  4. A police officer may at all reasonable times examine and inspect\nall files and records relating to the shipment of such vehicle which are\nin the custody of the shipper or of the person who prepares the export\npapers.\n  5. Any person who shall violate, aid and abet the violation of, or\nconspire or attempt to violate this section shall be guilty of a Class A\nmisdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>