<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-RR"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-RR"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-06-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-RR"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-RR/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-RR/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-RR/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-RR/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_RR">
        <num>399-RR</num>
        <heading>September eleventh victim compensation fund and World Trade Center health program notification</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_RR__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the "eligible time period" and "notice area" shall be the same as\nprovided for in the September eleventh victim compensation fund pursuant\nto 49 USC 40101 and World Trade Center health program pursuant to 42 USC\n300mm.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_RR__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the "September eleventh victim compensation fund" shall be the\nSeptember eleventh victim compensation fund established under the Air\nTransportation Safety and System Stabilization Act (49 USC 40101).\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_RR__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the "World Trade Center health program" shall be the World Trade\nCenter health program established under 42 USC 300mm.\n  2. The department of economic development shall, in consultation with\nthe department of labor and any other appropriate state or municipal\nentity, develop rules and regulations necessary to promote awareness and\nnotification to any past or present businesses and their employees which\noperated within the New York city disaster area during the eligible time\nperiod of their potential eligibility under the September eleventh\nvictim compensation fund and the World Trade Center health program. This\nsubdivision shall apply to both current and former employees. The\ndepartment of economic development shall determine the most appropriate\nmessage and format that the state agencies may use to assist potentially\neligible employers and employees with such awareness or notification.\n  3. The department of economic development shall be authorized to\nconsult with the special master of the September eleventh victim\ncompensation fund and the program administrator of the World Trade\nCenter health program relating to matters including, but not limited to,\nmessaging and format to be used in the promotion of the September\neleventh victim compensation fund and the World Trade Center health\nprogram and if the messages should be tailored for the specific\ngeographic areas covered by the World Trade Center health program in a\ndifferent manner than those covered by both the World Trade Center\nhealth program and the September eleventh victim compensation fund.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>