<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_B">
        <num>399-B</num>
        <heading>Contracts for the use of the streets for hack stands</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 399-b. Contracts for the use of the streets for hack stands.  The\nowner, lessee or other occupant of any real property, or any other\nperson, copartnership or corporation, who shall make or enter into any\nagreement, contract or arrangement whatsoever whereby the right is\nattempted to be granted or is granted to any person, copartnership,\nassociation or corporation to use any portion of any public highway,\nstreet, avenue, boulevard, park or other public property owned by the\nstate of New York or any municipality therein for the purpose of\npermitting any vehicle to stand while awaiting passengers for hire or as\na private hack stand, and any owner, lessee or other person,\ncopartnership or corporation who shall make or enter into any contract\nor arrangement for the payment of or receives thereby any sum of money,\npercentage or profits or other thing of value under any such contract,\nagreement, consent or arrangement for such use of such public property\nas such private hack stand, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>