<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-EEE"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-EEE"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-EEE"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-EEE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-EEE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-EEE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-EEE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_EEE">
        <num>399-EEE</num>
        <heading>Disabling of services to stolen wireless phones</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_EEE__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"International mobile equipment identifier (IMEI)" shall mean:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_EEE__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a mobile equipment identifier;\n  (ii) electronic serial number; or\n  (iii) any other number or signal that:\n  (A) identifies a unique mobile wireless phone; and\n  (B) has the same function and purposes as a number described in\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_EEE__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or (ii) of this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_EEE__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"GSMA block list" means an industry database that relies on\ninformation reported by at least fifty commercial mobile operators, is\nsubject to access controls, is certified to the ISO/IEC 27001 or an\nequivalent standard for information security management systems, and\nprovides publicly available information to enable sellers, consumers,\nand law enforcement to check an IMEI against lists of mobile device\nequipment identification numbers to help prevent the use or activation\nof mobile phones identified as stolen or fraudulently obtained.\n  2. Limiting wireless service to stolen phones. Any person, firm,\npartnership, association, limited liability company, corporation, or\nother business entity providing wireless telephone services, as such\nterm is defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_EEE__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section twelve\nhundred twenty-five-c of the vehicle and traffic law, shall have and\nmaintain a program reasonably designed to prevent the activation on its\nnetwork of a phone with an international mobile equipment identity\nnumber (IMEI) that appears on the GSMA block list.\n  3. Reporting of stolen wireless phones. Any person, firm, partnership,\nassociation, limited liability company, corporation, or other business\nentity providing wireless telephone services, as such term is defined in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_EEE__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section twelve hundred twenty-five-c\nof the vehicle and traffic law, who is informed by a retail store\noperator of the theft of new, non-activated wireless phones, shall take\nreasonable steps to report the IMEI numbers of those stolen phones to\nthe GSMA block list.\n  4. Disabling of service to stolen wireless phone. Any person, firm,\npartnership, association, limited liability company, corporation, or\nother business entity providing wireless telephone services, as such\nterm is defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_EEE__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section twelve\nhundred twenty-five-c of the vehicle and traffic law, shall have and\nmaintain a program reasonably designed to enable it to suspend service\nto a stolen wireless phone upon notification by a verified customer that\na wireless phone has been stolen. Such program shall require the person\nor business entity providing wireless telephone services take reasonable\nsteps to report the IMEI numbers of the stolen phone to the GSMA block\nlist.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 399-eee's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>