<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-Z-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-Z-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-11-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-Z-1"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-Z-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-Z-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-Z-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-Z-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_Z_1">
        <num>399-Z-1</num>
        <heading>Telecommunication companies blocking certain numbers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_Z_1__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a number that is not a valid North American numbering plan number;\n  (ii) a valid North American numbering plan number that is not\nallocated to a provider by the North American numbering plan\nadministrator or the pooling administrator; and\n  (iii) a valid North American numbering plan number that is allocated\nto a provider by the North American number plan administrator or pooling\nadministrator, but is unused, so long as the provider blocking the calls\nis the allocatee of the number and confirms that the number is unused or\nhas obtained verification from the allocatee that the number is unused\nat the time of the blocking.\n  c. providers shall not block a voice call if the call is an emergency\ncall placed to 911.\n  d. providers shall not block a voice call to a subscriber who has\nrequested that no inbound calls be blocked.\n  3. For purposes of blocking calls from certain originating numbers as\nauthorized in this section, a provider may rely on caller identification\nservice information to determine the originating number.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule, or regulation, a\nvoice service provider shall be considered to be in compliance with this\nsection and any rule or regulation adopted thereunder if such provider\nhas filed a certification with the federal communications commission\nthat the provider's traffic is either signed with STIR/SHAKEN or subject\nto a compliant robocall mitigation program. A copy of such certification\nshall be made available to the attorney general or the public service\ncommission, upon request.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 399-z-1's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>