<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-II"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-II"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-11-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-II"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-II/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-II/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-II/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-II/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_II">
        <num>399-II</num>
        <heading>Furniture tip restraint device</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_II__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"furniture" shall mean a clothing storage unit that is\nfreestanding and at least twenty-seven inches in height including but\nnot limited to chests, dressers, armoires, and bureaus; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_II__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"tip restraint device" shall mean a mechanism that is designed to\nreduce the risk of furniture tipping over. Such mechanism may include\nstraps, wall brackets, steel cables, or plug and screw sets.\n  2. No person, firm, partnership, association, limited liability\ncompany, corporation, or other entity shall sell or offer to sell new\nfurniture to a consumer at retail unless the furniture conforms to\nstandards endorsed or established by the federal Consumer Product Safety\nCommission or, if no such standard exists, a standard established by\nASTM International which requires furniture to contain a tip restraint\ndevice and carry a permanent warning label, including but not limited\nto, ASTM F2057.\n  3. A person, firm, partnership, association, limited liability\ncompany, corporation, or other entity may sell or offer to sell new\nfurniture that does not meet the requirements in subdivision two of this\nsection if the furniture sold is outside the scope of the standards\nprescribed in subdivision two of this section and contains a compatible\ntip restraint device and carries a permanent warning label, or if the\nfurniture is outside the scope of the standards prescribed in\nsubdivision two of this section and the retailer:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_II__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>maintains in stock\nand prominently displays within the store tip restraint devices\navailable for sale that are compatible with such furniture; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_II__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nposts a notice, in a conspicuous location which may be easily seen or\nreached by customers, that, in legible format, states: "Certain\nfurniture may become unstable and tip over, leading to possible injury\nor death. Tip restraint devices may prevent tipping of furniture when\nproperly installed."\n  4. Any person, firm, partnership, association, limited liability\ncompany, corporation, or other entity that sells or offers to sell new\nfurniture to a consumer at retail in violation of the provisions of this\nsection shall be liable for a civil penalty not to exceed five hundred\ndollars for each violation.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 399-ii's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>