<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_H">
        <num>399-H</num>
        <heading>Disposal of records containing personal identifying information</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>social security number;\n  (ii) driver's license number or non-driver identification card number;\nor\n  (iii) mother's maiden name, financial services account number or code,\nsavings account number or code, checking account number or code, debit\ncard number or code, automated teller machine number or code, electronic\nserial number or personal identification number;\n  e. "Personal identification number" means any number or code which may\nbe used alone or in conjunction with any other information to assume the\nidentity of another person or access financial resources or credit of\nanother person.\n  2. Disposal of records containing personal identifying information. No\nperson, business, firm, partnership, association, or corporation, not\nincluding the state or its political subdivisions, shall dispose of a\nrecord containing personal identifying information unless the person,\nbusiness, firm, partnership, association, or corporation, or other\nperson under contract with the business, firm, partnership, association,\nor corporation does any of the following:\n  a. shreds the record before the disposal of the record; or\n  b. destroys the personal identifying information contained in the\nrecord; or\n  c. modifies the record to make the personal identifying information\nunreadable; or\n  d. takes actions consistent with commonly accepted industry practices\nthat it reasonably believes will ensure that no unauthorized person will\nhave access to the personal identifying information contained in the\nrecord.\n  Provided, however, that an individual person shall not be required to\ncomply with this subdivision unless he or she is conducting business for\nprofit.\n  3. Penalties; disposal and use. Whenever there shall be a violation of\nthis section, an application may be made by the attorney general in the\nname of the people of the state of New York to a court or justice having\njurisdiction to issue an injunction, and upon notice to the defendant of\nnot less tha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>