<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-YYY"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-YYY"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-YYY"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-YYY/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-YYY/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-YYY/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-YYY/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_YYY">
        <num>399-YYY</num>
        <heading>Satellite television company providing television and/or telephone services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_YYY__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>maintaining contractual or billing\nresponsibility of a separated account with the provider;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_YYY__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>approval of\nseparation by the primary account holder, if the primary account holder\nis not the person making such request; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_YYY__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a prohibition or\nlimitation on the separation as a result of arrears accrued by the\naccount. Such satellite television company shall release such person\nfrom such contract no later than seven days after receiving such opt-out\nrequest. Such satellite television company shall dispose of information\nsubmitted by such person no later than thirty days after receiving such\ninformation in a manner as to maintain confidentiality of such\ninformation. A claim for opting-out of such contract without charge\nshall be made in good faith. Such satellite television company shall\nwaive the otherwise applicable fee, penalty or charge for such person\nrequesting to opt-out of such contract. Every satellite television\ncompany shall make information about the options and process described\nin this section readily available to consumers on the website and any\nmobile application of the provider, in physical stores, and in other\nforms of public-facing consumer communication.\n  2. For the purposes of this section, the following terms shall have\nthe following meanings:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_YYY__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Direct broadcast satellite service", means the distribution or\nbroadcasting by satellite of video programming or services directly to\nreceiving equipment located at an end user subscriber's or an end user\ncustomer's premises, including, but not limited to, the provision of\npremium channels, the provision of music or other audio services or\nchannels, and any other service received in connection with the\nprovision of direct broadcast satellite service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_YYY__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Direct broadcast satellite service provider", means a person who\ntransmits, broadcasts or otherwise provides direct broadcast satellite\nservice to subscribers or customers in the state.\n  * 3. A covered provider and any officer, director, employee, vendor or\nagent thereof shall not be subject to liability for any claims arising\nfrom an action taken or omission made with respect to compliance with\nsubdivision one of this section.\n  * NB Effective June 30, 2023\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>