<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-QQ"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-QQ"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-QQ"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-QQ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-QQ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-QQ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-QQ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_QQ">
        <num>399-QQ</num>
        <heading>Sale or promotional distribution of utility knives, box cutters, or box cart cutters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 399-qq. Sale or promotional distribution of utility knives, box\ncutters, or box cart cutters. 1. No person, firm, or corporation shall\nsell or offer to sell or give away as either a retail or wholesale\npromotion a utility knife, box cutter, or box cart cutter to any person\nunder eighteen years of age.\n  2. For purposes of this section, the term "utility knife", "box\ncutter", or "box cart cutter" means a knife consisting of a razor blade,\nretractable or non-retractable, attached to or contained within a\nplastic or metal housing.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not preclude the temporary\ntransfer of a utility knife, box cutter, or box cart cutter to a person\nunder eighteen years of age by such person's employer where such device\nis possessed only on the employer's premises and only during the course\nand scope of such person's employment.\n  4. No provision of this section shall be deemed to restrict the\nauthority of any county, city, town or village to enact and enforce\nadditional local laws, ordinances or codes, or portions thereof,\nprovided the provisions thereof are not inconsistent with the provisions\nof this section.\n  5. Any person, firm, or corporation who violates the provisions of\nthis section shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than five\nhundred dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>