<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_M">
        <num>399-M</num>
        <heading>Disclosures in advertisement and sale of unassembled goods</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_M__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement\nthat the merchandise must be assembled prior to use;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_M__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a listing of\ntools necessary for assembly or use; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_M__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a listing of any additional\nparts not supplied by the seller or manufacturer, necessary for assembly\nor use; and the box or other container contains simple, clear and\naccurate instructions for assembly and use in English. For the purposes\nof the foregoing, a sign placed in close proximity to the merchandise\nshould be clear and conspicuous and a notice indicated on or affixed to\na box or other container in which the merchandise is offered for sale\nshall be printed in not less than twelve-point bold face type.\n  Where notice required by this section is given by a sign placed in\nclose proximity to the merchandise, as provided herein, the retail\npurchaser shall have the right to return the merchandise within a\nreasonable period of time and not unduly worn or damaged for a full\nrefund.\n  3. No person, firm, partnership, association or corporation or agent\nor employee thereof shall sell or offer for sale at retail, merchandise\nwhich is unassembled but is on display in an assembled condition unless\na sign indicating that the product must be assembled is prominently\nplaced in close proximity to the display.\n  4. No person, firm, partnership, association or corporation or agent\nor employee thereof shall advertise for sale at retail any merchandise\nwhich is unassembled unless said advertisement prominently sets forth\nthe fact that the merchandise is unassembled and must be assembled prior\nto use.\n  5. A violation of this section shall entitle the buyer to cancel or\nrescind the purchase and obtain a refund of the entire amount paid by\nhim.\n  6. Whenever there shall be a violation of this section, an application\nmay also be made by the attorney general in the name of the people of\nthe state of New York to a court or justice having jurisdiction to issue\nan injunction, and upon notice to the defendant of not less than five\ndays, to enjoin and restrain the continuance of such violation; and if\nit shall appear to the satisfaction of the court or justi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_M__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eighty-three hundred three of the civil\npractice law and rules, and direct restitution. In connection with any\nsuch proposed application, the attorney general is authorized to take\nproof and make a determination of the relevant facts and to issue\nsubpoenas in accordance with the civil practice law and rules.\n  7. The provisions of this section shall not apply to unassembled model\nkits and toy and hobby products, the primary purpose of which is\nassembly by the consumer as a recreational activity.\n  8. The requirement of this section to provide notice, on the package\nin which merchandise is offered for sale, or by a sign in close\nproximity to the merchandise, that such merchandise is unassembled shall\nnot apply to merchandise which is purchased for the purpose of being\nconnected to or installed in conjunction with other property, real or\npersonal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>