<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-X"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-X"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-X"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_X">
        <num>399-X</num>
        <heading>Towed motor vehicles</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_X__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever there shall be a violation of this section,\nan application may be made by the attorney general in the name of the\npeople of the state of New York to a court or justice having\njurisdiction to issue an injunction, and upon notice to the defendant of\nnot less than five days, to enjoin and restrain the continuance of such\nviolations; and if it shall appear to the satisfaction of the court or\njustice that the defendant has, in fact, violated this section, an\ninjunction may be issued by such court or justice, enjoining and\nrestraining any further violation, without requiring proof that any\nperson has, in fact, been injured or damaged thereby. In any such\nproceeding the court may make allowances to the attorney general as\nprovided in paragraph six of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_X__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eighty-three\nhundred three of the civil practice law and rules, and direct\nrestitution. Whenever the court shall determine that a violation of this\nsection has occurred, the court may impose a civil penalty of not less\nthan fifty dollars and not more than one thousand dollars for each such\nviolation. In connection with any such proposed application, the\nattorney general is authorized to take proof and make a determination of\nthe relevant facts and to issue subpoenas in accordance with the civil\npractice law and rules.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_X__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this section may be enforced concurrently by the\ntown attorney, city corporation counsel, or other lawful designee of a\nmunicipality or local government, and all moneys collected thereunder\nshall be retained by such municipality or local government.\n  4. Applicability. The provisions of this section shall not apply to\ncommercial towers or storage lot operators operating wholly within\ncities having a population of one million or more.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>