<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-BB"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-BB"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-BB"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_BB">
        <num>399-BB</num>
        <heading>Certain dry cleaning institutions; option for six months donation of articles of clothing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 399-bb. Certain dry cleaning institutions; option for six months\ndonation of articles of clothing. 1. A retail dry cleaning institution\nmay post the following notice:\n                  IN ACCORDANCE WITH NEW YORK STATE LAW\n                         GARMENTS NOT PICKED UP\n                            WITHIN SIX MONTHS\n                       WILL BE DONATED TO CHARITY\n  Such notice shall be at a minimum eleven inches in height by seventeen\ninches in length and the printed characters shall be 1.25 inches in\nheight and at least .5 inches in width.  Such notice shall be printed in\na legible manner and shall be posted in a prominent and conspicuous\nlocation in the consumer area of the dry cleaning institution. Such\nnotice shall also be stamped or printed in at least twelve point bold\nprint on the receipt given to each consumer.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of the abandoned\nproperty law, a retail dry cleaning institution that has posted such a\nnotice and provided such a receipt may donate a garment or household\nitem that has not been retrieved within six months to a bona fide\ncharitable organization, church, or other not-for-profit organization.\nThe dry cleaning institution shall obtain a detailed written receipt\nspecifically describing each item donated to the bona fide charitable\norganization, church, or not-for-profit organization. The dry cleaning\ninstitution shall attach such receipt to each such consumer receipt and\nshall keep such receipts for a period of at least three years following\nthe donation for purposes of demonstrating compliance with the\nrequirements of this section.\n  3. The six month period shall commence from the date indicated upon\nthe receipt that the consumer is due to retrieve his or her items. In\nthe event that such date is not indicated upon the receipt, the six\nmonth period shall commence two weeks from the date the consumer brought\nhis or her items to the retail dry cleaning institution.\n  4. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a retail dry\ncleaning institution from adopting a written policy which provides for a\nlonger period of time before such a donation may be made.\n  5. The provisions of this section shall not apply to those items\nbrought to a retail dry cleaning institution for the purposes of storing\nsuch items.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>