<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-FF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-FF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-FF"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-FF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-FF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-FF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-FF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_FF">
        <num>399-FF</num>
        <heading>Petting zoos</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_FF__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"petting zoo" shall mean a place where a collection of animals are\nkept for the express purpose of viewing, touching, holding and petting\nby patrons and visitors to the establishment; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_FF__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"hand washing or hand cleansing facility" shall mean any method of\ncleansing the hands that kills germs and bacteria including, but not\nlimited to, soap and running water, anti-bacterial fluids, foams or\ngels, and anti-bacterial or antiseptic wipes or towels.\n  2. All petting zoo operators shall provide and maintain at least one\nclearly designated hand washing facility for patrons and visitors to the\nestablishment to wash or cleanse their hands upon exiting such petting\nzoo area. Such hand washing or hand cleansing facility shall be\nmaintained at or within no more than fifty feet of the exit from such\npetting zoo area.\n  3. Every exit from a petting zoo area shall have a sign conspicuously\nposted that shall state, in a clear and legible typeface, the following:\n"Animals at petting zoos may carry germs and bacteria that cause\ndisease. It is strongly recommended that persons wash their hands upon\nexiting the petting zoo area". Such sign shall also indicate the\ndirection in which such hand washing or hand cleansing facility is\nlocated.\n  4. Any operator of a petting zoo who fails to maintain a hand washing\nor hand cleansing facility and proper signage in violation of this\nsection shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount of up to five\nhundred dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>