<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-ZZZZZ"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-ZZZZZ"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-ZZZZZ"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-ZZZZZ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-ZZZZZ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-ZZZZZ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-399-ZZZZZ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ">
        <num>399-ZZZZZ</num>
        <heading>Broadband service for low-income consumers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is eligible for free or\nreduced-priced lunch through the National School Lunch Program; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nis eligible for, or receiving the supplemental nutrition assistance\nprogram benefits; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is eligible for, or receiving Medicaid\nbenefits; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is eligible for, or enrolled in senior citizen rent\nincrease exemption; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is eligible for, or enrolled in disability\nrent increase exemption; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is a recipient of an affordability\nbenefit from a utility. Such low-income broadband service shall provide\na minimum download speed equal to the greater of twenty-five megabits\nper second download speed or the download speed of the provider's\nexisting low-income broadband service sold to customers in the state\nsubject to exceptions adopted by the Public Service Commission where\nsuch download speed is not reasonably practicable.\n  3. Broadband service for low-income consumers, as set forth in this\nsection, shall be provided at a cost of no more than fifteen dollars per\nmonth, inclusive of any recurring taxes and fees such as recurring\nrental fees for service provider equipment required to obtain broadband\nservice and usage fees. Broadband service providers shall allow\nlow-income broadband service subscribers to purchase standalone or\nbundled cable and/or phone services separately. Broadband service\nproviders may, once every five years, and after thirty days' notice to\nits customers and the department of public service, increase the price\nof this service by the lesser of the most recent change in the consumer\nprice index or a maximum of two percent per year of the price for such\nservice.\n  4. A broadband service provider who offers a high speed broadband\nservice to eligible low-income customers, as such term is used in\nsubdivision two of this section, at a download speed of two hundred\nmegabits per second or greater at a cost of no more than twenty dollars\nper month, inclusive of any recurring taxes and fees such as recurring\nrental fees for service provider equipment required to obtain broadband\nservice and usage fees, shall be considered to be in compliance with the\nrequirements of subdivisions two and three of this section. Such\nproviders may, once every two years, and after thirty days' notice to\nits customers and the department of public service, increase the price\nof such service by the lesser of the most recent change in the consume...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the service\noffered pursuant to this section;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of consumers enrolled\nin such service;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the procedures being used to\nverify the eligibility of customers receiving such service;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a\ndescription and samples of the advertising or marketing efforts\nundertaken to advertise or promote such service;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of\nall retail rate products, including pricing, offered by such person,\nbusiness, corporation, or their agents;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description, including\nspeed and price, of all broadband products offered in the state of New\nYork;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the number of customers in arrears for the\npayment for broadband service, percentage of customers in arrears that\nqualify for low-income broadband service, the number of households that\nhave had their service terminated as a result of non-payment, the number\nof customers whose service was terminated for arrears arising from\nnon-payment for services other than broadband service, and the number of\nhouseholds that have their broadband service restored after being\ndelinquent on their payments; and such other information as the\ndepartment of public service may require.\n  9. The department of public service shall, within two years of the\neffective date of this section and at least every five years thereafter,\nundertake a proceeding to determine if the minimum broadband download\nspeed in this section should be increased to the federal communications\ncommission's benchmark broadband download speed, or to another minimum\nbroadband download speed if the federal communications commission has\nnot increased its benchmark by such date. The department of public\nservice shall also:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>undertake appropriate measures to inform the\npublic about available broadband products, including retail rate product\nofferings and low-income offerings; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>periodically, but no less\nthan once every five years, review eligibility requirements for the\nlow-income service required pursuant to this section, and update such\nrequirements as may be necessary to meet the needs of consumers.\n  10. Whenever there shall be a violation of this section, an\napplication may be made by the attorney general in the name of the\npeople of the state of New York to a court or justice having\njurisdiction by a special proceeding to issue an injunction, and upon\nnotice to the defendant of not less than five days, to enjoin and\nrestrain the continuance of such violation; and if it shall appear to\nthe satisfaction of the court or justice that the defendant has, in\nfact, violated this section, an injunction may be issued by the court or\njustice, enjoining and restraining any further violations, without\nrequiring proof that any person has, in fact, been injured or damaged\nthereby. In any such proceeding, the court may make allowances to the\nattorney general as provided in paragraph six of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399_ZZZZZ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection eighty-three hundred three of the civil practice law and rules,\nand direct restitution. Whenever the court shall determine that a\nviolation of this section has occurred, the court may impose a civil\npenalty of not more than one thousand dollars per violation. In\nconnection with any such proposed application, the attorney general is\nauthorized to take proof and make a determination of the relevant facts\nand to issue subpoenas in accordance with the civil practice law and\nrules.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 399-zzzzz's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>