<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-403"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-403"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-06-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="403"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-403/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-403/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-403/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-403/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_403">
        <num>403</num>
        <heading>Advisory committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 403. Advisory committee. 1. There shall be established within the\ndepartment an advisory committee which shall consist of nine members\nbroadly representative of the appearance enhancement industry; including\none person engaged in the practice of either nail specialty or waxing;\ntwo persons engaged in natural hair styling; one of whom shall be\nknowledgeable in the practice of styling techniques which place tension\non the hair roots, and one of whom shall ensure strict adherence to\nquality services for all clients of all hair types, including, but not\nlimited to, curl pattern, hair strand thickness, and volume of hair; one\nperson engaged in esthetics; two persons engaged in cosmetology; two\npersons engaged in training of persons for such practices and one person\nlicensed as a dermatologist. The secretary shall appoint such persons to\nserve on the advisory committee, provided, that two shall be appointed\nby the secretary on the recommendation of the temporary president of the\nsenate and two shall be appointed by the secretary on the recommendation\nof the speaker of the assembly. Each member of the committee shall be\nappointed for terms of two years. Any member may be reappointed for\nadditional terms. The secretary shall designate from among the members\nof the committee a chairperson who shall serve at the pleasure of the\nsecretary.\n  2. The advisory committee shall meet no less than three times each\nyear.\n  3. The advisory committee shall advise the secretary on all matters\nrelating to this article, and on such other matters as the secretary\nshall request. In advising the secretary on matters concerning\nprofessional education or curriculum, inclusive of the maintenance of\ncultural and ethnic awareness within the prescribed curriculum in regard\nto hair types, including, but not limited to, curl pattern, hair strand\nthickness, and volume of hair, the advisory committee shall, to the\nextent practicable, consult with the state education department. The\nadvisory committee is directed, in consultation with the department of\nstate, the New York state office for the prevention of domestic violence\nand an advocacy group recognized by the federal department of health and\nhuman services, which has the ability to coordinate statewide and with\nlocal communities on programming and educational materials related to\nthe prevention and intervention of domestic violence in New York state,\nto develop, provide for and integrate awareness training on domestic\nviolence and sexual assault for all prospective students seeking to be\nlicensed under this article. Further, on a voluntary basis for those\nseeking to renew their license as provided for in this article to\ndevelop and provide access to educational material for domestic violence\nand sexual assault awareness.\n  4. The secretary shall designate an employee of the department to act\nas secretary of the advisory committee, and shall provide such advisory\ncommittee such stenographic or other assistance as may be necessary.\n  5. Members of the advisory committee shall receive no compensation but\nshall be entitled to actual and necessary traveling and other expenses\nwhile engaged in the performance of such member's duties hereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>