<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-09-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404">
        <num>404</num>
        <heading>Rules and regulations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 404. Rules and regulations. The secretary shall promulgate rules and\nregulations which establish standards for practice and operation by\nlicensees and trainees under this article in order to ensure the health,\nsafety and welfare of the public including licensees and trainees when\nthey are working within such establishments. Such rules and regulations\nshall include, but not be limited to, the sanitary conditions and\nprocedures required to be maintained, a minimum standard of training\nappropriate to the duties of nail specialists, trainees, waxers, natural\nhair stylists, estheticians, and cosmetologists and the provision of\nservice by nail specialists, trainees, waxers, natural hair stylists,\nestheticians or cosmetologists at remote locations other than the\nlicensee's home provided that such practitioner holds an appearance\nenhancement business license to operate at a fixed location or is\nemployed by the holder of an appearance enhancement business license.\nRegulations setting forth the educational requirements for nail\nspecialists and trainees shall include education in the area of causes\nof infection and bacteriology. Regulations setting forth the educational\nrequirements for cosmetologists or natural hair stylists shall include\neducation regarding the provision of services to individuals with all\nhair types and textures, including, but not limited to, various curl or\nwave patterns, hair strand thicknesses, and volumes of hair. In\npromulgating such rules and regulations the secretary shall consult with\nthe state education department, the advisory committee established\npursuant to this article, any other state agencies and private industry\nrepresentatives as may be appropriate in determining minimum training\nrequirements.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>