<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-407"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-407"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-09-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="407"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-407/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-407/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-407/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-407/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_407">
        <num>407</num>
        <heading>Examinations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 407. Examinations. 1. The examinations for the license to practice\nnatural hair styling, esthetics, nail specialty and cosmetology shall be\npractical and written. The examinations for the license to practice\nwaxing shall be limited to a written examination only. The secretary\nshall determine reasonable standards of performance for each license and\nshall evaluate the prospective applicants and applicants on the basis of\nsuch standards. The objectives of the examinations shall be to insure\nthat prospective applicants and applicants have sufficient basic skills\nto safeguard the health and safety of the public and to insure that\nprospective applicants and applicants have attained adequate levels of\nskill to competently engage in the activities authorized by the license.\n  2. The secretary shall prepare examination questions for persons to\nqualify for licensure under this article. Such examination questions\nshall include, where applicable, questions relating to providing\nservices to individuals with varying hair types and textures. All such\nexaminations shall be the same for all persons for the license sought at\nany given examination. Such test shall not be limited to any specific\nmethod or system.\n  3. Examinations shall be in the English language and, at the\ndiscretion of the secretary, may be translated or transposed into any\nother language if requested by the prospective applicant and upon\nsatisfactory proof of the need therefor provided that a request for such\na translated examination is made of the secretary at the time the\napplication for license is filed. In the case of physically disabled\npersons, provision for the alternative administration of the examination\nmay be made, provided a request for such procedure is made of the\nsecretary a reasonable time in advance of the examination. Examinations\nshall be held at least quarterly and shall be given in at least four\nconvenient places in the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>