<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-409"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-409"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-409/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-409/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-409/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-409/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409">
        <num>409</num>
        <heading>Fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 409. Fees. 1. The non-refundable fee for an application for a\nlicense to engage in the practice of nail specialty, waxing, natural\nhair styling, esthetics or cosmetology, shall be forty dollars initially\nand for each renewal thereof the fee shall be forty dollars; the fee for\na temporary license and each renewal shall be ten dollars.\n  2. The fee for an appearance enhancement business license shall be\nsixty dollars initially and sixty dollars for each renewal thereof.\n  3. Upon a determination that it is in the best public interest to do\nso, the secretary may promulgate rules imposing fees not to exceed\ntwenty dollars for the registration and renewal of the registration of a\ntrainee.\n  4. The secretary shall receive a non-refundable examination fee of\nfifteen dollars from each person who takes a written examination\npursuant to this article. Fees collected pursuant to this article shall\nbe deposited to the credit of the business and licensing services\naccount established pursuant to the provisions of section ninety-seven-y\nof the state finance law.\n  5. The fee for issuing a duplicate license certificate, in\nsubstitution for one lost, destroyed or mutilated shall be ten dollars.\n  6. The fee for changing a name on an appearance enhancement business\nlicense shall be thirty dollars.\n  7. The fee for changing the address on a license shall be ten dollars.\n  8. The fees herein set forth shall be those for licenses issued for\nthe license period of four years.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>