<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-41-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-41-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-41-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-41-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-41-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-41-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_A">
        <num>41-A</num>
        <heading>Continuing education requirement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 41-a. Continuing education requirement. 1. Every person licensed as\na collateral loan broker pursuant to this article shall, between June\nthirtieth, two thousand seven and June twenty-ninth, two thousand nine,\nand during every two year period thereafter, complete not less than\ntwelve hours of continuing education instruction offered in a course or\nprogram approved by any mayor or licensing authority which licenses\ncollateral loan brokers pursuant to this article. In cities having a\npopulation of one million or more, the commissioner of consumer affairs\nshall, on or before January thirty-first, two thousand seven, approve\nnot less than one twelve hour continuing education instruction course or\nprogram for collateral loan brokers and not less than one eight hour\ncontinuing education instruction course or program for managers of\ncollateral loan broker businesses, as required by subdivision two of\nthis section. Every such course or program shall be made available\nthrough at least one distance learning methodology, such as written\nmaterials and questionnaires, internet courses or other electronic means\nand shall also be made available through seminars or workshops,\ncommencing on or before June thirtieth, two thousand seven. Every mayor\nand licensing authority shall consult with one or more trade\nassociations representing collateral loan brokers prior to approving any\ncontinuing education instruction course or program pursuant to this\nsection.\n  2. Every collateral loan broker which employs more than three\nemployees, shall designate one individual as the manager of the\ncollateral loan broker business. Upon such designation the mayor or\nlicensing authority, which licenses the collateral loan broker, shall be\nprovided notice by such broker of the individual who has been designated\nas manager of the business. Every individual designated as the manager\nof a collateral loan broker business shall, between June thirtieth, two\nthousand seven and June twenty-ninth, two thousand nine, and during\nevery two year period thereafter, complete not less than eight hours of\ncontinuing education instruction for such managers offered in a course\nor program approved by any mayor or licensing authority which licenses\ncollateral loan brokers pursuant to this article.\n  3. Each collateral loan broker shall designate a manager for each\nlocation at which such broker conducts business and employs more than\nthree employees and every such manager shall comply with the provisions\nof subdivision two of this section.\n  4. Each approved provider of continuing education instruction pursuant\nto this section and each collateral loan broker shall maintain the\nrecords of the provision or receipts of such instruction for not less\nthan four years.\n  5. The failure to comply with the provisions of this section shall be\ngrounds for the suspension, revocation or refusal to issue any license\nissued pursuant to this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>