<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-410"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-410"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-11-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410">
        <num>410</num>
        <heading>Administration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a conviction for which an executive pardon has\nbeen issued pursuant to the executive law; (ii) a conviction which has\nbeen vacated and replaced by a youthful offender finding pursuant to\narticle seven hundred twenty of the criminal procedure law, or the\napplicable provisions of law of any other jurisdiction; or (iii) a\nconviction the records of which have been expunged or sealed pursuant to\nthe applicable provisions of the laws of this state or of any other\njurisdiction; and (iv) a conviction for which other evidence of\nsuccessful rehabilitation to remove the disability has been issued.\n  Provided, however, a fine shall not be imposed for the causes\nspecified in paragraph f of this subdivision.\n  In lieu of or in conjunction with the suspension or revocation of a\nlicense or registration, or the imposition of a fine pursuant to this\nsection, the secretary may issue a reprimand. When a license or\nregistration issued pursuant to this article is revoked, such license or\nregistration shall not be reinstated or reissued until after the\nexpiration of a period of one year from the date of such revocation. No\nlicense or registration shall be issued after a second revocation.\n  2. Unlicensed activities. a. The secretary may issue an order\ndirecting the cessation of any activity related to nail specialty,\nwaxing, natural hair styling, esthetics or cosmetology for which a\nlicense is required by this article upon a determination that a person,\npartnership, limited liability company or business corporation, engaging\nin the business or occupation of, or holding himself, herself or itself\nout as or acted, temporarily or otherwise, as a nail specialist, natural\nhair stylist, esthetician or cosmetologist within this state without a\nvalid license being in effect. The secretary shall, before making such\ndetermination and order, afford such person, partnership, limited\nliability company or business corporation an opportunity to be heard in\nperson or by couns...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bond or\n(ii) liability insurance or liability coverage which is covered through\na bond. The secretary shall, before making such determination and order,\nafford such person, partnership, limited liability company or business\ncorporation an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel in\nreference thereto in an adjudicatory proceeding held pursuant to section\nfour hundred eleven of this article. The enforcement of this provision\nshall require the department of financial services to certify in writing\nto the secretary that any bonds or liability insurance that is required\nby the department is readily available to appearance enhancement\nbusinesses from the market place.\n  d. The attorney general, acting on behalf of the secretary, may\ncommence an action or proceeding in a court of competent jurisdiction to\nobtain a judgment against such person, partnership, limited liability\ncompany or business corporation in an amount equal to that assessed as a\ncivil penalty. Said judgment shall thereafter be enforceable by any\nmeans authorized by the civil practice law and rules.\n  e. Where an appearance enhancement business operator continues to\noperate without a license following the issuance of an order by the\nsecretary directing cessation, the attorney general, acting on behalf of\nthe secretary, may commence an action or proceeding in a court of\ncompetent jurisdiction against such operator to obtain an order\nenjoining further operation of such business. An appearance enhancement\nbusiness that has been ordered to cease operation shall not re-open\nwithout first obtaining a license as required by this article and paying\nany assessed fines.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>