<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-411"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-411"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="411"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-411/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-411/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-411/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-411/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_411">
        <num>411</num>
        <heading>Denial of license; complaints; notice of hearing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 411. Denial of license; complaints; notice of hearing. 1. Denial of\nlicense or registration. The department shall, before making a final\ndetermination to deny an application for a license or registration,\nnotify the applicant in writing of the reasons for such proposed denial\nand shall afford the applicant an opportunity to be heard in person or\nby counsel prior to denial of the application. Such notification shall\nbe served personally or by certified mail or in any manner authorized by\nthe civil practice law and rules for service of a summons. If a hearing\nis requested, such hearing shall be held at such time and place as the\ndepartment shall prescribe. If the applicant fails to make a written\nrequest for a hearing within thirty days after receipt of such\nnotification, then the notification of denial shall become the final\ndetermination of the department. The department, acting by such officer\nor person in the department as the secretary may designate, shall have\nthe power to subpoena and bring before the officer or person so\ndesignated any person in this state, and administer an oath to and take\ntestimony of any person or cause his deposition to be taken. A subpoena\nissued under this section shall be regulated by the civil practice law\nand rules. If, after such hearing, the application is denied, written\nnotice of such denial shall be served upon the applicant personally or\nby certified mail or in any manner authorized by the civil practice law\nand rules for the service of a summons.\n  2. Revocation, suspension, reprimands, fines; unlicensed activities.\nThe department shall, before revoking or suspending any license or\nregistration or imposing any fine or reprimand on the holder thereof, or\nbefore issuing any order directing the cessation of unlicensed\nactivities, and at least ten days prior to the date set for the hearing,\nnotify in writing the holder of such license or registration, or the\nperson alleged to have engaged in unlicensed or unregistered activities,\nof any charges made and shall afford such person an opportunity to be\nheard in person or by counsel in reference thereto. Such written notice\nmay be served by delivery of same personally to the licensee or\nregistrant or person charged, or by mailing same by certified mail to\nthe last known business or other address provided by such person to the\nsecretary of state, or by any method authorized by the civil practice\nlaw and rules for the service of a summons. The hearing on such charges\nshall be at such time and place as the department shall prescribe.\n  3. The department, acting by such officer or person in the department\nas the secretary may designate, shall have the power to subpoena and\nbring before the officer or person so designated any person in this\nstate, and administer an oath to and take testimony of any person or\ncause his deposition to be taken. A subpoena issued under this section\nshall be regulated by the civil practice law and rules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>