<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-433"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-433"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-11-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="433"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-433/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-433/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-433/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-433/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_433">
        <num>433</num>
        <heading>Powers of the secretary of state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 433. Powers of the secretary of state. In addition to the powers and\nduties elsewhere prescribed in this article, the secretary of state\nshall have power: 1. To appoint an adequate number of assistants,\ninspectors and other employees as may be necessary to carry out the\nprovisions of this article, to prescribe their duties, and to fix their\ncompensation within the amount appropriated therefor.\n  2. To examine into the qualifications and fitness of applicants for\nlicenses or certificates and of prospective applicants under this\narticle.\n  3. To require all persons licensed or registered under this article to\nsubmit to physical examination by a physician or nurse practitioner\nselected by the secretary of state.\n  4. To keep records of all licenses issued, suspended or revoked.\n  5. To prepare a manual of rules and regulations for the conduct of\nexaminations and to furnish copies thereof to persons desiring the same\nupon payment of a reasonable fee therefor.\n  6. To adopt such rules and regulations not inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this article, as may be necessary with respect to the form\nand content of applications for licenses, the reception thereof, the\ninvestigation and examination of applicants and/or prospective\napplicants taking examinations and their qualifications, and the other\nmatters incidental or appropriate to the secretary of state's powers and\nduties as prescribed by this article and for the proper administration\nand enforcement of the provisions of this article, and to amend or\nrepeal any of such rules and regulations.\n  7. To grant a temporary license to engage in the practice of\nbarbering, in his own discretion, where a situation exists which will\nrender a hardship on a community to be without a licensed barber. Such\ntemporary license shall be granted to a holder of a certificate of\nregistration as an apprentice who has had some training or experience in\nthe practice of barbering and shall be valid only as long as the\nsecretary of state may decide, or as long as the hardship condition\nexists.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>