<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-435"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-435"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="435"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-435/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-435/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-435/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-435/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_435">
        <num>435</num>
        <heading>License without examination; temporary licenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, respectively, of subdivision one of section four hundred\nthirty-four of this article and the required annual license fee, is\nfiled with the secretary of state not later than December thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred fifty-one. Nothing in this subdivision shall entitle\nany person to such license without examination who, since the effective\ndate of this article, has taken and been unsuccessful in an examination\nconducted pursuant thereto.\n  2. The secretary of state shall issue a temporary license to any\nperson over the age of seventeen years, who, upon taking effect of this\narticle, has been actually and continuously engaged in the practice of\nbarbering in this state for a period of not less than six months, as\nsubstantiated by sworn affidavits or other evidence satisfactory to the\nsecretary of state and provided application therefor, accompanied by the\nphotographs, evidence, and the certificate required by paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, respectively, of subdivision one of section four hundred\nthirty-four of this article and one-quarter of the required license fee,\nis filed with the secretary of state.\n  3. A temporary license issued under this section shall expire six\nmonths after the date of issuance and such temporary licensee shall not\nbe entitled to any further license until he has taken a regularly\nscheduled examination and qualified for a regular license under the\nprovisions of this article. The secretary of state may, however, in his\ndiscretion, for good cause shown, extend the term of such a temporary\nlicense for an additional period not exceeding six months upon the\npayment of an additional fee equivalent to one-half of the license fee\nprescribed by this article.\n  4. Any person who has duly applied for a license pursuant to\nsubdivision one or subdivision two of this section may engage in the\npractice of barbering pending the determination of his application.\n  5. The secretary of state shall upon application and without\nexamination, issue a license to any person over the age of seventeen\nyears who has been duly licensed by any other state, territory,\nprotectorate or dependency of the United States to engage in the\npractice of barbering upon compliance with standards and requirements\nnot lower, in the judgment of the secretary of state, than those of this\nstate, provided, however, that either such state extends similar\nreciprocity to licensees of this state or the applicant is a member of\nthe household of a member of the armed forces of the United States,\nnational guard or reserves and was a member of such household before\nsuch member relocated to the state. Such application shall be\naccompanied by the photographs, evidence and the certificate required by\nparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, respectively, of subdivision one of section\nfour hundred thirty-four of this article and the required license fee.\n  6. If any person, eligible for any license, mentioned in this section,\nbe in the military service at or during the time application for such\nlicense is required to be filed and license fee paid, according to the\nprovisions of this section, the period within which said application may\nbe filed and license fee may be paid, is extended in behalf of such\nperson, until three months after the termination of said military\nservice, any provision contained in this article to the contrary,\nnotwithstanding.\n  In the case of persons who are or were in the military service and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nhave been or will be discharged under conditions other than\ndishonorable, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have a qualifying condition, as defined in section\none of the veterans' services law, and received a discharge other than\nbad conduct or dishonorable from such service, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_435__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are discharged\nLGBT veterans, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law,\nand have received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable\nfrom such service, the period of one year specified in subdivision one\nof this section and the period of six months specified in subdivision\ntwo of this section need not be continuous. The length of time such\nperson was engaged in the practice of barbering before entering the\nmilitary service may be added to any period of time during which such\nperson was or is engaged in the practice of barbering after the\ntermination of military service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>