<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-44"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-44"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="44"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-44/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-44/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-44/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-44/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44">
        <num>44</num>
        <heading>Memorandum to be given</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The holder of this ticket may redeem the article pledged at any\ntime prior to sale at private sale or public auction first following\ndefault.  The article pledged may not be sold at private sale or auction\nuntil it has remained four months in the collateral loan broker's\npossession.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the article pledged is sold at private sale or public auction,\nmoney, if any, in excess of the amount of the loan, interest, lawful\nauctioneer's commission, if applicable, lawful extra care charges and\nthe expenses of the advertisement of sale, if applicable, shall be paid\nto the holder of the pawn ticket.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the collateral loan broker shall purchase the article pledged\nat auction the holder shall have an additional ten days to redeem the\narticle pledged by paying to the collateral loan broker the amount of\nthe loan, interest, lawful auctioneer's commission, lawful extra care\ncharges and the expense of the advertisement of sale.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A holder may sell this ticket to a third party at any time prior\nto private sale or auction, or he may sell this ticket to the collateral\nloan broker any time ninety or more days after the article was pledged.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If this ticket is sold to a collateral loan broker the holder may\nredeem the ticket within ten days after the sale by paying to the\ncollateral loan broker the amount paid for the ticket.\n  3. Notwithstanding any general, special or local law or ordinance to\nthe contrary, if a collateral loan broker in good faith and without\nknowledge extends credit on a loan, the collateral for which was\nentrusted to the pledgor on consignment or was entrusted by a merchant\ndealing in goods of the kind pledged to the pledgor who was a merchant\ndealing in goods of the kind pledged, the collateral loan broker shall\nbe required to relinquish the collateral to the legal owner provided the\namount of the loan and interest due is paid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>