<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-440"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-440"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="440"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-440/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-440/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-440/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-440/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_440">
        <num>440</num>
        <heading>Fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 440. Fees. 1. The fee for a license to engage in the practice of\nbarbering shall be forty dollars and for each renewal thereof the fee\nshall be forty dollars.\n  2. The fee for a license to conduct a barber shop shall be sixty\ndollars and for each renewal thereof the fee shall be sixty dollars.\n  3. The fee for taking a written or practical examination under this\narticle shall be fifteen dollars.\n  4. The fee for the registration or the renewal of the registration of\nan apprentice shall be twenty dollars.\n  5. The fee for issuing a duplicate license in substitution for one\nlost, destroyed or mutilated shall be ten dollars.\n  6. The fee for changing a name on a license shall be thirty dollars.\n  7. The fee for changing the address on a license shall be ten dollars.\n  8. The fees hereinabove set forth shall be those for licenses issued\nfor the license period of four years. Notwithstanding the provisions of\nsubdivision one of section four hundred thirty-nine of this article,\nafter April first, two thousand eleven, the secretary of state shall\nassign staggered expiration dates for outstanding licenses that have\nbeen previously renewed and such licenses shall thereafter expire four\nyears from the assigned date unless renewed. The secretary of state\nshall assign dates to existing licenses in a manner which shall result\nin a term of not less than four years.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>