<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-458-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-458-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="458-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-458-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-458-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-458-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-458-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_458_H">
        <num>458-H</num>
        <heading>Deceptive acts prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 458-h. Deceptive acts prohibited. It is hereby declared to be an\nunfair and deceptive trade practice and unlawful for a credit services\ncompany to:\n  1. Misrepresent directly or indirectly in its advertising, promotional\nmaterials, sales presentation, or in any manner: the nature of the\nservices to be performed; the time within which services will be\nperformed; the ability to improve a consumer's credit report or credit\nrating; the amount or type of credit a consumer can expect to receive as\na result of the performance of the services offered; the qualifications,\ntraining or experience of its personnel.\n  2. Make or counsel or advise any consumer to make any statement which\nis untrue or misleading and which is known, or which by the exercise of\nreasonable care should be known, to be untrue or misleading, to a\nconsumer credit reporting agency or to any person who has extended\ncredit to a consumer or to whom a consumer is applying for an extension\nof credit, with respect to a consumer's credit worthiness, credit\nstanding, or credit capacity.\n  3. Represent directly or indirectly in its advertising, promotional\nmaterials, sales presentation, or in any manner that it can procure or\nobtain a credit card for a consumer unless that credit services company\nhas authority to issue the credit card being advertised.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>