<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-460-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-460-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-09-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="460-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-460-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-460-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-460-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-460-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_460_C">
        <num>460-C</num>
        <heading>Required notices</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>One sign shall be at least eleven inches by seventeen inches, and\nshall contain the following in not less than sixty point type:\n  "THE INDIVIDUAL PROVIDING ASSISTANCE TO YOU UNDER THIS CONTRACT IS NOT\nAN ATTORNEY LICENSED TO PRACTICE LAW OR ACCREDITED BY THE BOARD OF\nIMMIGRATION APPEALS TO PROVIDE REPRESENTATION TO YOU BEFORE THE UNITED\nSTATES CITIZENSHIP AND IMMIGRATION SERVICES, THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND\nSECURITY, THE EXECUTIVE OFFICE FOR IMMIGRATION REVIEW, THE DEPARTMENT OF\nLABOR, THE DEPARTMENT OF STATE OR ANY IMMIGRATION AUTHORITIES AND MAY\nNOT GIVE LEGAL ADVICE OR ACCEPT FEES FOR LEGAL ADVICE. FOR A FREE LEGAL\nREFERRAL CALL THE OFFICE FOR NEW AMERICANS HOTLINE AT (phone number of\nthe office for new Americans). TO FILE A COMPLAINT ABOUT AN IMMIGRANT\nASSISTANCE SERVICE PROVIDER CALL THE OFFICE FOR NEW AMERICANS HOTLINE AT\n(phone number of the office for new Americans), THE NEW YORK STATE\nOFFICE OF ATTORNEY GENERAL AT (phone number of the office of attorney\ngeneral), OR YOUR LOCAL DISTRICT ATTORNEY OR PROSECUTOR'S OFFICE AT\n(phone number of the local district attorney)." The service provider\nshall be responsible for providing the accurate and up-to-date phone\nnumbers required on such sign.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A separate sign shall be posted in a location visible to customers\nin conspicuous size type and which contains the schedule of fees for\nservices offered and the statement:\n"YOU MAY CANCEL ANY CONTRACT WITHIN 3 BUSINESS DAYS AND GET BACK YOUR\nDOCUMENTS AND ANY MONEY YOU PAID."\n  2. Notice in advertisements. Every provider who advertises immigrant\nassistance services, whether by signs, pamphlets, newspapers, or any\nother written communication shall post or otherwise include with such\nadvertisement a notice in the language in which the advertisement\nappears. This notice shall be of a conspicuous size and shall state:\n"THE INDIVIDUAL OFFERING TO PROVIDE IMMIGRANT ASSISTANCE SERVICES IS NOT\nAN ATTORNEY LICENSED TO PRACTICE LAW OR ACCREDITED BY THE BOARD OF\nIMMIGRATION APPEALS TO PROVIDE REPRESENTATION BEFORE THE UNITED STATES\nCITIZENSHIP AND IMMIGRATION SERVICES, THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND\nSECURITY, THE EXECUTIVE OFFICE FOR IMMIGRATION REVIEW, THE DEPARTMENT OF\nLABOR, THE DEPARTMENT OF STATE OR ANY IMMIGRATION AUTHORITIES AND MAY\nNOT GIVE LEGAL ADVICE OR ACCEPT FEES FOR LEGAL ADVICE."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>