<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-484"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-484"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="484"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-484/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-484/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-484/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-484/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_484">
        <num>484</num>
        <heading>Enforcement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_484__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who operates a crane without a certificate of\ncompetence issued by the commissioner of labor as required by section\nfour hundred eighty-two of this article shall be deemed to have violated\nthis article. The commissioner may impose a civil penalty upon such\nperson of no more than one thousand dollars for the initial violation,\nno more than two thousand dollars for the second violation, and no more\nthan three thousand dollars for a third or subsequent violation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_484__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any employer, contractor or agent thereof who willfully permits a\nperson to operate a crane without a certificate of competence issued by\nthe commissioner of labor as required by section four hundred eighty-two\nof this article shall be deemed to have violated this article. The\ncommissioner may impose a civil penalty upon such employer, contractor,\nor agent of no more than five thousand dollars for the initial\nviolation, and no more than ten thousand dollars for a second or\nsubsequent violation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_484__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When two final determinations have been rendered under this\nsection against a person who operates a crane in violation of this\narticle, such person shall be ineligible to apply for a certificate of\ncompetence from the commissioner of labor for a period of two years from\nthe date of the second final determination.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>