<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-490-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-490-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="490-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-490-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-490-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-490-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-490-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_490_F">
        <num>490-F</num>
        <heading>Non-retail sales responsibilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 490-f. Non-retail sales responsibilities. 1. Any person that acts as\nan operator or manager of a website that serves as a platform to\nfacilitate by a competitive bidding process or solely between third\nparties the resale, sale or distribution of children's products or\ndurable juvenile products shall conspicuously post on its homepage\nadvisory language which notifies buyers or sellers of children's\nproducts or durable juvenile products of the importance of checking\nrecall lists before engaging in such transactions that incorporates a\ndirect link to the recall information available at the United States\nconsumer product safety commission website.\n  2. Secondhand dealers who sell children's products and/or durable\nchildren's products shall post a notice instructing consumers on how to\nobtain recall information and advisory language notifying buyers and\nsellers of children's products or durable juvenile products of the\nimportance of checking recall lists before engaging in such\ntransactions. Such notice shall be prominently posted at the point of\nsale or at the entrance to the premises where the product is offered for\nsale.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>