<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="495-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_495_C">
        <num>495-C</num>
        <heading>Lithium-ion battery safety resources</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 495-c. Lithium-ion battery safety resources. The department of\nstate, in consultation with the division of homeland security and\nemergency services and the New York state energy research and\ndevelopment authority, shall develop and maintain safety resources,\ninformation, and protocols in regard to fire hazard prevention relating\nto, but not limited to, lithium-ion batteries, second-use lithium-ion\nbatteries, bicycles with electric assist as defined in section one\nhundred two-c of the vehicle and traffic law, limited use motorcycles as\ndefined in section one hundred twenty-one-b of the vehicle and traffic\nlaw, and micromobility devices. The department of state shall post such\nsafety resources, information and protocols on their website. Such\nsafety resources, information and protocols shall be designed to educate\nthe public on how to respond to and deal with emergency circumstances in\nregard to incidents associated with, but not limited to, the use and\ncharging of lithium-ion batteries, second-use lithium-ion batteries,\nbicycles with electric assist as defined in section one hundred two-c of\nthe vehicle and traffic law, limited use motorcycles as defined in\nsection one hundred twenty-one-b of the vehicle and traffic law, and\nmicromobility devices. Such safety resources, information and protocols\nshall include, but not be limited to, charging tips, how to dispose of\nlithium-ion batteries, handling and preventing lithium-ion battery\nfires.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>