<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="495-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_495_B">
        <num>495-B</num>
        <heading>Tags on charging cords of micromobility devices, limited use motorcycles, and bicycles with electric assist</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 495-b. Tags on charging cords of micromobility devices, limited use\nmotorcycles, and bicycles with electric assist. 1. No person, firm,\npartnership, association, or corporation shall manufacture, distribute,\nassemble, recondition, sell or offer for sale at retail any\nmicromobility device, limited use motorcycles as defined in section one\nhundred twenty-one-b of the vehicle and traffic law, or bicycle with\nelectric assist as defined in section one hundred two-c of the vehicle\nand traffic law unless there is a red tag affixed to the charging cord\nof such micromobility device, limited use motorcycles as defined in\nsection one hundred twenty-one-b of the vehicle and traffic law, or\nbicycle with electric assist which clearly and conspicuously states\n"UNPLUG WHEN NOT IN USE". Such tag shall include additional consumer\nsafety information regarding safe usage of the product and its charging\nequipment and shall be affixed to the cord near the end which is plugged\ninto the electricity source.\n  2. The department of state shall promulgate rules and regulations\nproviding guidance on the consumer safety information required to be on\nthe tag pursuant to subdivision one of this section.\n  3. The department of state shall post a model tag containing the\ninformation outlined in subdivision one of this section that persons,\nfirms, partnerships, associations, and corporations can affix to such\ncharging cords as outlined in subdivision one of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>