<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-10-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="495"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-495/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_495">
        <num>495</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 495. Definitions. As used in this article, the following terms shall\nhave the following meanings:\n  1. "Lithium-ion battery" means a rechargeable battery with an organic\nsolvent electrolyte and positive and negative electrodes which utilize\nan intercalation compound in which lithium is stored.\n  2. "Second-use lithium-ion battery" means a lithium-ion battery that\nhas been assembled, refurbished, repaired, repurposed or reconditioned\nusing cells removed from used batteries.\n  3. "Micromobility device" means an electric scooter as defined in\nsection one hundred fourteen-e of the vehicle and traffic law, an\nelectrical personal assistive mobility device as defined in section one\nhundred fourteen-d of the vehicle and traffic law, or other personal\nmobility device powered by a lithium-ion battery, including but not\nlimited to a skateboard or unicycle. The term "micromobility device"\nshall not include bicycles with electric assist as defined in section\none hundred two-c of the vehicle and traffic law, limited use\nmotorcycles as defined in section one hundred twenty-one-b of the\nvehicle and traffic law, wheelchairs or other electrically driven\nmobility assistance devices as defined in section one hundred thirty-a\nof the vehicle and traffic law, or any vehicle that is capable of being\nregistered with the department of motor vehicles.\n  4. "Accredited testing laboratory" means a nationally recognized\ntesting laboratory as recognized by the federal occupational safety and\nhealth administration or an independent laboratory that has been\ncertified by an accrediting body to ISO 17025 or ISO 17065.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>