<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="503"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_503">
        <num>503</num>
        <heading>Administration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 503. Administration. 1. The commissioner is hereby authorized and\ndirected to prescribe such rules and regulations, including provisions\nfor maintenance of records relating to products, fabrics or related\nmaterials, and for the labeling for a product, fabric or related\nmaterial, as may be necessary and proper for purposes of administration\nand enforcement of this article.\n  2. The commissioner is hereby authorized and directed to promulgate\nthe standards of flammability and shall include such standards of\nflammability in such rules and regulations which he may publish.\n  3. Such standards, rules and regulations, promulgated by the\ncommissioner pursuant to this article, shall be filed in the office of\nthe secretary of state before becoming effective and may be amended and\nrevised from time to time. Each such standard, rule or regulation or\namendment thereto shall become effective twelve months from the date on\nwhich such standard, rule, regulation or amendment is promulgated,\nunless the commissioner finds for good cause shown that an earlier or\nlater effective date is in the public interest and publishes the reason\nfor such finding. Each such standard, rule or regulation or amendment\nthereto shall exempt products, fabrics or related materials in inventory\nor with the trade as of the date on which the standard, rule or\nregulation or amendment thereto becomes effective except that if the\ncommissioner finds that any such product, fabric or related material is\nso highly flammable as to be dangerous when used by consumers for the\npurpose for which it is intended, he may under such conditions as the\ncommissioner may prescribe, withdraw, or limit the exemptions for such\nproduct, fabric or related material.\n  4. The commissioner is authorized to cooperate on matters related to\nthe purposes of this article with any department or agency of the\nfederal, state or municipal government; with any state, territory or\npossession of the United States or with the District of Columbia; or\nwith any department, agency or political subdivision thereof; or with\nany person.\n  5. The commissioner may obtain from any person by regulation or\nsubpoena issued pursuant thereto such information in the form of\ntestimony, books, records, or other writings as is pertinent to the\nfindings or determinations which he is required or authorized to make\npursuant to this article.\n  All information reported to or otherwise obtained by the commissioner\nor his representative pursuant to this subdivision which information\ncontains or relates to a trade secret shall be considered confidential,\nexcept that such information may be disclosed to other officers or\nemployees concerned with carrying out this article or when relevant in\nany proceeding under this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>