<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-504"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-504"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="504"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-504/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-504/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-504/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-504/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_504">
        <num>504</num>
        <heading>Enforcement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 504. Enforcement. 1. Every place where products, fabrics or related\nmaterials are manufactured or sold shall be subject to inspection by the\ncommissioner who shall have power to inspect the manufacture and sale or\ndelivery of all products, fabrics or related materials covered by this\narticle. The commissioner shall have power to cause examinations and\ntests to be made thereof and power to place off sale and to seize and\nhold for evidence any product, fabric or related material which he has\nreason to believe is made or sold or held in possession in violation of\nthis article. For the purpose of administering and enforcing the\nprovisions of this article the commissioner shall have and may use the\npowers conferred on him by the labor law in addition to the powers\nconferred herein. No person shall interfere with, obstruct or otherwise\nhinder any inspector, officer or employee of the department in the\nperformance of his duties.\n  2. No person shall sell, alter, interfere with or remove in whole or\nin part any product, fabric or related material which has been placed\noff sale nor shall such product, fabric or related material be removed\nfrom the premises where placed off sale or seized until such product,\nfabric or related material is released by the commissioner. All\nproducts, fabrics or related materials placed off sale or seized shall\nbe subject to frequent examination by inspectors of the department and\nmust be so placed and stored as to be readily accessible at all times\nand shall be produced for examination upon demand of any inspector made\nupon the person or persons in charge of the establishment or premises\nwhere such products, fabrics or related materials were placed off sale\nor were seized.\n  3. Whenever the department ascertains that any product, fabric or\nrelated material has been manufactured or has been offered for sale in\nviolation of the provisions of this article, proceedings for the\nconfiscation of such product, fabric or related material may be\ninstituted by the commissioner in the supreme court in the county\nwherein such product, fabric or related material may be found.\n  4. If the court shall find that such product, fabric or related\nmaterial does not comply with the standards established by this article\nand the rules and regulations promulgated hereunder it shall be disposed\nof by destruction or by delivery to the owner or claimant thereof upon\npayment of legal costs and charges and upon execution of good and\nsufficient bond that such product, fabric or related material will not\nbe disposed of for wear or use until properly and adequately treated or\nprocessed so that it shall comply with the provisions of this article\nand the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant to this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>