<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-518-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-518-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="518-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-518-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-518-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-518-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-518-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_518_A">
        <num>518-A</num>
        <heading>Presentment of social security number as condition for accepting a check, traveler's check, gift certificate, money order or other negoti...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 518-a. Presentment of social security number as condition for\naccepting a check, traveler's check, gift certificate, money order or\nother negotiable instrument in payment of sales transaction prohibited.\n1. No seller in any sales transaction shall record on a check,\ntraveler's check, gift certificate, money order, other negotiable\ninstrument or attachment thereto, a social security number of a buyer in\nsuch transaction as a condition for accepting such instrument as payment\nin such transaction. Nothing contained in this subdivision shall\nprohibit a seller from so recording the identifying number from a\nbuyer's driver's license where such number is identical to or is a part\nof the buyer's social security number.\n  2. A violation of the provisions of this section shall be punishable\nby a civil fine not to exceed one hundred dollars for a first violation\nand not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars for subsequent violations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>