<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-519"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-519"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="519"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-519/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-519/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-519/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-519/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_519">
        <num>519</num>
        <heading>Disclosure by commercial establishments honoring credit cards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 519. Disclosure by commercial establishments honoring credit cards.\n1. Any person who honors credit cards that may be used to purchase or\nlease property on the credit of the issuer or of the holder and requires\na minimum purchase before accepting credit cards or refuses to allow the\nuse of such card on discounted or sale items must post such limitations\nor conditions conspicuously and in all advertisements that mention that\ncredit cards are accepted. The disclosure provisions with respect to\nthese requirements shall be satisfied if the retail installment credit\nagreement discloses the fact that the use of the credit card requires a\nminimum purchase or shall not be used to purchase sale items, or if the\nissuer of the credit card notifies the holder in writing that the use of\nthe card requires a minimum purchase or that the card shall not be used\nto purchase sale items. This section shall not apply to minimum purchase\nrequirements or other restrictions which are applicable regardless of\nthe method of payment.\n  2. Any person violating the provisions of this section shall be\nsubject to a civil fine of not more than one hundred dollars on the\nfirst violation and not more than two hundred fifty dollars on the\nsecond and all subsequent violations.\n  3. This section does not annul, alter, affect or exempt any person\nsubject to the provisions of this section from complying with the laws,\nordinances, rules or regulations of any locality relating to disclosure\nof limitations and conditions of credit card purchases, except to the\nextent that those local laws, ordinances, rules or regulations are\ninconsistent with any provision of this section and then only to the\nextent of the inconsistency.  However, any local law, ordinance, rule or\nregulation shall not be considered inconsistent with any provision of\nthis section if such local law, ordinance, rule or regulation gives\ngreater protection to the consumer.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>