<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="520-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_520_A">
        <num>520-A</num>
        <heading>Certain credit and debit card transaction forms required</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such\ninformation is necessary for shipping, delivery or installation of\npurchased merchandise or for special orders; or (ii) the person, firm,\npartnership or corporation processes credit or debit card transactions\nby mailing transaction forms to a designated bankcard center for\nsettlement.\n  4. No person, firm, partnership, association or corporation which\naccepts a personal check, gift certificate, traveler's check or money\norder in payment for goods or services used or bought for use primarily\nfor personal, family or household purposes, and which as a condition of\nsuch acceptance requires that the check drawer or redeemer of the gift\ncertificate, traveler's check or money order provide a credit or charge\ncard, shall record on such check, gift certificate, traveler's check or\nmoney order or elsewhere, the card account number. Nothing in this\nsubdivision shall be construed to prohibit any person, firm,\npartnership, association or corporation, as a condition for the\nacceptance of a check, gift certificate, traveler's check or money order\nin payment for goods or services from:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requesting a purchaser to\ndisplay a credit or charge card as a means of identification, or as an\nindication of credit worthiness or financial responsibility; or (ii)\nrecording on the check, gift certificate, traveler's check or money\norder the type of credit or charge card so displayed and/or the credit\nor charge card expiration date; provided, further, that nothing in this\nsubdivision shall require any business entity to accept a check, gift\ncertificate, traveler's check or money order in payment for goods or\nservices whether or not a credit or charge card is displayed.\n  4-a. a. No person, firm, partnership, association, limited liability\ncompany, corporation, or other entity that accepts charge, credit, or\ndebit cards for the transaction of business shall print the expiration\ndate of the charge, credit, or debit card nor shall any person, firm,\ncorporation, partnership, association, limited liability company, or\nother entity print more than the last five digits of the charge, credit,\nor debit card account number upon any receipt provided to the card\nholder.\n  b. This subdivision shall apply only to receipts that are\nelectronically printed and shall not apply to transactions in which the\nsole means of recording the person's charge, credit, or debit card\nnumber is by handwriting or by an imprint or copy of the credit card.\n  c. The provisions of this subdivision shall apply to all cash\nregisters or other machines or devices, which electronically print\nreceipts for charge, credit, or debit card transactions, that are placed\nin service on or after January first, two thousand four.\n  d. For all cash registers or other machines or devices that\nelectronically print receipts for charge, credit, or debit card\ntransactions in service prior to January first, two thousand four, the\nprovisions of this subdivision shall not apply until January first, two\nthousand seven.\n  e. A person, firm, corporation, partnership, association, limited\nliability...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eighty-three\nhundred three of the civil practice law and rules, and direct\nrestitution. In connection with any such proposed application the\nattorney general is authorized to take proof and make a determination of\nthe relevant facts and to issue subpoenas in accordance with the civil\npractice law and rules.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>