<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="520"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_520">
        <num>520</num>
        <heading>Application forms or solicitation for credit cards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_520__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this section shall be deemed or construed to\nprohibit an issuer from disclosing additional terms, conditions, or\ninformation, whether or not relating to the disclosures required under\nthis section, in conjunction with the disclosures required by this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All application forms for a credit card agreement, including\nthose in a magazine, newspaper, or other publication, distributed by\nsomeone other than the issuer in this state on or after January first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-eight shall contain a statement in substantially\nthe following form:\n  "If you wish to receive disclosure of the terms of this credit card,\ncheck here and return to the address on this application".\n  A box shall be printed in or next to this statement for placement of\nsuch a check mark.\n  However, this requirement does not apply if the application contains\nthe disclosures provided for in subdivisions one through four of this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_520__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this section, "Regulation Z" and all of the terms\nused in this section shall have the same meaning as attributed to them\nin Federal Regulation Z (12 C.F.R. Sec.226.1 et seq.).\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_520__subsec_b__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section shall not apply to any application form or written\nadvertisement where the credit to be extended will be secured by a lien\non real property or a lien on an existing ownership interest in\ncertificates of stock or other evidences of an ownership interest in a\nproprietary lease from a corporation or partnership formed for the\npurpose of the co-operative ownership of real estate.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_520__subsec_b__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an issuer is required under federal law to make any disclosure\nof the terms applicable to a credit card plan or account under this\nsection in connection with application forms or solicitation, the seller\nor issuer shall be deemed to have complied with the requirements of this\nsection with respect to those application forms or solicitations if the\nseller or issuer complies with the federal disclosure requirements.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_520__subsec_b__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any application form or preapproved written solicitation to enter\ninto a retail installment credit agreement in which the retail seller or\nfinancing agency may take or retain a purchase money security interest,\nas set forth in paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision twelve of section four\nhundred thirteen of the personal property law, which is mailed or\notherwise made available to an individual residing in this state on or\nafter the effective date of this subdivision, by or on behalf of an\nissuer, whether or not the issuer is located in this state, other than\nan application form or solicitation included in a magazine, newspaper,\nor other publication distributed by someone other than the issuer, shall\ncontain a clear and conspicuous written notice or disclosure to the\nbuyer that the retail seller or financing agency has or may retain a\nsecurity interest in merchandise covered under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_520__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision twelve of section four hundred thirteen of the personal\nproperty law until the full payment price of said merchandise is paid.\nFurther provided, however, in all instances, said written notice must be\nprovided to any buyer prior to the first transaction made under any such\nretail installment credit agreement in which a security interest has\nbeen or may be taken or retained.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>