<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-53"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-53"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="53"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53">
        <num>53</num>
        <heading>Registration statements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 53. Registration statements. After September first, nineteen hundred\nsixty, no person, corporation, partnership, firm or association shall\ncarry on the business of collateral loan broker within the state of New\nYork unless and until such collateral loan broker shall have caused to\nbe filed in the office of the state comptroller upon forms prescribed by\nhim a statement, duly verified as hereinafter provided, to be known as\n"Collateral Loan Broker's Registration Statement" containing:\n  a. The name of such collateral loan broker.\n  b. The address of the principal office of such collateral loan broker,\nif any, wherever situated, and the address or addresses of the principal\noffice of such collateral loan broker within this state, if any.\n  c. If such collateral loan broker be a partnership, the names,\nresidences and business addresses of the partners, including special or\nlimited partners, and of all other individuals participating as\nprincipals in the profits of such business, specifying as to each the\nnature of his relation to such business.\n  d. If such collateral loan broker be other than an individual or\npartnership, the name of the state where incorporated or organized and\nthe names, residences and business addresses of its principal officers,\nwherever located, and all its officers in this state, specifying as to\neach the nature of his relation to such business.\n  e. The date on which such collateral loan broker acquired a license\nand the name and location of the local governing body under whose hand\nand seal or authority said license was obtained under the provisions of\nthis article.\n  f. In the event that after any collateral loan broker shall have filed\na statement as above, any change shall take place in the personnel of\nthe partners, principals, officers or in the location of the principal,\nsuch collateral loan broker shall file a statement with the state\ncomptroller to be known as a "Collateral Loan Broker's Supplemental\nRegistration Statement", duly verified as hereinafter provided, setting\nforth in full the details thereof.\n  g. Each such collateral loan broker statement and each collateral loan\nbroker supplemental statement shall be verified by the collateral loan\nbroker, or if such collateral loan broker be a partnership, by a general\npartner thereof, or, if such collateral loan broker be other than an\nindividual or partnership, by a principal officer thereof, and shall\nstate that the facts therein stated are true to his own knowledge;\nproviding that in case of a statement or supplemental statement by a\ncollateral loan broker other than an individual the person verifying the\nsame may state on information and belief the facts therein included with\nrespect to any other individual, if such collateral loan broker\nstatement or supplemental statement shall have attached thereto an\naffidavit of such other individual stating that all facts contained in\nsaid collateral loan broker statement or supplemental statement with\nrespect to him are true.\n  h. The state comptroller may in his discretion adopt forms for the use\nof collateral loan brokers for filing any statement with his department\npursuant to the provisions of this section and furnish such forms to\ncollateral loan brokers without charge or fee therefor. The state\ncomptroller shall collect the following fees:\n  For filing each "Collateral Loan Broker's Registration Statement",\nfive dollars; for filing each "Collateral Loan Broker's Supplemental\nStatement", two dollars and fifty cents.\n  The fees herein enumerated shall be payable at the time of filing and\nno filing shall be deemed effective within the meaning of this section\nuntil such fees have been paid.\n  i. Whenever a collateral loan broker shall have filed any registration\nstatement or supplemental registration statement required to be filed\nunder the provisions of this section or shall have prepared in such\nregistration statement or supplemental registration statement and have\nforwarded the same together with the fees required by subdivision h of\nthis section, postage prepaid and properly addressed, to the office of\nthe state comptroller in Albany, such collateral loan broker, as to the\nfiling of such collateral loan broker's statement or supplemental\nregistration statement shall be deemed to have complied with the\nrequirements of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>