<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="607-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_607_A">
        <num>607-A</num>
        <heading>Storage of furs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 607-a. Storage of furs. In addition to any other provision of this\narticle, a fur storage operator shall be subject to the following:\n  1. If there is any statement of limitation in damages in an agreement\nfor the storage of furs, such agreement shall contain on its face\nimmediately above the consumer bailor's signature the following notice\n"DO NOT SIGN THIS AGREEMENT UNLESS THE DECLARED VALUE OF EACH ARTICLE TO\nBE STORED OR SERVICED IS STATED."\n  2. Where the consumer bailor does not personally deliver furs for\nstorage and the fur storage operator, in the normal course of his\nbusiness, makes an appraisal of such furs before accepting them for\nstorage, the fur storage operator, for purposes of compliance with the\ndisclosure provisions of this article, shall be deemed to have complied\nif he supplies a consumer bailor with a written storage agreement within\nthirty days of receipt of such furs. Provided, however, that nothing\ncontained in this subdivision shall diminish any existing duty of care\nwhich the fur storage operator owes to the consumer bailor.\n  3. For the purposes of this section, a fur storage operator means a\nwarehouseman whose storage business is limited to furs and other items\nof valuable clothing and furs means articles of wearing apparel intended\nto be worn by individuals and consisting in whole or in part of animal\nfur.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>