<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="607"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_607">
        <num>607</num>
        <heading>Required disclosures</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_607__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Name and address of warehouseman and consumer bailor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_607__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Street address of warehouse where goods will be stored.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_607__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The reasonably estimated monthly storage charge for the particular\nhousehold goods to be stored expressed in dollars. The actual monthly\ncharge shall not exceed the given estimate by more than ten percent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_607__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An itemization of other charges imposed or which may be imposed in\nconnection with the storage, a description of each such charge, whether\nthe charge is mandatory or optional, and the amount of each charge\nexpressed in dollars. Where such charges can only be estimated, a\nreasonable estimate must be set forth and the actual charges shall not\nexceed such estimates by more than ten percent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_607__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An inventory by item number of all goods accepted for storage or\nof the packages containing them together with a notation of the\ncondition of each of the goods accepted; a statement that the bailor\nshould review the condition noted for each of the goods before they are\npicked up for storage to make sure that a proper description of the\ncondition of each of the goods has been entered on the inventory; and a\nstatement that the bailor before signing the storage agreement should\nnote on it by item number any exception he may have as to the condition\ndescriptions. The notation of the condition of the goods by the\nwarehouseman or his agent shall be expressed in readily understandable\nterms.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_607__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement of any limitation of damages limiting the amount of\nthe warehouseman's liability in case of loss or damage of the goods\nsetting forth a specific liability per article or item of value per unit\nof weight beyond which the warehouseman will not be liable; provided\nthat if damages are so limited, a statement shall be included that such\nliability may on the written request of the bailor at the time of\nsigning such storage agreement or within a reasonable time thereafter be\nincreased on part or all of the goods stored, in which event increased\nrates may be charged based on such increased valuation. The rates\ncharged for an increased valuation shall be set forth and a\npre-addressed request form to enable the bailor to request an increased\nvaluation shall be provided.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_607__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any other material terms and conditions of the storage\ntransaction.\n  2. Every storage agreement as required by this section shall include\nthe business address and telephone number to be used by the consumer\nbailor in making inquiries concerning the storage transaction.\n  3. Every storage agreement as required by this section shall contain\nthe following conspicuous notices:\n  Notice: The monthly storage charge and other charges stated in this\n  agreement are either the actual or reasonably estimated charges you\n  must pay. If the charges are estimated the final charges you will be\n  required to pay may not exceed the estimate by more than ten percent.\n  Notice: Storage charges do not include any charges for moving your\n  goods from your home to the warehouse or from the warehouse to your\n  home.\n  4. When a warehouseman accepts household goods for storage on behalf\nof a consumer bailor after a warrant of eviction has been executed\npursuant to section seven hundred forty-nine of the real property\nactions and proceedings law, the warehouseman shall within three days\nafter receipt of the goods mail a copy of a statement containing the\ndisclosures required by subdivisions one, two and three of this section\nto the consumer bailor by registered or certified mail at his last known\nresidence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>