<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-621"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-621"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="621"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-621/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-621/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-621/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-621/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_621">
        <num>621</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Membership in any group, club, association or organization which\nprovides any of the foregoing services and which is organized pursuant\nto the provisions of the not-for-profit corporation law; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Boarding accommodations; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Travel arrangements contracted for less than one year in advance;\nor\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contracts which incorporate warranties of services or repair given\nin conjunction with appliances or other goods, where the sale of goods\nis the primary object of the contract; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Services by a college or university chartered by the university of\nthe state of New York, a secondary school, an elementary school, a\nnursery school or kindergarten; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contracts for services to provide instruction, training or\nassistance to acquire a vocation or skill conducted in a training school\nor by home study.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contracts for programs which provide instruction for improving\ntennis skills, and are of eight weeks duration or less where the full\nfee does not exceed two hundred fifty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contracts relating solely to the seasonal use of tennis\nfacilities.\n  2. "Health club" as used in this article means any person, firm,\ncorporation, partnership, unincorporated association, or other business\nenterprise offering instruction, training or assistance or the\nfacilities for the preservation, maintenance, encouragement or\ndevelopment of physical fitness or well being. Such term shall include\nbut shall not be limited to health spas, sports, tennis, racquet ball,\nplatform tennis and health clubs, figure salons, health studios,\ngymnasiums, weight control studios, martial arts and self-defense\nschools or any other similar course of physical training.\n  3. "Secretary" as used in this article shall mean the secretary of\nstate.\n  4. "Seller" as used in this article means any person, firm,\ncorporation, partnership, unincorporated association or other business\nenterprise which operates or intends to operate a health club.\n  5. "Buyer" as used in this article means any individual who enters\ninto a contract for services with a health club.\n  6. "Cardiopulmonary resuscitation" or "CPR" as used in this article\nmeans measures, as specified in regulations promulgated by the\ncommissioner of health, to restore function or support ventilation in\nthe event of a cardiac or respiratory arrest. Cardiopulmonary\nresuscitation shall not include measures to improve ventilation and\ncardiac functions in the absence of an arrest.\n  7. "Automated external defibrillator" or "AED" as used in this article\nmeans a medical device approved by the federal food and drug\nadministration that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is capable of recognizing the presence or\nabsence in a patient of ventricular fibrillation and rapid ventricular\ntachycardia;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is capable of determining, without intervention by an\noperator, whether defibrillation should be performed on the patient;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nupon determining that defibrillation should be performed, automatically\ncharges and requests delivery of an electrical impulse to the patient's\nheart; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_621__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon action by an operator, delivers an appropriate\nelectrical impulse to the patient's heart to perform defibrillation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>