<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-624"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-624"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="624"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_624">
        <num>624</num>
        <heading>Rights of cancellation of contracts for services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_624__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every contract for services shall provide that after such three\nbusiness day period for cancellation as provided in subdivision two of\nthis section, the buyer's estate may cancel a contract for services if\nthe buyer dies. The buyer may also cancel after three business days if\nthe buyer becomes significantly physically disabled for a period in\nexcess of three months, or moves their residence to a location more than\ntwenty-five miles from a health club operated by the seller, or after\nthe services are no longer available or substantially available as\nprovided in the contract because of the seller's permanent\ndiscontinuance of operation or substantial change in operation. Nothing\ncontained herein shall restrict or prohibit the seller from offering or\nproviding in such contract additional or broader reasons for\ncancellation. The seller may require reasonable evidence for a\ncancellation pursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_624__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such contract shall contain the following notice captioned in at\nleast twelve point bold type:\nADDITIONAL RIGHTS TO CANCELLATION:\n  You may also cancel this contract for any of the following reasons:\n  If upon a doctor's order, you cannot physically receive the services\nbecause of significant physical disability for a period in excess of\nthree months.\n  If you die, your estate shall be relieved of any further obligation\nfor payment under the contract not then due and owing.\n  If you move your residence more than twenty-five miles from any health\nclub operated by seller.\n  If the services cease to be offered as stated in the contract.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_624__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All moneys paid pursuant to such contract cancelled for the\nreasons contained in this subdivision shall be refunded within ten\nbusiness days of receipt of such notice of cancellation; provided\nhowever that the seller may retain the expenses incurred and the portion\nof the total price representing the services used or completed, and\nfurther provided that the seller may demand the reasonable cost of goods\nand services which the buyer has consumed or wishes to retain after\ncancellation of the contract. In no instance shall the seller demand\nmore than the full contract price from the buyer. If the buyer has\nexecuted any credit or loan agreement to pay for all or part of health\nclub services, any such negotiable instrument executed by the buyer\nshall also be returned within ten business days.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_624__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every contract for services shall provide that such health club\nshall accept cancellation of a membership by the buyer or the buyer's\nestate, as provided in this section, no later than three business days\nafter receiving notice of the cancellation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_624__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a contract for services is due for renewal on an annual\nbasis, such contract for services following the initial contract shall\nprovide that such health club shall accept cancellation of renewal of a\nmembership, by the buyer or the buyer's estate, provided such request is\nmade within fifteen business days after such renewal takes effect. Where\na contract for service is due for renewal on a monthly basis, such\ncontract for services following the initial contract shall provide that\nsuch health club shall accept cancellation of renewal of a monthly\nmembership, by the buyer or the buyer's estate provided such request is\nmade within three business days after such renewal takes effect.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_624__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such health club shall accept notice of cancellation of a\nmembership through methods including, but not limited to, website,\nelectronic mail, telephone, mail, or in person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_624__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a health club allows a buyer to enter into a contract for\nservices through a website, such health club shall accept a notice of\ncancellation of such contract through such website in addition to the\nmethods provided pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_624__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>