<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-642"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-642"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="642"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-642/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-642/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-642/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-642/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_642">
        <num>642</num>
        <heading>Weight loss services; notice</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_642__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conspicuously post a\nsign, measuring at least nine inches by fourteen inches, where consumers\nare offered the services or products, in writing, in at least ten point\nprint, or (ii) provide in writing, in at least ten point print, to\nindividuals and consumers prior to the purchase of such goods or\nservices the following notice or some other notice which substantially\ncontains or provides the following information.\n                    WEIGHT LOSS AND DIETING INFORMATION\n  a. WARNING! Rapid weight loss may cause serious health problems. Rapid\nweight loss is weight loss of more than 1 1/2 to 2 pounds per week or\nweight loss of more than 1 percent of body weight per week after the\nsecond week of participation in a weight loss program.\n  b. Consult your physician before starting any weight loss program or\nusing any diet medications or formulas.\n  c. Long term weight control is the safest and most important goal of\nany diet program. Permanent lifestyle changes such as eating nutritious\nfoods, calorie control and increasing physical activity help promote\nlong term weight loss according to medical experts.\n  d. Ask the person providing or selling you weight loss advice or diet\nproducts, medications or formulas about their qualifications and\ntraining in nutrition and health.\n  e. You have the right to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_642__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Ask questions about the potential health risks of this program or\nproduct, its nutritional content, and its psychological-support and\neducational components;\n  (ii) Know the price of treatment, including the price of any extra\nproducts, services, supplements and laboratory tests; and\n  (iii) Know the program duration of the program recommended to you.\n  2. The provisions of this section shall not apply to direct sellers,\nretail stores or pharmacies selling weight loss products and providing\ninformation to the public regarding individual products, unless such\nbusinesses offer both weight loss services and weight loss products.\nFurthermore, the provisions of this section shall not apply to weight\nloss services provided to an individual by any person, firm or\ncorporation which provides weight loss services incidental to their\nprimary professional services to such individual and which does not\noffer to sell weight loss services or weight loss products to the\npublic.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>