<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-670*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-670*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="670*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-670*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-670*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-670*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-670*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_670*2">
        <num>670*2</num>
        <heading>Repair, replacement and refund under new wheelchair warranties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_670*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Accept return of the wheelchair and replace the wheelchair with a\ncomparable new wheelchair and refund any collateral costs.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_670*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Accept return of the wheelchair and refund to the consumer and to\nany holder of a perfected security interest in the consumer's\nwheelchair, as their interest may appear, the full purchase price plus\nany finance charge amount paid by the consumer at the point of sale and\ncollateral costs, less a reasonable allowance for use. A reasonable\nallowance for use may not exceed the amount obtained by multiplying the\nfull purchase price of the wheelchair by a fraction, the denominator of\nwhich is one thousand eight hundred twenty-five and the numerator of\nwhich is the number of days that the wheelchair was driven before the\nconsumer first reported the nonconformity to the wheelchair dealer.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_670*2__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_670*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>With respect to a consumer described under subparagraph four\nof paragraph b of subdivision one of this section, accept return of the\nwheelchair, refund to the wheelchair lessor and to any holder of a\nperfected security interest in the wheelchair, as their interest may\nappear, the current value of the written lease and refund to the\nconsumer the amount that the consumer paid under the written lease plus\nany collateral costs, less a reasonable allowance for use.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_670*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The current value of the written lease equals the total amount for\nwhich that lease obligates the consumer during the period of the lease\nremaining after its early termination, plus the wheelchair dealer's\nearly termination costs and the value of the wheelchair at the lease\nexpiration date if the lease sets forth that value, less the wheelchair\nlessor's early termination savings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_670*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A reasonable allowance for use may not exceed the amount obtained\nby multiplying the total amount for which the written lease obligates\nthe consumer by a fraction, the denominator of which is one thousand\neight hundred twenty-five and the numerator of which is the number of\ndays that the consumer drove the wheelchair before first reporting the\nnonconformity to the manufacturer, wheelchair lessor or wheelchair\ndealer.\n  c. To receive a comparable new wheelchair or a refund due under\nsubparagraph one or two of paragraph b of this subdivision, a consumer\ndescribed under subparagraph one, two or three of paragraph b of\nsubdivision one of this section, shall offer to the manufacturer of the\nwheelchair having the nonconformity to transfer possession of that\nwheelchair to that manufacturer. No later than twenty days after that\noffer, the manufacturer shall provide the consumer with the comparable\nnew wheelchair or refund. When the manufacturer provides the new\nwheelchair or refund, the consumer shall return the wheelchair having\nthe nonconformity to the manufacturer, along with any endorsements\nnecessary to transfer real possession to the manufacturer.\n  d.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_670*2__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To receive a refund due under subparagraph three of paragraph b\nof this subdivision, a consumer described under subparagraph four of\nparagraph b of subdivision one of this section shall offer to return the\nwheelchair having the nonconformity to its manufacturer. No later than\nthirty days after that offer, the manufacturer shall provide the refund\nto the consumer. When the manufacturer provides the refund, the consumer\nshall return to the manufacturer the wheelchair having the\nnonconformity.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_670*2__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To receive a refund due under subparagraph three of paragraph b of\nthis subdivision, a wheelchair lessor shall offer to transfer possession\nof the wheelchair having the nonconformity to its manufacturer. No later\nthan thirty days after that offer, the manufacturer shall provide the\nrefund to the wheelchair lessor. When the manufacturer provides the\nrefund, the wheelchair lessor shall provide to the manufacturer any\nendorsements necessary to transfer legal possession to the manufacturer.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_670*2__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No person may enforce the lease against the consumer after the\nconsumer receives a refund due under subparagraph three of paragraph b\nof this subdivision.\n  e. No wheelchair returned by a consumer or wheelchair lessor in this\nstate pursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision, or by a consumer or\nwheelchair lessor in another state under a similar law of that state,\nmay be sold or leased again in this state unless full disclosure of the\nreasons for return is made to any prospective buyer or lessee.\n  4. a. Each consumer shall have the option of submitting any dispute\narising under this section upon the payment of a prescribed filing fee\nto an alternate arbitration mechanism established pursuant to\nregulations promulgated hereunder by the New York state attorney\ngeneral. Upon application of the consumer and payment of the filing fee,\nall manufacturers shall submit to such alternate arbitration.\n  b. Such alternate arbitration shall be conducted by a professional\narbitrator ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>