<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-673"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-673"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="673"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-673/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-673/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-673/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-673/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_673">
        <num>673</num>
        <heading>Wrongful disclosure of video tape rental records</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_673__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to a grand jury pursuant to a grand jury subpoena;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_673__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pursuant to a court order, in a civil proceeding upon a showing of\ncompelling need for the information that cannot be accommodated by any\nother means, or in a criminal proceeding upon a showing of legitimate\nneed for the information that cannot be accommodated by any other means,\nif:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_673__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the consumer is given reasonable notice, by the person seeking the\ndisclosure, of the court proceeding relevant to the issuance of the\ncourt order;\n  (ii) the consumer is afforded the opportunity to appear and contest\nthe claim of the person seeking the disclosure; and\n  (iii) the court imposes appropriate safeguards against unauthorized\ndisclosure;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_673__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to a law enforcement agency pursuant to a warrant lawfully\nobtained under the laws of this state or the United States; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_673__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to a court pursuant to a civil action for conversion commenced by\nthe video tape service provider or to enforce collection of fines for\noverdue or unreturned video tapes, and then only to the extent necessary\nto establish the fact of the rental. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a\ncourt shall impose appropriate safeguards against unauthorized\ndisclosure.\n  3. A video tape service provider may disclose personally identifiable\ninformation concerning any consumer:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_673__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the consumer;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_673__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to any person with the informed, written consent of the consumer;\nor\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_673__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to any person if the disclosure is incident to the ordinary course\nof business of the video tape service provider.\n  4. Personally identifiable information obtained in any manner other\nthan as provided in this section shall not be received in evidence in\nany trial, hearing, arbitration, or other proceeding in or before any\ncourt, grand jury, department, officer, agency, regulatory body,\nlegislative committee or other authority of the state or any political\nsubdivision thereof.\n  5. A person subject to this section shall destroy personally\nidentifiable information as soon as practicable, but no later than one\nyear from the date the information is no longer necessary for the\npurpose for which it was collected and there are no pending requests or\norders for access to such information under this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>