<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="69-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_69_M">
        <num>69-M</num>
        <heading>License required</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 69-m. License required. 1. On and after October first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-two, no person shall engage in the business of\ninstalling, servicing or maintaining security or fire alarm systems or\nhold himself out as being able so to do unless he is licensed therefor\npursuant to this article.  Nothing herein shall prohibit a person\nlicensed in accordance with the provisions of this article from\nemploying individuals to assist in the installation, servicing or\nmaintaining of security or fire alarm systems, provided such licensee\nissues identification cards on a form prescribed by the secretary of\nstate to each unlicensed individual.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\na license shall not be required of a person to engage in the business of\ninstalling, servicing or maintaining security or fire alarm systems if\nsuch an alarm system is to be installed in a motor vehicle, water vessel\nor aircraft or is a battery-operated smoke detection device.\nFurthermore, a property owner or proprietor who purchases or owns an\nalarm system to be installed by him or his employees onto his property\nor place of business shall not fall under the provisions of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>