<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="69-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_69_N">
        <num>69-N</num>
        <heading>Powers of the secretary of state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 69-n. Powers of the secretary of state. In addition to the powers\nand duties elsewhere prescribed in this article, the secretary of state\nshall have power:\n  1. To appoint an adequate number of assistants, inspectors and other\nemployees as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this\narticle, to prescribe their duties, and to fix their compensation within\nthe amount appropriated therefor.\n  2. To examine into the qualifications and fitness of applicants for\nlicenses under this article.\n  3. To keep records of all licenses issued, suspended or revoked.\n  4. To prepare a manual of rules and regulations for the conduct of\nexaminations and to furnish copies thereof to persons desiring the same\nupon payment of a reasonable fee therefor.\n  5. To adopt such rules and regulations not inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this article, as may be necessary with respect to the form\nand content of applications for licenses, the reception thereof, the\ninvestigation and examination of applicants and their qualifications,\nand the other matters incidental or appropriate to his powers and duties\nas prescribed by this article and for the proper administration and\nenforcement of the provisions of this article, and to amend or repeal\nany of such rules and regulations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>