<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="69-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-69-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_69_P">
        <num>69-P</num>
        <heading>License without examination</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_69_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_69_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, respectively, of subdivision one of section\nsixty-nine-o of this article and the required annual license fee, is\nfiled with the secretary of state.\n  2. The secretary of state shall upon application and without\nexamination, issue a license to any person over the age of eighteen\nyears who has been duly licensed by any other state, territory,\nprotectorate or dependency of the United States to engage in the\nbusiness of installing, servicing or maintaining security or fire alarm\nsystems upon compliance with standards and requirements not lower, in\nthe judgment of the secretary of state, than those of this state,\nprovided, however, that such state extends similar reciprocity to\nlicensees of this state. Such application shall be accompanied by the\nrequirements of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_69_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_69_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, respectively, of subdivision one\nof section sixty-nine-o of this article and the required license fee.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_69_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any person, eligible for any license, mentioned in this\nsection, be in the military service at or during the time application\nfor such license is required to be filed and license fee paid, according\nto the provisions of this section, the period within which said\napplication may be filed and license fee may be paid, is extended in\nbehalf of such person, until three months after the termination of said\nmilitary service, any provision contained in this article to the\ncontrary, notwithstanding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_69_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the case of persons who are or were in the military service and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_69_P__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have been or will be discharged under conditions other than\ndishonorable, or (ii) have a qualifying condition, as defined in section\none of the veterans' services law, and received a discharge other than\nbad conduct or dishonorable from such service, or (iii) are discharged\nLGBT veterans, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law,\nand have received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable\nfrom such service, the period of two years specified in subdivision one\nof this section need not be continuous. The length of time such person\nwas engaged in the business of installing, servicing or maintaining\nsecurity or fire alarm systems before entering the military service may\nbe added to any period of time during which such person was or is\nengaged in the business of installing, servicing or maintaining security\nor fire alarm systems after the termination of military service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>