<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-697-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-697-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="697-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-697-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-697-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-697-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-697-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_697_D">
        <num>697-D</num>
        <heading>New farm equipment bill of rights</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 697-d. New farm equipment bill of rights. A supplier shall provide\nthe following notice, entitled "New Farm Equipment Bill of Rights" along\nwith a written copy of the provisions of this article, to its authorized\ndealers in this state, and the dealer shall provide such bill of rights\nto each consumer at the time of purchase or lease of farm equipment.\nSuch notice shall be printed in conspicuous ten point bold face type.\n                    NEW FARM EQUIPMENT BILL OF RIGHTS\n  (1) IN ADDITION TO ANY WARRANTIES PROVIDED FOR YOUR FARM EQUIPMENT,\nYOUR NEW FARM EQUIPMENT, PURCHASED WITHIN OR OUTSIDE OF THIS STATE, IS\nWARRANTED AGAINST ALL MATERIAL DEFECTS FOR ONE YEAR.\n  (2) YOU MUST REPORT ANY PROBLEMS TO THE WARRANTOR OR ITS DEALER IN\nWRITING WITHIN THE WARRANTY PERIOD. ALTHOUGH, IF IN THE LAST THIRTY DAYS\nOF THE WARRANTY, YOU ARE ONLY ABLE TO PROVIDE A VERBAL NOTICE, YOU WILL\nHAVE UP TO THIRTY DAYS AFTER THE EXPIRATION OF THE WARRANTY TO PROVIDE A\nWRITTEN NOTICE.\n  (3) A WARRANTOR OR A DEALER MAY NOT CHARGE FOR THE PARTS OR LABOR\nINVOLVED IN THE REPAIR OF THE DEFECT WITHIN THE WARRANTY PERIOD.\n  (4) IF THE SAME PROBLEM CANNOT BE REPAIRED AFTER FOUR ATTEMPTS DURING\nTHE WARRANTY PERIOD; OR IF YOUR EQUIPMENT IS OUT OF SERVICE TO REPAIR A\nPROBLEM FOR A TOTAL OF THIRTY DAYS DURING THE WARRANTY PERIOD; OR IF THE\nSUPPLIER OR ITS DEALER REFUSES TO REPAIR A SUBSTANTIAL DEFECT OR\nCONDITION WITHIN TWENTY DAYS OF RECEIPT OF WRITTEN NOTICE SENT BY YOU TO\nTHE SUPPLIER; THEN YOU MAY BE ENTITLED, AT YOUR OPTION, TO EITHER\nCOMPARABLE FARM EQUIPMENT OR A REFUND OF YOUR PURCHASE PRICE FROM THE\nWARRANTOR, MINUS A USE ALLOWANCE.\n  (5) A WARRANTOR MAY DENY LIABILITY IF THE PROBLEM IS CAUSED BY ABUSE,\nNEGLECT, OR UNAUTHORIZED MODIFICATIONS OF THE EQUIPMENT.\n  (6) A WARRANTOR MAY REFUSE TO EXCHANGE COMPARABLE EQUIPMENT OR REFUND\nYOUR PURCHASE PRICE IF THE PROBLEM DOES NOT SUBSTANTIALLY IMPAIR THE\nVALUE, SAFETY OR USE OF YOUR FARM EQUIPMENT.\n  (7) IF THE WARRANTOR DOES NOT HAVE AN ARBITRATION PROCEDURE, YOU MAY\nRESORT TO ANY REMEDY BY LAW AND MAY BE ENTITLED TO YOUR ATTORNEY'S FEES\nIF YOU PREVAIL.\n  (8) NO CONTRACT OR AGREEMENT CAN VOID ANY OF THESE RIGHTS.\n  (9) AS AN ALTERNATIVE TO THE ARBITRATION PROCEDURE MADE AVAILABLE\nTHROUGH THE WARRANTOR, YOU MAY INSTEAD CHOOSE TO SUBMIT YOUR CLAIM TO AN\nINDEPENDENT ARBITRATOR, APPROVED BY THE ATTORNEY GENERAL. YOU WILL HAVE\nTO PAY A FEE FOR SUCH AN ARBITRATION. CONTACT YOUR LOCAL CONSUMER OFFICE\nOR ATTORNEY GENERAL'S OFFICE TO FIND OUT HOW TO ARRANGE FOR INDEPENDENT\nARBITRATION.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>