<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-7"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-7"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7">
        <num>7</num>
        <heading>Public sports and exercises on Sunday</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7. Public sports and exercises on Sunday. All public sports,\nexercises or shows, except professional golf tournaments and games of\nthe World University Games conducted in Erie, Genesee and Niagara\ncounties in nineteen hundred ninety-three, upon the first day of the\nweek, and all noise unreasonably disturbing the peace of the day are\nprohibited, except as hereinafter provided.\n  Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, it shall be lawful to\nconduct, witness, participate or engage in any form of public sports,\nexercises or shows which are conducted or engaged in primarily for the\nentertainment of spectators, not specifically prohibited by any\nprovision of the law, on the first day of the week after five minutes\npast one o'clock in the afternoon, to witness which the public is\ninvited or an admission fee is charged, either directly or indirectly,\nin a city, town or village as shall be permitted by local law or\nordinance heretofore or hereafter adopted by the common council or other\nlegislative body of the city, town or village permitting such public\nsports, exercises or shows on such day and after such hour provided,\nhowever, the failure of a city, town or village in which a municipally\nowned stadium, arena or facility is located, to adopt such a local law\nor ordinance shall not prohibit such public sports, exercises or shows\nbeginning after five minutes past one o'clock in the afternoon on the\nfirst day of the week in any such stadium, arena or facility.\n  Nothing herein contained shall be deemed to prohibit private sports,\ngames or recreational activities which are engaged in primarily for the\npersonal enjoyment, recreation and health of the participants, on the\nfirst day of the week, conducted in a manner which does not constitute a\nserious interruption of the repose or religious liberty of the\ncommunity.\n  Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, it shall be\nlawful for pari-mutuel facilities licensed in accordance with article\ntwo of the racing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law to conduct or\nengage in activities authorized under their licensure on the first day\nof the week after twelve o'clock post meridian.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>