<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-70-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-70-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-08-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="70-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-70-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-70-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-70-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-70-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_70_A">
        <num>70-A</num>
        <heading>Bail enforcement agents and watch, guard or patrol agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 70-a. Bail enforcement agents and watch, guard or patrol agencies.\n1. The department of state shall have the power to issue separate\nlicenses to bail enforcement agents and to watch, guard or patrol\nagencies. Nothing in this article shall prevent a private investigator\nlicensed hereunder from performing the services of a watch, guard or\npatrol agency or bail enforcement agent as defined in this article;\nhowever, a watch, guard or patrol agency or bail enforcement agent may\nnot perform the services of a private investigator as defined in this\narticle.\n  2. No person, firm, company, partnership, limited liability company or\ncorporation shall engage in the business of bail enforcement agents or\nthe business of watch, guard or patrol agency, or advertise his, their\nor its business to be that of bail enforcement agent or watch, guard or\npatrol agency, notwithstanding the name or title used in describing such\nagency or notwithstanding the fact that other functions and services may\nalso be performed for fee, hire or reward, without having first obtained\nfrom the department of state a license so to do, as hereinafter\nprovided, for each bureau, agency, sub-agency, office and branch office\nto be owned, conducted, managed or maintained by such person, firm,\ncompany, partnership, limited liability company or corporation for the\nconduct of such business.\n  3. Any person, firm, company, partnership or corporation who violates\nany provision of this section shall be guilty of a class B misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>