<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-733"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-733"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="733"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-733/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-733/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-733/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-733/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_733">
        <num>733</num>
        <heading>Warrantor liability for authorized aftermarket rustproofing; notification</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 733. Warrantor liability for authorized aftermarket rustproofing;\nnotification. 1. It shall be unlawful for a warrantor to include in any\nwarranty agreement a clause that purports to limit a buyer's warranty\nprotection on the basis that the buyer has, or may have, a claim under\nan existing warranty.\n  2. It shall be unlawful for a warrantor to fail to notify a buyer in\nwriting within ten business days of inspecting the buyer's motor vehicle\nfor rust damage whether the warranty claim will be allowed or denied. If\nthe claim is denied, the specific reasons for the denial shall be stated\nin writing.\n  3. It shall be unlawful for a warrantor to fail to honor a buyer's\nwarranty claim on the basis that the aftermarket rustproofing was\napplied improperly, if such service was provided by a person authorized\nby the warrantor.\n  4. Nothing contained in this section shall be deemed to prevent a\nwarrantor from refusing to honor a warranty claim based upon the failure\nof a buyer to comply with provisions of a warranty with respect to the\nproper care and maintenance of the aftermarket rustproofing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>