<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-75"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-75"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-75/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-75/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-75/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-75/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75">
        <num>75</num>
        <heading>Posting and surrender of license certificate</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 75. Posting and surrender of license certificate. Immediately upon\nthe receipt of the license certificate issued by the department of state\npursuant to this article, the licensee named therein shall cause such\nlicense certificate to be posted up and at all times displayed in a\nconspicuous place in the bureau, agency, sub-agency, office or branch\noffice for which it is issued, so that all persons visiting such place\nmay readily see the same. Such license certificate shall at all\nreasonable times be subject to inspection by the secretary of state or\nan authorized representative or representatives of the department of\nstate. It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, partnership, limited\nliability company or corporation holding such license certificate to\npost such certificate or to permit such certificate to be posted upon\npremises other than those described therein or to which it has been\ntransferred pursuant to the provisions of this article, or knowingly to\nalter, deface or destroy any such license certificate. Every license\ncertificate shall be surrendered to the department of state within\nseventy-two hours after its terms shall have expired or after notice in\nwriting to the holder that such license has been revoked. Failure to\ncomply with any of the provisions of this section is a misdemeanor and\nsufficient cause for the revocation of a license.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>