<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="750-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_750_F">
        <num>750-F</num>
        <heading>Licenses; display; renewal; duplicates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 750-f. Licenses; display; renewal; duplicates.  1. All licenses\nshall be for a period of two years.\n  2. No license shall be assignable or transferable except as\nhereinafter provided.\n  3. A license to conduct the business of operating a pet cemetery or\npet crematorium issued to an individual may be assigned or transferred\nfor the remainder of the license period to a partnership or corporation\nif such individual is a member of such partnership or an officer of such\ncorporation at the time of such assignment or transfer. A license issued\nto a partnership may be assigned or transferred for the remainder of the\nlicense period to any one member of such partnership, provided he\nobtains the consent of all of the other members of such partnership. A\nlicense issued to a corporation may be assigned or transferred for the\nremainder of the license period to any officer of the corporation,\nprovided he obtains the consent of all of the other officers of such\ncorporation. The application for such transfer or assignment must be\naccompanied by the requirements of section seven hundred fifty-e of this\narticle and by proof satisfactory to the department that the\nrequirements herein provided have been complied with. No assignment or\ntransfer shall become effective unless and until the endorsement has\nbeen made on the face of the license by the department and such license,\nso endorsed, has been returned to the assignee or transferee. All such\nendorsements shall be made without payment of any fee. A bona fide\npurchaser of such business from the holder of the license thereof may\ncontinue to use the license of the seller from the date of the sale,\nprovided there is endorsed on the face thereof the name of the\npurchaser, the date of the sale, and the signature of the seller and the\npurchaser; and provided further within five days from the date of the\nsale, an application, in accordance with the provisions of this article,\nshall be presented by the purchaser to the secretary of state for a\nlicense to conduct the business of operating a pet cemetery or pet\ncrematorium. Such license shall be valid until the purchaser's license\napplication is either granted or denied by the secretary of state.\n  4. A license to conduct the business of operating a pet cemetery or\npet crematorium issued to an individual or to a partnership may be used\nafter the death of the licensed individual or co-partner by his next of\nkin or duly appointed administrator or executor in the name of the\nestate from the date of death of such individual or co-partner, provided\nthat there is endorsed upon the face of the license after the name of\nthe decedent the word "deceased", the date of death and the name of the\nnext of kin, administrator or executor under whose authority the license\nis being used, provided that within thirty days from the date of death\nof the licensee, an application, in accordance with the provisions of\nthis article, shall be presented by the next of kin, administrator or\nexecutor to the secretary of state for a license to conduct the business\nof operating a pet cemetery or pet crematorium. Such license shall be\nvalid until the next of kin's, administrator's or executor's license\napplication is either granted or denied by the secretary of state.\n  5. A license to conduct the business of operating a pet cemetery or\npet crematorium shall be conspicuously posted upon the premises where\nthe licensee is engaged in the business of operating a pet cemetery or\npet crematorium.\n  6. Any license which has not been suspended or revoked, may, upon the\npayment of the renewal fee prescribed by this article, be renewed for\nadditional periods of two years from its expiration, upon the filing of\nan application for such renewal, on a form to be prescribed by the\nsecretary of state.\n  7. Any person failing to file application and fee for renewal of a\nlicense to conduct the business of operating a pet cemetery or pet\ncrematorium within forty-five days immediately following the expiration\nof his or her last license shall pay an additional fee of sixty dollars,\nand if he or she fails to file application and fee for renewal within\nninety days he or she shall be ineligible for such license until he or\nshe shall have again met the requirements set forth in this article.\n  8. A duplicate license may be issued for one lost, destroyed or\nmutilated upon application therefor on a form prescribed by the\nsecretary of state and the payment of the fee prescribed therefor by\nthis article. Each such duplicate license shall have the word\n"duplicate" stamped across the face thereof and shall bear the same\nnumber as the one it replaces.\n  9. Notice in writing shall be given the secretary of state within\nthirty days at his or her office in Albany by the holder of a license to\nconduct the business of operating a pet cemetery or pet crematorium of\nany change in address of the business or residence of the person engaged\nin the business of operating a pet cemetery or pet crematorium together\nwith the return of license, whereupon a properly signed endorsement will\nbe made on the face of the license as to such change and the license\nthen returned to the licensee. A change of address by a licensee without\nsuch notice and endorsement of license shall operate to cancel the\nlicense.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>