<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="750-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_750_Q">
        <num>750-Q</num>
        <heading>Maintenance fees for pet cemeteries</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_750_Q__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The annual maintenance fee, billed each calendar year shall be\nplaced by the pet cemetery owner in the general account of the pet\ncemetery to be used for pet cemetery operation and maintenance during\nthe succeeding years. For the purposes of this section and section seven\nhundred fifty-r of this article, the term pet cemetery operation and\nmaintenance shall mean all costs incurred to operate and maintain a pet\ncemetery including salaries and bonuses for employees, officers and\ndirectors, but shall not include any fines or penalties imposed by the\nsecretary of state or other agency or court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_750_Q__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the annual maintenance fee is not paid within ninety days of\nthe date of which it is due, the pet cemetery owner shall notify the pet\nowner in writing that such fee is due and payable. If such annual\nmaintenance fee is not paid within ninety days of such writing, the\ndisposal rights or rights to continuing care of a pet grave of the pet\nowner shall terminate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_750_Q__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the annual maintenance fee is not paid within one hundred\neighty days of the date of which it is due, the disposal rights of a pet\nowner shall then terminate and the pet cemetery owner may at anytime\nthereafter remove such pet and if removed dispose of remains by mass\ncremation or mass burial.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_750_Q__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this section shall prevent a pet owner from prepaying\nannual maintenance fees for any number of years in advance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>