<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="750-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_750_A">
        <num>750-A</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_750_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>rendering plants licensed pursuant to article five-C of the\nagriculture and markets law, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_750_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a landfill or other disposal facility at which solid waste, or its\nresidue after treatment, is intentionally placed and at which, solid\nwaste shall remain indefinitely.\n  6. "Pet crematorium" means any land, place, structure, facility or\nbuilding provided by any person for a fee, whether or not for profit, to\nveterinarians or members of the general public for the cremation of\npets. However, a pet crematorium shall not provide for permanent\ninterment or inurnment of pet remains. Provided, however, this\ndefinition shall not apply to facilities designed for resource recovery\nas defined in section 27-0701 of the environmental conservation law.\nProvided further, that it shall not include any disposal facility\nregulated under title fifteen of article twenty-seven of the\nenvironmental conservation law that is primarily engaged in incineration\nof medical waste.\n  7. "Pet" means any domestic animal that has been adapted or tamed to\nlive in intimate association with people but is not limited to, dogs,\ncats, rodents, fish, birds, snakes, turtles, lizards, frogs and rabbits.\n  8. "Pet owner" means the person who is listed as the owner of the pet\nin veterinary records or pet cemetery or crematorium records or his or\nher agent or employee. In the event that such pet owner is a minor then\na parent or legal guardian or his or her agent or employee shall be\ndeemed the pet owner for the purposes of the pet disposal form required\nin section seven hundred fifty-s of this article.\n  9. "Individual burial" means the interment of a single pet's remains\nin a separate grave. However, nothing in this section shall prevent the\ninterment of more than one pet in a grave with the written consent of\nthe pet owner.\n  10. "Mass burial" means the interment of pet remains communally in a\ngrave containing more than one pet.\n  11. "Individual cremation" means the cremation of a single pet's\nremains in a separate receptacle that allows the pet's cremains to\nremain separate...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>