<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-V"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-V"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="750-V"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_750_V">
        <num>750-V</num>
        <heading>Duties of pet cemetery owners and operators</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 750-v. Duties of pet cemetery owners and operators. All pet cemetery\nowners and operators shall have the following duties:\n  1. To keep permanently maps and records containing the specific site\nof each pet grave, the grave owner's last known address, the date of\nburial, the size of such grave, the contract for sale of such grave and\npet disposal forms provided however that the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall apply only to individual burials.\n  2. To keep complete records of the names of trustees of any trust\naccounts and complete records of all trust fund money.\n  3. To clearly inform customers of the option of paying maintenance\nfees for care of pet graves, including costs and benefits for permanent\ncare for pet graves and annual care for pet graves.\n  4. To cooperate with all reasonable requests of inspectors appointed\nby the secretary of state to inspect pet cemeteries and pet\ncrematoriums.\n  5. To provide notice to customers about hours that the cemetery will\nopen to customers to view pet graves.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>