<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="750"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-750/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_750">
        <num>750</num>
        <heading>Declaration of policy</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 750. Declaration of policy. The legislature hereby finds and\ndeclares that the relationships that humans develop with other members\nof the animal kingdom that are taken into our homes and kept as pets are\nunique and special. These relationships can enrich our lives and\nincrease our happiness. Even after the death of a pet, human attachment\nto the memory of the pet often remains very strong and many people feel\nthe need to memorialize their love for their animal by burying their pet\nin a pet cemetery. Pet cemeteries, their managers and owners have a\nspecial responsibility to their customers who have entrusted their pets'\nremains with them.  These pet cemeteries have a duty to act in an\nethical and lawful manner to prevent grieving pet owners from\nexperiencing further any emotional pain or financial manipulation.\nPerpetrations of fraud against grieving pet owners are unconscionable.\n  The legislature further finds and declares that the people of this\nstate have a vital interest in the establishment, maintenance and\npreservation of pet cemeteries and pet crematoriums and the proper\noperation of the businesses and individuals which own and manage the\nsame. This article is determined an exercise of the police powers of\nthis state to protect the well-being of our citizens, to promote the\npublic welfare, to promote the health of the public and to prevent pet\ncemeteries and pet crematoriums from falling into disrepair and\ndilapidation and becoming a burden upon the community.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>