<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-752"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-752"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="752"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-752/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-752/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-752/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-752/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_752">
        <num>752</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_752__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 501 of the federal Internal Revenue\nCode, 26 U.S.C. 501, or any subsequent corresponding sections of the\nfederal Internal Revenue Code, as from time to time amended, that duly\nlicensed as an animal shelter pursuant to article twenty-six-C of the\nagriculture and markets law. For purposes of sections seven hundred\nfifty-three-a, seven hundred fifty-three-b, seven hundred fifty-three-c\nand seven hundred fifty-three-d of this article, "pet dealer" shall mean\nany person who engages in the sale or offering for sale of more than\nnine animals per year for profit to the public. Such definition shall\ninclude breeders who sell animals; but it shall not include the\nfollowing:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_752__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any breeder who sells or offers to sell directly to the consumer\nfewer than twenty-five animals per year that are born and raised on the\nbreeders residential premises.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_752__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any municipal pound or shelter established and maintained pursuant\nto subdivision one of section one hundred fourteen of the agriculture\nand markets law and duly licensed as an animal shelter pursuant to\narticle twenty-six-C of the agriculture and markets law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_752__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any duly incorporated society for the prevention of cruelty to\nanimals, duly incorporated humane society, duly incorporated animal\nprotective association or other duly incorporated animal adoption or\nanimal rescue organization that is exempt from taxes pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_752__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_752__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 501 of the federal Internal\nRevenue Code, 26 U.S.C. 501, or any subsequent corresponding sections of\nthe federal Internal Revenue Code, as from time to time amended, that is\nduly licensed as an animal shelter pursuant to article twenty-six-C of\nthe agriculture and markets law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_752__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any retail pet shop as defined in subdivision eight of this\nsection.\n  4. "Commissioner" shall mean the commissioner of agriculture and\nmarkets.\n  5. "Person" means any individual, corporation, partnership,\nassociation, municipality, or other legal entity.\n  6. "Nonelective surgical procedure" means a surgical procedure that is\nnecessary to preserve or restore the health of an animal, to prevent an\nanimal from experiencing pain or discomfort, or to correct a condition\nthat would interfere with an animal's ability to walk, run, jump, or\notherwise function in a normal manner.\n  7. "Clinically ill" means an illness that is apparent to a\nveterinarian based on observation, examination, or testing of an animal\nor upon review of the medical records relating to the animal.\n  8. "Retail pet shop" means any for-profit place of business that sells\nor offers for sale animals to be kept as household pets, pet food or\nsupplies, but shall not include breeders who sell or offer to sell\ndirectly to the consumer animals that are born and raised on the\nbreeder's residential premises.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>