<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="753-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_753_C">
        <num>753-C</num>
        <heading>Animal pedigree registration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A pet dealer that\nsells animals registered or registrable with a pedigree registry shall\npost conspicuously within close proximity to those animals a notice that\nstates: "Pedigree registration means that the particular registry\nmaintains information on the parentage and identity of the animal".\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For every animal sold by a pet dealer that is sold with the\nrepresentation that the animal is registered or registrable with an\nanimal pedigree registry organization, the following fully completed\ndisclosure shall be made by the pet dealer in writing on a sheet\nseparate from any other statement in substantially the following form:\n"Disclosure of Animal pedigree registration: Description of animal: The\nanimal you are purchasing is registered/registrable (circle one) with\nthe (enter name of registry). Registration means that (enter name of\nregistry) maintains information regarding the parentage and identity of\nthis animal. Persons buying animals represented by a pet dealer as being\nregistrable are entitled to the papers necessary to effect such\nregistration within 120 days of purchase. Failure to provide such papers\nentitles the purchaser to remedies under law. However, if the purchaser\nnotifies the pet dealer within the 120 day period that he or she has not\nreceived such papers, the pet dealer shall have an additional 60 days\ncommencing at the end of the 120 day period in which to provide the\ndocuments. Acknowledged:  Date: Purchaser's Signature."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The disclosure shall be signed and dated by the purchaser of the\nanimal, acknowledging receipt of a copy of the statement. The pet dealer\nshall retain a copy of the signed disclosure.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>