<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="753-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_753_B">
        <num>753-B</num>
        <heading>Information statement for purchaser</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The breeder's and, if applicable, broker's name and address, if\nknown, or, if not known, the source of the cat. If the person from whom\nthe cat was obtained is a dealer licensed by the United States\ndepartment of agriculture, the person's name, address, and federal\nidentification number;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The date of the cat's birth, unless unknown because of the source\nof the cat, the date the pet dealer received the cat, and the location\nwhere the cat was received;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A record of immunizations and worming treatments administered, if\nany, to the cat as of the time of sale while the cat was in the\npossession of the pet dealer, including the dates of administration and\nthe type of vaccines or worming treatments administered;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A record of any known disease, sickness, or congenital condition\nthat adversely affects the health of the cat at the time of sale;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A record of any veterinary treatment or medication received by the\ncat while in the possession of the pet dealer and either of the\nfollowing:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement, signed by the pet dealer at the time of sale,\nindicating all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_753_B__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The cat has no known disease or\nillness;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_753_B__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The cat has no known congenital or hereditary condition\nthat adversely affects the health of the cat at the time of sale; or\n  (ii) A record of any known congenital or hereditary condition,\ndisease, or illness that adversely affects the health of the cat at the\ntime of sale, along with a statement signed by a licensed veterinarian\nthat authorizes the sale of the cat, recommends necessary treatment, if\nany, and verifies that the condition, disease or illness does not\nrequire hospitalization or non-elective surgical procedures, and is not\nlikely to require hospitalization or non-elective surgical procedures in\nthe future. A veterinarian statement is not required for intestinal or\nexternal parasites unless their presence makes the cat clinically ill or\nis likely to make the cat clinically ill. The statement shall be valid\nfor fourteen business days following examination of the cat by the\nveterinarian.\n  2. For dogs:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The breeder's and, if applicable, broker's name and address, if\nknown, or if not known, the source of the dog. If the person from whom\nthe dog was obtained is a dealer licensed by the United States\ndepartment of agriculture, the person's name, address, and federal\nidentification number;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The date of the dog's birth and the date and location the pet\ndealer received the dog. If the dog is not advertised or sold as a\npurebred, registered or registrable, the date of birth may be\napproximated if not known by the seller;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The breed, sex, color and identifying marks at the time of sale.\nIf the dog is from a United States department of agriculture licensed\nsource, the individual identifying tag, tattoo, or collar number for\nthat animal. If the breed is unknown or mixed, the record shall so\nindicate. If the dog is being sold as being capable of registration, the\nnames and registration numbers of the sire and dam, and the litter\nnumber, if known;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A record of inoculations and worming treatments administered, if\nany, to the dog as of the time of sale while the dog was in the\npossession of the pet dealer, including dates of administration and the\ntype of vaccines and/or worming treatments administered;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A record of any veterinary treatment or medication received by the\ndog while in the possession of the pet dealer and either of the\nfollowing:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement, signed by the pet dealer at the time of sale,\nindicating all of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_753_B__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The dog has no known disease or\nillness;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_753_B__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The dog has no known congenital or hereditary condition\nthat adversely affects the health of the dog at the time of the sale; or\n  (ii) A record of any known congenital or hereditary condition, disease\nor illness that adversely affects the health of the dog at the time of\nsale, along with a statement signed by a licensed veterinarian that\nauthorizes the sale of the dog, recommends necessary treatment, if any,\nand verifies that the condition, disease, or illness does not require\nhospitalization or non-elective surgical procedures, and is not likely\nto require hospitalization or non-elective surgical procedures in the\nfuture. A veterinarian statement is not required for intestinal or\nexternal parasites unless their presence makes the dog clinically ill or\nis likely to make the dog clinically ill. The statement shall be valid\nfor fourteen business days following examination of the dog by the\nveterinarian.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notification that dogs residing in New York state must be\nlicensed, and that a license may be obtained from the municipality in\nwhich the dog resides.\n  3. A disclosure made pursuant to subdivision one or two of this\nsection shall be signed by both the pet dealer certifying the accuracy\nof the statement and the purchaser acknowledging receipt of the\nstatement. At the time of sale, each pet dealer shall provide the\npurchaser with information on the value of spaying and neutering of dogs\nand cats.\n  4. Every pet dealer shall post conspicuously within close proximity to\nthe cages of dogs and cats offered for sale, a notice containing the\nfollowing language in one hundred-point type: "Information on the source\nof these dogs and cats and the veterinary treatments received by these\ndogs and cats is available for review by prospective purchasers."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>