<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="753"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-753/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_753">
        <num>753</num>
        <heading>Sale of animal</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_753__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The right to return the animal and receive a refund of the\npurchase price including sales tax and reasonable veterinary costs\ndirectly related to the veterinarian's certification that the animal is\nunfit for purchase pursuant to this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The right to return the animal and to receive an exchange animal\nof the consumer's choice of equivalent value and reasonable veterinary\ncosts directly related to the veterinarian's certification that the\nanimal is unfit for purchase pursuant to this section; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_753__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The right to retain the animal and to receive reimbursement from a\npet dealer for veterinary services from a licensed veterinarian of the\nconsumer's choosing, for the purpose of curing or attempting to cure the\nanimal. The reasonable value of reimbursable services rendered to cure\nor attempting to cure the animal shall not exceed the purchase price of\nthe animal. The value of such services is reasonable if comparable to\nthe value of similar services rendered by other licensed veterinarians\nin proximity to the treating veterinarian. Such reimbursement shall not\ninclude the costs of initial veterinary examination fees and diagnostic\nfees not directly related to the veterinarian's certification that the\nanimal is unfit for purchase pursuant to this section.\n  The commissioner by regulations shall prescribe a form for, and the\ncontent of, the certification that an animal is unfit for purchase,\nwhich shall be provided by an examining veterinarian to a consumer upon\nthe examination of an animal which is subject to the provisions of this\nsection. Such form shall include, but not be limited to, information\nwhich identifies the type of animal, the owner, the date and diagnosis\nof the animal, the treatment recommended if any, and an estimate or the\nactual cost of such treatment. Such form shall also include the notice\nprescribed in section seven hundred fifty-four of this article.\n  The commissioner by regulations shall prescribe information which\nshall be provided in writing by the pet dealer to the consumer upon the\nsale of the animal. Such information shall include, but not be limited\nto, a description, including breed of the animal, the date of purchase,\nthe name, address and telephone number of the consumer, and the amount\nof the purchase. The pet dealer shall certify such information by\nsigning the document in which it is contained.\n  2. The refund and/or reimbursement required by subdivision one of this\nsection shall be made by the pet deale...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>