<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-778-DDD"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-778-DDD"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="778-DDD"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-778-DDD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-778-DDD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-778-DDD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-778-DDD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_778_DDD">
        <num>778-DDD</num>
        <heading>Enforcement; action by the attorney general</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 778-ddd. Enforcement; action by the attorney general. Where the\nattorney general shall have reason to believe that there is an alleged\nviolation of this article based upon, among other things, a consumer\nreport of an alleged violation, the attorney general, in the name of the\npeople of the state of New York, shall dispatch a cease and desist\nletter to the entity at issue, specifying the alleged violation or\nviolations and the remedies to cure such violation or violations within\na designated timeline. Where, after receipt of the cease and desist\nletter and the expiration of such designated timeline, the entity\ncontinues to violate the provisions of this article, an application may\nbe made by the attorney general in the name of the people of the state\nof New York to a court or justice having jurisdiction by a special\nproceeding to issue an injunction, and upon notice to the respondent of\nnot less than five days, to enjoin and restrain the continuance of such\nviolation or violations; and if it shall appear to the satisfaction of\nthe court or justice that the respondent has, in fact, violated this\narticle, an injunction may be issued by such court or justice, enjoining\nand restraining any further violation, without requiring proof that any\nperson has, in fact, been injured or damaged thereby. Whenever the court\nshall determine that a violation of this article has occurred, the court\nmay impose a civil penalty of not more than one thousand dollars for\neach violation. This section shall not be construed to limit any other\ncriminal or civil liability such entity may be subject to under law.\n  * NB Effective March 12, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>