<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-788"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-788"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="788"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-788/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-788/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-788/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-788/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_788">
        <num>788</num>
        <heading>Legislative intent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 788. Legislative intent. The legislature recognizes and acknowledges\nthe value of hearing aids to many individuals with hearing loss and\nrecognizes the valuable service provided by hearing aid dispensers and\ndispensing audiologists to such individuals by providing access to\nappropriate amplification devices and other valuable services related to\ntheir use. Due to the large number of individuals with hearing loss who\ndo not use hearing aids, the legislature furthermore recognizes the\npositive benefits of the increased use of hearing aids. It is the intent\nof the legislature and this article to protect the hearing-impaired\npublic by ensuring competent, honest and accountable dispensers of\nhearing aids who will protect the health, safety and welfare of the\npeople of this state.\n  The legislature finds and declares that existing laws regulating the\ndispensing of hearing aids have been ineffective in providing adequate\nprotection. To ensure against consumer abuses and thereby protect the\npublic, the legislature determines that more rigorous education,\ntraining and business practice standards should be applied to those\npersons registered to dispense hearing aids pursuant to this article. It\nis the intention of the legislature to apply standards to more fully\nprotect the general public, and to ensure continued consumer access to\nsafe, reliable and appropriate hearing aid dispensing services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>