<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-794"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-794"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="794"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-794/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-794/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-794/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-794/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_794">
        <num>794</num>
        <heading>Continuing education requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_794__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section seven hundred ninety of this article may\nsatisfy the requirements of subdivision one of this section by\ndemonstrating to the secretary compliance with such continuing\ncompetency requirements as are prescribed by article one hundred\nfifty-nine of the education law, provided, however, that, such persons\nshall submit documentation showing the successful completion of four\ncontinuing education credits relating to the dispensing of hearing aids.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_794__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within one year of the effective date of this article, the\nsecretary shall promulgate rules and regulations establishing the\nmethod, content and supervision requirements for the continuing\neducation course or courses provided for in this section. Properly\nprepared written materials of the subject matter of each course shall be\ndistributed and each course shall be taught by an instructor who meets\nrequirements established by the secretary upon the recommendation of the\nboard. Any person or organization offering a course shall apply to the\nsecretary for authorization to offer such course or courses pursuant to\nsaid rules and regulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_794__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Credits shall be awarded based on one hour of credit for each\nsixty minutes of participation. The secretary may prescribe the form or\nforms on which participation and credits are documented. At the\nconclusion of each approved course, a certificate of completion shall be\ntransmitted to the secretary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>