<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-795"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-795"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="795"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-795/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-795/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-795/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-795/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_795">
        <num>795</num>
        <heading>Renewal of certificate of registration or temporary certificate of registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 795. Renewal of certificate of registration or temporary certificate\nof registration. 1. The secretary shall provide a method for the\nbiennial review of a certificate of registration and temporary\ncertificate of registration.\n  2. The department shall reissue a certificate of registration upon\nreceipt of a renewal application, the renewal fee, and a written\nstatement affirming compliance with all other requirements set forth in\nthis article including evidence of compliance with section seven hundred\nninety-four of this article. A registrant shall retain, if applicable, a\ncertificate from a manufacturer or independent testing agent certifying\nthat the testing room utilized by such registrant meets the requirements\nof section seven hundred ninety-eight of this article and, if\napplicable, a certificate from a manufacturer or independent testing\nagent stating that all audiometric testing equipment used by the\nregistrant has been calibrated on an annual basis according to rules and\nregulations promulgated by the secretary, consistent with ANSI\nrequirements or in accordance with standards promulgated under article\none hundred fifty-nine of the education law.\n  3. Any certificate of registration which is not renewed at the end of\nthe biennial period of registration as prescribed by the secretary shall\nautomatically revert to an inactive status. If the certificate of\nregistration has not been renewed within thirty days subsequent to the\nbiennial expiration date, the secretary shall send notice by mail to the\nlast known address of the registrant. Such notice shall advise the\nregistrant of the inactive status and the procedures required to\nreactivate a valid certificate of registration. Such notice shall detail\nthe criteria and fees to be satisfied for reactivation. If such\nregistration is not reactivated, on the ninetieth day after the end of\nthe biennial registration period, such registration shall lapse.\n  4. The department shall reissue a temporary certificate of\nregistration valid for a period of one year upon the receipt of a\nrenewal application, the renewal fee and a written statement verifying\ncontinued supervision by a registered hearing aid dispenser.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>