<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-81"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-81"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="81"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_81">
        <num>81</num>
        <heading>Employees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>His full name, age and residence address.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The business or occupation engaged in for the three years\nimmediately preceding the date of the filing of the statement, setting\nforth the place or places where such business or occupation was engaged\nin, and the name or names of employers, if any.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That he has not been convicted of a felony or of any offense\ninvolving moral turpitude or of any of the misdemeanors or offenses\ndescribed in subdivision one of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such further information as the department of state may by rule\nrequire to show the good character, competency, and integrity of the\nperson executing the statement.\n  3. Immediately upon the verification of an employee's statement, the\nholder of a license certificate by whom such person has been or is to be\nemployed shall cause two sets of fingerprints of the two hands of such\nperson to be recorded in such manner as the department of state may by\nrule prescribe. The holder of a license certificate shall immediately\nstamp in indelible ink the employee's statement and each set of\nfingerprints with the name, year and license certificate number of such\nholder and a number, which number shall be determined by the number of\nsuch statements furnished to such holder and shall be in numerical\nsequence.\n  4. The holder of a license certificate shall affix one set of such\nfingerprints to the employee's statement in such manner that the prints\ncan be examined without disclosing the contents of the employee's\nstatement and shall retain such statement and prints so long as he shall\nbe licensed under this article by the department of state.\n  5. The holder of a license certificate shall file the other set of\nfingerprints with the department of state by forwarding the same by\nregistered mail to the office of the secretary of state, Albany, New\nYork, within twenty-four hours of such employment.\n  6. Within five days after the filing of such fingerprints the\nsecretary of state shall cause such fingerprints to be compared with\nfingerprints filed with the division of criminal justice services and,\nif he finds any record of any conviction as defined in the criminal\nprocedure law of a felony or any other offense specified in subdivision\none of this section, he shall immediately notify the holder of such\nlicense certificate and shall also refer the matter to the\nattorney-general. The secretary of state may also submit fingerprints to\nthe federal bureau of inv...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>