<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-82"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-82"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="82"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-82/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-82/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-82/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-82/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_82">
        <num>82</num>
        <heading>Employees not to divulge information or make false reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 82. Employees not to divulge information or make false reports.  Any\nperson who is or has been an employee of a holder of a license shall not\ndivulge to any one other than his employer, or as his employer shall\ndirect, except as he may be required by law, any information acquired by\nhim during such employment in respect of any of the work to which he\nshall have been assigned by such employer.  Any such employee violating\nthe provisions of this section and any such employee who shall wilfully\nmake a false report to his employer in respect of any of such work,\nshall be guilty of a misdemeanor. The employer of any employee believed\nto have violated this section shall without any liability whatsoever\nupon said employer supply the secretary of state or such officer or\nperson in the department of state as the secretary of state may\ndesignate, all the known facts and circumstances in connection with the\nsaid employee's transaction or performance or action believed to be in\nviolation of this article and the secretary of state or his authorized\nrepresentative shall, should the facts and circumstances be deemed to\nwarrant, conduct further investigation and submit the evidence thus\nacquired to the attorney-general of the state for appropriate action in\naccordance with the provisions of section eighty-five of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>