<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-830"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-830"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="830"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-830/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-830/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-830/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-830/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_830">
        <num>830</num>
        <heading>Sale of sodium nitrate and sodium nitrite</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 830. Sale of sodium nitrate and sodium nitrite. 1. No person,\ncorporation, partnership, limited liability company, firm or any other\nbusiness entity doing business within this state shall sell or offer for\nsale sodium nitrate or sodium nitrite to any person under the age of\ntwenty-one. This restriction shall not apply to foods containing sodium\nnitrate or sodium nitrite in compliance with the requirements of 9 CFR\nPart 424 or 21 CFR Part 172.\n  2. Any person, corporation, partnership, limited liability company,\nfirm, or any other business entity doing business within the state\nselling, offering for sale, or distributing sodium nitrate or sodium\nnitrite, except as permitted by subdivision one of this section, shall\nrequire proof of legal age prior to allowing an individual to purchase\nor receive a shipment of sodium nitrate or sodium nitrite. Such\nidentification need not be required of any individual who reasonably\nappears to be at least thirty years of age, provided, however, that such\nappearance shall not constitute a defense in any proceeding alleging the\nsale or distribution of sodium nitrate or sodium nitrite to an\nindividual under twenty-one years of age.\n  3. Any person, corporation, partnership, limited liability company,\nfirm or any other business entity that violates the provisions of this\nsection shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than two hundred\nfifty dollars for an initial offense and not more than five hundred\ndollars for the second and each subsequent offense, provided this\nsection shall not be construed to limit any other criminal or civil\nliability such person, corporation, partnership, limited liability\ncompany, firm or other business entity may be subject to under law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>