<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-832"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-832"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="832"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-832/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-832/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-832/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-832/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_832">
        <num>832</num>
        <heading>Restricted access to retail sale of ipecac</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 832. Restricted access to retail sale of ipecac. 1. Any retail\nestablishment that sells any product or products containing as the only\nactive ingredient ipecac, shall limit access to such products in a\nmanner designed to prevent the misuse or abuse of such products. Such\nlimitations shall include removing such products from shelves and other\nlocations that are directly accessible by customers, and placing such\nproducts behind a pharmacy counter so that a consumer must request such\nproducts in order to obtain such products from an employee working in\nthe pharmacy. If the retail establishment wishes to sell such products\nbut does not maintain a pharmacy at that retail location, such products\nshall be made secure such that they may only be accessed by a manager,\nassistant manager, acting manager or other supervisory personnel at such\nlocation.\n  2. As used in this section "retail establishment" means every vendor\nthat in the regular course of business sells products containing ipecac\nat retail directly to the public including, but not limited to,\npharmacies, grocery stores, and other retail stores.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>