<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-833"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-833"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="833"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-833/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-833/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-833/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-833/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_833">
        <num>833</num>
        <heading>Restricted access to retail sale of dextromethorphan, commonly known as "dxm"</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 833. Restricted access to retail sale of dextromethorphan, commonly\nknown as "dxm". 1. No retail establishment offering for sale any product\nor products containing as an active ingredient dextromethorphan, shall\npermit the sale of such products to persons under the age of eighteen\nwithout a valid prescription. Retail establishments shall require proof\nof legal age for purchase of such products. Such identification need not\nbe required of any individual who reasonably appears to be at least\ntwenty-five years of age, provided, however, that such appearance shall\nnot constitute a defense in any proceeding alleging the sale of any\nproduct or products containing as an active ingredient dextromethorphan\nto an individual under eighteen years of age. Any retail establishment\nwhich violates the provisions of this section shall be subject to a fine\nof two hundred fifty dollars for each such violation.\n  2. As used in this section "retail establishment" means every vendor\nthat in the regular course of business sells products containing\ndextromethorphan at retail directly to the public including, but not\nlimited to, pharmacies, grocery stores, and other retail stores.\n  3. This section shall supersede any local laws or ordinances\nregulating the sales of products containing dextromethorphan.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 391-s's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>