<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-834"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-834"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="834"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-834/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-834/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-834/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-834/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_834">
        <num>834</num>
        <heading>Sale of whipped cream chargers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 834. Sale of whipped cream chargers. 1. For purposes of this\nsection, the term "whipped cream charger" shall mean a steel cylinder or\ncartridge filled with nitrous oxide (N2O) that is used as a whipping\nagent in a whipped cream dispenser.\n  2. No person, corporation, partnership, limited liability company,\nfirm or any other business entity doing business within this state shall\nsell or offer for sale a whipped cream charger to any person under the\nage of twenty-one.\n  3. Any person, corporation, partnership, limited liability company,\nfirm, or other business entity doing business within the state selling,\noffering for sale, or distributing whipped cream chargers shall require\nproof of legal age prior to allowing an individual to purchase or\nreceive a shipment of whipped cream chargers. Such identification need\nnot be required of any individual who reasonably appears to be at least\ntwenty-five years of age, provided, however, that such appearance shall\nnot constitute a defense in any proceeding alleging the sale or\ndistribution of whipped cream chargers to an individual under twenty-one\nyears of age.\n  4. Any person, corporation, partnership, limited liability company,\nfirm or any other business entity that violates the provisions of this\nsection shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than two hundred\nfifty dollars for an initial offense and not more than five hundred\ndollars for the second and each subsequent offense.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>