<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-852"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-852"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="852"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-852/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-852/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-852/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-852/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_852">
        <num>852</num>
        <heading>Power of municipality to revoke license or permit</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 852. Power of municipality to revoke license or permit. 1. A county,\ntown, city or village which issues a license or permit authorizing any\nperson, firm or corporation to engage in the selling or offering for\nsale of any merchandise may revoke such license or permit upon a\nfinding, pursuant to a hearing held thereon, that such person, firm or\ncorporation has sold or offered for sale merchandise in violation of\nthis article.\n  2. The possession with intent to sell or offering for sale of\ndrug-related paraphernalia as defined herein is hereby declared to be a\nnuisance, and where any such drug-related paraphernalia shall be taken\nfrom the possession of any person, the same shall be surrendered and\nforfeited to the sheriff of the county wherein the same shall be taken,\nexcept that in a city having a population of seventy-five thousand or\nmore, the same shall be surrendered and forfeited to the police\ncommissioner or other head of the police force or department of said\ncity and except that in the counties of Nassau and Suffolk, the same\nshall be surrendered and forfeited to the commissioner of the county\npolice department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>