<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="875-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_875_B">
        <num>875-B</num>
        <heading>Security</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_875_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all firearms, rifles and shotguns shall be secured, other than\nduring business hours, in a locked fireproof safe or vault on the\ndealer's business premises or in a secured and locked area on the\ndealer's business premises; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ammunition shall be stored separately from firearms, rifles and\nshotguns and out of reach of customers.\n  2. The dealer's business premises shall be secured by a security alarm\nsystem that is installed and maintained by a security alarm operator\nproperly licensed pursuant to article six-D of this chapter. Standards\nfor such security alarm systems shall be established by the\nsuperintendent in regulation. Such security alarm systems may be\ndeveloped by a federal or state agency, a not-for-profit organization,\nor another entity specializing in security alarm standards approved by\nthe superintendent for the purposes of this act. The security alarm\nsystem shall be capable of being monitored by a central station, and\nshall provide, at a minimum, complete protection and monitoring for all\naccessible openings, and partial motion and sound detection at certain\nother areas of the premises. The dealer location shall additionally be\nequipped with a video recording device at each point of sale and each\nentrance and exit to the premises, which shall be recorded from both the\nindoor and outdoor vantage point and shall maintain such recordings for\na period of not less than two years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>