<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="875-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-875-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_875_F">
        <num>875-F</num>
        <heading>Maintenance of records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 875-f. Maintenance of records. Every dealer shall establish and\nmaintain a book, or if the dealer should choose, an electronic-based\nrecord of purchase, sale, inventory, and other records at the dealer's\nplace of business in such form and for such period as the superintendent\nshall require, and shall submit a copy of such records to the New York\nstate police every April and October. Such records shall at a minimum\ninclude the following:\n  1. the make, model, caliber or gauge, manufacturer's name, and serial\nnumber of all firearms, rifles and shotguns that are acquired or\ndisposed of not later than one business day after their acquisition or\ndisposition. Monthly backups of these records kept in a book shall be\nmaintained in a secure container designed to prevent loss by fire,\ntheft, or flood. If the dealer chooses to maintain an electronic-based\nrecord system, those records shall be backed up on an external server or\nover the internet at the close of each business day;\n  2. all firearms, rifles and shotguns acquired but not yet disposed of\nshall be accounted for through an inventory check prepared once each\nmonth and maintained in a secure location;\n  3. firearm, rifle and shotgun disposition information, including the\nserial numbers of firearms, rifles and shotguns sold, dates of sale, and\nidentity of purchasers, shall be maintained and made available at any\ntime to government law enforcement agencies and to the manufacturer of\nthe weapon or its designee; and\n  4. every dealer shall maintain records of criminal firearm, rifle and\nshotgun traces initiated by the federal bureau of alcohol, tobacco,\nfirearms and explosives ("ATF"). All ATF Form 4473 transaction records\nshall be retained on the dealer's business premises in a secure\ncontainer designed to prevent loss by fire, theft, or flood.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>