<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-BBB"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-BBB"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-BBB"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-BBB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-BBB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-BBB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-BBB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_BBB">
        <num>89-BBB</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-bbb. Definitions. When used in this article, the following terms\nshall have the following meanings:\n  1. "Commissioner" means the commissioner of the division of criminal\njustice services.\n  2. "Division" means the division of criminal justice services.\n  3. "Secretary" means the secretary of state.\n  4. "Department" means the department of state.\n  6. "Armored car carrier" means any individual, partnership,\nassociation, limited liability company, corporation, or any other\nentity, engaging in the business of providing armored car services for\nhire.\n  7. "Armored car services" means engaging in the business of providing\nsecured transportation, protection and safeguarding of valuable cargo\nfrom one place or point to another, including the provision of cash\nservices for automated teller machines, by means of specially designed\nand constructed bullet-resistant armored vehicles and armored car\nguards.\n  8. "Armored car guard" has the meaning ascribed to that term by\nsubdivision eight of section eighty-nine-ppp of this chapter.\n  9. "Valuable cargo" means money, cash, currency, coin, bullion,\nprecious metals and articles made therefrom, gems and jewelry,\nnegotiable and non-negotiable securities, bonds, notes, checks, drafts,\ncoupons, or other valuable instruments, documents or certificates,\nincluding tapes, computer disks, or other electronic or magnetic media,\nU.S. Postage Stamps, food stamps, and other articles of unusual value.\n  10. "Licensee" means an armored car carrier that has been issued a\nlicense in accordance with the provisions of this article.\n  11. "Principal" means any person controlling an interest greater than\nten percent of an armored car carrier.\n  12. "Officer" means the four primary officers of a corporation,\nnormally defined as president, vice-president, secretary and treasurer.\n  13. "Serious offense" has the meaning ascribed to that term by\nsubdivision thirteen of section eighty-nine-f of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>