<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-DDD"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-DDD"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-DDD"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-DDD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-DDD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-DDD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-DDD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_DDD">
        <num>89-DDD</num>
        <heading>Application for licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-ddd. Application for licenses. 1. Application for a license\nrequired under this article shall be in writing, subscribed by the\napplicant under oath, and in the form prescribed by the secretary, and\nshall contain the following:\n  a. The exact name and the address of the applicant and its date of\nincorporation or organization, as applicable;\n  b. The name and the business and residential address of each principal\nand officer of the applicant;\n  c. The complete address where the business of the applicant is to be\nconducted, showing the street and number, if any, post office and\nbuilding and room number, if any, the office building and room number,\nif any, and the municipality and county;\n  d. If the applicant has one or more branches, subsidiaries or\naffiliates operating in the state, the complete address of each such\nplace of business; and\n  e. A complete set of two fingerprint cards for each principal and\nofficer of the applicant on a standard fingerprint card approved by the\ndivision and a fee pursuant to subdivision eight-a of section eight\nhundred thirty-seven of the executive law, and amendments thereto, for\nthe cost of the division's full search and retain procedures, which fee\nshall be remitted by the department to the division for deposit by the\ncomptroller into the general fund.  Before approving such application\nthe secretary, or his or her designee, shall forward one copy of such\nfingerprint card and the processing fee to the division upon receipt of\nsuch fingerprints. The division shall forward to the secretary a report\nwith respect to the applicant's previous criminal history, if any, or a\nstatement that the applicant has no previous criminal history according\nto its files. Upon the written request of an armored car carrier, the\nsecretary shall require each principal and officer of the applicant to\nsubmit to an additional fingerprint check by the Federal Bureau of\nInvestigation, and to remit the appropriate fee therefor. If additional\ncopies of fingerprints are required the applicant shall furnish them\nupon request.\n  2. Upon original application for a license to operate as an armored\ncar carrier, the applicant shall pay an application fee in the amount of\nthree hundred dollars. Upon application for a license renewal, the\nlicensee shall pay a renewal processing fee in the amount of three\nhundred dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>