<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-FFF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-FFF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-FFF"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-FFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-FFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-FFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-FFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_FFF">
        <num>89-FFF</num>
        <heading>Licensing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-fff. Licensing. 1. Each license issued under this article shall\nstate the address or addresses at which the business is to be conducted\nand shall state fully the name of the licensee, and the date and place\nof its incorporation or organization, as applicable, and the expiration\ndate of the license. A copy of such license shall be prominently posted\nin each place of business of the licensee. Such license shall not be\ntransferable or assignable.\n  2. In the event the location at which the business is to be conducted\nshall be changed, the licensee shall forthwith notify the secretary in\nwriting, who shall thereupon without charge attach to the license a\nrider setting forth such changed location.\n  3. In the event that there shall be any changes among the principals\nor officers of any licensee, the licensee shall forthwith notify the\nsecretary in writing, of the name and address of each new principal or\nofficer, and shall submit a complete set of two fingerprint cards, and\nthe appropriate fee, for each such principal or officer in accordance\nwith the provisions of paragraph e of subdivision one of section\neighty-nine-ddd of this article.\n  4. Prior to the sale or transfer of all or the majority of the stock\nor assets of any armored car carrier, the new principals or officers of\nthe purchaser or transferee shall apply for a new license with the\ndepartment in accordance with the provisions of sections eighty-nine-ddd\nand eighty-nine-eee of this article. Such application shall be made at\nleast sixty days prior to such sale or transfer. If the purchaser or\ntransferee is an existing licensee under this article, then such\nlicensee need not reapply for licensure hereunder, but shall notify the\ndepartment in writing of such purchase or transfer at least sixty days\nprior thereto.\n  5. A license granted under the provisions of this article may be\nrenewed by the department upon the application therefor by the licensee,\nin such form as the department may prescribe, accompanied by the\nnonrefundable renewal processing fee pursuant to subdivision two of\nsection eighty-nine-ddd of this article. In no event shall renewal be\ngranted more than six months after the date of expiration of a license.\nNo individual, partnership, association, limited liability company,\ncorporation, or any other entity shall engage in the business of\nproviding armored car services subject to this article during any period\nwhich may exist between the date of expiration of a license and the\nrenewal thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>