<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_G">
        <num>89-G</num>
        <heading>Employment of security guards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_89_G__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An application for a registration card completed and sworn to by\nsuch person pursuant to subdivision one of section eighty-nine-h of this\narticle;\n  (ii) A certification by the security guard company that it has\nexercised due diligence to verify as true the information contained in\nsuch person's application;\n  (iii) A certification that such person has completed the preassignment\ntraining required by subdivision two of section eighty-nine-h of this\narticle;\n  (iv) Two photographs of such person taken within thirty days prior to\nthe filing of the application of a size prescribed by the secretary and\ntwo sets of fingerprints of such person. The fingerprints shall be taken\non a standard fingerprint card approved by the division; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_89_G__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fees prescribed by subdivision ten of section eighty-nine-h of\nthis article.\n  2. It shall be incumbent upon each security guard company to exercise\ndue diligence in verifying that the information contained in every\napplication for a registration card it files with the department is true\nprovided, however, the secretary shall, upon consultation with the\nsecurity guard advisory council, promulgate rules and regulations to\nspecify the minimum due diligence required to be exercised by such\ncompanies in order to verify the information required pursuant to\nsubdivisions five and seven of section eighty-nine-h of this article.\n  3. Except as provided in section seven hundred fifty-two of the\ncorrection law, no security guard company shall knowingly employ to\nperform security guard functions, any individual:\n  a. who has been convicted of a serious offense, or of a misdemeanor in\nthe state or of any offense in any other jurisdiction which, if\ncommitted in this state, would constitute a misdemeanor, and which, in\nthe discretion of the secretary, bears such a relationship to the\nperformance of the duties of a security guard, as to constitute a bar to\nemployment; or\n  b. who in any jurisdiction has been denied authorization to perform\nsecurity guard functions or whose authorization to perform security\nguard functions has been suspended or revoked on grounds which would\nconstitute a basis for denying, suspending or revoking a registration\ncard in this state.\n  4. For each security guard employed by a security guard company as of\nthe effective date of this section such security guard company shall at\na time assigned by the secretary, pursuant to a staggered schedule,\ncomply with the provisions of paragraphs a and b of subdivision one of\nthis section and the provisions of section eighty-nine-n of this\narticle. Until the assigned filing date, such security guard company may\ncontinue to employ such person to perform security guard functions. No\nse...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_89_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>violated the provisions of this\narticle or the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_89_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has engaged in fraud, deceit or misrepresentation.\n  10. All security guard companies shall maintain books and records of\nemployees who are security guards and shall, upon request, make such\nbooks and records available to the secretary of state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>