<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_K">
        <num>89-K</num>
        <heading>Issuance and denial of registration cards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-k. Issuance and denial of registration cards. 1. Requirements of\nregistration cards. Unless the department determines that the applicant\ndoes not meet the requirements of section eighty-nine-h of this article\nor is unable to perform security guard functions, it shall issue a\nregistration card in a form prescribed by the department, which shall\ninclude, among other information, the expiration date of such card and\nany renewal thereof, authorizing the applicant to perform security guard\nfunctions. If the department determines that an applicant does not meet\nthe requirements of section eighty-nine-h of this article, it shall deny\nthe application for a registration card.  Upon issuance of the\nregistration card or denial of the application therefor, the department\nshall forthwith give notice of such issuance or denial to such applicant\nand to the security guard company which employs such applicant, by\nregular mail.\n  2. Administrative review. Denial of a registration card hereunder\nshall be reviewable by an administrative hearing as set forth in\nsubdivisions two, three, four and five of section seventy-nine of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>