<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_L">
        <num>89-L</num>
        <heading>Suspension, revocation and reissuance of registration cards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_89_L__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by the court pending any\nprosecution for a serious offense. In order for the court to impose such\nsuspension it must find that the accusatory instrument conforms to the\nrequirements of section 140.40 of the criminal procedure law and there\nexists reasonable cause to believe that the holder committed the serious\noffense with which he is charged. At such time, the holder shall be\nentitled to an opportunity to make a statement regarding the enumerated\nissues and to present witnesses and other evidence tending to rebut the\ncourt's findings. Where the suspension is imposed upon a pending charge\nof a serious offense which is a class A misdemeanor and the holder has\nrequested a hearing pursuant to article one hundred seventy of the\ncriminal procedure law, or where the suspension is imposed upon a\npending charge of a serious offense which is a felony and the holder has\nrequested a hearing pursuant to article one hundred eighty of the\ncriminal procedure law, the court shall conduct such hearing. If upon\ncompletion of such hearing, the court fails to find that there is\nreasonable cause to believe that the holder committed a serious offense,\nor if the charges are dismissed or the holder is acquitted of such\ncharges or the conviction is reversed on appeal, the court shall\npromptly notify the secretary and direct restoration of such\nregistration card unless such registration card is suspended or revoked\npursuant to any other provision of this section. If a holder is\nconvicted of a serious offense, the court shall promptly notify the\nsecretary and the suspension shall remain in effect pending a hearing\nheld pursuant to subdivision three of this section; or (ii) by an\nofficer designated by the secretary pursuant to the state administrative\nprocedure act to preside over a hearing, on application by the secretary\non notice to the holder, where such officer finds that such holder has\nbeen charged with a serious offense and reasonable cause exists to\nbelie...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_89_L__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the holder has been convicted of a serious\noffense, (ii) the holder has been charged with a serious offense and\nsuch officer finds that reasonable cause exists to believe that the\nholder committed the serious offense with which the holder is charged,\nor (iii) such officer finds that reasonable cause exists to believe that\nthe employment of the holder as a security guard constitutes a danger to\nthe health, safety or well-being of the public.\n  5. No registration card may be suspended pursuant to this section\nbased upon the fact that a holder is charged with or convicted of one or\nmore serious offenses, or of a misdemeanor in the state which, in the\ndiscretion of the secretary, bears such a relationship to the\nperformance of the duties of a security guard, as to constitute a bar to\nemployment unless:\n  a. there is a direct relationship between one or more such serious\noffenses and the registration card or employment of the holder as a\nsecurity guard; or\n  b. the possession of a registration card by the holder or the\nemployment of the holder as a security guard would involve an\nunreasonable risk to property or to the safety or welfare of specific\nindividuals or the general public.\n  6. Fines. Where it is determined after hearing that the holder has\nviolated one or more provisions of this article pursuant to paragraph c\nof subdivision two of this section, the secretary may, in lieu of\nrevocation or suspension of the registration card of such holder, impose\na fine not to exceed one thousand dollars for each violation payable to\nthe department.\n  7. Surrender of suspended or revoked registration card. a. When the\ncourt suspends a registration card pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_89_L__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nparagraph a of subdivision four of this section, the holder shall\nforthwith surrender the registration card to the court and the court\nshall promptly send the registration card to the secretary.\n  b. Upon suspension or revocation of the registration card by the\nsecretary or by the officer designated by the secretary to preside over\nthe hearing, pursuant to this section, the holder shall, if present at\nthe time of such suspension or revocation, surrender the registration\ncard forthwith.  If the holder is not present at the time of such\nsuspension or revocation, the secretary shall send notice of such\nsuspension or revocation to the holder at the address indicated on the\nregistration card or such other last known address, by personal service\nor by certified mail return receipt requested, in which case the holder\nshall within five days following receipt of such notice surrender the\nregistration card by delivering same in person or by certified mail to a\nlocation designated by the secretary. Notice of suspension or revocation\nshall be given by the secretary to the security guard company by which\nthe holder was employed at the time of such suspension or revocation.\n  8. Reissuance of registration card. A suspended or revoked\nregistration card may be reissued only by the secretary or by a person\ndeputized by the secretary. Except as otherwise provided in this\nsection, where a registration card has been revoked, it may not be\nreissued for at least one year following revocation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>