<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_M">
        <num>89-M</num>
        <heading>Renewal of registration cards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-m. Renewal of registration cards. 1. Registration cards shall\nexpire two years from the date of issuance or last renewal as the case\nmay be. Not less than sixty nor more than ninety days prior to the\nexpiration date of a registration card, the department shall mail to\neach registrant at his last known address, notice of renewal and a\nregistration renewal form. Registration cards shall not be renewed\nunless not more than sixty nor less than thirty days prior to the\nexpiration date of the registration card, the holder submits to the\ndepartment, a registration renewal form sworn to or affirmed by the\nholder under the penalty of perjury together with a biennial renewal fee\nin the amount of twenty-five dollars payable to the department and a\ncertificate certifying that the holder has satisfactorily completed the\nrequired annual in-service training courses as prescribed by the\ncommissioner pursuant to subdivision one of section eight hundred\nforty-one-c of the executive law. Unless the department determines the\nexistence of facts which would constitute cause for denial, revocation\nor suspension of the registration card pursuant to this article, it\nshall renew the registration card. Denial of renewal hereunder shall be\nreviewable by an administrative hearing as set forth in section\nseventy-nine of this chapter. The twenty-five dollar biennial renewal\nfee collected by the department shall be deposited to the licensing\nexaminations services account established pursuant to the provisions of\nsection 97-aa of the state finance law. Notice that a registration card\nhas expired or has not been renewed pursuant to this section shall be\ngiven by the secretary to the holder of such registration card and to\nthe security guard company by which such holder was employed at the time\nof such expiration or non-renewal.\n  2. A registration card which was not renewed or which expired may be\nreissued only in a manner prescribed by rules and regulations\npromulgated by the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>