<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-RRR"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-RRR"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-RRR"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-RRR/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-RRR/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-RRR/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-RRR/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_RRR">
        <num>89-RRR</num>
        <heading>Application for registration card</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-rrr. Application for registration card. An application for an\narmored car guard registration card shall be verified and subscribed by\nthe applicant and shall contain the following information:\n  1. Full name;\n  2. Aliases or maiden name;\n  3. Current residence and telephone number;\n  4. Any conviction of a crime, as that term is defined in section 10.00\nof the penal law;\n  5. A complete set of two fingerprint cards on a standard fingerprint\ncard approved by the division. Before approving such application the\nsecretary, or his or her designee, shall transmit to the division one\ncopy of such fingerprint card and the fee required pursuant to\nsubdivision seven of this section and cause to be conducted a search of\nstate files to ascertain whether the applicant has a previous criminal\nhistory. Upon the written request of an armored car carrier, the\nsecretary shall require each applicant to submit to an additional\nfingerprint check by the federal bureau of investigation, and to remit\nthe appropriate fee therefor. The secretary may cause an investigation\nto be conducted to verify the information contained in the application\nprovided. The department, in consultation with the division, may waive\nsuch background checks, investigations and fees if, in its opinion, the\napplicant has been subject to previous background checks and\ninvestigation requirements which meet or exceed the requirements of this\nsection or the federal "Armored Car Industry Reciprocity Act of 1993,"\npub. l. 103-55 (15 U.S.C. ยง 5901 et seq.), and amendments thereto. The\ndepartment, in consultation with the division, may not be required to\nconduct background checks or investigations for applicants who are also\nemployed as peace officers. If additional copies of fingerprints are\nrequired the applicant shall furnish them upon request;\n  6. Two photographs of such applicant taken within thirty days prior to\nthe filing of the application of a size prescribed by the department;\nand\n  7. An application processing fee of fifty dollars and a fee pursuant\nto subdivision eight-a of section eight hundred thirty-seven of the\nexecutive law, and amendments thereto, for the cost of the division's\nfull search and retain procedures, which fee shall be remitted by the\ndepartment to the division for deposit by the comptroller into the\ngeneral fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>