<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_S">
        <num>89-S</num>
        <heading>Reporting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-s. Reporting. On or before February first, nineteen hundred\nninety-four, and on or before February first of each succeeding year,\nthe secretary, upon consultation with the commissioner and the security\nguard advisory council, shall report to the governor, the temporary\npresident of the senate and the speaker of the assembly on the\nimplementation, procedures, operation, training, and enforcement of the\nsecurity guard act of nineteen hundred ninety-two, together with any\nrecommendations relating thereto. Such report shall include, but not be\nlimited to:\n  a. the number of security guards registered and maintained in the\nsecurity guard registry;\n  b. the number of applicants for registration, and the number of\napplications denied with the reason or reasons therefor;\n  c. statistics related to the time it takes to process fingerprint\ncards, applications and inquiries to the registry by security guard\ncompanies;\n  d. the number and length of suspensions and revocations, and the\nnumber and amount of fines imposed;\n  e. the amount of fees collected by the department and the division;\n  f. the level of appropriation authority available to the department\nand the division and the amount of money expended by the department and\ndivision for the purposes of carrying out the provisions of this\narticle; and\n  g. any other information which the department and the division deem\nnecessary. The division shall provide the department with any\ninformation necessary to comply with the requirements of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>