<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-SSS"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-SSS"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-08-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-SSS"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-SSS/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-SSS/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-SSS/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-SSS/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_SSS">
        <num>89-SSS</num>
        <heading>Training requirements; waiver or exemption</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-sss. Training requirements; waiver or exemption. 1. Every armored\ncar guard, other than a police officer, employed by an armored car\ncarrier shall be required to satisfactorily complete a qualified\nfirearms training course. Such course shall include appropriate range\ninstruction by a qualified firearms instructor, and range qualification\nwith each type and caliber of firearm he or she will have access to\nwhile on duty.\n  2. Such course shall be given and administered by armored car carriers\nor their designees. Every armored car carrier shall maintain a record of\nand certify to the secretary, in writing, the satisfactory completion of\nsuch course by any armored car guard.\n  3. Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit an armored car\ncarrier from voluntarily providing training programs and courses which\nexceed the minimum requirements provided by this section.\n  4. The commissioner shall waive the training requirements specified in\nsubdivision one of this section, with respect to applicants employed by\narmored car carriers, if the applicant provides appropriate\ndocumentation to demonstrate that he or she was or is subject to\ntraining requirements which meet or exceed the requirements established\npursuant to such subdivision.\n  5. An armored car guard who has been or was previously employed as a\npeace officer for eighteen months or more who exhibits a valid\ncertificate awarded pursuant to subdivision six of section 2.30 of the\ncriminal procedure law attesting to his or her satisfactory completion\nof the training requirements imposed by section 2.30 of the criminal\nprocedure law, shall be exempt from the requirements of subdivision one\nof this section, provided that such peace officer has completed a course\nof firearms training recognized by the division. Nothing in this\nsubdivision shall be deemed to authorize such guard to carry, possess,\nrepair or dispose of a firearm unless the appropriate license therefor\nhas been issued pursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>