<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-TTT"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-TTT"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-TTT"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-TTT/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-TTT/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-TTT/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-TTT/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_TTT">
        <num>89-TTT</num>
        <heading>Annual training; background checks</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-ttt. Annual training; background checks. 1. a. In addition to the\nminimum firearms training required by section eighty-nine-sss of this\narticle, each armored car guard, other than a police officer, shall\nsatisfactorily complete an eight hour in-service firearms training\ncourse, recognized by the division, at least annually. Such course shall\nbe administered by armored car carriers, or their designees, and shall\ninclude requalification with the firearms he or she will have access to\nwhile on duty, under the supervision of a qualified firearms instructor.\nEvery armored car carrier shall maintain a record of and certify to the\nsecretary, in writing, the satisfactory completion of such course by any\narmored car guard.\n  b. An armored car guard who is also employed as a peace officer for\neighteen months or more shall be exempt from the requirements of\nparagraph a of this subdivision as long as he or she is currently\nemployed as a peace officer and provides to his or her employer proof of\nsuch annual in-service firearms training required under such paragraph.\n  2. The secretary or his or her designee shall annually ensure that\neach armored car guard holding a valid registration card is subject to\nthe division's ongoing criminal history search and retain procedures.\n  3. Notwithstanding the provisions of this article, an armored car\nguard and his or her employer shall comply with the provisions of the\nfederal "Armored Car Industry Reciprocity Act of 1993," pub. l. 103-55\n(15 U.S.C. ยง 5901 et seq.), and amendments thereto.\n  4. Every armored car carrier shall permit the department to inspect,\nreview or copy training records to ensure compliance with the provisions\nof this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>