<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-U"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-U"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-U"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_U">
        <num>89-U</num>
        <heading>Process server records, penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 89-u. Process server records, penalties. 1. Each process server\nshall maintain a legible record of all service made by him as prescribed\nin this section.\n  2. The record to be maintained shall include the following\ninformation, where applicable:\n  a. the title of the action;\n  b. the name of the person served, if known;\n  c. the date and approximate time service was effected;\n  d. the address where service was effected;\n  e. the nature of the papers served;\n  f. the court in which the action has been commenced;\n  g. the index number of the action, if known.\n  3. If service is effected pursuant to subdivisions one, two, or three\nof section three hundred eight of the civil practice law and rules, the\nrecord shall also include the description of the person served,\nincluding, but not limited to, sex, color of skin, hair color,\napproximate age, height and weight and other identifying features.\n  4. If service is effected pursuant to subdivision four of section\nthree hundred eight of the civil practice law and rules, the record\nshall also include the dates, addresses and time of attempted service\npursuant to subdivisions one, two or three of such section.\n  5. If the process server files an affidavit of service with the court,\nhis record shall include the date of such filing.\n  6. Process servers shall retain each record required to be kept under\nthis article for a period of two years from the date of service. Where a\nprocess server is employed as a process server by any person, a copy of\nsuch records shall also be maintained by such person at his principal\noffice in this state for the same period.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>