<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-W"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-W"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="89-W"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-89-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_89_W">
        <num>89-W</num>
        <heading>Applicability</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 89-w. Applicability. The provisions of this article shall not\napply to a not-for-profit security guard company, public entity, or\ntenant or third-party security provider of such tenant of a publicly\nowned sports venue with a capacity of at least sixty thousand people\nlocated in the county of Erie, which hires a security guard or guards\nfor a specific event or events solely for its own proprietary use and\nwhich employs such security guards only on a temporary basis for a total\nperiod not exceeding fifteen days per year. Notwithstanding anything to\nthe contrary, such tenant or third-party security provider of a publicly\nowned sports venue with a capacity of at least sixty thousand people\nlocated in the county of Erie shall ensure that no less than fifty\npercent of the security guards that such tenant or third-party security\nprovider hires have obtained a license under this article.\n  * NB Effective until September 20, 2027\n  * ยง 89-w. Applicability. The provisions of this article shall not\napply to a not-for-profit security guard company or public entity which\nhires a security guard or guards for a specific event or events solely\nfor its own proprietary use and which employs such security guards only\non a temporary basis for a total period not exceeding fifteen days per\nyear.\n  * NB Effective September 20, 2027\n  * NB Numerically this section should be in Art. 8 but its subject\nmatter places it in Art. 7-A.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>