<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-KKK"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-KKK"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="899-KKK"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-KKK/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-KKK/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-KKK/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-KKK/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_899_KKK">
        <num>899-KKK</num>
        <heading>Registration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_899_KKK__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the department of state has notified the applicant in writing that\nthe application has been denied, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_899_KKK__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the department of state has not issued a registration within sixty\ndays after the application for the registration was filed.\n  6. A request for a hearing may not be made more than fifteen days\nafter the department has mailed a written notice to the applicant that\nthe application has been denied and stating in substance the department\nof state's findings supporting denial of the application.\n  7. Notwithstanding the prior approval requirement of subdivision one\nof this section, a consumer litigation funding company that registered\nwith the department of state between the effective date of this article\nor when the department of state has made applications available to the\npublic, whichever is later, and one hundred eighty days thereafter may\nengage in consumer litigation funding while the company's registration\nis pending approval with the department of state. All funding agreements\nentered into prior to the effective date of this article are not subject\nto the terms of this article.\n  8. No consumer litigation funding company may use any form of consumer\nlitigation funding contract in this state unless it has been filed with\nthe department of state in accordance with the filing procedures set\nforth by the secretary of state.\n  9. The secretary of state is hereby authorized to adopt rules and\nregulations to implement the provisions of this section as needed.\n  * NB Effective June 17, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>