<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="899-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_899_N">
        <num>899-N</num>
        <heading>Civil remedies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 899-n. Civil remedies. 1. An educational institution shall have a\nright of action against an athlete agent for damages caused by any\nviolation of this article. In an action brought pursuant to this\nsection, the court may award reasonable attorney's fees to a prevailing\nplaintiff.\n  2. The damages of an educational institution pursuant to subdivision\none of this section shall include losses and expenses incurred because,\nas a result of the conduct of an athlete agent or former\nstudent-athlete, the educational institution was injured by a violation\nof this article or was penalized, disqualified or suspended from\nparticipation in athletics by a national association for the promotion\nand regulation of athletics, by an athletic conference, or by reasonable\nself-imposed disciplinary action taken to mitigate sanctions likely to\nbe imposed by such an organization.\n  3. A right of action under this section shall not accrue until the\neducational institution discovers or by the exercise of reasonable\ndiligence would have discovered the violation by the athlete agent or\nformer student-athlete.\n  4. This article shall not be deemed to restrict rights, remedies or\ndefenses of any person under law or equity.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>