<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="899-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-899-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_899_A">
        <num>899-A</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 899-a. Definitions. As used in this article the following terms\nshall have the following meanings:\n  1. "Agency contract" means an agreement in which a student-athlete\nauthorizes a person to negotiate or solicit on behalf of the\nstudent-athlete a professional sports-services contract or an\nendorsement contract.\n  2. "Athlete agent" means an individual who enters into an agency\ncontract with a student-athlete or, directly or indirectly, recruits or\nsolicits a student-athlete to enter into an agency contract. Such term\nincludes an individual who represents to the public that the individual\nis an athlete agent. This term shall not include a spouse, parent,\nsibling, grandparent or guardian of the student-athlete, or an\nindividual acting solely on behalf of a professional sports team or\nprofessional sports organization.\n  3. "Athletic director" means an individual responsible for\nadministering the overall athletic program of an educational institution\nor, if an educational institution has separately administered athletic\nprograms for male students and female students, the athletic program for\nmales or the athletic program for females, as appropriate.\n  4. "Contact" means a communication, direct or indirect, between an\nathlete agent and a student-athlete, to recruit or solicit the\nstudent-athlete to enter into an agency contract.\n  5. "Endorsement contract" means an agreement under which a\nstudent-athlete is employed or receives consideration to use on behalf\nof the other party any value that the student-athlete may have because\nof publicity, reputation, following or fame obtained because of athletic\nability or performance.\n  6. "Intercollegiate sport" means a sport played at the collegiate\nlevel for which eligibility requirements for participation by a\nstudent-athlete are established by a national association which promotes\nor regulates such sport and is recognized by the educational institution\nthat said student-athlete attends.\n  7. "Person" means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate,\ntrust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint\nventure, government, governmental subdivision, agency, instrumentality,\npublic corporation, or any other legal or commercial entity.\n  8. "Professional sports-services contract" means an agreement under\nwhich an individual is employed, or agrees to render services, as a\nplayer on a professional sports team, with a professional sports\norganization or as a professional athlete.\n  9. "Record" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium\nor that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in\nperceivable form.\n  10. "Registration" means registration as an athlete agent pursuant to\nthis article.\n  11. "State" means a state of the United States, the District of\nColumbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any\nterritory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the\nUnited States.\n  12. "Student-athlete" means an individual who engages in, is eligible\nto engage in, may be eligible in the future to engage in or was eligible\nin the past thirty days to engage in any intercollegiate or\ninterscholastic sport. If an individual is permanently ineligible to\nparticipate in a particular intercollegiate sport, such individual shall\nnot be considered a student-athlete thirty days after losing his or her\neligibility for purposes of that sport.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>