<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-9"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-9"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-9/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-9/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-9/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-9/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9">
        <num>9</num>
        <heading>Public traffic on Sunday</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9. Public traffic on Sunday.  All manner of public selling or\noffering for sale of any property upon Sunday is prohibited, except as\nfollows: 1. Articles of food may be sold, served, supplied and delivered\nat any time before ten o'clock in the morning:\n  2. Meals may be sold to be eaten on the premises where sold at any\ntime of the day;\n  3. Caterers may serve meals to their patrons at any time of the day;\n  4. Prepared tobacco, bread, milk, eggs, ice, soda-water, fruit,\nflowers, confectionery, souvenirs, items of art and antiques,\nnewspapers, magazines, gasoline, oil, tires, cemetery monuments, drugs,\nmedicine and surgical instruments may be sold and delivered at any time\nof the day.\n  5. Grocers, delicatessen dealers and bakeries may sell, supply, serve\nand deliver cooked and prepared foods, between the hours of four o'clock\nin the afternoon and half-past seven o'clock in the evening, in addition\nto the time provided for in subdivision one hereof, and, elsewhere than\nin cities and villages having a population of forty thousand or more,\ndelicatessen dealers, bakeries and farmers' markets or roadside stands\nselling fresh vegetables and other farm produce, and fishing tackle and\nbait stores may sell, supply, serve and deliver merchandise usually sold\nby them, at any time of the day.\n  6. Persons, firms or corporations holding licenses and/or permits\nissued under the provisions of the alcoholic beverage control law\npermitting the sale of beer at retail, may sell such beverages at retail\non Sunday before three antemeridian and after twelve noon for\noff-premises consumption to persons making purchases at the licensed\npremises to be taken by them from the licensed premises.\n  7. Sale at public auction of thoroughbred, standardbred and quarter\nhorse racehorses.\n  The provisions of this section, however, shall not be construed to\nallow or permit the public sale or exposing for sale or delivery of\nuncooked flesh foods or meats, fresh or salt, at any hour or time of the\nday. Delicatessen dealers shall not be considered as caterers within\nsubdivision three hereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>