<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-909"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-909"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-06-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="909"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-909/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-909/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-909/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-909/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_909">
        <num>909</num>
        <heading>Safety recalls</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_909__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>verify that the shared vehicle is not subject to any open safety\nrecalls appearing on the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration\nrecall database created under 49 C.F.R. 573.15 for which the recall\nrepair has not been made and shall not permit a shared vehicle to be\nshared in a peer-to-peer car sharing program unless the vehicle recall\nrepair has been made; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_909__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>notify such shared vehicle owner of the requirements under\nsubdivision two of this section.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_909__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the shared vehicle owner has received notice of a safety\nrecall on a shared vehicle, before it is enrolled in a peer-to-peer car\nsharing program such shared vehicle owner shall not make such vehicle\navailable as a shared vehicle in a peer-to-peer car sharing program\nuntil the necessary safety recall repair has been made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_909__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a shared vehicle owner has received notice of a safety recall\non a shared vehicle while the shared vehicle is available on a\npeer-to-peer car sharing program, the shared vehicle owner shall remove\nthe shared vehicle from such peer-to-peer car sharing program, as soon\nas practicable, and in no case longer than seventy-two hours after\nreceipt of such notice, and it shall not be made available thereafter\nuntil the necessary repairs under the safety recall shall have been\ncompleted.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_909__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a shared vehicle owner has received notice of a safety recall\non a shared vehicle while such shared vehicle is in the possession of a\nshared vehicle driver, the shared vehicle owner shall notify the\npeer-to-peer car sharing program administrator about the safety recall\nas soon as practicable, and in no case longer than forty-eight hours\nafter receipt of such notice, so that the shared vehicle driver can be\nnotified and the shared vehicle can be removed from the peer-to-peer car\nsharing program until the necessary safety recall repair has been made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_909__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A shared vehicle owner shall not enroll a vehicle in a\npeer-to-peer car sharing program unless such vehicle has been issued a\nvalid safety inspection in compliance with article five of the vehicle\nand traffic law. A peer-to-peer car sharing program administrator shall\nnot permit a vehicle to be shared unless the shared vehicle owner has\nfurnished proof to the program of such safety inspection in compliance\nwith article five of the vehicle and traffic law within the preceding\ntwelve months.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>