<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GBS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-919"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-919"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-06-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="919"/>
          <FRBRname value="GBS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gbs/section-919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_919">
        <num>919</num>
        <heading>Enforcement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_919__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever there shall be a violation of this section, an\napplication may be made by the attorney general in the name of the\npeople of the state of New York to a court of competent jurisdiction by\na special proceeding for the imposition of a fine or the issuance of an\ninjunction against any violation of this section, upon notice to such\npeer-to-peer car sharing program of not less than five days, to enjoin\nand restrain the continuance of such violations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_919__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the court finds that the defendant has, in fact, violated this\nsection, an injunction may be issued by such court, enjoining and\nrestraining any further violation, without requiring proof that any\nperson has, in fact, been injured or damaged thereby.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_919__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any proceeding authorized pursuant to this subdivision, the\ncourt may direct restitution and make allowances to the attorney general\nas provided in section sixty-three of the executive law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_919__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In support of any application pursuant to this subdivision, the\nattorney general is authorized to take proof, determine relevant fact\nand issue subpoenas in accordance with the civil practice law and rules.\n  3. Any clause or provision of a peer-to-peer car sharing agreement\ninconsistent with the provisions of this article shall be deemed void as\nagainst public policy.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>