<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-02-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="111-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_111_C">
        <num>111-C</num>
        <heading>Functions, powers and duties of social services officials</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681a</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>)\ninformation regarding past-due support owed by the parent owing support.\nSuch information must be made available whenever a parent who owes\npast-due support, and shall indicate the name of the parent and the\namount of the delinquency. However, such information shall not be made\navailable to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a consumer reporting agency that the office determines\ndoes not have sufficient capability to systematically and timely make\naccurate use of such information, or (ii) an entity that has not\nfurnished evidence satisfactory to the office that the entity is a\nconsumer reporting agency. In determining whether a consumer reporting\nagency lacks sufficient capability to systematically and timely make\naccurate use of such information, the office may require such agency to\ndemonstrate its ability to comply with the provisions of section three\nhundred eighty-j of the general business law and any other requirements\nthe office may prescribe by regulation. A social services official, at\nleast ten days prior to making the information available to a consumer\nreporting agency, must provide notice to the parent who owes the support\ninforming such parent of the proposed release of the information to the\nconsumer reporting agency and informing such parent of the opportunity\nto be heard and the methods available for contesting the accuracy of the\ninformation.\n  3. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the social services official shall\nnot be required to establish the parentage of any child born\nout-of-wedlock, or to secure support for any child, with respect to whom\nsuch official has determined that such actions would be detrimental to\nthe best interests of the child, in accordance with procedures and\ncriteria established by regulations of the department consistent with\nfederal law.\n  4. a. A social services district represents the interests of the\ndistrict in performing its functions and duties as provided in this\ntitle and not the interests of any party. The interests of a district\nshall include, but are not limited to, establishing parentage, and\nestablishing, modifying and enforcing child support orders.\n  b. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the provision of child\nsupport services pursuant to this title does not constitute nor create\nan attorney-c...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>