<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="111-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_111_A">
        <num>111-A</num>
        <heading>Federal aid; state plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง  111-a.  Federal aid; state plan.  1.  The department is hereby\ndesignated as the single state agency to supervise the administration of\nthe state's child support program provided for by this title, and a\nsingle organizational unit shall be established within the department\nfor such purposes.\n  2.  The department shall develop and submit a state child support\nprogram plan as required by part D of title IV of the federal social\nsecurity act to the federal department of health, education and welfare\nfor approval pursuant to such part in order to qualify the state for\nfederal aid under such part.  The department shall act for the state in\nany negotiations relative to the submission and approval of such plan\nand shall make such arrangements as may be necessary to obtain and\nretain such approval and to secure for the state the benefits of the\nprovisions of such federal act relating to child support programs.  The\ndepartment shall promulgate regulations not inconsistent with law as may\nbe necessary to assure that such plan conforms to the provisions of such\npart and any federal regulations adopted pursuant thereto.  The\ndepartment shall make all reports required by law to be made to such\nfederal department in the form and manner required by federal\nregulations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>