<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-01-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="111-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_111_I">
        <num>111-I</num>
        <heading>Child support standards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall publish annually a child support\nstandards chart. The child support standards chart shall include:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_I__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe revised poverty income guideline for a single person as reported by\nthe federal department of health and human services; (ii) the revised\nself-support reserved as defined in section two hundred forty of the\ndomestic relations law; (iii) the dollar amounts yielded through\napplication of the child support percentage as defined in section two\nhundred forty of the domestic relations law and section four hundred\nthirteen of the family court act; and (iv) the combined parental income\namount.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The combined parental income amount to be reported in the child\nsupport standards chart and utilized in calculating orders of child\nsupport in accordance with subparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section four hundred thirteen of the family court act\nand subparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one-b of section\ntwo hundred forty of the domestic relations law as of January\nthirty-first, two thousand fourteen shall be one hundred forty-one\nthousand dollars; provided, however, beginning March first, two thousand\nsixteen and every two years thereafter, the combined parental income\namount shall increase by the sum of the average annual percentage\nchanges in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (CPI-U) as\npublished by the United States department of labor bureau of labor\nstatistics for the prior two years multiplied by the current combined\nparental income amount and then rounded to the nearest one thousand\ndollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall publish the child support standards chart\non an annual basis by April first of each year and in no event later\nthan forty-five days following publication of the annual poverty income\nguideline for a single person as reported by the federal department of\nhealth and human services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>