<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="111-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_111_H">
        <num>111-H</num>
        <heading>Support collection unit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_H__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthereof shall not apply. Upon receipt of written revocation of such\nrequest, the support collection unit shall notify the employer or income\npayor that the levy is no longer effective, and the execution shall be\nreturned.\n  * NB There are 2 sb 2's\n  * 2. The support collection unit shall establish a system that will\nallow it to inform the petitioner and respondent of any case in which a\nrequired payment has not been made within two weeks after it was due and\nto assist in securing voluntary compliance with such orders or in\npreparation and submission of a petition for a violation of a support\norder, and shall implement such system no later than July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-eight based on a plan submitted to and approved\nby the department on or before December first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-seven.\n  * NB Expired January 1, 1978 (There are 2 sb 2's)\n  3. The support collection unit shall require that a person applying\nfor child support enforcement services provide his or her name, address\nand social security number and disclose whether he or she is in receipt\nof safety net assistance or family assistance; provided, however, that a\nsocial security number may be required only where permitted under\nfederal law.\n  4. Any and all moneys paid into the support collection unit pursuant\nto an order of support made under the family court act or the domestic\nrelations law, where the petitioner is not a recipient of public\nassistance, shall upon payment into such support collection unit be\ndeemed for all purposes to be the property of the person for whom such\nmoney is to be paid.\n  5. Except as provided in subdivision six of this section, any funds\npaid to a support collection unit established by a social services\ndistrict which have not been disbursed after two years of diligent\nefforts to locate the person entitled to such funds shall be paid to the\nstate comptroller in accordance with subdivision seven of this section\nunless informatio...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the names and last known addresses, if any, of the\npersons entitled to receive such abandoned property;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the title of\nany proceeding relating to such abandoned property; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such other\nidentifying information as the state comptroller may require.\n  8. Banks and other fiduciary institutions are authorized and required\nto report to the support collection unit, when so requested, full\ninformation relative to any fund therein deposited by a petitioner or\nrespondent in a proceeding under section two hundred thirty-six or two\nhundred forty of the domestic relations law or article five-B of the\nfamily court act, where there is an order of support payable through the\nsupport collection unit or article four, five or five-A of the family\ncourt act.\n  9. Employers are authorized and required to report to the support\ncollection unit, when so requested, full information as to the earnings\nof a petitioner or respondent in a proceeding under section two hundred\nthirty-six or two hundred forty of the domestic relations law or article\nfive-B of the family court act, where there is an order of support\npayable through the support collection unit or article four, five,\nfive-A or five-B of the family court act. Employers also are authorized\nand required to report to the support collection unit, when so\nrequested, information relating to any group health plans available for\nthe provision of care or other medical benefits by insurance or\notherwise for the benefit of the employee and/or the child or children\nfor whom such parties are legally responsible for support.\n  10. The support collection unit is authorized and required to report\nto the family court, when so requested, full information relative to\namounts paid or any arrearages by a respondent in a proceeding under\narticles four, five, five-A or article five-B of the family court act.\n  11. The department may provide for the performance of the collection\nand disbursement functions of the support collection units by contract\nwith a fiscal agent. For purposes of any reference to support collection\nunit in this chapter or any other law, the fiscal agent under contract\nwith the ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_111_H__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A support obligor may challenge in writing the correctness of\nthe determination of the support collection unit pursuant to this\nsection and section one hundred seventy-one-i of the tax law that the\nobligor's arrearage should be collected through the department of\ntaxation and finance, and in support of the challenge may submit\ndocumentation demonstrating mistaken identity, error in calculation of\narrears, financial exemption from such collection, the absence of an\nunderlying court order establishing arrears to support such\ndetermination. Such documents may include a copy of the order of support\npursuant to which the obligor claims to have made payment, other\nrelevant court orders, copies of cancelled checks, receipts for support\npayments, pay stubs or other documents identifying wage withholding,\nproof of identity, and like documents. The support collection unit shall\nreview the documentation submitted by the support obligor, shall adjust\nthe support obligor's account if ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_111_H__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A support obligor may within thirty days of the date of notice\ndenying his or her challenge by the support collection unit file\nobjections to such denial with the bureau of special hearings; child\nsupport unit of the department which shall review the support collection\nunit's determination to refer the obligor's case to the department of\ntaxation and finance for collection pursuant to subdivision sixteen of\nsection one hundred eleven-b of this title. If the support obligor\ntimely files such objections with such bureau the support collection\nunit shall not notify the department of taxation and finance of their\nauthority to collect the arrearages until fifteen days after entry of an\norder by the administrative law judge denying the objections.\n  14. If the support obligor is required to participate in work programs\npursuant to section four hundred thirty-seven-a of the family court act,\nand the court enters an order of support on behalf of the persons in\nreceipt of public a...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>