<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="111-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_111_J">
        <num>111-J</num>
        <heading>Interception of unemployment insurance benefits</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The\ndepartment shall determine on a periodic basis whether any individual\nreceiving unemployment insurance benefits pursuant to article eighteen\nof the state's labor law owes child support obligations which are being\nenforced by the department or the child support enforcement unit of a\nsocial services district and shall enforce any child support obligations\nwhich are owed by such individual but are not being met through an\nagreement with such individual to have specific amounts withheld from\nsuch benefits otherwise payable to such individual and by submitting a\ncopy of such agreement to the New York state department of labor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the absence of such an agreement, the department shall enforce\nany such child support obligations as authorized by the court in any\norder establishing such obligations and as otherwise provided by law.\n  2. Any amounts of unemployment insurance benefits deducted, withheld\nand paid over by the department of labor pursuant to section five\nhundred ninety-six of the labor law shall be treated as if it were paid\nto the person entitled to such compensation and paid by such person to\nthe department or appropriate child support collection unit toward\nsatisfaction of such person's child support obligations. Each agency or\ndistrict receiving payments deducted by the department of labor shall\nreimburse that department for the administrative costs attributable\nthereto.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>