<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_D">
        <num>131-D</num>
        <heading>Substance abuse rehabilitative and preventive services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131-d. Substance abuse rehabilitative and preventive services.\n  1. Any inconsistent provision of this chapter or other law\nnotwithstanding, social services officials shall provide substance abuse\nservices, to eligible needy substance abusers and persons who are\nsubstance dependent, under aid to dependent children, in accordance with\nregulations of the department, if and so long as federal aid is\navailable therefor.\n  2. Each social services official shall provide such services either\ndirectly or by purchase from a public or private non-profit agency;\nprovided, however, that such services are approved by the state division\nof substance abuse services and that any facility furnishing such\nservices is supervised and approved by the state division of substance\nabuse services.\n  3. If and so long as federal funds are available therefor, the\ndepartment shall be responsible for providing eligible services pursuant\nto this section, provided, however, such services shall be furnished\nthrough a cooperative agreement with the state division of substance\nabuse services. Provided, further that the scope of the responsibility\nof the department hereunder shall not extend beyond the authorization of\nsuch division to furnish such services either directly or through\ncontract.\n  4. There shall be such cooperative agreements, between the department\nand the state division of substance abuse services and other appropriate\nstate departments and agencies as shall be necessary to assure that\nthere will be a maximum utilization of existing rehabilitative and\npreventive services and that the purposes and objectives of this section\nwill be effectively accomplished.\n  5. Any inconsistent provision of law notwithstanding, expenditures\nmade by a social services official under this section shall be deemed\nexpenditures for and administration of public assistance and care, and\nshall be subject to reimbursement by the state in accordance with the\nprovisions of section one hundred fifty-three of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>