<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-AA"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-AA"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-AA"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_AA">
        <num>131-AA</num>
        <heading>Monthly statistical reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_AA__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Work participation rates. A statistical table containing data\nrelated to federally required work participation rates including, but\nnot limited to, the numerator applied to the required federal\ncalculation for work participation and the denominator applied to the\nfederal calculation for work participation; and any other information\nthat the commissioner deems to be appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_AA__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Earned income. A statistical table containing data related to the\naggregate amount of earned income reported by public assistance\nrecipients including, but not limited to, aggregate earned income used\nin the calculation of public assistance benefits, both before and after\nthe earnings disregard is applied to such benefits, the number of cases\nfor which earned income is applied to the calculation of such benefits,\nboth before and after the earnings disregard, and any other information\nthat the commissioner deems to be appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_AA__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sanctioned cases. A statistical table containing data related to\nthe number of cases in sanction status and the reason for such sanction\nincluding, but not limited to, the number of sanctioned cases included\nin the federal work participation calculation, the number of sanctioned\ncases not included in the federal work participation calculation, and\nany other information that the commissioner deems to be appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_AA__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Home energy assistance program (HEAP). For each county and New\nYork city, a statistical table containing data related to the allocation\nof federal and state monies for the HEAP program and the number and\ndollar amount of benefits provided including, but not limited to, the\nnumber, dollar amount and average dollar amount of regular autopay\nbenefits, regular non-autopay benefits, emergency benefits, allocation\nfor administrative costs, and any other information that the\ncommissioner deems to be appropriate.\n  3. Upon issuance, the reports required by this section shall be posted\non the office of temporary and disability assistance website, and shall\nalso be submitted by the commissioner to the governor, the temporary\npresident of the senate, the speaker of the assembly, the chair of the\nsenate finance committee and the chair of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>