<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-W"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-W"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-W"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_W">
        <num>131-W</num>
        <heading>Limitations in the payment of rent arrears</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131-w. Limitations in the payment of rent arrears. Districts shall\nnot provide assistance to pay rent arrears, property taxes or mortgage\narrears for persons not eligible for home relief, aid to dependent\nchildren, emergency assistance to needy families with children or\nemergency assistance for aged, blind and disabled persons, except to\npersons who are without income or resources immediately available to\nmeet the emergency need, whose gross household income does not exceed\none hundred twenty-five percent of the federal income official poverty\nline and who sign a repayment agreement agreeing to repay the assistance\nin a period not to exceed twelve months.  The districts shall enforce\nthe repayment agreements by any legal method available to a creditor, in\naddition to any rights it has pursuant to this chapter. The department\nshall promulgate regulations to implement this section which shall,\namong other things, establish standards for the contents of repayment\nagreements and establish standards to ensure that assistance is provided\nonly in emergency circumstances.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>