<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-U"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-U"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-U"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_U">
        <num>131-U</num>
        <heading>Domestic violence services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131-u. Domestic violence services. 1. Notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provision of law, a social services district shall, in\naccordance with the provisions of this section and regulations of the\ndepartment, offer and provide emergency shelter and services at a\nresidential program for victims of domestic violence, as defined in\narticle six-A of this chapter, to the extent that such shelter and\nservices are necessary and available to a victim of domestic violence,\nas defined in article six-A of this chapter, and in need of emergency\nshelter and services, who was residing in the social services district\nat the time of the alleged domestic violence.\n  2. The department shall annually establish, subject to the approval of\nthe director of the budget, a daily rate of reimbursement for each\nresidential program for victims of domestic violence, as defined in\narticle six-A of this chapter, certified by the department which\nprovides emergency shelter and services to persons eligible for such\nemergency shelter and services pursuant to this section. A social\nservices district financially responsible for a victim of domestic\nviolence shall reimburse a residential program for victims of domestic\nviolence for the costs of emergency shelter and services provided to\nsuch victim at the daily reimbursement rate established by the\ndepartment reduced by any other reimbursement available for such costs.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>