<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-I*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-I*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-I*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-I*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-I*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-I*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-I*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_I*2">
        <num>131-I*2</num>
        <heading>Family loan program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 131-i. Family loan program. 1. From amounts appropriated for such\npurpose, the department of labor in consultation with the department is\nhereby authorized and directed to solicit proposals to establish\nprograms to be known as family loan programs. Such programs shall\nprovide small, no-interest loans to custodial parents with income below\ntwo hundred percent of the federal poverty level and who are working or\nenrolled in a post-secondary education program, to aid in covering the\ncosts of unexpected expenses that could interfere with their ability to\nmaintain employment or continue education. Loans awarded through a\nfamily loan program may be paid directly to a third party on behalf of a\nloan recipient and in either case shall not constitute income or\nresources for the purposes of public assistance and care so long as the\nfunds are used for the intended purpose.\n  2. The commissioner of labor shall enter into written agreements with\nnot-for-profit organizations or local government agencies to administer\nloan pools. Agreements shall be entered into with no more than four\norganizations and/or agencies, no more than one of which shall be\nlocated in the city of New York.\n  3. Program sites shall be approved based on the demonstrated ability\nof the organization or governmental agency to secure funding from\nprivate and/or public sources sufficient to establish a loan pool to be\nmaintained through repayment agreements entered into by eligible\nlow-income families. Funds awarded by the department of labor to\napproved program sites shall be used for the express purposes of\ncovering staffing and administration costs associated with administering\nthe loan pool.\n  4. From amounts appropriated for such purpose, the department of labor\nin consultation with the office of temporary and disability assistance\nis hereby authorized and directed to solicit proposals to establish up\nto four new family loan programs. Such programs shall operate according\nto provisions set forth in subdivision one through three of this\nsection; provided, however, that such programs may provide no- or\nlow-interest loans, and further provided that applications submitted by\na consortium of not-for-profit organizations or local government\nagencies shall be viewed as one program and may receive greater funding\nby the department of labor than an application submitted by a single\norganization or agency. Low-interest loans shall not exceed a rate\ngreater than two-thirds of the prime rate. No not-for-profit\norganization or local government agency awarded funding from\nappropriations made in the nineteen hundred ninety-seven--nineteen\nhundred ninety-eight fiscal year shall be eligible for funds made\navailable from appropriations made in the nineteen hundred\nninety-nine--two thousand fiscal year.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 131-i's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>