<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_P">
        <num>131-P</num>
        <heading>Group health insurance benefits; condition of eligibility</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131-p. Group health insurance benefits; condition of eligibility.\nNotwithstanding any other inconsistent provision of law and to the\nextent permissible under federal law, any applicant for or recipient of\nsafety net assistance or family assistance who is or becomes employed\nand whose   employer provides group health insurance benefits, including\nbenefits for a spouse and dependent children of such applicant or\nrecipient, shall apply for and utilize such benefits as a condition of\neligibility for safety net assistance or family assistance.  Such\napplicant or recipient shall also utilize such benefits provided by\nformer employers as long as such benefits are available. The department\nshall promulgate regulations to determine the eligibility requirements\nof those applicants and recipients who have more than one employer\noffering group health insurance benefits.\n  The provisions of this section shall apply to such applicants upon\ntheir initial certification for family assistance or safety net\nassistance and to such recipients upon their recertifications for such\nassistance following the date on which this section becomes effective.\nThe cost of premiums paid by such applicants or recipients for such\ncoverage shall be deducted from such applicant's or recipient's earnings\nas an expense incident to his or her employment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>