<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-138-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-138-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="138-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-138-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-138-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-138-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-138-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_138_A">
        <num>138-A</num>
        <heading>Responsibility of the department for recipients in family care</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 138-a. Responsibility of the department for recipients in family\ncare.  1. Any inconsistent provision of this chapter or other law\nnotwithstanding, the department shall be responsible for furnishing\npublic assistance and care to mentally disabled persons residing in\nfamily care homes licensed by the office of mental health or the office\nfor people with developmental disabilities who are admitted to such\nfacilities in accordance with regulations of the office which licenses\nthe facility. However, the department may, at its option, discharge such\nresponsibility, in whole or in part, through social services districts\ndesignated to act as agents of the department. While so designated, a\nsocial services district shall act as agent of the department and shall\nbe entitled to reimbursement as provided in section one hundred\nfifty-three of this article.\n  2. The department shall possess and may exercise like powers and\nperform like duties in respect to the assistance and care of persons in\nfamily care as social services officials exercise and perform in\nrelation to persons in their respective jurisdictions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>