<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="143-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_143_B">
        <num>143-B</num>
        <heading>Avoidance of abuses in connection with rent checks</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_143_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be a valid defense in any action or summary proceeding\nagainst a welfare recipient for non-payment of rent to show existing\nviolations in the building wherein such welfare recipient resides which\nrelate to conditions which are dangerous, hazardous or detrimental to\nlife or health as the basis for non-payment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_143_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any such action or proceeding the plaintiff or landlord shall\nnot be entitled to an order or judgment awarding him possession of the\npremises or providing for removal of the tenant, or to a money judgment\nagainst the tenant, on the basis of non-payment of rent for any period\nduring which there was outstanding any violation of law relating to\ndangerous or hazardous conditions or conditions detrimental to life or\nhealth. For the purposes of this paragraph such violation of law shall\nbe deemed to have been removed and no longer outstanding upon the date\nwhen the condition constituting a violation was actually corrected, such\ndate to be determined by the court upon satisfactory proof submitted by\nthe plaintiff or landlord.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_143_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The defenses provided herein in relation to an action or\nproceeding against a welfare recipient for non-payment of rent shall\napply only with respect to violations reported to the appropriate public\nwelfare department by the appropriate department or agency having\njurisdiction over violations.\n  6. Nothing in this section shall prevent the public welfare department\nfrom making provision for payment of the rent which was withheld\npursuant to this section upon proof satisfactory to it that the\ncondition constituting a violation was actually corrected. Where rents\nwere reduced by order of the appropriate rent commission, the public\nwelfare department may make provision for payment of the reduced rent in\nconformity with such order.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>