<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="144"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_144">
        <num>144</num>
        <heading>Power of public welfare officials and service officers to administer oaths; power of public welfare officials to subpoena persons liable ...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 144. Power of public welfare officials and service officers to\nadminister oaths; power of public welfare officials to subpoena persons\nliable for support and compel production of records.  Public welfare\nofficials and service officers shall have power to administer oaths and\ntake affidavits in all matters pertaining to their office and to elicit,\nby examination under oath, statement of facts from applicants for or\nrecipients of assistance or care.  Public welfare officials shall have\nfurther power to subpoena persons liable by law for the support of\napplicants for or recipients of assistance or care, compel the\nattendance of such persons and take their testimony under oath for the\npurpose of determining the ability of such persons to contribute towards\nthe support of such applicants for or recipients of assistance or care,\nand in connection therewith to compel the production of books, papers,\nrecords and documents.  Such persons shall be entitled to the same\nmileage fees as are allowed to witnesses required to attend in civil\nactions in courts of record.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>