<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-153-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-153-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="153-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-153-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-153-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-153-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-153-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_153_A">
        <num>153-A</num>
        <heading>Reimbursement for services to social services districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 153-a. Reimbursement for services to social services districts.  1.\nExpenditures made by a department, bureau, division or other unit of a\ncounty or city for services to, on behalf of, or directly related to the\noperations of a social services district, pursuant to the provisions of\nthis chapter or any other provision of law, may, if approved by the\ndepartment, be subject to reimbursement by the state, if and so long as\nsuch expenditures are subject to federal reimbursement and only to the\nextent of such federal reimbursement.  There may be paid to each such\nsocial services district the amount of federal funds, if any, properly\nreceived or to be received on account of such expenditures.  This\nsection shall not apply to reimbursement for expenditures related to the\nlocation of absent parents, establishment of paternity or enforcement of\nsupport reimburseable under title six-A of article three of this\nchapter.\n  2. a. Claims for such reimbursement from federal funds shall be made\nin such form and manner and at such times and for such periods as the\ndepartment shall determine, including claims for any such expenditures\nmade on or after January 1, l970.\n  b. When certified by the department, such reimbursement from federal\nfunds shall be paid from the state treasury upon the audit and warrant\nof the comptroller out of funds made available therefor.\n  c. When the monies allotted to the state by the federal security\nagency, or other authorized federal agency, for such services to social\nservices districts for any quarter or other authorized period shall have\nbeen received by the department of taxation and finance, the department\nshall, as soon as possible, certify to the comptroller the amount to\nwhich each social services district is entitled for such quarter or\nother authorized period and such amount shall be paid out of the state\ntreasury after audit by the comptroller to the respective social\nservices district.\n  3. Payment of such reimbursement from federal funds shall be made to\nthe fiscal officer of the social services district entitled thereto\npursuant to the provisions of this chapter or any other provision of\nlaw.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>