<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-176"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-176"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="176"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_176">
        <num>176</num>
        <heading>Veteran advisory committees; duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In every county,\ncity or town which has elected to furnish veteran assistance, pursuant\nto the provisions of this title, in which there are more than one\nveteran organization or more than one post, camp or garrison of any\nveteran organization, there shall be appointed and constituted a joint\nveteran assistance advisory committee to consist of one representative\nfrom each post, camp and garrison of each such veteran organization,\nchosen in such manner as the post, camp or garrison shall direct, to\nserve for one year, commencing the first day of January. Each such\ncommittee shall choose a chairman and such other officers as it may deem\nnecessarry or require.  In counties and cities the deputy commissioner\nor director of the veteran assistance division or bureau of the public\nwelfare department shall serve ex officio as secretary of the committee.\nIn towns, the town welfare officer shall serve ex officio as such\nsecretary, unless he is not a veteran and his deputy or assistant is a\nveteran, in which case such deputy or assistant, as the case may be,\nshall serve as such secretary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any town which has elected to furnish veteran assistance\npursuant to the provisions of this title, in which there is only one\nveteran organization and only one post, camp or garrison thereof, such\npost, camp or garrison shall constitute a veterans assistance advisory\ncommittee, consisting of its chairman and two other representatives\ndesignated by it, which committee shall serve for one year commencing\nthe first day of January. The town welfare officer, his deputy or\nassistant, if a veteran, shall serve ex officio as the secretary of the\ncommittee; if neither be a veteran, the town welfare officer shall serve\nas such secretary.\n  2. All committees constituted under subdivision one of this section\nshall have and perform the following functions and duties:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of county or city committees, to submit to the\npublic welfare official of the county or city in which it operates a\nlist of veterans qualified to serve as deputy commissioner or director\nof the veterans assistance division or bureau in the county or city\ndepartment of welfare, as the case may be, whenever there be a vacancy\nin that office.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of town committees, to submit to the town public\nwelfare officer a list of veterans qualified to serve as his deputy or\nassistant to furnish veteran assistance, whenever there be a vacancy in\nthat office.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To keep informed all posts, camps or garrisons of each veteran\norganization in its territory concerning the administration of veteran\nassistance and the activities of the veteran assistance division or\nbureau.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To transmit to the veteran assistance division, bureau or official\nadministering veteran assistance in its territory, the views of the\nveteran organizations operating in such territory.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To advise the public welfare official of the county, city or town\nadministering veteran assistance in its territory on matters relating to\nassistance and care given to veterans and their families.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>