<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-193"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-193"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="193"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-193/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-193/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-193/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-193/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_193">
        <num>193</num>
        <heading>Public homes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 193. Public homes. 1. Each public welfare district may establish and\nmaintain a public home, which may include an infirmary for the care of\nchronically sick patients in addition to facilities for the care of\nacutely ill patients, and may operate a farm in connection therewith, or\nmay contract with another public welfare district for the care and\nmaintenance of persons in need of institutional care who are unable to\npay for such care. If facilities are available in a public home the\ncommissioner of public welfare may establish regulations authorizing the\nadmission and care therein of persons in need of institutional care who\nare able and willing to pay, in whole or in part for such care and\nprescribing the conditions under which such admissions may be made. A\nperson in need of institutional care who is unable to pay therefor shall\nnot be refused care in the public home operated and maintained by the\npublic welfare district in which he resides or is found, when persons\nable to pay for their care are receiving care in such home.\n  2. If the state commissioner of social welfare shall approve, a public\nwelfare district may use a building or buildings formerly used as a\ntuberculosis hospital or sanatorium, or as a part thereof, for a public\nhome, a public home infirmary or an infirmary of a public home.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>