<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-303-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-303-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="303-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-303-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-303-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-303-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-303-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_303_A">
        <num>303-A</num>
        <heading>Grants of assistance for guide dogs, hearing dogs and service dogs; certain cases</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 303-a. Grants of assistance for guide dogs, hearing dogs and service\ndogs; certain cases. 1. It shall be the duty of the social services\nofficial to provide assistance, in accordance with regulations of the\ndepartment, to a person with a disability using a guide dog, hearing dog\nor service dog who has been determined to be eligible for or is\nreceiving federal supplemental security income benefits and/or\nadditional state payments, for the purchase of food for such dog.\n  2. Such regulations of the department shall fix an amount of not less\nthan thirty-five dollars a month, and the  method and frequency of\ndistribution and procedures for the determination and periodical\nredetermination of eligibility for such assistance.\n  3. Such assistance shall not be granted to any person for whom earned\nincome has been exempted for such purpose pursuant to federal law or\nregulation.\n  4. The full amount properly expended by social services districts\nunder this section, including costs of administration, shall be\nreimbursed by the state, notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of\nsection three hundred one of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>