<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-335-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-335-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="335-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-335-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-335-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-335-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-335-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_335_C">
        <num>335-C</num>
        <heading>Pilot programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 335-c. Pilot programs. From the funds specifically appropriated\ntherefor the commissioner of the office of temporary and disability\nassistance in cooperation with the commissioner of the office of\nchildren and family services may conduct pilot programs in up to five\nsocial services districts to provide intensive employment and other\nsupportive services including job readiness and job placement services\nto non-custodial parents who are unemployed or who are working less than\ntwenty hours per week; who are recipients of public assistance or whose\nincome does not exceed two hundred percent of the federal poverty level;\nand who have a child support order payable through the support\ncollection unit as created by section one hundred eleven-h of this\nchapter or have had paternity established for his or her child and a\ncourt proceeding has been initiated to obtain an order of child support,\nand the custodial or non-custodial parent is receiving child support\nservices through a social services district. Non-custodial parents\ndetermined to be eligible for participation in the pilot programs shall\nbe informed of the opportunity to participate in such programs on a\nvoluntary basis. The pilot programs shall have as one component\nparenting education for the non-custodial parents. Non-custodial parents\nshall be required to attend such parenting education as a condition of\nparticipating in the pilot programs.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>