<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="336-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_336_D">
        <num>336-D</num>
        <heading>Job search activities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 336-d. Job search activities.  1. Each applicant for or recipient of\npublic assistance shall, upon request of the social services official,\ndemonstrate that he or she is engaged in an active and continuing effort\nto achieve self-sufficiency as defined by the department.  Such effort\nshall include but not be limited to an active and continuing search for\nemployment, or for persons otherwise exempt in accordance with section\nthree hundred thirty-two of this title, and where deemed appropriate by\nthe social services official, activities that foster preparation for\nemployment.  Each such applicant or recipient shall have an affirmative\nduty to accept any offer of lawful employment in which he or she may\nengage. The failure of a social services district to assign applicants\nand recipients to activities pursuant to this title shall not relieve\nsuch persons from the requirements  of this section. An individual who\nfails to comply with the requirements of the section shall be subject to\nthe provisions set forth in subdivision five of section one hundred\nthirty-one of this chapter and of section three hundred forty-one and\nthree hundred forty-two of this title.\n  2. The social services official shall, if deemed appropriate by such\nofficial, supervise job search activities assigned pursuant to this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>