<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="364-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_364_D">
        <num>364-D</num>
        <heading>Medical assistance research and demonstration projects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Social services districts shall be required to participate in\nthe operation of such research and demonstration projects as the\ndepartment may approve. Social services districts shall cooperate with\nthe department in the conduct of such projects whenever the department\nshall request or require such participation or cooperation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law to the contrary,\nexpenditures made in connection with any research demonstration project\nundertaken pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be subject\nto state reimbursement under section three hundred sixty-eight-a of this\ntitle.\n  3. The research and demonstration projects undertaken pursuant to the\nprovisions of this section shall limit the individuals participating\nthereunder to those persons with respect to whom the department has\ndetermined that there is a reasonable expectation that the total cost of\nbenefits under such project would be less than the total cost of\nbenefits for such individual if the research and demonstration program\nwere not in effect.\n  4. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this chapter or any\nother law to the contrary, the commissioner may, subject to the approval\nof the director of the budget, approve any or all of the research and\ndemonstration projects specified in subdivision one of this section, and\napply for the appropriate waivers under federal law and regulation, and\nmay waive any of the provisions of this chapter, when such action would\nbe likely to assist in promoting the objectives of this title.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each project undertaken pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection, the department shall submit an interim report and final report\nto the governor and the legislature. The interim report shall be due\neighteen months after the date of approval of the project by the\ndepartment; the final report shall be due at the conclusion of the\nproject.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such reports shall include a listing of the accomplishments of the\nresearch and demonstration project, and shall evaluate the progress made\nin achieving the objectives of the project.\n  6. This section shall be effective with respect to each such project,\nother than the "New York State Alcoholism Services Demonstration\nProject", if and as long as, federal participation is available for\nexpenditures made for such research and demonstration project conducted\npursuant to the provisions of this section.\n  * NB Expired July 22, 1986 -- Eldercare: A Social Health Maintenance\nOrganization expired April 9, 2007 per chapter 58 of 2007 Part C ยง 6.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>