<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="364-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-364-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_364_H">
        <num>364-H</num>
        <heading>Foster family care demonstration programs for elderly or disabled persons</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>recruitment, selection and training of families to serve as foster\nfamilies;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>selection of those elderly or disabled persons who will receive\nfoster family care services under the demonstration project authorized\nherein, and assessment of their needs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provision of or arrangement for necessary medical services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>monitoring the care being received by the person in the foster\nfamily care home, and assessing the continuing viability of placement in\nsuch home.\n  3. Persons eligible to participate in the foster family care\ndemonstration programs authorized by this section shall be:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>medically eligible for placement in a skilled nursing facility or\na health related facility or eligible for home care services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>capable of being cared for in the community if a suitable home\nenvironment and medical support services are provided; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lacking the home, resources or family support to live in the\ncommunity.\n  4. Families who participate in the foster family care demonstration\nprogram shall be willing and able to provide:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>room and board;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>supervision of or assistance with the activities of daily living;\nand\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_364_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>personal care and other related services which may be necessary to\nmaintain the person in the community.\n  5. In designating a hospital, facility, or program to provide a foster\nfamily care program, the department shall be satisfied as to the\ncost-effectiveness of the proposal as compared to institutional long\nterm care.\n  6. The commissioner may waive the provisions of titles one and two of\narticle seven of this chapter and regulations of the department relative\nthereto as necessary to implement the provisions of this section;\nprovided, however, the commissioner shall be satisfied that the health,\nsafety and welfare of persons participating in the foster care programs\nare not affected negatively by such waivers.\n  7. This section shall not be interpreted to restrict a medical\nassistance recipient's choice of provider of services to which he is\nentitled pursuant to this title or to authorize any change in the\neligibility criteria for medical assistance.\n  8. A medical assistance recipient may discontinue participation in a\nfoster family care demonstration program at any time.\n  9. The department shall utilize all potential sources of funding for\nsuch foster family care programs including, but not limited to, funding\navailable through titles sixteen, eighteen, nineteen and twenty of the\nfederal social security act and the federal older Americans act of 1965,\nas amended. Services provided as part of a foster family care program\nand related administrative expenses not otherwise eligible for coverage\nunder these or other funding sources shall be eligible for reimbursement\nunder the medical assistance program for the purposes of this\ndemonstration as long as federal financial participation is available.\nThe department shall take all steps necessary to secure such funding\nincluding the submission of applicable waivers. Copies of waiver\nsubmissions shall be provided to the chairman of the senate finance\ncommittee and the chairman of the assemb...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>