<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="365-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_365_B">
        <num>365-B</num>
        <heading>Local medical plans: professional directors</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 365-b. Local medical plans: professional directors. 1. A local\nsocial services medical plan shall be developed and maintained by each\nsocial services district under the guidance or direction of a\nprofessional director. Such plan shall conform to the regulations of the\ndepartment and shall be submitted to the department and the state\ndepartment of health for review, certification and approval pursuant to\nthe regulations of the department and this title.\n  2. The commissioner of social services of each social services\ndistrict shall appoint a person, possessing the qualifications\nestablished by the public health and health planning council and\npromulgated by the department pursuant to section three hundred\nsixty-four of this title, to serve on a full or part-time basis. Each\nprofessional director shall serve under the general direction of the\ncommissioner of social services and shall have the responsibility for\nsupervising the program of medical assistance for needy persons in his\nsocial services district, pursuant to the regulations of the department.\nThe state commissioner of health may authorize two or more social\nservices districts to appoint the same person to serve as professional\ndirector in each of such districts.\n  3. In addition to any other duty or responsibility which may be\nassigned or delegated pursuant to law or regulation, each professional\ndirector shall be responsible for monitoring the professional\nactivities, directly related to the program, of providers practicing in\nhis social services district, and shall take all steps required or\nauthorized by law or regulation to ensure that such activities are in\ncompliance with the provisions of this chapter, the public health law\nand regulations promulgated thereunder, and do not violate the\nprovisions of section sixty-five hundred nine of the education law or\nregulations promulgated pursuant thereto.\n  4. For purposes of this section "provider" shall mean any person\nreceiving payment under this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>