<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-04-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="365-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_365_L">
        <num>365-L</num>
        <heading>Health homes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish, in accordance with\napplicable federal law and regulations, standards for the provision of\nhealth home services to Medicaid enrollees with chronic conditions,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nestablish payment methodologies for health home services based on\nfactors including but not limited to the complexity of the conditions\nproviders will be managing, the anticipated amount of patient contact\nneeded to manage such conditions, and the health care cost savings\nrealized by provision of health home services,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish the\ncriteria under which a Medicaid enrollee will be designated as being an\neligible individual with chronic conditions for purposes of this\nprogram,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>assign any Medicaid enrollee designated as an eligible\nindividual with chronic conditions to a provider of health home\nservices.\n  2. In addition to payments made for health home services pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section, the commissioner is authorized to pay\nadditional amounts to providers of health home services that meet\nprocess or outcome standards specified by the commissioner. Such\nadditional amounts may be paid with state funds only if federal\nfinancial participation for such payments is unavailable.\n  2-a. Up to fifteen million dollars in state funding may be used to\nfund health home infrastructure development. Such funds shall be used to\ndevelop enhanced systems to support Health Home operations including\nassignments, workflow, and transmission of data. Funding will also be\ndisbursed pursuant to a formula established by the commissioner to be\ndesignated health homes. Such formula may consider prior access to\nsimilar funding opportunities, geographic and demographic factors,\nincluding the population served, and prevalence of qualifying\nconditions, connectivity to providers, and other criteria as established\nby the commissioner.\n  2-b. The commissioner is authorized to make lump sum payments or\nadjust rates of payment to providers up to a gross amount of five\nmillion dollars, to establish coordination between the health homes and\nthe criminal justice system and for the integration of information of\nhealth homes with state and local correctional facilities, to the extent\npermitted by law. Such rate adjustments may be made to health homes\nparticipating in a criminal justice pilot program with the purpose of\nenrolling incarcerated individuals with serious mental illness, two or\nmore chronic conditions, including substance abuse disorders, or\nHIV/AIDS, into such health home. Health homes receiving funds under this\nsubdivision shall be required to document and demonstrate the effective\nuse of funds distributed herein.\n  2-...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>can demonstrate experience in the delivery of health, and mental\nhealth and/or alcohol and substance abuse services and/or services to\npersons with developmental disabilities, and the capacity to offer\nintegrated delivery of such services in each location approved by the\ncommissioner; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>meet the standards established pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection for providing and receiving payment for health home services;\nprovided, however, that an entity meeting the standards established\npursuant to subdivision one of this section shall not be required to be\nan integrated service provider pursuant to this subdivision.\n  In establishing a single set of operating and reporting requirements\nand a single set of construction and survey requirements for entities\ndescribed in this subdivision, the commissioners of the department of\nhealth, the office of mental health, the office for people with\ndevelopmental disabilities, and the office of alcoholism and substance\nabuse services are authorized to waive any regulatory requirements as\nare necessary to avoid duplication of requirements and to allow the\nintegrated delivery of services in a rational and efficient manner.\n  8.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of health is authorized to contract with one\nor more entities to assist the state in implementing the provisions of\nthis section. Such entity or entities shall be the same entity or\nentities chosen to assist in the implementation of the multipayor\npatient centered medical home program pursuant to section twenty-nine\nhundred fifty-nine-a of the public health law. Responsibilities of the\ncontractor shall include but not be limited to: developing\nrecommendations with respect to program policy, reimbursement, system\nrequirements, reporting requirements, evaluation protocols, and provider\nand patient enrollment; providing technical assistance to potential\nmedical home and health home providers; data collection; data sharing;\nprogram evaluation, and preparation of reports.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of sections one hundred\ntwelve and one hundred sixty-three of the state finance law, or section\none hundred forty-two of the economic development law, or any other law,\nthe commissioner of health is authorized to enter into a contract or\ncontracts under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision without a competitive\nbid or request for proposal process, provided, however, that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_L__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of health shall post on its website, for a period\nof no less than thirty days:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_365_L__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A description of the proposed services to be provided pursuant to\nthe contract or contracts;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_365_L__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The criteria for selection of a contractor or contractors;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_365_L__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The period of time during which a prospective contractor may seek\nselection, which shall be no less than thirty days after such\ninformation is first posted on the website; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_365_L__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The manner by which a prospective contractor may seek such\nselection, which may include submission by electronic means;\n  (ii) All reasonable and responsive submissions that are received from\nprospective contractors in timely fashion shall be reviewed by the\ncommissioner of health; and\n  (iii) The commissioner of health shall select such contractor or\ncontractors that, in his or her discretion, are best suited to serve the\npurposes of this section.\n  9. The contract entered into by the commissioner of health prior to\nJanuary first, two thousand thirteen pursuant to subdivision eight of\nthis section may be amended or modified without the need for a\ncompetitive bid or request for proposal process, and without regard to\nthe provisions of sections one hundred twelve and one hundred\nsixty-three of the state finance law, section one hundred forty-two of\nthe economic development law, or any other provision of law, excepting\nthe responsible vendor requirements of the state finan...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>