<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-05-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="365-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_365_N">
        <num>365-N</num>
        <heading>Department of health assumption of program administration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_N__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may take necessary action to review the\naccuracy of determinations of initial and ongoing eligibility under the\nmedical assistance program, and to identify and eliminate inappropriate\ninstances of concurrent or duplicate benefits and authorizations. The\ncommissioner is authorized to contract with one or more entities to\nassist the state in implementing the provisions of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_N__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of sections one hundred twelve and\none hundred sixty-three of the state finance law, or section one hundred\nforty-two of the economic development law, or any contrary provision of\nlaw, the commissioner is authorized to enter into a contract or\ncontracts under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_N__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision without a competitive\nbid or request for proposal process, provided, however, that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_N__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of health shall post on its website, for a period\nof no less than thirty days:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_365_N__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A description of the proposed services to be provided pursuant to\nthe contract or contracts;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_365_N__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The criteria for selection of a contractor or contractors;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_365_N__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The period of time during which a prospective contractor may seek\nselection, which shall be no less than thirty days after such\ninformation is first posted on the website; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_365_N__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The manner by which a prospective contractor may seek such\nselection, which may include submission by electronic means;\n  (ii) All reasonable and responsive submissions that are received from\nprospective contractors in timely fashion shall be reviewed by the\ncommissioner; and\n  (iii) The commissioner shall select such contractor or contractors\nthat, in his or her discretion, are best suited to serve the purposes of\nthis section; and\n  (iv) No contract entered pursuant to this paragraph shall have a term\nthat ends later than March thirty-first, two thousand seventeen.\n  6. The commissioner shall submit an annual report to the governor,\ntemporary president of the senate, speaker of the assembly, the chair of\nthe senate health committee and the chair of the assembly health\ncommittee by December thirty-first, beginning in two thousand twelve and\nfor each year thereafter until the year following full implementation.\nThe initial report shall consist of modifications to the pla...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_N__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>assume specific functions related to the administration of the\nmedical assistance program; (ii) coordinate the implementation of\nprovisions of federal law with the assumption of the administration of\nthe medical assistance program; and (iii) address the financing of the\nmedical assistance program administration and any associated\nadministrative cost relief to local social services districts. The\nreport shall also indicate any function that the state intends to enter\ninto a contract with a public and/or private entity to perform, and the\ndate in which the state anticipates entering into any such contract. In\naddition, reports shall, at a minimum, indicate:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_N__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any progress the\ndepartment has made regarding its proposed timeline, including a summary\nof all functions assumed by the state during the previous year; (ii) any\nanticipated and/or actual delay from the proposed timeline; (iii) the\nreason for any such delay; and (iv) actions the department has\nundertaken to mitigate any such delay.\n  7. The commissioner shall promulgate such regulations that are\nnecessary to carry out the provisions of this section. In addition, the\ncommissioner shall make any amendments to the state plan for medical\nassistance, or develop and submit an application for any waiver or\napproval under the federal social security act, that are necessary and\nrequired to carry out the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>