<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="366-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_366_I">
        <num>366-I</num>
        <heading>Long-term care financing demonstration program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_366_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a level\nthat would permit a full medical assistance resource exemption pursuant\nto paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_366_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of this section; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_366_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a level or\nlevels that would permit a medical assistance resource exemption that is\nequivalent to the value of the contribution pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_366_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision four of this section.\n  4. Medical assistance eligibility. Upon completion of the defined\nprivate contribution required by such agreement, the person may apply\nfor medical assistance under this title and, if otherwise eligible,\nshall be eligible for such assistance either:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_366_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of an\nindividual who opts for a contribution level under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_366_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of this section, without regard to otherwise\napplicable resource requirements of this title; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_366_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of an\nindividual who opts for a contribution level under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_366_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of this section, without regard to an amount of\nresources that is equivalent to the value of the contribution. In either\ncase, eligibility for medical assistance under this title shall, with\nrespect to the amount of resources that are exempt from consideration\nunder this subdivision, be without regard to the lien and estate\nrecovery provisions of section three hundred sixty-nine of this title;\nprovided, however, that nothing herein shall prevent the imposition of a\nlien or recovery against property of an individual on account of medical\nassistance incorrectly paid.\n  5. The commissioner is authorized to enter into a contract with a\nprivate entity to assist in the administration of the demonstration\nprogram established by this section. Such a contract may include,\nwithout limitation, assistance in the development of the criteria for\nthe defined private contribution, drafting of the defined contribution\nagreement, accepting and processing applications for demonstration\nparticipation under this section, and accepting and processing\napplications for medical assistance for demonstration participants.\nNotwithstanding any inconsistent provision of sections one hundred\ntwelve and one hundred sixty-three of the state finance law, or section\none hundred forty-two of the economic development law, or any other law,\nthe commissioner is authorized to enter into a contract under this\nsubdivision without a competitive bid or request for proposal process.\n  6. If the commissioner exercises his or her authority to implement a\ndemonstration program under this section he or she shall submit a report\nto the governor, president pro tem of the senate and speaker of the\nassembly by the first day of November, two thousand fifteen, on the\nimplementation of this section. Such report shall include a statement as\nto the extent to which individuals have opted to participate in the\ndemonstration, an analysis of the impact of the demonstration on m...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>