<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-367-P*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-367-P*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="367-P*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-367-P*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-367-P*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-367-P*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-367-P*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_367_P*2">
        <num>367-P*2</num>
        <heading>Payment for limited home care services agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 367-p. Payment for limited home care services agencies. 1.\nNotwithstanding any law to the contrary, the commissioner shall, subject\nto the approval of the director of the budget, establish rates of\npayment for services provided by limited home care services agencies,\nlicensed by the department of health pursuant to section thirty-six\nhundred five of the public health law, to eligible individuals who are\nresidents of adult homes and enriched housing programs certified by the\ndepartment in accordance with article seven of this chapter. Services\nfor which reimbursement shall be available are personal care services\nprovided directly by the agency and authorized and provided in\naccordance with the rules and regulations of the department; and the\nadministration of medications and application of sterile dressings by a\nregistered nurse provided, however, that the services provided by such\nagency are not services that must be provided to residents of such\nfacilities pursuant to article seven of this chapter.\n  2. Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, a limited home care\nservices agency licensed by the department of health shall be reimbursed\nat a rate that is significantly less than the current costs of providing\nsuch services through a personal care provider or certified home health\nagency in the same service area.\n  3. For purposes of this section, an eligible individual means an\nindividual who is eligible for medical assistance, as determined by the\nappropriate social services district, which has also determined that\nsuch individual has a medical need for services and that such\nindividual's needs can safely and appropriately be met by the limited\nhome care services agency in the adult home or enriched housing program.\n  4. Prior to authorizing payment for services provided to an eligible\nindividual by a limited home care services agency, the appropriate\nsocial services district must determine that the service proposed to be\nprovided by such agency is cost-effective in comparison to other\navailable and appropriate service delivery options available in the\ndistrict.\n  5. The commissioner of health shall establish rates of payment for\nservices provided pursuant to this section by November fifteenth,\nnineteen hundred ninety-seven.\n  * NB Expires June 30, 2027\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 367-p's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>