<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="368-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_368_B">
        <num>368-B</num>
        <heading>State reimbursement to local health districts; chargebacks</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_368_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of federal funds, if any, properly received or to be\nreceived on account of such expenditures; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_368_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fifty per centum of the amount expended for such administrative\nexpenses, after first deducting therefrom any federal funds properly\nreceived or to be received on account thereof.\n  2.  The department of health shall submit a quarterly report to the\ndepartment of expenditures for administrative expenses incurred by each\nof the state health districts in the performance of the cooperative\nagreement entered into pursuant to section three hundred sixty-four-a of\nthis title.  Upon receipt of such report, the department shall deduct\nthe amount of federal funds, if any, properly received or to be received\non account of such expenditures from the total amounts reported for each\nsuch district  Fifty per centum of the balance shall be apportioned\namong the public welfare districts served by such district in the ratio\nthat the total expenditures by each such public welfare district for\nmedical assistance for needy persons for the quarter bears to the total\nexpenditures by all such public welfare districts for such quarter.  The\nproportionate share shall be deducted from the next payment due each of\nsuch public welfare districts pursuant to section three hundred\nsixty-eight-a of this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>