<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-370"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-370"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="370"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-370/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-370/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-370/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-370/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_370">
        <num>370</num>
        <heading>Community centers and services for senior citizens; when social services official to furnish</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 370.  Community centers and services for senior citizens; when\nsocial services official to furnish. 1.  A social services official of a\ncounty, city or town is authorized, provided funds have been made\navailable therefor, to provide at public expense one or more community\ncenters and services for senior citizens residing in his territory who\nare eligible therefor pursuant to the provisions of this title.  Such\ncenters and services may be provided only in cases where it is\ndetermined, under criteria established by the department, that there is\na need therefor.\n  2.  The furnishing of such centers and services is hereby declared to\nbe proper municipal purpose for which the moneys of a county, city or\ntown may be raised and expended.  A county, city or town may receive and\nexpend moneys from the state, the federal government or private\nindividuals, corporations or associations for furnishing such centers\nand services.\n  3.  Community centers and services for senior citizens under this\ntitle may be provided by a social services official either directly or\nthrough the purchase or rental of such centers and services from a\nprivate non-profit corporation, company or association provided they are\noperated and furnished in compliance with regulations of the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>