<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-384"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-384"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="384"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-384/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-384/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-384/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-384/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_384">
        <num>384</num>
        <heading>Guardianship and custody of children not in foster care</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if both parents shall then be living, by the parents of such\nchild, or by the surviving parent, if either parent of such child be\ndead;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if either one of such parents shall have for a period of six\nmonths then next preceding abandoned such child, by the other of such\nparents;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if such child is born out of wedlock, by the mother of such child,\nand by the father of such child, if such father's consent would be\nrequired for the child's adoption, pursuant to section one hundred\neleven of the domestic relations law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if both parents of such child are dead, or if such child is born\nout of wedlock and the mother of such child is dead by the guardian of\nthe person of such child lawfully appointed, with the approval of the\ncourt or officer which appointed such guardian to be entered of record.\n  2. Terms.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such guardianship shall be in accordance with the\nprovisions of this article and the instrument shall be upon such terms\nand subject to such conditions as may be agreed upon by the parties\nthereto. The instrument shall recite that the authorized agency is\nthereby authorized and empowered to consent to the adoption of such\nchild in the place and stead of the person signing the instrument, and\nmay recite that the person signing the instrument waives any notice of\nsuch adoption; provided, however, that an authorized agency shall not\naccept a surrender instrument conditioned upon adoption by a particular\nperson, unless the agency has fully investigated and certified or\napproved such person as a qualified adoptive parent. Any surrender\ninstrument subject to the provisions of this section shall include an\nadoption information registry birth parent registration consent form,\nstating whether or not such biological parent or parents whose consent\nis subject to the provisions of this section, consents to the receipt of\nidentifying information by the child to be adopted, upon registration\nwith the adoption information registry established by section forty-one\nhundred thirty-eight-c of the public health law and upon the adoptee\nreaching the age of eighteen. If such consent is made, it shall be\nrevocable by either of the biological parents at any time. The\nrevocation of the consent by one of the parents shall revoke the consent\nof both parents.  The failure of a biological parent to complete the\nconsent form shall have no effect on the finality of the consent to\nadoption. A copy of the form required by this subdivision, shall be\nforwarded to the state adoption information registry for inclusion in\nthe records maintained by such registry. Any fees authorized to be\ncharged by the state adoption registry for filing documentation with\nsuch registry shall be waived for the form required by this subdivision.\nNo such agency shall draw or receive money from p...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a surrender instrument designates a particular person or\npersons who will adopt a child, such person or persons, the child's\nbirth parent or parents, the authorized agency having care and custody\nof the child and the child's attorney, may enter into a written\nagreement providing for communication or contact between the child and\nthe child's parent or parents on such terms and conditions as may be\nagreed to by the parties.\n  If a surrender instrument does not designate a particular person or\npersons who will adopt the child, then the child's birth parent or\nparents, the authorized agency having care and custody of the child and\nthe child's attorney may enter into a written agreement providing for\ncommunication or contact, on such terms and conditions as may be agreed\nto by the parties. Such agreement also may provide terms and conditions\nfor communication with or contact between the child and the child's\nbiological sibling or half-sibling, if any. If any such sibling or\nhalf-sibling is fourteen years of age or older, such terms and\nconditions shall not be enforceable unless such sibling or half-sibling\nconsents to the agreement in writing. If the court before which the\nsurrender instrument is presented for approval determines that the\nagreement concerning communication and contact is in the child's best\ninterests, the court shall approve the agreement. If the court does not\napprove the agreement, the court may nonetheless approve the surrender;\nprovided, however, that the birth parent or parents executing the\nsurrender instrument shall be given the opportunity at that time to\nwithdraw such instrument. Enforcement of any agreement prior to the\nadoption of the child shall be in accordance with subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection one thousand fifty-five-a of the family court act. Subsequent to\nthe adoption of the child, enforcement of any agreement shall be in\naccordance with section one hundred twelve-b of the domestic relations\nlaw.\n  3. Instrument. The instrument herein provided shall be executed and\nacknowledged</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>before any judge or surrogate in this state having\njurisdiction over adoption proceedings, except that if the child is\nbeing surrendered as a result of, or in connection with, a proceeding\nbefore the family court pursuant to article ten or ten-A of the family\ncourt act, the instrument shall be executed and acknowledged in the\nfamily court that exercised jurisdiction over such proceeding and shall\nbe assigned, wherever practicable, to the judge who last presided over\nsuch proceeding; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the presence of one or more witnesses and\nacknowledged by such witness or witnesses, in the latter case before a\nnotary public or other officer authorized to take proof of deeds, and\nshall be recorded in the office of the county clerk in the county where\nsuch instrument is executed, or where the principal office of such\nauthorized agency is located, in a book which such county clerk shall\nprovide and shall keep under seal. Such record shall be subject to\ninspection and examination only as provided in subdivisions three and\nfour of section three hundred seventy-two of this title. Notwithstanding\nany other provision of law, if the parent surrendering the child for\nadoption is in foster care the instrument shall be executed before a\njudge of the family court.\n  Whenever the term surrender or surrender instrument is used in any law\nrelating to the adoption of children who are not in foster care, it\nshall mean and refer exclusively to the instrument hereinabove described\nfor the commitment of the guardianship of the person and the custody of\na child to an authorized agency by his parents, parent or guardian; and\nin no case shall it be deemed to apply to any instrument purporting to\ncommit the guardianship of the person and the custody of a child to any\nperson other than an authorized agency, nor shall such term or the\nprovisions of this section be deemed to apply to any instrument\ntransferring the care and custody of a child to an authorized agency\npursuant to section three hundred eighty-four-a of this chapter.\n  Any person or persons having custody of a child for the purpose of\nadoption through an authorized agency shall be permitted as a matter of\nright, as an interested party, to intervene in any proceeding commenced\nto set aside a surrender purporting to commit a guardianship of the\nperson or custody of a child executed under the provisions of this\nsection. Such intervention may be made anonymously or in the true name\nof said person.\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_384__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the authorized agency shall notify the parent, unless such notice\nis expressly waived by a statement written by the parent and appended to\nor included in such instrument, the attorney for the child and the court\nthat approved the surrender within twenty days of any substantial\nfailure of a material condition of the surrender prior to the\nfinalization of the adoption of the child; and\n  (ii) except for good cause shown, the authorized agency shall file a\npetition on notice to the parent unless notice is expressly waived by a\nstatement written by the parent and appended to or included in such\ninstrument and the child's attorney in accordance with section one\nthousand fifty-five-a of the family court act within thirty days of such\nfailure, in order for the court to review such failure and, where\nnecessary, to hold a hearing; provided, however, that, in the absence of\nsuch filing, the parent and/or attorney for the child may file such a\npetition at any time up to sixty days after notification of such\nfailure. Such petition filed by a parent or attorney for the child must\nbe filed prior to the child's adoption; and\n  (iii) the parent is obligated to provide the authorized agency with a\ndesignated mailing address, as well as any subsequent changes in such\naddress, at which the parent may receive notices regarding any\nsubstantial failure of a material condition, unless such notification is\nexpressly waived by a statement written by the parent and appended to or\nincluded in such instrument.\n  Nothing in this paragraph shall limit the notice on the instrument\nwith respect to a failure to comply with a material condition of a\nsurrender subsequent to the finalization of the adoption of the child.\n  4. Upon petition by an authorized agency, a judge of the family court,\nor a surrogate, may approve such surrender, on such notice to such\npersons as the surrogate or judge may in his or her discretion\nprescribe. If the child is being surrendered as a res...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>