<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-389"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-389"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="389"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-389/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-389/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-389/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-389/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_389">
        <num>389</num>
        <heading>Penalty for violations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_389__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person, corporation, society, institution or other\norganization who or which violates the provisions of subdivision six of\nsection three hundred seventy-four of this chapter shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor, for the first such offense. Any person, corporation,\nsociety, institution or other organization who or which violates the\nprovisions of subdivision six of section three hundred seventy-four of\nthis chapter, after having been once convicted of violating such\nprovisions, shall be guilty of a felony.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_389__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_389__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, any person, corporation, society, institution or other\norganization who or which violates subdivision six of section three\nhundred seventy-four of this title, where such unlawful compensation or\nthing of value accepted or received exceeds five thousand dollars in\nvalue, shall be guilty of a class E felony as defined in the penal law.\nAny person, corporation, society, institution, or other organization who\nor which violates subdivision six of section three hundred seventy-four\nof this title, where such unlawful compensation or thing of value\naccepted or received exceeds five thousand dollars in value, after\nhaving been previously convicted of violating subdivision six of section\nthree hundred seventy-four of this title, shall be guilty of a class D\nfelony as defined in the penal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>