<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="390-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_390_N">
        <num>390-N</num>
        <heading>Child care support center; operating certificate required</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_N__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>standards and training requirements set forth in section three\nhundred ninety-a of this title for child day care program employees;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_N__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>criminal history review and background clearance requirements of\nsection three hundred ninety-b of this title for prospective employees\nof a child day care program; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_N__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other requirements established by the regulations of the\noffice of children and family services.\n  5. Any child day care program licensed or registered by the office of\nchildren and family services shall be authorized to request placement of\na substitute caregiver by a child care support center in accordance with\nprocedures established by the child care support center.\n  6. Operating certificates issued under this section shall remain valid\nunless surrendered by the child care support center or revoked by the\noffice of children and family services. The office of children and\nfamily services may revoke an operating certificate at any time upon a\ndetermination that the child care support center has not operated in\naccordance with applicable state or federal law.\n  7. The office of children and family services shall deny an\napplication for certification of a child care support center if the\napplicant had an operating certificate revoked within the two years\nprior to the date of application.\n  * NB Effective May 9, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>