<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-02-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="390-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_390_L">
        <num>390-L</num>
        <heading>Securing of furniture</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_L__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsection three hundred ninety of this title, or any authorized agency as\ndefined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_L__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision ten of section three hundred\nseventy-one of this title, including any agency boarding home or group\nhome.\n  2. Any facility to which this section applies shall take measures to\nsecurely anchor to the floors or walls of such facility all items of\nlarge furniture and all electronic appliances capable of being tipped\nover due to design, height, weight, stability or other features, using\nangle-braces, anchors or other anchoring devices. Any item of furniture\nor electronic device which cannot be so anchored shall be removed from\nthe facility.\n  3. If a violation of the provisions of this section is discovered by\nthe office of children and family services or any local social services\ndistrict authorized to inspect the facility at which the violation\noccurs, the agency discovering the violation shall provide written\nnotice of the violation to the operator of the facility and to the\noffice of children and family services if such office is not the\ninspecting agency within ten calendar days of the discovery of the\nviolation. The operator of the facility shall correct the violation\nimmediately, upon notice. If the violation is not corrected, the office\nof children and family services may take enforcement action in\naccordance with the applicable sections of state law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>