<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="390-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-390-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_390_J">
        <num>390-J</num>
        <heading>Performance summary card in a city having a population of one million or more</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Child care service" shall mean any person who provides child day\ncare in a city having a population of one million or more that is\nrequired to obtain a permit to operate pursuant to the health code of\nsuch city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Performance summary card" shall mean an individualized placard\nthat summarizes the health and safety inspections of a child care\nservice to reflect its compliance with applicable laws. The performance\nsummary card shall summarize recent inspection violations and\nsuspensions as required by rules promulgated by the department issuing\nsuch card. A performance summary card may also include additional\ninformation such as the capacity of the child care service, the length\nof time for which such child care service has operated, a comparison of\nthe child care service to other child care services in the same social\nservices district, and other information required by such department's\nrules.\n  2. Performance summary card. The department of health and mental\nhygiene of a city having a population of one million or more shall issue\na performance summary card to each child care service that is required\nto be permitted by the board of health of such city. Such performance\ncard shall be updated and reissued by such department at least once\nevery twelve months. The child care service shall conspicuously post its\nmost recently issued performance summary card at or near its entrance in\naccordance with rules promulgated by such department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>