<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409_F">
        <num>409-F</num>
        <heading>Uniform case recording</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law to the\ncontrary, records relating to children pursuant to this section shall be\nmade available to officers and employees of the state comptroller or of\nthe city comptroller of the city of New York, or of the county officer\ndesignated bylaw or charter to perform the auditing function in any\ncounty not wholly contained within a city, for purposes of a duly\nauthorized performance audit; provided, however, that such comptroller\nor officer shall have certified to the keeper of such records that he or\nshe has instituted procedures developed in consultation with the\ndepartment to limit access to client-identifiable information to persons\nrequiring such information for purposes of the audit, that such persons\nshall not use such information in any way except for purposes of the\naudit and that appropriate controls and prohibitions are imposed on the\ndissemination of client-identifiable information obtained in the conduct\nof the audit. Information pertaining to the substance or content of any\npsychological, psychiatric, therapeutic, clinical or medical reports,\nevaluations or like materials or information pertaining to such child or\nthe child's family shall not be made available to such officers and\nemployees unless disclosure of such information is absolutely essential\nto the specific audit activity and the department gives prior written\napproval.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any failure to maintain the confidentiality of client-identifiable\ninformation shall subject such comptroller or officer to denial of any\nfurther access to records until such time as the audit agency has\nreviewed its procedures concerning controls and prohibitions imposed on\nthe dissemination of such information and has taken all reasonable and\nappropriate steps to eliminate such lapses in maintaining\nconfidentiality to the satisfaction of the department. The department\nshall establish the grounds for denial of access to records contained\nunder this section and shall recommend as necessary a plan of\nremediation to the audit agency. Except as provided in this section,\nnothing in this subdivision shall be construed as limiting the powers of\nsuch comptroller or officer to access records which he is otherwise\nauthorized to audit or obtain under any other applicable provision of\nlaw. Any person given access to information pursuant to this subdivision\nwho releases data or information to persons or agencies not authorized\nto receive such information shall be guilty of a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>