<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-409-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409_N">
        <num>409-N</num>
        <heading>Implementation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 409-n. Implementation. 1. The department shall plan for the\nimplementation of the services case management system during the period\nfrom the first day of July, nineteen hundred eighty-four to the\nthirty-first day of March, nineteen hundred eighty-five.\n  2. Subject to the appropriation of funds, the provisions of this title\nshall be implemented from the first day of October, nineteen hundred\neighty-five in a select number of representative pilot social services\ndistricts which shall be designated by the commissioner in consultation\nwith the advisory board established pursuant to this title, in\ncommunities with a higher than state average teen population applying\nfor or receiving public assistance.\n  3. Subject to the appropriation of funds, social services districts\nwhich had not implemented the provisions of this title by the\nthirty-first day of March, nineteen hundred eighty-seven shall be\nrequired to implement the provisions of this title during the period\nApril first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven through March thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred ninety. The social services districts subject to the\nprovisions of this subdivision shall implement this title in accordance\nwith a schedule to be developed by the department which will ensure\nstatewide implementation by the thirty-first day of March, nineteen\nhundred eighty-eight.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>