<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-V"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-V"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410-V"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_V">
        <num>410-V</num>
        <heading>Allocation of block grant funds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 410-v. Allocation of block grant funds.  1. The part of the block\nthat is determined to be available to social services districts for\nchild care assistance shall be apportioned among the social services\ndistricts by the department according to an allocation plan developed by\nthe department and approved by the director of the budget.  The\nallocation plan shall be based, at least in part, on historical costs\nand on the availability and cost of, and the need for, child care\nassistance in each social services district.  Annual allocations shall\nbe made on a federal fiscal year basis.\n  2. Reimbursement under the block grant to a social services district\nfor its expenditures for child care assistance shall be available for\nseventy-five percent of the district's expenditures for child care\nassistance provided to those families in receipt of public assistance\nwhich are eligible for child care assistance under this title and for\none hundred percent of the social services district's expenditures for\nother eligible families; provided, however, that such reimbursement\nshall be limited to the social services district's annual state block\ngrant allocation.\n  3. Any portion of a social services district's block grant allocation\nfor a particular federal fiscal year that is not claimed by such\ndistrict during that federal fiscal year shall be added to that social\nservices district's block grant allocation for the next federal fiscal\nyear.\n  4.  Any claims for child care assistance made by a social services\ndistrict for services that occurred from October first, nineteen hundred\nninety-six through September thirtieth, nineteen hundred ninety-seven,\nother than claims made under title XX of the federal social security\nact, shall be counted against the social services district's first block\ngrant allocation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>