<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CCC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CCC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410-CCC"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CCC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CCC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CCC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CCC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_CCC">
        <num>410-CCC</num>
        <heading>Child day care facility development</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>design studies and services and other development or\nredevelopment work in connection with the design and development of\nchild day care centers; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>studies, surveys or reports, including\npreliminary planning studies to assess a particular site or sites or\nfacility or facilities for the development of child day care centers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In determining grants to be awarded, the department shall consider\nthe following:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that a not-for-profit organization applying for a\ngrant under this subdivision is a bonafide organization which shall have\ndemonstrated by its immediate past and current activities its ability to\nlead or to assist in the development of projects, such as child day care\ncenters meeting the needs of low-income families; (ii) the need for day\ncare centers in the area; (iii) the potential viability for a child day\ncare center to succeed in the area; and (iv) such other matters as the\ndepartment determines necessary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Grants shall be awarded to eligible entities where the department\nidentifies an insufficient supply of child day care programs. Grants\nawarded pursuant to the request for proposals shall not exceed\nseventy-five thousand dollars per project.\n  3. Child care construction grants.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The child care construction\ngrants awarded pursuant to this section and section sixteen-g of the\nurban development corporation act shall be available for not-for-profit\nchild care facilities construction projects owned or to be owned by\nnot-for-profit corporations for use as child day care centers that will\nbe duly approved, licensed, inspected, supervised, and regulated as may\nbe determined to be necessary and appropriate by the department, except\nthat with respect to child day care centers located in the city of New\nYork, such child day care centers will be duly approved, licensed,\ninspected, supervised, and regulated as may be determined to be\nnecessary and appropriate by the commissioner of the department of\nhealth of the city of New York.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Grants shall be made through contracts to not-for-profit\ncorporations for child care facilities construction projects pursuant to\na request for proposal process jointly developed by the department and\nthe urban development corporation in consultation with the department of\neconomic development. The department shall receive, initially review,\nand assess applications to determine which projects should be referred\nto the urban development corporation and to rank by groups, the referred\nprojects according to the capacity of such projects to meet identified\nneeds for child day care. In assessing such applications, the department\nshall consider:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the need for day care services in the area; (ii) the\npotential viability for a child day care center to succeed in the area;\n(iii) the qualifications of the proposed provider to operate a child\ncare center; (iv) the potential for meeting applicable regulatory\nrequirements;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the appropriateness of the site for licensing as a day\ncare center and (vi) such other matters as the department determines\nnecessary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_CCC__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the timely completion of the department's initial review and\nselection of applications meeting criteria, the department shall\nimmediately submit such selected applications and the group rankings of\nsuch applications to the urban development corporation which, in\nconsultation with the department of economic development, shall select\naward recipients. No later than upon submission of the selected\napplications, the department shall also suballocate all moneys\nappropriated for such purposes to such corporation.\n  4. Programs conducted pursuant to this section of law are limited to\nthe amounts appropriated therefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>