<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_CC">
        <num>410-CC</num>
        <heading>Start up grants for child day care</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 410-cc. Start up grants for child day care. The commissioner shall\nprovide funds to start up grants to not-for-profit organizations or\ncorporations for the development of new or expanded all day child day\ncare programs including costs related to planning, renting, renovating,\noperating, and purchasing equipment. The commissioner shall establish\nguidelines including, but not limited to, allowable costs, and criteria\nfor eligibility for grants giving preference to those child day care\nproviders who will, to the maximum extent feasible, target services to\nhouseholds having incomes up to two hundred percent of the federal\npoverty standard.  The commissioner shall publicize the availability of\nfunds. No awards shall be granted which exceed twenty-five hundred\ndollars for a new family day care provider or new group family day care\nprovider, and one hundred thousand dollars for a new child day care\ncenter. Child care resource and referral agencies may receive family day\ncare start up grants not to exceed two thousand five hundred dollars per\nnew provider if the agency trains such new family provider and thereby\nexpands the supply of family day care programs in the community. The\ncommissioner shall give preference to those communities which are\nsignificantly underserved by existing programs and to those programs\nwhich and those providers who will serve infants under two years of age.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>