<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-Z"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-Z"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410-Z"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_Z">
        <num>410-Z</num>
        <heading>Reporting requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each social services district shall maintain a waiting list of\neligible families who have applied for child care assistance pursuant to\nthis title and who have not received such assistance. Such waiting list\nshall contain information including, but not limited to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the date the child care assistance was requested;\n  (ii) the date the child care assistance was received;\n  (iii) the age of the child or children the assistance was requested on\nbehalf of; and\n  (iv) the total number of families on such waiting list as of the first\nday of each month.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each district shall issue a report to the office of children and\nfamily services by October fifteenth, two thousand twenty-seven, and\nannually thereafter detailing month-to-month information required\npursuant to this subdivision for the preceding period of October first\nthrough September thirtieth, and shall include the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the average length of time for families on the waiting list;\n  (ii) the number of families on the waiting list for each of the\nfollowing time periods:\n  (A) less than two weeks,\n  (B) two weeks to less than a month,\n  (C) one month to less than three months,\n  (D) three months to less than six months,\n  (E) six months to less than a year, and\n  (F) one year or more;\n  (iii) the average age of children represented on the waiting list;\n  (iv) the number of children represented on the waiting list eligible\nfor each:\n  (A) infant,\n  (B) toddler,\n  (C) pre-school, and\n  (D) school-aged subsidized child care slots; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of existing infant, toddler, pre-school and school-aged\nsubsidized child care slots;\n  (vi) the number of families who would receive child care assistance\nexcept that they are waiting for available slots in a particular child\ncare program; and\n  (vii) other information as the district deems appropriate.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each social services district shall collect data regarding the\nincome of families who applied for child care assistance pursuant to\nthis title, specifying:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of families who were denied;\n  (ii) the number of families who received such assistance; and\n  (iii) a listing of the incomes pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision of the families who applied for such assistance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each district shall issue a report to the office of children and\nfamily services by October fifteenth, two thousand twenty-seven, and\nannually thereafter, detailing month-to-month information collected\npursuant to this subdivision for the preceding period of October first\nthrough September thirtieth, and shall include the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of all families who applied for and received child care\nassistance pursuant to this title whose:\n  (A) incomes were under fifty percent of the state median income level\nfor their family size,\n  (B) incomes were between fifty percent and seventy-five percent of the\nstate median income level for their family size, and\n  (C) incomes were between seventy-five and eighty-five percent of the\nstate median income level for their family size; and\n  (ii) the number of all families who applied for and were denied child\ncare assistance pursuant to this title whose:\n  (A) incomes were under fifty percent of the state median income level\nfor their family size,\n  (B) incomes were between fifty percent and seventy-five percent of the\nstate median income level for their family size, and\n  (C) incomes were between seventy-five percent and eighty-five percent\nof the state median income level for their family size.\n  4. The office of children and family services shall compile such\nreports pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two, and paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision three of this section, into one comprehensive report\ncontaining all required information on a county by county basis. Such\nreport shall be provided to the governor, the speaker of the assembly,\nthe temporary president of the senate, the chairperson of the assembly\ncommittee on children and families, the chairperson of the senate\ncommittee on children and families, the chairperson of the assembly\ncommittee on social services, the chairperson of the senate committee on\nsocial services, the chairperson of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee and the chairperson of the senate finance committee no later\nthan December first, two thousand twenty-seven, and annually thereafter.\n  5. Reports issued and compiled under this section shall not use the\nname, address, or any other identifying information of an individual who\nis the subject of the report and shall ensure the anonymity of those\nincluded in the reports.\n  * NB Effective October 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>