<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_C">
        <num>410-C</num>
        <heading>State reimbursement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Expenditures made by counties,\ncities, and towns for day care and its administration, and day care\ncenter projects, pursuant to the provisions of this title, shall, if\napproved by the department, be subject to reimbursement by the state, in\naccordance with the regulations of the department, as follows: There\nshall be paid to each county, city or town</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_410_C__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount of federal\nfunds, if any, properly received or to be received on account of such\nexpenditures;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_410_C__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fifty per centum of its expenditures for day care and\nits administration and day care center projects, after first deducting\ntherefrom any federal funds received or to be received on account\nthereof, and any expenditures defrayed by fees paid by parents or by\nother private contributions.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purpose of this title, expenditures for administration of\nday care shall include expenditures for compensation of employees in\nconnection with the furnishing of day care, including but not limited to\ncosts incurred for pensions, federal old age and survivors insurance and\nhealth insurance for such employees; training programs for personnel,\noperation, maintenance and service costs; and such other expenditures\nsuch as equipment costs, depreciation and charges and rental values as\nmay be approved by the department. It shall not include expenditures for\ncapital costs. In the case of day care purchased from a non-profit\ncorporation constituting an eligible borrower pursuant to title five-a\nof this article, expenditures shall include an allocable proportion of\nall operating costs of such facility as may be approved by the\ndepartment including but not limited to the expenditures enumerated in\nthis paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and expenditures for amortization, interest and other\nfinancing costs of any mortgage loan made to such non-profit\ncorporation.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Claims for state reimbursement shall be made in such form and\nmanner and at such times and for such periods as the department shall\ndetermine.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When certified by the department, state reimbursement shall be\npaid from the state treasury upon the audit and warrant of the\ncomptroller out of funds made available therefor.\n  3. The department is authorized in its discretion to approve and\ncertify to the comptroller for payment, advances to counties, cities or\ntowns in anticipation of the state reimbursement provided for in this\nsection.\n  4. Payment of state reimbursement and advances shall be made to local\nfiscal officers as in the case of state reimbursement for public\nassistance and care under other provisions of this chapter.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this subdivision "school age child day care\nprograms" shall mean programs which offer care to school age children\nunder the age of fourteen before or after the period when these children\nare in school. Such programs may include, but are not limited to,\nprograms provided in school buildings in accordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision one of section four hundred fourteen of the education\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall, within appropriations made available\ntherefor, select proposed school age child day care programs which shall\nbe eligible to receive an award of no more than twenty-five thousand\ndollars for start up or expansion costs, including planning, rental,\noperational and equipment costs, or minor renovations identified as\nbeing necessary in order for the program to comply with applicable state\nor local building, fire safety or licensing standards, based on plans\nsubmitted to him. The commissioner shall give preference to those areas\nof the state which are significantly underserved by existing school age\nchild day care programs and to those programs which involve parents in\nthe development and implementation of programs. The commissioner shall\npublicize this availability of funds to be used for purposes of this\nsubdivision in awarding grants. Plans may be submitted by private\nnot-for-profit corporations, organizations or governmental subdivisions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, social services\ndistricts shall be authorized to purchase services which are to be\nprovided pursuant to this subdivision from programs which have been\napproved by the commissioner to receive funds pursuant to this\nsubdivision.\n  6. Any other provision of law notwithstanding, and within amounts\nappropriated therefor, the department shall have authority to make\nstart-up grants to prospective programs that will provide child day\ncare, as such term is defined in section three hundred ninety of this\narticle, from any funds available for such purpose.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>