<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410">
        <num>410</num>
        <heading>Day care; when public welfare official to furnish</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Day care under this title shall mean care in a group facility,\nin a family home, in a group family day care home or in a day care\ncenter project as defined in title five-a of this article for part of\nthe day.  Day care may be provided by a social services official either\ndirectly or through purchase. Purchase of such care may be made only\nfrom a private non-profit corporation or association except when the\ncommissioner shall have approved the purchase of such care from private\nproprietary facilities by a social services official who has\ndemonstrated that conveniently accessible non-profit facilities are\ninadequate to provide required care. Purchase of such care may also be\nmade from a school district in accordance with state and federal\nrequirements pursuant to a contract between the social services district\nand the school district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Care under this title may be provided only in group facilities,\nfamily homes, group family day care homes or in a day care center\nproject as defined in title five-a which are operated in compliance with\napplicable regulations of the office of children and family services. A\ngroup facility shall include a public school which provides day care\npursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as hereinafter provided, care under this title shall not\ninclude care, supervision, training or participation in kindergartens,\nnursery schools or other schools, classes or activities operated or\nconducted by public or private schools. However such care shall include\nday care provided by a school district pursuant to the provisions of\nthis subdivision and subdivision thirty-three of section sixteen hundred\nfour of the education law in accordance with a contract entered into\nbetween such school district and a social services district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall encourage social services districts and day\ncare providers to offer flexible hours of day care. Each provider may\nprovide a flexible schedule in accordance with the rules and regulations\nof the commissioner and an application for day care services shall not\nbe denied solely by reason of the time of day or days that care will be\nrequired provided that an available day care provider can accommodate\nsuch hours or days of care in accordance with such regulations.\n  4. The provisions of this title shall not apply to child care\nassistance provided under title five-C of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>