<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-424-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-424-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="424-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-424-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-424-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-424-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-424-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_424_B">
        <num>424-B</num>
        <heading>Children in the care of certain public and private agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 424-b. Children in the care of certain public and private agencies.\nNotwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of law, when a report of\nchild abuse or maltreatment involves a child being cared for in a home\noperated or supervised by an authorized agency or the office of children\nand family services, such report shall be accepted and maintained by the\noffice of children and family services and shall be referred for the\npurposes of conducting an investigation to the appropriate staff within\nthe office of children and family services where the child is in the\ncare of such agency; and where the child is in a home operated or\nsupervised by an authorized agency, to the social services district\nwherein such home is located. The office or social services district\nreceiving such referral shall undertake an appropriate investigation of\nthe report, in accordance with the terms and conditions set forth in\nthis title. Any person who is alleged to have abused or maltreated a\nchild in a report accepted and referred pursuant to this section shall\nbe accorded the procedural rights set forth in section four hundred\ntwenty-two and in subdivision six of section four hundred twenty-four of\nthis title. Nothing in this section shall impose any duty or\nresponsibility on any child protective service pursuant to section four\nhundred twenty-two, four hundred twenty-four or any other provision of\nthis article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>