<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="45-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_A">
        <num>45-A</num>
        <heading>Single room occupancy support services program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 45-a.  Single room occupancy support services program.  There is\nhereby established under the administration of the commissioner a single\nroom occupancy support services program, to provide financial\nassistance, subject to limitations stated in appropriations therefor, in\nthe form of grants, to eligible applicants for eligible costs of\nservices to assist eligible residents of single room occupancy units to\nlive independently.  The commissioner, subject to the approval of the\ndirector of the budget and within amounts appropriated therefor, shall\nrequest proposals from local social services districts for funds to\nsupport grants made pursuant to this title.  Copies of such requests for\nproposals shall be simultaneously distributed to eligible applicants\nknown to the commissioner and the availability of such proposals shall\nbe publicized by the department. Local social services districts will be\nchosen competitively based upon such proposals for funding. Criteria to\nbe used by the commissioner in awarding funding among local social\nservices districts shall include but not be limited to the anticipated\nneed for single room occupancy units within each district; the ability\nof the local social services district to properly supervise the single\nroom occupancy support services program; and the appropriateness of the\nsupport services for the population to be served.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>