<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-459-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-459-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="459-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-459-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-459-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-459-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-459-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_459_C">
        <num>459-C</num>
        <heading>Non-residential services for victims of domestic violence</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 459-c. Non-residential services for victims of domestic violence. 1.\nIn accordance with the provisions of this section and the regulations of\nthe department, a social services district shall offer and provide\nnon-residential services including but not limited to, information and\nreferral services, advocacy, counseling, community education and\noutreach activities, and hotline services, to a victim of domestic\nviolence whether or not the victim is eligible for public assistance. A\nsocial services district may provide such non-residential services\ndirectly or may purchase such services from a not-for-profit\norganization operating a residential program and/or a non-residential\nprogram for victims of domestic violence.\n  2. To the extent that funds are appropriated expressly therefore and a\nsocial services district has exhausted its allocation under title XX of\nthe federal social security act, state reimbursement shall be available\nfor fifty percent of the expenditures made by a social services district\nfor those non-residential services provided to victims of domestic\nviolence which are included in the social services district's multi-year\nconsolidated services plans and annual implementation reports approved\nby the department pursuant to section thirty-four-a of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>