<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="462-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_462_A">
        <num>462-A</num>
        <heading>Responsibility for inspection and supervision</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 462-a. Responsibility for inspection and supervision. 1. The office\nof children and family services shall inspect and supervise secure and\nnon-secure detention facilities and those office of children and family\nservices residential facilities authorized by article nineteen-G of the\nexecutive law and those residential facilities operated as approved\nrunaway programs or transitional independent living support programs\npursuant to article nineteen-H of the executive law.\n  2. The appropriate offices of the state department of mental hygiene\nshall inspect and supervise those facilities subject to articles\nthirty-one and thirty-two of the mental hygiene law.\n  3. For those facilities which care for a significant number of\nmentally disabled children, the department shall enter into written\ncooperative agreements no later than October first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-seven with the department of mental hygiene for joint inspection\nand supervision of such facilities, as appropriate.\n  4. The office of children and family services shall inspect and\nsupervise all other child care facilities subject to its regulation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>