<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="462-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-462-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_462_B">
        <num>462-B</num>
        <heading>Responsibility for enforcement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 462-b. Responsibility for enforcement. 1. The office of children and\nfamily services shall exercise the enforcement powers enumerated in\nsection four hundred sixty-d of this article which may apply to secure\nand non-secure detention facilities and to those office of children and\nfamily services residential facilities authorized by article nineteen-G\nof the executive law and those residential facilities operated as\napproved runaway programs or transitional independent living support\nprograms pursuant to article nineteen-H of the executive law.\n  2. The appropriate offices of the state department of mental hygiene\nshall exercise the enforcement powers enumerated in section four hundred\nsixty-d of this article which may apply to those facilities subject to\narticles thirty-one and thirty-two of the mental hygiene law.\n  3. With respect to facilities which care for a significant number of\nmentally disabled children, the department shall enter into written\ncooperative agreements no later than October first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-seven with the department of mental hygiene establishing\ncircumstances under which the department will at the request of the\ndepartment of mental hygiene act to limit or modify the operating\ncertificate of any facility so as to preclude such facility from\naccepting, caring for or continuing to care for mentally disabled\nchildren.\n  4. The office of children and family services shall exercise the\nenforcement powers enumerated in section four hundred sixty-d of this\narticle with respect to all other child caring facilities subject to its\nregulation either independently or at the request of the department of\nmental hygiene.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>