<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-476"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-476"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="476"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-476/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-476/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-476/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-476/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_476">
        <num>476</num>
        <heading>Verified accounts against counties, cities and towns</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 476.  Verified accounts against counties, cities and towns. 1.  The\nofficers mentioned in the last section shall annually, on or before the\nfifteenth day of October, present to the clerk of the board of\nsupervisors of the county, or of the county in which such town is\nsituated, or to the city clerk of a city from which any such person is\ncommitted or appointed, a verified report and statement of the account\nof such institution with such county, town or city, up to the first day\nof October, and in case of a claim for clothing, an itemized statement\nof the same; and if a part of the board, care, tuition or clothing has\nbeen paid by any person or persons, the account shall show what sum has\nbeen so paid; and the report shall show the name, age, sex, nationality\nand residence of each person mentioned in the account, the name of the\nofficer who made the appointment or commitment, and the date and length\nof the same, and the time to which the account has been paid, and the\namount claimed to such first day of October, the sum per week or per\nannum charged, and if no part of such account has been paid, the report\nshall show such fact.\n  2.  Any officer who shall refuse or neglect to make such report shall\nnot be entitled to receive any compensation or pay for any services,\nsalary or otherwise, from any town, city or county affected thereby.\n  3.  The clerk of the board of supervisors who shall receive any such\nreport or account shall file and present the same to the board of\nsupervisors of his county on the second day of the annual meeting of the\nboard next after the receipt of the same.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>