<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="481-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_481_D">
        <num>481-D</num>
        <heading>William B</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 481-d. William B. Hoyt Memorial children and family trust fund\nadvisory board. 1. There is hereby established in the department, a\nWilliam B. Hoyt Memorial children and family trust fund advisory board.\nThe board shall meet regularly for the purpose of advising and making\nrecommendations to the department in developing program standards\nrelating to the establishment of family violence, including\nintergenerational family violence, prevention and service programs,\ndeveloping requests for proposals and evaluating the effectiveness of\nfunded programs. The members of the board shall receive no compensation\nfor their services, but shall be reimbursed for their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred during the performance of their duties.\n  2. The board shall consist of thirteen members to be appointed by the\ngovernor, two of whom shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the\nspeaker of the assembly, one of whom shall be appointed upon the\nrecommendation of the minority leader of the assembly, two of whom shall\nbe appointed upon the recommendation of the temporary president of the\nsenate, and one of whom shall be appointed upon the recommendation of\nthe minority leader of the senate. Members of the board shall be\nappointed for a term of three years. The governor shall designate one\nmember to serve as chairman of the board. To the maximum extent possible\nmembers shall be chosen to represent equally those knowledgeable in,\nconcerned with or committed to the field of domestic violence and/or\nchild abuse. Members of the board may be chosen from groups including\nbut not limited to: local social services districts; local youth boards\nor youth bureaus; child abuse and neglect task forces; statewide\ncoalitions against domestic violence; alcoholism services; public\nagencies, not-for-profit corporations and educational institutions\nconcerned with or providing professional training in family violence and\nchild welfare services; family violence self-help and advocacy groups;\nthe legal, social work, mental health, medical, clergy, judicial and law\nenforcement professions; groups dealing with services to the abused\nelderly; other professionals that provide family violence services and\nother concerned individuals or organizations, including parents or\nguardians of children who were or are in receipt of services funded\npursuant to this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>