<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-66"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-66"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="66"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-66/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-66/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-66/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-66/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_66">
        <num>66</num>
        <heading>County appointments and bonds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 66.  County appointments and bonds.  1.  The legislative body of the\ncounty may authorize the appointment of any number of deputy\ncommissioners of social services, physicians to care for sick persons in\ntheir homes, other assistants and employees, including attorneys to\nperform duties it considers necessary to carry out the provisions of\nthis chapter.  However, such legislative body may also authorize that\nsuch attorneys, in addition to performing the duties assigned to them by\nthe county commissioner, may be deputized by the county attorney to\nperform duties on his behalf in connection with the work of the social\nservices department.\n  2.  The county commissioner shall appoint deputy commissioners,\nphysicians, assistants and employees so authorized and direct their\nwork.\n  3.  Each county commissioner and deputy commissioner shall be required\nto give bond before entering upon his duties.  The board of supervisors\nshall fix the amount of such bond and may require and fix the amount of\nbond to be given by any other assistant or employee whose appointment is\nauthorized.  The expense of any bond required in connection with the\nwork of a county public welfare official or employee shall be paid from\ncounty public welfare funds.\n  4.  In accordance with federal and state regulations each county\nsocial services commissioner shall appoint a citizens advisory committee\nor committees to exercise and perform such functions, powers, and duties\nas the regulations of the department may require.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>