<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-67"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-67"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="67"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-67/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-67/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-67/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-67/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_67">
        <num>67</num>
        <heading>Town public welfare officers; appointment of staff</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 67.  Town public welfare officers; appointment of staff.  1. The\ntown board of each town responsible for the expense of providing safety\nnet assistance for persons residing or found in such town shall appoint\na social services  official or authorize a supervisor of the town to act\nas  such official. It may in its discretion appoint an assistant town\nsocial services official and other employees to assist the town social\nservices official in carrying out his or her duties. The town social\nservices official, his or her assistant and other employees shall hold\noffice during the pleasure of the town board. The town board shall fix\nthe salary to be paid a town social services official, his or her\nassistant or other employees or fix the amount per hour to be paid them\nwhen they are performing any duty connected with their office.\n  2.  The town public welfare officer shall be responsible for the\nauthorization of the assistance and care for which the town is\nresponsible and shall assist the county commissioner in the\nadministration of assistance and care to persons residing or found in\nhis town for whose care the county public welfare district is\nresponsible.  Except as otherwise agreed and arranged by and between the\ncounty commissioner and the town public welfare officer, the town public\nwelfare officer shall receive all applications for public assistance and\ncare made in his town by residents of such town, and he shall forward\neach such application to the county commissioner immediately after the\nreceipt of the same.  He shall have all the powers and perform all the\nduties of a public welfare official applicable to the work hereby\nassigned.\n  3.  In case of emergency and until it is possible for the county\ncommissioner either to take charge of the case or to make a complete\ninvestigation, the town public welfare officer may grant such temporary\nassistance and care as may be necessary.  All such grants made by the\ntown public welfare officer shall be made in accordance with the rules\nand regulations of the department and the regulations established by the\ncounty commissioner of public welfare.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>