<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-69"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-69"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="69"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-69/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-69/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-69/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-69/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_69">
        <num>69</num>
        <heading>Responsibility for public assistance and care in a county social services district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 69. Responsibility for public assistance and care in a county social\nservices district. The responsibility for the  administration of public\nassistance and care in a county social services district and the expense\nthereof may either be  borne by the county social services district or\nbe divided between such district and the towns and cities therein as\nhereinafter provided.\n  1. Unless otherwise determined by the board of supervisors as\nhereinafter provided, each town shall be responsible for the expense of\nproviding safety net assistance for persons residing or found in such\ntown.\n  2. Unless otherwise determined by the board of supervisors as\nhereinafter provided, a city forming a part of a county social services\ndistrict shall be responsible for the expense of  providing safety net\nassistance for any person residing or found in its territory.\n  3. A county social services district shall be responsible for the\nexpense of providing all assistance and care for persons residing or\nfound in a town or city in its territory for which such town or city is\nnot responsible under the provisions of subdivisions one and two of this\nsection.  The expense of such assistance and care granted by a county\nsocial services district shall be subject to reimbursement by the state\nin the cases provided for by section sixty-two or by any other provision\nof this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>