<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-73"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-73"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="73"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-73/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-73/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-73/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-73/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_73">
        <num>73</num>
        <heading>Power of the board of supervisors to change the administrative system of the county social services district</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such resolution shall not take effect in a city in a county\nsocial services district unless it is confirmed by act of the\nlegislative body of the city in accordance with the provisions of this\nparagraph.  The legislative body of such a city may confirm the\nresolution of the board of supervisors</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_73__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or before the first day of\nOctober in the year in which such resolution was adopted by the board of\nsupervisors, and make such confirmation effective on the first day of\nJanuary next succeding such confirmation, provided the resolution of the\nboard of supervisors takes effect in the towns of the county on or\nbefore such first day of January, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_73__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>at any other time or date, and\nmake such confirmation effective on any date not earlier than the date\nthe resolution of the board of supervisors takes effect in the towns of\nthe county, provided the board of supervisors shall by resolution\nspecifically approve such confirmation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On the day after a city confirms a resolution of the board of\nsupervisors pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, the mayor or the city clerk shall\nsend a written notice of such confirmation to the clerk of the board of\nsupervisors of the county.  He shall also send a copy of such notice to\nthe county commissioner of social services and the county commissioner\nshall thereupon notify the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a city in the county social services district shall confirm\nthe resolution of the board of supervisors in accordance with the\nprovisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, the county social services district shall,\non and after the effective date of such confirmation be responsible for\nadministration of public assistance and care in such city, and\nthereafter all provisions of this chapter as to the powers and duties of\na city in a county social services district and of city social services\nofficers shall be inoperative in such city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless and until a city in the county social services district\nshall confirm the resolution of the board of supervisors in accordance\nwith the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, the responsibility of such city\nfor assistance and care in its territory shall not be affected by such\nresolution, and the city shall be governed by the provisions of this\nchapter and other laws relating to cities which form part of a county\nsocial services district and to city social services officers; and the\ncity shall continue to be responsible for the cost of public assistance\nand care under the provisions of subdivision two of section sixty-nine,\nexcept as otherwise provided in title three-a of this article.  The cost\nof any assistance and care given to local charges residing or found in\nsuch city, paid by the county social services district under the\nprovisions of subdivision three of section sixty-nine, shall be a charge\non the county social services district.\n  3.  The board of supervisors shall make such additional appropriations\nand authorize the appointment of such number of deputy commissioners,\nother assistants and employees as it may deem necessary to provide\nadequate administration of the public assistance and care for which the\ncounty social services district is made responsible under the provisions\nof this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>