<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-74-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-74-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="74-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-74-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-74-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-74-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-74-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_74_A">
        <num>74-A</num>
        <heading>Administration of assistance by county for city; reimbursements and advances; cost to county to be raised by tax on taxable property of c...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 74-a.  Administration of assistance by county for city;\nreimbursements and advances; cost to county to be raised by tax on\ntaxable property of city and to be included in county tax levy.  1.  The\ncounty shall administer in and for the city the public assistance and\ncare for the administration of which the city is responsible and shall\nbe entitled to all reimbursements and advances against reimbursements on\naccount of the assistance and care so administered to which the city\nwould otherwise be entitled and which would otherwise be payable to the\ncity in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.\n  2.  The cost to the county of all assistance and care thus\nadministered by the county in and for the city shall be a charge against\nand be levied as a tax upon the taxable property of the city and the\namount to be so raised by tax shall be included by the county in its\nnext ensuing tax levy.\n  3.  This section is applicable only to those cities described in\nsubdivision one of section seventy-four of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>