<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-81"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-81"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="81"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_81">
        <num>81</num>
        <heading>Reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such\nreports and furnish such information to the department with respect to\nthe work of the county social services district as is required by this\nchapter and the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An annual report to the board of supervisors concerning the work\nof the county social services district and additional reports at such\ntimes and covering such facts as the board of supervisors may require.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any of the cost of assistance and care paid for by the county\nsocial services district is charged back to the towns and cities\nthereof, a report to the county treasurer at the end of the fiscal year,\nstating the per capita maintenance cost per day in the county home and\nan itemized statement of the amount to be charged each town and city for\nthe assistance and care given either in the county home or elsewhere to\npersons residing or found in each town or city and a statement of all\nexpenditures and receipts in behalf of such persons.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Current reports to the city and town social services officers of\npersons residing in their cities and towns who are in receipt of public\nassistance and care from the county.\n  2.  A town social services officer shall make:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An annual report to the town board concerning his work and\nadditional reports at such times and covering such facts as the town\nboard may require.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An annual report to the county commissioner and any additional\nreports at such time and covering such facts as may be required by the\ncounty commissioner or the department.\n  3.  A city commissioner of social services shall make:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such reports to the department with respect to his work as are\nrequired by this chapter and the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An annual report to the mayor of the city or to any other\nofficial or board authorized to receive such report and additional\nreports at such times and covering such facts as may be required.\n  4.  Such annual reports shall include an itemized statement of all\nmoney received by the social services official and all money expended by\nhim, and a detailed statement in regard to the recipients of public\nassistance and care.  Town and city social services officers shall\nfurnish the county commissioner with all data, relating to their work\nand persons in receipt of public assistance and care, necessary to\nenable the county commissioner to make the reports required by the\ndepartment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>