<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-92"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-92"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="92"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-92/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-92/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-92/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-92/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_92">
        <num>92</num>
        <heading>Deficiency appropriations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_92__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Should the sums\nappropriated for medical assistance for needy persons, family\nassistance, or care and protection of children pursuant to article six\nof this chapter and their administration be expended or contracted or\nbecome exhausted during the year for the purposes for which they were\nappropriated, or should no appropriation have been made, additional sums\nshall be appropriated by the proper appropriating bodies, as occasion\ndemands, to carry out the provisions of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_92__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In cities such additional sums if appropriated shall be paid from\nunexpended balances not required by law to be expended for a specific\npurpose, or from contingent funds when such exist.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_92__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In counties, such additional appropriations shall be paid from\nfunds in the county treasury available therefor, provided that such\nfunds were raised by taxes levied in a territory identical with that in\nwhich such sums may be expended, and then only to the extent of any\nexcess thereof not needed for other purposes under other provisions of\nthis chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_92__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing contained in this section, however, shall be construed to\nprevent the financing of such deficiency appropriations pursuant to the\nlocal finance law.\n  2.  All the provisions of subdivision one in regard to cities shall be\napplicable to towns in Dutchess county, and, in every city or town\nthereof, except in the city of Poughkeepsie, the amount of such\nadditional sums must first be approved by the county commissioner of\npublic welfare by writing filed with the city or town clerk.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>