<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.14"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.14"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="120.14"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_120_14">
        <num>120.14</num>
        <heading>Menacing in the second degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 120.14 Menacing in the second degree.\n  A person is guilty of menacing in the second degree when:\n  1. He or she intentionally places or attempts to place another person\nin reasonable fear of physical injury, serious physical injury or death\nby displaying a deadly weapon, dangerous instrument or what appears to\nbe a pistol, revolver, rifle, shotgun, machine gun or other firearm; or\n  2. He or she repeatedly follows a person or engages in a course of\nconduct or repeatedly commits acts over a period of time intentionally\nplacing or attempting to place another person in reasonable fear of\nphysical injury, serious physical injury or death; or\n  3. He or she commits the crime of menacing in the third degree in\nviolation of that part of a duly served order of protection, or such\norder which the defendant has actual knowledge of because he or she was\npresent in court when such order was issued, pursuant to article eight\nof the family court act, section 530.12 of the criminal procedure law,\nor an order of protection issued by a court of competent jurisdiction in\nanother state, territorial or tribal jurisdiction, which directed the\nrespondent or defendant to stay away from the person or persons on whose\nbehalf the order was issued.\n  Menacing in the second degree is a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>