<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.70"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.70"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-11-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="120.70"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.70/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.70/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.70/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-120.70/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_120_70">
        <num>120.70</num>
        <heading>Luring a child</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 120.70 Luring a child.\n  1. A person is guilty of luring a child when he or she lures a child\ninto a motor vehicle, aircraft, watercraft, isolated area, building, or\npart thereof, for the purpose of committing against such child any of\nthe following offenses: an offense as defined in section 70.02 of this\nchapter; an offense as defined in section 125.25 or 125.27 of this\nchapter; a felony offense that is a violation of article one hundred\nthirty of this chapter; an offense as defined in section 135.25 of this\nchapter; an offense as defined in sections 230.30, 230.33, 230.34 or\n230.34-a of this chapter; an offense as defined in sections 255.25,\n255.26, or 255.27 of this chapter; or an offense as defined in sections\n263.05, 263.10, or 263.15 of this chapter. For purposes of this\nsubdivision "child" means a person less than seventeen years of age.\nNothing in this section shall be deemed to preclude, if the evidence\nwarrants, a conviction for the commission or attempted commission of any\ncrime, including but not limited to a crime defined in article one\nhundred thirty-five of this chapter.\n  2. Luring a child is a class E felony, provided, however, that if the\nunderlying offense the actor intended to commit against such child\nconstituted a class A or a class B felony, then the offense of luring a\nchild in violation of this section shall be deemed respectively, a class\nC felony or class D felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>