<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-135.60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-135.60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="135.60"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-135.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-135.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-135.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-135.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_135_60">
        <num>135.60</num>
        <heading>Coercion in the third degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 135.60 Coercion in the third degree.\n  A person is guilty of coercion in the third degree when he or she\ncompels or induces a person to engage in conduct which the latter has a\nlegal right to abstain from engaging in, or to abstain from engaging in\nconduct in which he or she has a legal right to engage, or compels or\ninduces a person to join a group, organization or criminal enterprise\nwhich such latter person has a right to abstain from joining, or compels\nor induces a person to produce, disseminate, or otherwise display an\nimage or images depicting nudity of such person or depicting such person\nengaged in sexual conduct as defined in subdivisions two and three of\nsection 235.20 of this chapter, by means of instilling in him or her a\nfear that, if the demand is not complied with, the actor or another\nwill:\n  1. Cause physical injury to a person; or\n  2. Cause damage to property; or\n  3. Engage in other conduct constituting a crime; or\n  4. Accuse some person of a crime or cause criminal charges to be\ninstituted against him or her; or\n  5. Expose a secret or publicize an asserted fact, whether true or\nfalse, tending to subject some person to hatred, contempt or ridicule;\nor\n  6. Cause a strike, boycott or other collective labor group action\ninjurious to some person's business; except that such a threat shall not\nbe deemed coercive when the act or omission compelled is for the benefit\nof the group in whose interest the actor purports to act; or\n  7. Testify or provide information or withhold testimony or information\nwith respect to another's legal claim or defense; or\n  8. Use or abuse his or her position as a public servant by performing\nsome act within or related to his or her official duties, or by failing\nor refusing to perform an official duty, in such manner as to affect\nsome person adversely; or\n  9. Perform any other act which would not in itself materially benefit\nthe actor but which is calculated to harm another person materially with\nrespect to his or her health, safety, business, calling, career,\nfinancial condition, reputation or personal relationships.\n  10. Report his or her immigration status or suspected immigration\nstatus.\n  Coercion in the third degree is a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>