<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-140.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-140.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="140.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-140.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-140.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-140.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-140.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_140_15">
        <num>140.15</num>
        <heading>Criminal trespass in the second degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 140.15 Criminal trespass in the second degree.\n  A person is guilty of criminal trespass in the second degree when:\n  1. he or she knowingly enters or remains unlawfully in a dwelling; or\n  2. being a person required to maintain registration under article\nsix-C of the correction law and designated a level two or level three\noffender pursuant to subdivision six of section one hundred\nsixty-eight-l of the correction law, he or she enters or remains in a\npublic or private elementary, parochial, intermediate, junior high,\nvocational or high school knowing that the victim of the offense for\nwhich such registration is required attends or formerly attended such\nschool. It shall not be an offense subject to prosecution under this\nsubdivision if: the person is a lawfully registered student at such\nschool; the person is a lawful student participant in a school sponsored\nevent; the person is a parent or a legal guardian of a lawfully\nregistered student at such school and enters the school for the purpose\nof attending their child's or dependent's event or activity; such school\nis the person's designated polling place and he or she enters such\nschool building for the limited purpose of voting; or if the person\nenters such school building for the limited purposes authorized by the\nsuperintendent or chief administrator of such school.\n  Criminal trespass in the second degree is a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>