<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-145.50"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-145.50"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="145.50"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-145.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-145.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-145.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-145.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_145_50">
        <num>145.50</num>
        <heading>Penalties for littering on railroad tracks and rights-of-way</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 145.50 Penalties for littering on railroad tracks and rights-of-way.\n  1. No person shall throw, dump, or cause to be thrown, dumped,\ndeposited or placed upon any railroad tracks, or within the limits of\nthe rights-of-way of any railroad, any refuse, trash, garbage, rubbish,\nlitter or any nauseous or offensive matter.\n  2. Where a highway or road lies in whole or part within a railroad\nrights-of-way, nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting\nthe use in a reasonable manner of ashes, sand, salt or other material\nfor the purpose of reducing the hazard of, or providing traction on\nsnow, ice or sleet situated on such highway or road.\n  3. A violation of the provisions of subdivision one of this section\nshall be punishable by a fine not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars\nand/or a requirement to perform services for a public or not-for-profit\ncorporation, association, institution or agency not to exceed eight\nhours and for any second or subsequent violation by a fine not to exceed\nfive hundred dollars and/or a requirement to perform services for a\npublic or not-for-profit corporation, association, institution or agency\nnot to exceed eight hours.\n  4. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to apply to a railroad or\nits employees when matter deposited by them on the railroad tracks or\nrights-of-way is done pursuant to railroad rules, regulations or\nprocedures.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>