<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-156.40"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-156.40"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156.40"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-156.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-156.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-156.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-156.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_40">
        <num>156.40</num>
        <heading>Operating an unlawful electronic sweepstakes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Electronic machine or device" means a mechanically, electrically\nor electronically operated machine or device that is owned, leased or\notherwise possessed by a sweepstakes sponsor or promoter, or any\nsponsors, promoters, partners, affiliates, subsidiaries or contractors\nthereof; that is intended to be used by a sweepstakes entrant; that uses\nenergy; and that displays the results of a game entry or game outcome to\na participant on a screen or other mechanism at a business location,\nincluding a private club; provided, that an electronic machine or device\nmay, without limitation:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>be server-based;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>use a simulated game terminal as a representation of the prizes\nassociated with the results of the sweepstakes entries;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>utilize software such that the simulated game influences or\ndetermines the winning or value of the prize;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>select prizes from a predetermined finite pool of entries;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>utilize a mechanism that reveals the content of a predetermined\nsweepstakes entry;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>predetermine the prize results and stores those results for\ndelivery at the time the sweepstakes entry results are revealed;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>utilize software to create a game result;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>require deposit of any money, coin or token, or the use of any\ncredit card, debit card, prepaid card or any other method of payment to\nactivate the electronic machine or device;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>require direct payment into the electronic machine or device, or\nremote activation of the electronic machine or device;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>require purchase of a related product having legitimate value;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>reveal the prize incrementally, even though it may not influence\nif a prize is awarded or the value of any prize awarded;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>determine and associate the prize with an entry or entries at the\ntime the sweepstakes is entered; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>be a slot machine or other form of electrical, mechanical, or\ncomputer game.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Enter" or "entry" means the act or process by which a person\nbecomes eligible to receive any prize offered in a sweepstakes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_40__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Entertaining display" means any visual information, capable of\nbeing seen by a sweepstakes entrant, that takes the form of actual game\nplay or simulated game play.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_40__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Prize" means any gift, award, gratuity, good, service, credit or\nanything else of value, which may be transferred to a person, whether\npossession of the prize is actually transferred, or placed on an account\nor other record as evidence of the intent to transfer the prize.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_40__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Sweepstakes" means any game, advertising scheme or plan, or other\npromotion, which, with or without payment of any consideration, a person\nmay enter to win or become eligible to receive any prize, the\ndetermination of which is based upon chance.\n  2. A person is guilty of operating an unlawful electronic sweepstakes\nwhen he or she knowingly possesses with the intent to operate, or place\ninto operation, an electronic machine or device to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conduct a sweepstakes through the use of an entertaining display,\nincluding the entry process or the reveal of a prize; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>promote a sweepstakes that is conducted through the use of an\nentertaining display, including the entry process or the reveal of a\nprize.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall be construed to make illegal any\nactivity which is lawfully conducted as the New York state lottery for\neducation as authorized by article thirty-four of the tax law;\npari-mutuel wagering on horse races as authorized by articles two,\nthree, four, five-A, and ten of the racing, pari-mutuel wagering and\nbreeding law; the game of bingo as authorized pursuant to article\nfourteen-H of the general municipal law; games of chance as authorized\npursuant to article nine-A of the general municipal law; gaming as\nauthorized by article thirteen of the racing, pari-mutuel wagering and\nbreeding law; or pursuant to the federal Indian Gaming Regulatory Act.\n  Operating an unlawful electronic sweepstakes is a class E felony.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>