<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.51"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.51"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="180.51"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_180_51">
        <num>180.51</num>
        <heading>Tampering with a sports contest in the first degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 180.51 Tampering with a sports contest in the first degree.\n  A person is guilty of tampering with a sports contest in the first\ndegree when, with intent to influence the outcome of a pari-mutuel horse\nrace:\n  1. He affects any equine animal involved in the conduct or operation\nof a pari-mutuel horse race by administering to the animal in any manner\nwhatsoever any controlled substance listed in section thirty-three\nhundred six of the public health law; or\n  2. He knowingly enters or furnishes to another person for entry or\nbrings into this state for entry into a pari-mutuel horse race, or rides\nor drives in any pari-mutuel horse race any running, trotting or pacing\nhorse, mare, gelding, colt or filly under an assumed name, or\ndeceptively out of its proper class, or that has been painted or\ndisguised or represented to be any other or different horse, mare,\ngelding, colt or filly from that which it actually is; or\n  3. He knowingly and falsely registers with the jockey club, United\nStates trotting association, American quarter horse association or\nnational steeplechase and hunt association a horse, mare, gelding, colt\nor filly previously registered under a different name; or\n  4. He agrees with one or more persons to enter such misrepresented or\ndrugged animal in a pari-mutuel horse race. A person shall not be\nconvicted of a violation of this subdivision unless an overt act is\nalleged and proved to have been committed by one of said persons in\nfurtherance of said agreement.\n  Tampering with a sports contest in the first degree is a class E\nfelony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>