<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.82"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.82"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190.82"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.82/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.82/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.82/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.82/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190_82">
        <num>190.82</num>
        <heading>Unlawful possession of personal identification information in the second degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 190.82 Unlawful possession of personal identification information in\n           the second degree.\n  A person is guilty of unlawful possession of personal identification\ninformation in the second degree when he or she knowingly possesses two\nhundred fifty or more items of personal identification information of\nthe following nature: a person's financial services account number or\ncode, savings account number or code, checking account number or code,\nbrokerage account number or code, credit card account number or code,\ndebit card number or code, automated teller machine number or code,\npersonal identification number, mother's maiden name, computer system\npassword, electronic signature or unique biometric data that is a\nfingerprint, voice print, retinal image or iris image of another person\nknowing such information is intended to be used in furtherance of the\ncommission of a crime defined in this chapter.\n  Unlawful possession of personal identification information in the\nsecond degree is a class E felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>