<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.25"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.25"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190.25"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190_25">
        <num>190.25</num>
        <heading>Criminal impersonation in the second degree</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_190_25__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pretends to be a public servant, or wears or displays without\nauthority any uniform, badge, insignia or facsimile thereof by which\nsuch public servant is lawfully distinguished, or falsely expresses by\nhis words or actions that he is a public servant or is acting with\napproval or authority of a public agency or department; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_190_25__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>so acts\nwith intent to induce another to submit to such pretended official\nauthority, to solicit funds or to otherwise cause another to act in\nreliance upon that pretense; or\n  4. Impersonates another by communication by internet website or\nelectronic means with intent to obtain a benefit or injure or defraud\nanother, or by such communication pretends to be a public servant in\norder to induce another to submit to such authority or act in reliance\non such pretense; or\n  5. Impersonates another person, without such other person's\npermission, by using the other person's electronic signature with intent\nto obtain a benefit or injure or defraud the other person or another\nperson. For the purposes of this subdivision, electronic signature shall\nhave the same meaning as set forth in subdivision three of section three\nhundred two of the state technology law.\n  Criminal impersonation in the second degree is a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>