<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.77"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.77"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-03-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190.77"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.77/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.77/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.77/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.77/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190_77">
        <num>190.77</num>
        <heading>Offenses involving theft of identity; definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 190.77 Offenses involving theft of identity; definitions.\n  1. For the purposes of sections 190.78, 190.79, 190.80, 190.80-a and\n190.85 of this article "personal identifying information" means a\nperson's name, address, telephone number, date of birth, driver's\nlicense number, social security number, place of employment, mother's\nmaiden name, financial services account number or code, savings account\nnumber or code, checking account number or code, brokerage account\nnumber or code, credit card account number or code, debit card number or\ncode, automated teller machine number or code, taxpayer identification\nnumber, computer system password, signature or copy of a signature,\nelectronic signature, unique biometric data that is a fingerprint, voice\nprint, retinal image or iris image of another person, telephone calling\ncard number, mobile identification number or code, electronic serial\nnumber or personal identification number, medical information, health\ninsurance information, or any other name, number, code or information\nthat may be used alone or in conjunction with other such information to\nassume the identity of another person.\n  2. For the purposes of subdivision one of this section and sections\n190.78, 190.79, 190.80, 190.80-a, 190.81, 190.82, 190.83 and 190.85 of\nthis article:\n  a. "electronic signature" shall have the same meaning as defined in\nsubdivision three of section three hundred two of the state technology\nlaw.\n  b. "personal identification number" means any number or code which may\nbe used alone or in conjunction with any other information to assume the\nidentity of another person or access financial resources or credit of\nanother person.\n  c. "member of the armed forces" shall mean a person in the military\nservice of the United States or the military service of the state,\nincluding but not limited to, the armed forces of the United States, the\narmy national guard, the air national guard, the New York naval militia,\nthe New York guard, and such additional forces as may be created by the\nfederal or state government as authorized by law.\n  d. "medical information" means any information regarding an\nindividual's medical history, mental or physical condition, or medical\ntreatment or diagnosis by a health care professional.\n  e. "health insurance information" means an individual's health\ninsurance policy number or subscriber identification number, any unique\nidentifier used by a health insurer to identify the individual or any\ninformation in an individual's application and claims history,\nincluding, but not limited to, appeals history.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>