<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.26"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.26"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190.26"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.26/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.26/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.26/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-190.26/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190_26">
        <num>190.26</num>
        <heading>Criminal impersonation in the first degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 190.26 Criminal impersonation in the first degree.\n  A person is guilty of criminal impersonation in the first degree when\nhe:\n  1. Pretends to be a police officer or a federal law enforcement\nofficer as enumerated in section 2.15 of the criminal procedure law, or\nwears or displays without authority, any uniform, badge or other\ninsignia or facsimile thereof, by which such police officer or federal\nlaw enforcement officer is lawfully distinguished or expresses by his or\nher words or actions that he or she is acting with the approval or\nauthority of any police department or acting as a federal law\nenforcement officer with the approval of any agency that employs federal\nlaw enforcement officers as enumerated in section 2.15 of the criminal\nprocedure law; and\n  2. So acts with intent to induce another to submit to such pretended\nofficial authority or otherwise to act in reliance upon said pretense\nand in the course of such pretense commits or attempts to commit a\nfelony; or\n  3. Pretending to be a duly licensed physician or other person\nauthorized to issue a prescription for any drug or any instrument or\ndevice used in the taking or administering of drugs for which a\nprescription is required by law, communicates to a pharmacist an oral\nprescription which is required to be reduced to writing pursuant to\nsection thirty-three hundred thirty-two of the public health law.\n  Criminal impersonation in the first degree is a class E felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>