<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.16"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.16"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="215.16"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.16/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.16/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.16/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.16/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_215_16">
        <num>215.16</num>
        <heading>Intimidating a victim or witness in the second degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 215.16 Intimidating a victim or witness in the second degree.\n  A person is guilty of intimidating a victim or witness in the second\ndegree when, other than in the course of that criminal transaction or\nimmediate flight therefrom, he:\n  1. Intentionally causes physical injury to another person for the\npurpose of obstructing, delaying, preventing or impeding the\ncommunication by such other person or another person of information\nrelating to a criminal transaction to any court, grand jury, prosecutor,\npolice officer or peace officer or for the purpose of compelling such\nother person or another person to swear falsely; or\n  2. Intentionally causes physical injury to another person on account\nof such other person or another person having communicated information\nrelating to a criminal transaction to any court, grand jury, prosecutor,\npolice officer or peace officer; or\n  3. Recklessly causes physical injury to another person by\nintentionally damaging the property of such other person or another\nperson, for the purpose of obstructing, delaying, preventing or impeding\nsuch other person or another person from communicating, or on account of\nsuch other person or another person having communicated, information\nrelating to a criminal transaction to any court, grand jury, prosecutor,\npolice officer or peace officer.\n  Intimidating a victim or witness in the second degree is a class D\nfelony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>