<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.39"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.39"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220.39"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.39/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.39/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.39/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.39/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220_39">
        <num>220.39</num>
        <heading>Criminal sale of a controlled substance in the third degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 220.39 Criminal sale of a controlled substance in the third degree.\n  A person is guilty of criminal sale of a controlled substance in the\nthird degree when he knowingly and unlawfully sells:\n  1. a narcotic drug; or\n  2. a stimulant, hallucinogen, hallucinogenic substance, or lysergic\nacid diethylamide and has previously been convicted of an offense\ndefined in article two hundred twenty or the attempt or conspiracy to\ncommit any such offense; or\n  3. a stimulant and the stimulant weighs one gram or more; or\n  4. lysergic acid diethylamide and the lysergic acid diethylamide\nweighs one milligram or more; or\n  5. a hallucinogen and the hallucinogen weighs twenty-five milligrams\nor more; or\n  6. a hallucinogenic substance and the hallucinogenic substance weighs\none gram or more; or\n  7. one or more preparations, compounds, mixtures or substances\ncontaining methamphetamine, its salts, isomers or salts of isomers and\nthe preparations, compounds, mixtures or substances are of an aggregate\nweight of one-eighth ounce or more; or\n  8. phencyclidine and the phencyclidine weighs two hundred fifty\nmilligrams or more; or\n  9. a narcotic preparation to a person less than twenty-one years old.\n  Criminal sale of a controlled substance in the third degree is a class\nB felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>