<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-05-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225_00">
        <num>225.00</num>
        <heading>Gambling offenses; definitions of terms</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_225_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nplayers pay or agree to pay something of value for chances, represented\nand differentiated by numbers or by combinations of numbers or by some\nother media, one or more of which chances are to be designated the\nwinning ones; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_225_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the winning chances are to be determined by a\ndrawing or by some other method based upon the element of chance; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_225_00__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the holders of the winning chances are to receive something of value\nprovided, however, that in no event shall the provisions of this\nsubdivision be construed to include a raffle as such term is defined in\nsubdivision three-b of section one hundred eighty-six of the general\nmunicipal law.\n  11. "Policy" or "the numbers game" means a form of lottery in which\nthe winning chances or plays are not determined upon the basis of a\ndrawing or other act on the part of persons conducting or connected with\nthe scheme, but upon the basis of the outcome or outcomes of a future\ncontingent event or events otherwise unrelated to the particular scheme.\n  12. "Unlawful" means not specifically authorized by law.\n  13. "Authorized gaming establishment" means any structure, structure\nand adjacent or attached structure, or grounds adjacent to a structure\nin which casino gaming, conducted pursuant to article thirteen of the\nracing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law, or Class III gaming, as\nauthorized pursuant to a compact reached between the state of New York\nand a federally recognized Indian nation or tribe under the federal\nIndian Gaming Regulatory Act of 1988, is conducted and shall include all\npublic and non-public areas of any such building, except for such areas\nof a building where either Class I or II gaming are conducted or any\nbuilding or grounds known as a video gaming entertainment facility,\nincluding facilities where food and drink are served, as well as those\nareas not normally open to the public, such as where records related to\nvideo lottery gaming operations are kept, except shall not include the\nracetracks or such areas where such video lottery gaming operations or\nfacilities do not take place or exist, such as racetrack areas or\nfairgrounds which are wholly unrelated to video lottery gaming\noperations, pursuant to section sixteen hundred seventeen-a and\nparagraph five of subdivision a of section sixteen hundred twelve of the\ntax law, as a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_225_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any device, not prescribed for use in casinio gaming by its rules,\nwhich is capable of assisting a player:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_225_00__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to calculate any probabilities material to the outcome of a\ncontest of chance; or\n  (ii) to receive or transmit information material to the outcome of a\ncontest of chance; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_225_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any object or article which, by virtue of its size, shape or any\nother quality, is capable of being used in casino gaming as an improper\nsubstitute for a genuine chip, cheque, token, betting coupon, debit\ninstrument, voucher or other instrument or indicia of value; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_225_00__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any unfair gaming equipment.\n  28. "Video lottery gaming" has the meaning set forth in subdivision\nsix of section sixteen hundred two of the tax law.\n  29. "Voucher" means an instrument of value generated by a video\nlottery terminal representing a monetary amount and/or play value owed\nto a customer at a specific video lottery terminal based on video\nlottery gaming winnings and/or amounts not wagered.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>