<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-230.45"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-230.45"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="230.45"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-230.45/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-230.45/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-230.45/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-230.45/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_230_45">
        <num>230.45</num>
        <heading>Limited immunity from prosecution</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_230_45__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reports the crime to a criminal law enforcement\nagency,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_230_45__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if medically necessary, seeks or receives health care\nservices as a result of the crime, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_230_45__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>attempts to assist in the\ninvestigation or prosecution of the crime. No such victim or witness to\nthe crime shall be charged or prosecuted for an offense under section\n230.00 or 230.03 of this article which is alleged to have been committed\nat or in reasonable proximity to the time of the crime or under\ncircumstances reasonably related to the crime for which the person is a\nvictim or witness. As used in this section, "crime" shall include an act\nthat reasonably appears to be a crime, regardless of whether it results\nin a conviction as a crime.\n  2. Where a victim or witness to a crime believes that the conditions\nfor immunity pursuant to subdivision one of this section have been met\nand such victim or witness has been erroneously charged under section\n230.00 or 230.03 of this article, such victim or witness may request a\nhearing to be conducted no later than fifteen days after the charge or\ncharges have been filed to move the court to decide whether conditions\nfor immunity have been met. At such hearing, the court shall be\npermitted to accept all legally permitted evidence, including legally\npermissible hearsay, in support of both parties. If, after conducting\nsuch hearing, and by clear and convincing evidence, the court determines\nthat the conditions for immunity were met, then the charge or charges\nshall be dismissed. If, after conducting such hearing, the court\ndetermines that the conditions for immunity were not met, then the\ncharges shall not be dismissed and immunity shall be denied.\n  * NB Effective February 17, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>