<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-241.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-241.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-06-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="241.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-241.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-241.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-241.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-241.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_241_00">
        <num>241.00</num>
        <heading>Harassment of a rent regulated tenant; definition of terms</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 241.00 Harassment of a rent regulated tenant; definition of terms.\n  As used in this article:\n  1. "Rent regulated tenant" shall mean a person occupying a housing\naccommodation or any lawful successor to the tenancy which is subject to\nthe regulations and control of residential rents and evictions pursuant\nto the emergency housing rent control law, the local emergency housing\nrent control act, the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen\nseventy-four, the New York city rent and rehabilitation law or the New\nYork city rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred sixty-nine, and\nsuch person is either a party to a lease or rental agreement for such\nhousing accommodation, a statutory tenant or a person who lawfully\noccupies such housing accommodation with such party to a lease or rental\nagreement or with such statutory tenant. The definition of "rent\nregulated tenant" as used in this subdivision shall be applicable only\nto the provisions of this article and shall not be applicable to any\nother provision of law.\n  2. "Housing accommodations" shall mean housing accommodations which\nare subject to the regulations and control of residential rents and\nevictions pursuant to the emergency housing rent control law, the local\nemergency housing rent control act, the emergency tenant protection act\nof nineteen seventy-four, the New York city rent and rehabilitation law\nor the New York city rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred\nsixty-nine.\n  3. "Owner" shall mean an owner, lessor, sublessor, assignee, net\nlessee, or a proprietary lessee of a housing accommodation in a\nstructure or premises owned by a cooperative corporation or association,\nor an owner of a condominium unit or the sponsor of such cooperative\ncorporation or association or condominium development, or any other\nperson or entity receiving or entitled to receive rent for the use or\noccupation of any housing accommodation, or an agent of or any person\nacting on behalf of any of the foregoing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>