<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="265.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_265_10">
        <num>265.10</num>
        <heading>Manufacture, transport, disposition and defacement of weapons and dangerous instruments and appliances</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 265.10 Manufacture, transport, disposition and defacement of weapons\n           and dangerous instruments and appliances.\n  1. Any person who manufactures or causes to be manufactured any\nmachine-gun, assault weapon, large capacity ammunition feeding device or\ndisguised gun is guilty of a class D felony. Any person who manufactures\nor causes to be manufactured any rapid-fire modification device is\nguilty of a class E felony. Any person who manufactures or causes to be\nmanufactured any switchblade knife, pilum ballistic knife, metal knuckle\nknife, undetectable knife, billy, blackjack, bludgeon, plastic knuckles,\nmetal knuckles, throwing star, chuka stick, sandbag, sandclub or\nslungshot is guilty of a class A misdemeanor.\n  2. Any person who transports or ships any machine-gun, firearm\nsilencer, assault weapon or large capacity ammunition feeding device or\ndisguised gun, or who transports or ships as merchandise five or more\nfirearms, is guilty of a class D felony. Any person who transports or\nships any rapid-fire modification device is guilty of a class E felony.\nAny person who transports or ships as merchandise any firearm, other\nthan an assault weapon, switchblade knife, pilum ballistic knife,\nundetectable knife, billy, blackjack, bludgeon, plastic knuckles, metal\nknuckles, throwing star, chuka stick, sandbag or slungshot is guilty of\na class A misdemeanor.\n  3. Any person who disposes of any machine-gun, assault weapon, large\ncapacity ammunition feeding device or firearm silencer is guilty of a\nclass D felony. Any person who disposes of any rapid-fire modification\ndevice is guilty of a class E felony. Any person who knowingly buys,\nreceives, disposes of, or conceals a machine-gun, firearm, large\ncapacity ammunition feeding device, rifle or shotgun which has been\ndefaced for the purpose of concealment or prevention of the detection of\na crime or misrepresenting the identity of such machine-gun, firearm,\nlarge capacity ammunition feeding device, rifle or shotgun is guilty of\na class D felony.\n  4. Any person who disposes of any of the weapons, instruments or\nappliances specified in subdivision one of section 265.01, except a\nfirearm, is guilty of a class A misdemeanor, and he is guilty of a class\nD felony if he has previously been convicted of any crime.\n  5. Any person who disposes of any of the weapons, instruments,\nappliances or substances specified in section 265.05 to any other person\nunder the age of sixteen years is guilty of a class A misdemeanor.\n  6. Any person who wilfully defaces any machine-gun, large capacity\nammunition feeding device or firearm is guilty of a class D felony.\n  7. Any person, other than a wholesale dealer, or gunsmith or dealer in\nfirearms duly licensed pursuant to section 400.00 of this chapter,\nlawfully in possession of a firearm or semiautomatic rifle, who disposes\nof the same without first notifying in writing the licensing officer in\nthe city of New York and counties of Nassau and Suffolk and elsewhere in\nthe state the executive department, division of state police, Albany, is\nguilty of a class A misdemeanor.\n  8. Any person, dealer, firm, partnership or corporation who\nintentionally designs or transforms a firearm, rifle, shotgun or\nmachine-gun to resemble a toy gun by either altering or concealing the\noriginal color or surface of the gun with the purpose of selling such\nweapon is guilty of a class D felony.\n  9. Any person who modifies a microstamping-enabled pistol or\nmicrostamping component with the intent to prevent the production of a\nmicrostamp is, for a first offense, guilty of a class B misdemeanor, and\nfor a second or subsequent offense, is guilty of a class A misdemeanor.\nFor the purposes of this subdivision, it shall not be unlawful to\nreplace the microstamping component of a microstamping-enabled pistol\nwhen the component is damaged or in need of replacement with another\nvalid microstamping component for the safe use of the firearm or\nreplacing such pin for a legitimate sporting purpose that is only used\nfor that legitimate purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>