<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.17"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.17"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-07-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="265.17"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_265_17">
        <num>265.17</num>
        <heading>Criminal purchase or disposal of a weapon</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 265.17 Criminal purchase or disposal of a weapon.\n  A person is guilty of criminal purchase or disposal of a weapon when:\n  1. Knowing that he or she is prohibited by law from possessing a\nfirearm, rifle or shotgun because of a prior conviction or because of\nsome other disability which would render him or her ineligible to\nlawfully possess a firearm, rifle or shotgun in this state, or knowing\nthat he or she is the subject of an outstanding warrant of arrest issued\nupon the alleged commission of a felony or serious offense, such person\npurchases or otherwise acquires a firearm, rifle or shotgun from another\nperson; or\n  2. Knowing that it would be unlawful for another person to possess a\nfirearm, rifle or shotgun, or knowing that another person is the subject\nof an outstanding warrant of arrest issued upon the alleged commission\nof a felony or serious offense, he or she purchases or otherwise\nacquires a firearm, rifle or shotgun for, on behalf of, or for the use\nof such other person; or\n  3. Knowing that another person is prohibited by law from possessing a\nfirearm, rifle or shotgun because of a prior conviction or because of\nsome other disability which would render him or her ineligible to\nlawfully possess a firearm, rifle or shotgun in this state, or knowing\nthat another person is the subject of an outstanding warrant of arrest\nissued upon the alleged commission of a felony or serious offense, a\nperson disposes of a firearm, rifle or shotgun to such other person.\n  Criminal purchase or disposal of a weapon is a class D felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>