<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-05-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="265.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_265_15">
        <num>265.15</num>
        <heading>Presumptions of possession, unlawful intent and defacement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if such weapon, instrument or appliance is\nfound upon the person of one of the occupants therein;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if such\nweapon, instrument or appliance is found in an automobile which is being\noperated for hire by a duly licensed driver in the due, lawful and\nproper pursuit of his or her trade, then such presumption shall not\napply to the driver; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the weapon so found is a pistol or\nrevolver and one of the occupants, not present under duress, has in his\nor her possession a valid license to have and carry concealed the same.\n  4. The possession by any person of the substance as specified in\nsection 265.04 is presumptive evidence of possessing such substance with\nintent to use the same unlawfully against the person or property of\nanother if such person is not licensed or otherwise authorized to\npossess such substance. The possession by any person of any dagger,\ndirk, stiletto, dangerous knife or any other weapon, instrument,\nappliance or substance designed, made or adapted for use primarily as a\nweapon, is presumptive evidence of intent to use the same unlawfully\nagainst another.\n  5. The possession by any person of a defaced machine-gun, firearm,\nrifle or shotgun is presumptive evidence that such person defaced the\nsame.\n  6. The possession of three or more firearms by any person is\npresumptive evidence that such person possessed the firearms with the\nintent to sell same.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>