<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="405.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_405_10">
        <num>405.10</num>
        <heading>Permits for indoor pyrotechnics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Name of the person, group, organization, or other entity\nsponsoring the production.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Date and time of day of the production.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Exact location of the production.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Name of the person actually in charge of firing the pyrotechnics\n(i.e., the pyrotechnic operator).\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Number, names, and ages of all assistants who are to be present.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Qualifications of the pyrotechnic operator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pyrotechnic experience of the operator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Confirmation of any applicable local, state, and federal licenses\nheld by the operator or assistant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Evidence of the permittee's insurance carrier or financial\nresponsibility.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Number and types of pyrotechnic devices and materials to be used,\nthe operator's experience with those devices and effects, and a\ndefinition of the general responsibilities of assistants.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Diagram of the grounds or facilities where the production is to be\nheld. This diagram shall show the point at which the pyrotechnic devices\nare to be fired, the fallout radius for each pyrotechnic device used in\nthe performance, the lines behind which the audience shall be\nrestrained, and the placement of sprinkler systems.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Point of on-site assembly of pyrotechnic devices.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Manner and place of storage of the pyrotechnic materials and\ndevices.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Material safety data sheet (MSDS) for the pyrotechnic materials to\nbe used.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certification that the set, scenery, and rigging materials are\ninherently flame-retardant or have been treated to achieve flame\nretardancy.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_p">
          <num>(p)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certification that all materials worn by performers in the fallout\narea during use of pyrotechnic effects shall be inherently\nflame-retardant or have been treated to achieve flame retardancy.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_p__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All plans shall be submitted as soon as is possible so that the\npermit authority has time to be present and to notify other interested\nparties. In no event shall such advance notice be less than five\nbusiness days.\n  d. A walk-through and a representative demonstration of the\npyrotechnics shall be approved by the permit authority before a permit\nis approved.  The permit authority may waive this requirement based on\npast history, prior knowledge, and other factors; provided that the\nauthority is confident that the discharge of pyrotechnics can be\nconducted safely.  The demonstration shall be scheduled with sufficient\ntime allowed to reset/reload the pyrotechnics before the arrival of the\naudience.\n  e. All pyrotechnic operators shall be at least twenty-one years old\nand licensed or approved by the permit authority in accordance with all\napplicable laws, if any. All assistants shall be at least eighteen years\nold.\n  3. Conduct of pyrotechnic performances. a. Two or more f...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_p__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All pyrotechnic devices shall be mounted in a secure manner to\nmaintain their proper positions and orientations so that, when they are\nfired, the pyrotechnic effects described in the plan submitted by the\npermittee are produced. Pyrotechnic devices shall be mounted so that no\nfallout from the device endangers human lives, results in personal\ninjury, or damages property. Pyrotechnic materials shall be fired only\nfrom equipment specifically constructed for the purpose of firing\npyrotechnic materials. The pyrotechnic operator shall be responsible for\nselecting equipment and materials that are compatible.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_p__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where rockets are launched before an audience, performers, or\nsupport personnel, the rockets shall be attached securely to a guide\nwire or cable with both ends securely attached and placed on an\nimpact-resistant surface located at the terminal end of the guide. This\nguide wire or cable shall be of sufficient strength and flame resistance\nto withstand the exhaust from the rocket. An effective arrangement to\nstop the rocket shall be provided.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_p__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pyrotechnics shall be:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>placed so that any hazardous debris\nfalls into a safe, flame-resistant area;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fired so that the\ntrajectory of their pyrotechnic material is not carried over the\naudience; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>placed for firing so that no flammable materials are\nwithin their fallout area.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pyrotechnic devices and materials used indoors shall be\nspecifically manufactured and marked for indoor use by the manufacturer.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Airbursts shall be permitted to be fired above the assembled\naudience, subject to the following conditions:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The airburst shall be suspended by a minimum 30-gauge metal wire\nthat is attached securely to a secure support acceptable to the\nauthority having jurisdiction.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The airburst shall occur at a minimum height of three times the\ndiameter of the effect.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where the effect is demonstrated, there shall be no burning or\nglowing particles below the fifteen-foot level above the floor.\n  c. Each pyrotechnic device fired during a performance shall be\nseparated from the audience by at least fifteen feet but not by less\nthan twice the fallout radius of the device. Concussion mortars shall be\nseparated from the audience by a minimum of twenty-five feet. There\nshall be no glowing or flaming particles within ten feet of the\naudience.\n  d.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The facility where pyrotechnic materials and devices are\nhandled and used shall be maintained in a neat and orderly condition and\nshall be kept free of any conditions that can create a fire hazard.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Smoking shall not be permitted within twenty-five feet of the area\nwhere pyrotechnics are being handled or fired; provided that smoking by\nperformers as part of the performance shall be permitted as blocked in\nrehearsals and if expressly approved by the pyrotechnic operator and the\npermit authority.\n  e.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The pyrotechnic effect operator shall advise all performers and\nsupport personnel that they are exposed to a potentially hazardous\nsituation when performing or otherwise carrying out their\nresponsibilities in the vicinity of a pyrotechnic effect. Performers and\nsupport personnel familiar and experienced with the pyrotechnic effects\nbeing used shall be permitted to be in the area of a pyrotechnic effect,\nbut only voluntarily and in the performance of their duties.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No part, projectile, or debris from the pyrotechnic material or\ndevice shall be propelled so that it damages overhead properties,\noverhead equipment, or the ceiling and walls of the facility.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Immediately before any performance, the pyrotechnic operator shall\nmake a final check of wiring, positions, hook-ups, and pyrotechnic\ndevices to ensure that they are in proper working order. The pyrotechnic\noperator also shall verify safety distances.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The placement and wiring of all pyrotechnic devices shall be\ndesigned to minimize the possibility of performers and support personnel\ndisturbing the devices during a performance.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The pyrotechnic operator shall exercise extreme care throughout\nthe performance to ensure that the pyrotechnic devices function\ncorrectly and that the performers, support personnel, and audience are\nclear of the devices.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_405_10__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When pyrotechnics are fired, the quantity of smoke developed shall\nbe controlled so as not to obscure the visibility of exit signs or paths\nof egress.\n  4. Bonds. Before granting and issuing a permit for a use of\npyrotechnics as provided in this section, the permit authority shall\nrequire an adequate bond from the applicant therefor, unless such\napplicant is a state entity, county park, city, village, or town, or\nfrom the person to whom a contract for such use shall be awarded, in a\nsum to be fixed by the permit authority, which, however, shall not be\nless than five hundred thousand dollars, conditioned for the payment of\nall damages which may be caused to a person or persons or to property by\nreason of the use so permitted and arising from any acts of the\npermittee, his or her agents, employees, contractors, or subcontractors.\nSuch bond shall run to the owner of the facility for which the permit is\ngranted and issued and shall be for the use and benefit of any person or\...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>