<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-460.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-460.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="460.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-460.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-460.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-460.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-460.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_460_00">
        <num>460.00</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_00__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to charge and prove patterns of criminal activity and their\nconnection to ongoing enterprises, legitimate or illegal, that are\ncontrolled or operated by organized crime, and (ii) to apply criminal\nand civil penalties designed to prevent and eliminate organized crime's\ninvolvement with such enterprises. The organized crime control act is a\nstatute of comparable purpose but tempered by reasonable limitations on\nits applicability, and by due regard for the rights of innocent persons.\nBecause of its more rigorous definitions, this act will not apply to\nsome situations encompassed within comparable statutes in other\njurisdictions. This act is vital to the peace, security and general\nwelfare of the state.\n  In part because of its highly diverse nature, it is impossible to\nprecisely define what organized crime is. This article, however, does\nattempt to define and criminalize what organized crime does. This\narticle focuses upon criminal enterprises because their sophistication\nand organization make them more effective at their criminal purposes and\nbecause their structure and insulation protect their leadership from\ndetection and prosecution.\n  At the same time, this article is not intended to be employed to\nprosecute relatively minor or isolated acts of criminality which, while\nrelated to an enterprise and arguably part of a pattern as defined in\nthis article, can be adequately and more fairly prosecuted as separate\noffenses. Similarly, particular defendants may play so minor a role in a\ncriminal enterprise that their culpability would be unfairly distorted\nby prosecution and punishment for participation in the enterprise.\n  The balance intended to be struck by this act cannot readily be\ncodified in the form of restrictive definitions or a categorical list of\nexceptions. General, yet carefully drawn definitions of the terms\n"pattern of criminal activity" and "criminal enterprise" have been\nemployed.  Notwithstanding the provisions of section 5....</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>