<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-480.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-480.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="480.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-480.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-480.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-480.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-480.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_480_10">
        <num>480.10</num>
        <heading>Procedure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_480_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Trial of forfeiture counts by jury or by the court. Evidence\nwhich relates solely to the issue of forfeiture shall not be presented\nduring the trial on the underlying felony offense or specified felony\noffense, and the defendant shall not be required to present such\nevidence prior to the verdict on such offense. A defendant who does not\npresent evidence in his defense with respect to the trial of the\nunderlying offense is not precluded on account thereof from presenting\nevidence during the trial of the forfeiture count or counts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_480_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Trial of forfeiture counts by the jury. After returning a verdict\nof guilty of a felony offense or specified felony offense, or where the\ndefendant has pled guilty to a felony offense or a specified felony\noffense and has not waived a jury trial of the forfeiture count or\ncounts pursuant to article three hundred twenty of the criminal\nprocedure law, the jury shall be given the forfeiture information and\nshall hear any additional evidence which is relevant and legally\nadmissible upon the forfeiture count or counts. After hearing such\nevidence, the jury shall then deliberate upon the forfeiture count or\ncounts, and based upon all the evidence admitted in connection with the\nindictment or superior court information and the forfeiture information,\nmay, if satisfied by proof beyond a reasonable doubt that the property,\nor a portion thereof, is subject to forfeiture pursuant to this article,\nreturn a verdict directing that such property, or portion thereof, is\nsubject to forfeiture.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_480_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Trial of forfeiture counts by the court. Where a defendant has\nwaived a jury trial of the forfeiture count or counts pursuant to\narticle three hundred twenty of the criminal procedure law, the court\nshall hear all evidence upon the forfeiture information and may, if\nsatisfied by proof beyond a reasonable doubt that the property, or a\nportion thereof, is subject to forfeiture under this article, render a\nverdict determining that such property, or a portion thereof, is subject\nto forfeiture under this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_480_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After the verdict of forfeiture, the court shall hear arguments\nand may receive additional evidence upon a motion of the defendant that\nthe verdict of forfeiture</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_480_10__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is against the weight of the evidence, or\n(ii) is, with respect to a forfeiture pursuant to this article,\ndisproportionate to the defendant's gain from the offense, or the\ndefendant's interest in the property, or the defendant's participation\nin the conduct upon which the forfeiture is based. Upon such a finding,\nthe court may in the interest of justice set aside, modify, limit or\notherwise condition the verdict of forfeiture.\n  7. A final judgment or order of forfeiture issued pursuant to this\narticle shall authorize the prosecutor to seize all property directed to\nbe forfeited under this article upon such terms and conditions as the\ncourt deems proper. If a property right is not exercisable or\ntransferable for value by the prosecutor, it shall expire and shall not\nrevert to the convicted person.\n  8. Where the forfeited property consists of real property, the court\nmay at any time prior to a verdict of forfeiture, enter an order\npursuant to subdivision four-a of section thirteen hundred eleven of the\ncivil practice law and rules.\n  9. No person shall forfeit any right, title, or interest in any\nproperty under this article who has not been convicted of a felony\noffense or specified felony offense, as the case may be. Any person\nclaiming an interest in property subject to forfeiture may institute a\nspecial proceeding to determine that claim, before or after the trial,\npursuant to section thirteen hundred twenty-seven of the civil practice\nlaw and rules; provided, however, that if such special proceeding is\ninitiated before trial on the forfeiture count or counts, it may, upon\nwritten motion of the prosecutor, and in the court's discretion, be\npostponed by the court until completion of the trial. In addition, any\nperson claiming an interest in property subject to forfeiture may\npetition for remission as provided for in subdivision seven of section\nthirteen hundred eleven of the civil practice law and rules.\n  10. Testimony of the defenda...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>