<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="60.01"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_60_01">
        <num>60.01</num>
        <heading>Authorized dispositions; generally</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may impose a revocable sentence as herein specified:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the court, where authorized by article sixty-five, may sentence a\nperson to a period of probation or to a period of conditional discharge\nas provided in that article; or\n  (ii) the court, where authorized by article eighty-five, may sentence\na person to a term of intermittent imprisonment as provided in that\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A revocable sentence shall be deemed a tentative one to the extent\nthat it may be altered or revoked in accordance with the provisions of\nthe article under which it was imposed, but for all other purposes shall\nbe deemed to be a final judgment of conviction.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any case where the court imposes a sentence of probation,\nconditional discharge, or a sentence of intermittent imprisonment, it\nmay also impose a fine authorized by article eighty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any case where the court imposes a sentence of imprisonment not\nin excess of sixty days, for a misdemeanor or not in excess of six\nmonths for a felony or in the case of a sentence of intermittent\nimprisonment not in excess of four months, it may also impose a sentence\nof probation or conditional discharge provided that the term of\nprobation or conditional discharge together with the term of\nimprisonment shall not exceed the term of probation or conditional\ndischarge authorized by article sixty-five of this chapter. The sentence\nof imprisonment shall be a condition of and run concurrently with the\nsentence of probation or conditional discharge.\n  3. Other dispositions. When a person is not sentenced as specified in\nsubdivision two, or when a sentence specified in subdivision two is\nrevoked, the sentence of the court must be as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A term of imprisonment; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A fine authorized by article eighty, provided, however, that when\nthe conviction is of a class B felony or of any felony defined in\narticle two hundred twenty, the sentence shall not consist solely of a\nfine; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Both imprisonment and a fine; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where authorized by section 65.20, unconditional discharge as\nprovided in that section; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Following revocation of a sentence of conditional discharge\nimposed pursuant to section 65.05 of this chapter or paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision two of this section, probation as provided in section 65.00\nof this chapter or to the sentence of imprisonment and probation as\nprovided for in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section.\n  4. In any case where a person has been sentenced to a period of\nprobation imposed pursuant to section 65.00 of this chapter, if the part\nof the sentence that provides for probation is revoked, the court must\nsentence such person to imprisonment or to the sentence of imprisonment\nand probation as provided for in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_01__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>