<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.09"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.09"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="60.09"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.09/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.09/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.09/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-60.09/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_60_09">
        <num>60.09</num>
        <heading>Authorized dispositions; resentencing of certain persons convicted of specified controlled substance offenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_09__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section and shall include credit\nfor any jail time incurred upon the subject conviction as well as credit\nfor any period of incarceration incurred pursuant to the sentence\noriginally imposed.\n  b. A court, upon an application specified in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_09__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsection may resentence a person as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_09__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the conviction was for a class A-III offense the court may\nimpose a new maximum term which shall be no less than three times the\namount of the minimum term imposed in the original sentence and no more\nthan twenty-five years;\n  (ii) if the conviction was for a class A-II offense the court may\nimpose a new minimum term which shall be no less than three years\nimprisonment and no more than eight and one-third years;\n  (iii) upon resentence of a person as specified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_09__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision the court shall resentence the person to the same\nminimum term previously imposed;\n  (iv) upon resentence of a person as specified in paragraph (ii) of\nthis subdivision the court shall impose a maximum term of life\nimprisonment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_60_09__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the conviction was for an offense as specified in section\n115.05 of this chapter and the offense which was the object of the\ncriminal facilitation was a class A-III felony then the court shall set\naside the conviction and substitute it with a conviction for violation\nof section 115.01 or 115.00 of this chapter, whichever is appropriate\nunder the facts of the case, and impose a sentence in accordance with\nthose provisions.\n  c. Upon resentence as provided in this section the court may not\nimpose a sentence greater than the sentence previously imposed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>