<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-65.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-65.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="65.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-65.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-65.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-65.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-65.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_65_15">
        <num>65.15</num>
        <heading>Calculation of periods of probation and of conditional discharge</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 65.15 Calculation of periods of probation and of conditional\n          discharge.\n  1. A period of probation or a period or additional period of\nconditional discharge commences on the day it is imposed. Multiple\nperiods, whether imposed at the same or at different times, shall run\nconcurrently.\n  2. When a person has violated the conditions of his or her probation\nor conditional discharge and is declared delinquent by the court, the\ndeclaration of delinquency shall interrupt the period of the sentence as\nof the date of the delinquency and such interruption shall continue\nuntil a final determination as to the delinquency has been made by the\ncourt pursuant to a hearing held in accordance with the provisions of\nthe criminal procedure law. Any order for the installation and\nmaintenance of a functioning ignition interlock device imposed pursuant\nto section 60.21 of this title shall remain in effect throughout the\ndelinquency and the court may extend the period of such installation and\nmaintenance by the period of the delinquency; provided, however, that\nthe defendant shall get credit for any period where the device was\ninstalled and maintained during the delinquency.\n  * 3. In any case where a person who is under a sentence of probation\nor of conditional discharge is also under an indeterminate or\ndeterminate sentence of imprisonment, imposed for some other offense by\na court of this state the service of the sentence of imprisonment shall\nsatisfy the sentence of probation or of conditional discharge unless the\nsentence of probation or of conditional discharge is revoked prior to\nthe next to occur of parole or conditional release under, or\nsatisfaction of, the sentence of imprisonment. Provided, however, that\nthe service of an indeterminate or determinate sentence of imprisonment\nshall not satisfy a sentence of probation if the sentence of probation\nwas imposed at a time when the sentence of imprisonment had one year or\nless to run.\n  * NB Effective until September 1, 2027\n  * 3. In any case where a person who is under a sentence of probation\nor of conditional discharge is also under an indeterminate sentence of\nimprisonment, or a reformatory sentence of imprisonment authorized by\nsection 75.00, imposed for some other offense by a court of this state\nthe service of the sentence of imprisonment shall satisfy the sentence\nof probation or of conditional discharge unless the sentence of\nprobation or of conditional discharge is revoked prior to the next to\noccur of parole or conditional release under, or satisfaction of, the\nsentence of imprisonment. Provided, however, that the service of an\nindeterminate or a reformatory sentence of imprisonment shall not\nsatisfy a sentence of probation if the sentence of probation was imposed\nat a time when the sentence of imprisonment had one year or less to run.\n  * NB Effective September 1, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>