<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="80.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_80_00">
        <num>80.00</num>
        <heading>Fine for felony</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_80_00__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for A-I felonies, one hundred thousand dollars;\n  (ii) for A-II felonies, fifty thousand dollars;\n  (iii) for B felonies, thirty thousand dollars;\n  (iv) for C felonies, fifteen thousand dollars.\nWhen imposing a fine pursuant to the provisions of this paragraph, the\ncourt shall consider the profit gained by defendant's conduct, whether\nthe amount of the fine is disproportionate to the conduct in which\ndefendant engaged, its impact on any victims, and defendant's economic\ncircumstances, including the defendant's ability to pay, the effect of\nthe fine upon his or her immediate family or any other persons to whom\nthe defendant owes an obligation of support.\n  2. As used in this section the term "gain" means the amount of money\nor the value of property derived from the commission of the crime, less\nthe amount of money or the value of property returned to the victim of\nthe crime or seized by or surrendered to lawful authority prior to the\ntime sentence is imposed.\n  3. When the court imposes a fine for a felony pursuant to paragraph b\nof subdivision one of this section, the court shall make a finding as to\nthe amount of the defendant's gain from the crime. If the record does\nnot contain sufficient evidence to support such a finding or to permit\nadequate consideration of the matters specified in paragraph c of\nsubdivision one of this section, the court may conduct a hearing upon\nsuch issues.\n  4. Exception. The provisions of this section shall not apply to a\ncorporation.\n  5. All moneys in excess of five thousand dollars received or collected\nin payment of a fine imposed pursuant to paragraph c of subdivision one\nof this section are the property of the state and the state comptroller\nshall deposit all such fines to the rehabilitative alcohol and substance\ntreatment fund established pursuant to section ninety-seven-cc of the\nstate finance law.\n  6. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of subdivision one of\nthis section a sentence to pa...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>