<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.05"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.05"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="85.05"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_85_05">
        <num>85.05</num>
        <heading>Modification and revocation of sentences of intermittent imprisonment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_05__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the court is satisfied during the term of the sentence that the\ndefendant has committed another offense during such term;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant has failed to report to the institution to which he\nhas been committed, or to the institution designated by the head of the\nagency to which he has been committed, on a day or dates specified in\nthe commitment and is unable or unwilling to furnish a reasonable and\nacceptable explanation for such failure; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_05__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant has violated a rule or regulation of the institution\nor agency to which he has been committed and the head of such\ninstitution or agency or someone delegated by him has reported such\nviolation in writing to the court.\n  2. Interruption of sentence. In any case where the defendant fails to\nreport to the institution or to an institution of the agency to which he\nhas been committed, the term of the sentence shall be interrupted and\nsuch interruption shall continue until the defendant either reports to\nsuch institution or appears before the court that imposed the sentence,\nwhichever occurs first. If the defendant reports to the institution\nbefore he appears before the court, he shall be brought before the\ncourt.\n  3. Action by court. The court shall not modify or revoke a sentence of\nintermittent imprisonment unless the defendant has been afforded an\nopportunity to be heard. Any modification of a sentence of intermittent\nimprisonment:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_05__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>may provide</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_05__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for different or additional or fewer days or parts\nof days on which the defendant is to be confined, or (ii) where the\ndefendant has failed to report as specified in the sentence, an\nextension of the term of the sentence for the period during which it was\ninterrupted, or (iii) for both; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall be by written order of the court and shall be delivered and\nfiled in the same manner as the original sentence, as specified in\nsubdivision two of section 85.10 of this article.\n  4. Jail time. Where a sentence of intermittent imprisonment is revoked\nand a sentence of imprisonment is imposed in its place for the same\noffense, time spent in confinement under the sentence of intermittent\nimprisonment shall be calculated as jail time under subdivision three of\nsection 70.30 of this chapter and shall be added to any jail time\naccrued against such sentence prior to imposition thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>