<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="85.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_85_00">
        <num>85.00</num>
        <heading>Sentence of intermittent imprisonment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the court is imposing sentence, upon a person other than a second\nor persistent felony offender, for a class D or class E felony or for\nany offense that is not a felony; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the court is not imposing any other sentence of imprisonment upon\nthe defendant at the same time; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_00__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant is not under any other sentence of imprisonment with\na term in excess of fifteen days imposed by any other court; and\n  3. Duration of sentence. A sentence of intermittent imprisonment may\nbe for any term that could be imposed as a definite sentence of\nimprisonment for the offense for which such sentence is imposed. The\nterm of the sentence shall commence on the day it is imposed and shall\nbe calculated upon the basis of the duration of its term, rather than\nupon the basis of the days spent in confinement, so that no person shall\nbe subject to any such sentence for a period that is longer than a\nperiod that commences on the date the sentence is imposed and ends on\nthe date the term of the longest definite sentence for the offense would\nhave expired, after deducting the credit that would have been applicable\nto a definite sentence for jail time but without regard to any credit\nauthorized to be allowed against the term of a definite sentence for\ngood behavior. The provisions of section five hundred-l of the\ncorrection law shall not be applicable to a sentence of intermittent\nimprisonment.\n  4. Imposition of sentence.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the court imposes a sentence of\nintermittent imprisonment the court shall specify in the sentence:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_00__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the court is imposing a sentence of intermittent\nimprisonment;\n  (ii) the term of such sentence;\n  (iii) the days or parts of days on which the sentence is to be served,\nbut except as provided in paragraph (iv) hereof such specification need\nnot include the dates on which such days fall; and\n  (iv) the first and last dates on which the defendant is to be\nincarcerated under the sentence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court, in its discretion, may specify any day or days or parts\nthereof on which the defendant shall be confined and may specify a\nperiod to commence at the commencement of the sentence and not to exceed\nfifteen days during which the defendant is to be continuously confined.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>