<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="85.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_85_10">
        <num>85.10</num>
        <heading>Commitment; notifications; warrants</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>detention of the defendant under the judgment shall be\nexecuted during the times specified in the sentence; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_85_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the court\nmay provide that the defendant is to report to a specified institution\non a specified date at a specified time to commence service of the\nsentence and in such case the defendant need not be taken into or\nretained in custody when sentence is imposed.\n  2. Notifications. A written copy of the sentence imposed by the court\nsigned by the judge who imposed the sentence shall be delivered to the\ndefendant and shall be annexed to the commitment and to each copy of the\ncommitment required to be delivered or filed. When the defendant is not\ntaken into or retained in custody at the time sentence is imposed, the\ncommitment and copy of the sentence shall forthwith be delivered to the\nperson whose duty it is to execute the judgment. If at any time the\ndefendant fails to report for confinement as provided in the sentence\nthe officer in charge of the institution or department to which such\ncommitment is made or someone designated by such officer shall forthwith\nnotify the court in writing of such failure to report.\n  3. Warrants. Upon receipt of any such notification the court may issue\na warrant to an appropriate police officer or peace officer directing\nhim to take the defendant into custody and bring him before the court.\nThe court may then commit such person to custody or fix bail or release\nhim on his own recognizance for future appearance before the court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>