<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-10.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-10.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-10.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-10.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-10.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-10.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_15">
        <num>10.15</num>
        <heading>Compensation, fees and expenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any compensation, fee or expense paid pursuant to the provisions\nof this article and article eighteen-B of the county law shall be a\nstate charge payable on vouchers approved by the court which fixed the\nsame, after audit by and on the warrant of the comptroller. Any\ncompensation, fee or expense paid to such counsel so appointed shall be\npaid out of funds appropriated to the administrative office for the\ncourts. Each claim for compensation and reimbursement shall be supported\nby a sworn statement specifying the time expended, services rendered,\nexpenses incurred and reimbursement or compensation applied for or\nreceived in the same case from any other source. The appropriate court\nshall review and determine the reasonableness of the claims, including\nthe number of hours expended out of court by counsel and psychiatric\nexaminers. When a court appoints counsel pursuant to article eighteen-B\nof the county law, such counsel shall be compensated in accordance with\nthe provisions of that article. Notwithstanding any other provision of\nlaw, psychiatric examiners who are appointed by a court under this\narticle, and who perform such examinations other than as government\nemployees, shall be compensated at an hourly rate to be set by the\nadministrative board of the judicial conference.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Members of the case review panel established by subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection 10.05 of this article shall be entitled to reimbursement for\nexpenses reasonably incurred for the performance of duties under this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state may contract with entities for the provision of legal\nrepresentation services to respondents in proceedings under this\narticle, within the amounts appropriated therefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>