<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.17"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.17"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13.17"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_17">
        <num>13.17</num>
        <heading>Programs, services, and operations in the office for people with developmental disabilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_17__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall establish policy and procedures for the\norganization, administration, and service delivery system under his or\nher jurisdiction and shall make provision for the effective rendition of\nsupports and services to individuals with developmental disabilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_17__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be, within the state operations offices of the office,\nthe developmental disabilities services offices named below serving the\nareas either currently or previously served by a school, for the care\nand treatment of persons with developmental disabilities and for\nresearch and teaching in the science and skills required for the care\nand treatment of such persons with developmental disabilities:\n  Bernard M. Fineson Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Brooklyn Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Broome Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Capital District Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Central New York Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Finger Lakes Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Institute for Basic Research in Developmental Disabilities\n  Hudson Valley Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Metro New York Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Long Island Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Sunmount Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Taconic Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Western New York Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  Staten Island Developmental Disabilities Services Office\n  The New York State Institute for Basic Research in Developmental\nDisabilities is designated as an institute for the conduct of medical\nresearch and other scientific investigation directed towards furthering\nknowledge of the etiology, diagnosis, treatment and prevention of\ndevelopmental disabilities.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_17__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall establish, at his or her discretion,\ndevelopmental disabilities regional offices and shall establish state\noperations offices that provide for the direct delivery of supports and\nservices by the office for people with developmental disabilities.\n  * NB There are 2 sb</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_17__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>'s\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_17__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may authorize other offices of the department\nand any public or private non-profit organization or political\nsubdivision of the state to deliver supports and services to individuals\nwith developmental disabilities, not inconsistent with the programs and\nobjectives of the office in any facility under his jurisdiction. The\ncommissioner may permit any facility under his jurisdiction to operate\nprograms for persons with mental disabilities, not inconsistent with\nprograms and objectives of the department, under contracts or agreements\nwith other offices within the department.\n  * NB There are 2 sb</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_17__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>'s\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_17__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event of a closure or transfer of a state-operated\nindividualized residential alternative (IRA), the commissioner shall:\n  1. provide appropriate and timely notification to the temporary\npresident of the senate, and the speaker of the assembly, and to\nappropriate representatives of impacted labor organizations. Such\nnotification to the representatives of impacted labor organizations\nshall be made as soon as practicable, but no less than ninety days prior\nto such closure or transfer except in the case of exigent circumstances\nimpacting the health, safety, or welfare of the residents of the IRA as\ndetermined by the office. Provided, however, that nothing herein shall\nlimit the ability of the office to effectuate such closure or transfer;\nand\n  2. make reasonable efforts to confer with the affected workforce and\nany other party he or she deems appropriate to inform such affected\nworkforce, the residents of the IRA, and their family members, where\nappropriate, of the proposed closure or transfer plan.\n  * NB Repealed March 31, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>