<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13.24"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_24">
        <num>13.24</num>
        <heading>Sheltered workshops, work activity and day training services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 13.24 Sheltered workshops, work activity and day training services.\n  1. As used in this section, the following terms shall have the\nfollowing meanings.\n  a. "Sheltered workshops" means a program operated for the purpose of\nproviding sheltered employment to persons with developmental\ndisabilities.\n  b. "Work activity and day training services" means pre-vocational\nactivities defined by regulation of the commissioner designed to enhance\nthe ability of a person with a developmental disability to receive\nvocational rehabilitation services.\n  2. The commissioner shall develop methods to fund by agreement the\nreasonably related cost of services, subject to the approval of the\ndirector of the budget, provided in sheltered workshops, work activity\nand day training services. The commissioner shall determine those\nfacilities and agencies providing such services and shall describe\ncharacteristics of clients receiving such services. The commissioner\nshall determine methods of improving the current financing system for\nsuch services.\n  3. The methods of improving the current financing system shall\ninclude, but not be limited to, the following:\n  a. Provision of equitable funding to all individuals with\ndevelopmental disabilities which is not dependent upon prior residence\nin facilities of the office.\n  b. Establishment of systems of provider accountability for units of\nservice rendered in return for payments made and development of an\nadvanced payment mechanism.\n  c. Recommendation of rules, regulations and standards for the payment\nfor provision of services.\n  4. The commissioner shall report to the legislature on the progress of\ndetermining methods of improving the current financing system on or\nbefore April first, nineteen hundred eighty-two.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>