<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.42"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.42"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-06-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13.42"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.42/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.42/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.42/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-13.42/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_42">
        <num>13.42</num>
        <heading>Autism spectrum disorders advisory board</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_42__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is hereby established within the office the autism spectrum\ndisorders advisory board. Such board shall consist of twenty-four\nmembers, fifteen of whom shall be appointed and nine of whom shall serve\nex officio. Of the appointed members, three shall be appointed by the\ngovernor, three shall be appointed by the temporary president of the\nsenate, three shall be appointed by the speaker of the assembly, three\nshall be appointed by the minority leader of the senate and three shall\nbe appointed by the minority leader of the assembly. Of the three\nmembers appointed by each appointing authority, one member shall have\nexpertise of work as a professional in the field of autism, one member\nshall be a family advocate and one member shall be a self-advocate in\nthe community that such advocate resides. A representative from each of\nthe following state agencies shall serve ex officio: the office for\npeople with developmental disabilities; the department of education; the\noffice of mental health; the office of children and family services; the\ndepartment of health; the developmental disabilities planning council;\nthe council on children and families; and the office of vocational and\neducational services for individuals with disabilities. The chair of the\nboard shall be selected by the governor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_42__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Members of the board shall serve for a term of three years, at\nwhich point such membership position shall be subject to reappointment.\nVacancies on the board shall be filled in the same manner as the\noriginal appointment once a member's term has expired, or if a member\nresigns before his or her term has expired. Members of the board shall\nreceive no compensation, but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary\nexpenses incurred in the performance of their duties within amounts\nappropriated therefor. As of the effective date of the chapter of the\nlaws of two thousand twenty-three which amended this subdivision, all\nappointees who are currently serving on the board shall be subject to\nthe term limit set forth pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_42__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board shall have the following tasks and duties:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_13_42__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Study and review the effectiveness of supports and services\ncurrently being provided to people diagnosed with autism spectrum\ndisorders;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_13_42__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Identify legislative and regulatory activity which may be required\nto improve existing service systems that support people diagnosed with\nautism spectrum disorders;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_13_42__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Identify methods of improving interagency coordination of services\nand maximize the impact and effectiveness of services and agency\nfunctions;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_13_42__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Identify strategies and methods of improving outreach and\ncoordination of services associated with autism spectrum disorders for\nminority group members including, but not limited to, African American,\nLatino and Asian children; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_13_42__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such other matters as may be deemed appropriate by the members of\nthe board.\n  At the discretion of the chair, the board may consult with\nstakeholders for the purpose of carrying out its tasks and duties in\naccordance with this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_42__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such board shall meet at least quarterly. Special meetings may be\ncalled by the chair. The agenda and meeting place of all regular or\nspecial meetings shall be made available to the public in advance of\nsuch meetings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_42__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The advisory board shall submit a written report to the governor,\nthe temporary president of the senate and the speaker of the assembly by\nno later than October first of the year next succeeding the effective\ndate of this section and annually thereafter, setting forth the\nrecommendations and activities of the council on matters within the\nscope of its duties as set forth in this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>