<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-15.05"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-15.05"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15.05"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-15.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-15.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-15.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-15.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_05">
        <num>15.05</num>
        <heading>Examining physician or psychologist and medical certificate</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_05__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person is disqualified from acting as an examining physician or\npsychologist in the following cases:\n  1. if he is a relative of the person applying for the admission or of\nthe person alleged to have a developmental disability.\n  2. if he is a manager, trustee, visitor, proprietor, officer,\ndirector, or stockholder of the school in which the resident resides or\nto which it is proposed to admit such person, except as otherwise\nprovided in this chapter, or if he has any pecuniary interest, directly\nor indirectly, in such school, provided that receipt of fees,\nprivileges, or compensation for treating or examining patients in such\nschool shall not be deemed to be such a pecuniary interest.\n  3. if he is on the staff of a proprietary facility to which it is\nproposed to admit such person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A certificate, as required by this article, must show that the\nperson has a developmental disability and shall be based on an\nexamination of the person alleged to have a developmental disability\nmade within six months prior to the date of admission. The date of the\ncertificate shall be the date of such examination. All certificates\nshall contain the facts and circumstances upon which the judgment of the\nexaminers is based and shall show that the condition of the person\nexamined is such that he needs care or treatment in a school and such\nother information as the commissioner may by regulation require.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>