<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_00">
        <num>16.00</num>
        <heading>Regulation and quality control of services for individuals with developmental disabilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 16.00 Regulation and quality control of services for individuals with\n          developmental disabilities.\n  This article sets forth provisions enabling the commissioner of the\noffice for people with developmental disabilities to regulate and assure\nthe consistent high quality of services provided within the state to its\ncitizens with developmental disabilities. The commissioner may adopt and\npromulgate any regulation reasonably necessary to implement and\neffectively exercise the powers and perform the duties conferred by this\narticle. This article shall govern the operation of programs, provision\nof services and the facilities hereinafter described and the\ncommissioner's powers and authority with respect thereto, and shall\nsupersede, as to such matters, sections of article thirty-one that are\ninconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.\n  Any provisions of this article which explicitly or implicitly apply\nto, or reference, persons who are mentally retarded, shall be deemed to\napply to, or reference, persons with developmental disabilities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>