<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16.21"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.21/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.21/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.21/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.21/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_21">
        <num>16.21</num>
        <heading>Injunctions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_21__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The supreme court may, on application of the commissioner, enjoin\nviolations or threatened violations of any provision of this article or\nviolations of the regulations of the office established pursuant to this\nchapter. Upon request of the commissioner, the attorney general may\nmaintain a proceeding in the supreme court in the name of the people of\nthe state to enjoin any such violation, provided that notice of such\nviolation or threatened violation and proposed referral to the attorney\ngeneral has been given to the violator by mailing notice thereof to the\nlast known address of the violator by registered mail. The court may,\nupon proof that such violation is one which may result in injury to any\nperson, whether or not such person is a party to such action, grant a\ntemporary restraining order upon such terms as may be just, pending the\ndetermination of the proceeding. No security on the part of the state\nshall be required.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_21__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the duty of the attorney general upon the request of\nthe commissioner to bring an action for an injunction against any person\nwho violates, disobeys or disregards any term or provision of this\nchapter or of any lawful notice, order or regulation pursuant thereto;\nprovided, however, that the commissioner shall furnish the attorney\ngeneral with such material, evidentiary matter or proof as may be\nrequested by the attorney general for the prosecution of such an action.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>