<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.35"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.35"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16.35"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-16.35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_35">
        <num>16.35</num>
        <heading>Developmental disabilities services quality improvement demonstration program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_35__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this section "facility" means any not-for-profit\nor public agency regulated by the office that provides services funded\nin whole or in part by the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_35__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any law, rule or regulation to the contrary, the\ncommissioner shall, within amounts appropriated, including federal\nfinancial participation if available, establish a demonstration program\nto improve the quality of care for facility clients through the increase\nor improvement of direct care staff at such facilities. In furtherance\nof such demonstration program for facilities selected through a\ncompetitive process, rates of payment or state aid shall be adjusted\naccordingly. Requests for proposals for eligible projects shall be\nissued by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_35__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such eligible projects shall be designated by the commissioner and\nmay include:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_16_35__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>an increase in direct care staff, either facility wide or targeted\nat a particular area of care or shift;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_16_35__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>increased training and education of direct care staff, including\nallowing direct care staff to increase their level of licensure or\ncertification relevant to facility care;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_16_35__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>efforts to decrease staff turn-over through wage, employee benefit\nimprovements, or other means; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_16_35__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>other efforts related to the recruitment and retention of direct\ncare staff that will effect the quality of care at such facility.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_35__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall consider, in selecting projects, the\nlikelihood that such project will improve the care for the residents of\nthe facility, the financial need of the facility and such other matters\nas the commissioner deems appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_35__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adjustments to rates of payment or state aid made pursuant to this\nsection shall be subject to available appropriations and shall not, in\naggregate, exceed five million dollars annually. The program shall\ncommence on April first, two thousand seven and end on March\nthirty-first, two thousand ten.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_35__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before June thirtieth, two thousand ten, the commissioner\nshall contract with an independent consultant to evaluate and report to\nthe commissioner, the speaker of the assembly and the temporary\npresident of the senate on the impact that the demonstration project has\nhad upon direct care staff recruitment, retention and quality of\nservices provided.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>