<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.06"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.06"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19.06"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.06/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.06/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.06/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.06/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_06">
        <num>19.06</num>
        <heading>Advisory council on underage alcohol consumption and youth substance abuse</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Council" shall mean the advisory council on underage alcohol\nconsumption and youth substance abuse created by this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Chairperson" shall mean the chairperson of the advisory council\non underage alcohol consumption and youth substance abuse.\n  2. Advisory council on underage alcohol consumption and youth\nsubstance abuse. There is hereby created an advisory council on underage\nalcohol consumption and youth substance abuse. The council shall consist\nof twenty-one members, who are broadly representative of the various\ngroups in society which are stakeholders in the effort to combat\nunderage alcohol consumption and youth substance abuse. Seven members\nshall be appointed by the governor, seven members by the temporary\npresident of the senate and seven members by the speaker of the\nassembly. In making such appointments, due consideration shall be given\nto the recommendations made by representative civic, educational, legal\nand advocacy groups and associations concerned with, or otherwise\nengaged in, the representation of the interests of the youth of New York\nstate.  The commissioner, the chairman of the state liquor authority,\nthe commissioner of mental health, the attorney general, the temporary\npresident of the senate and the speaker of the assembly shall be\nex-officio members of the council.\n  3. Term of office for council members.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term of office for each\nmember of the council shall be two years. Vacancies in the council\noccurring, other than by expiration of a term, shall be filled for the\nremainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as original\nappointments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the beginning of each two year term, the members of the council\nshall choose one member of the council to be a chairperson and one\nmember to be vice-chairperson. The members of the council shall receive\nno compensation for their services, but shall be reimbursed for all\nexpenses actually and necessarily incurred by them in the performance of\ntheir duties under this section within the amount made available by\nappropriation therefor.\n  4. Powers and duties of the council. The council shall have the\nfollowing powers and duties:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To receive information with respect to, and to study and analyze,\nincidents of underage consumption of alcoholic beverages, youth\nsubstance abuse, and to examine the elements of such incidents to\nidentify those factors that are consistently associated with such\nbehavior;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To identify and analyze the responses to underage drinking and\nyouth substance abuse made by governmental officials, including law\nenforcement officials and prosecutors, and to make recommendations as to\nwhether such responses appear to be achieving decreases in the incidence\nof such behavior, and if not, whether it appears that a change is\nrequired in policies and procedures;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To conduct public hearings as may be necessary to carry out its\nfunctions under this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To make recommendations with respect to the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>educational programs to teach children the dangers of underage\ndrinking and youth substance abuse;\n  (ii) training programs for law enforcement officials and prosecutors\nto sensitize them to the special nature of youth-related crime to\nencourage them to develop appropriate responses;\n  (iii) the appropriateness and effectiveness of existing civil and\ncriminal laws in redressing underage drinking and youth substance abuse\nand any changes that should be made in such laws; and\n  (iv) such other matters as may be deemed appropriate by the council\nafter consultation with involved parties;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To promulgate any necessary rules of order or procedures relating\nto the administration and performance of the powers and duties of the\ncouncil pursuant to this section; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_06__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To perform all other tasks necessary and convenient to carry out\nthe functions, powers and duties of the council and to effectuate the\npurposes of this section.\n  5. Report. The council shall submit a written report to the governor,\ntemporary president of the senate and the speaker of the assembly by no\nlater than October first of the year next succeeding the effective date\nof this section and annually thereafter, setting forth the\nrecommendations and activities of the council on matters within the\nscope of its powers and duties as set forth in this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>