<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.18-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.18-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-10-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19.18-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.18-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.18-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.18-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.18-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_18_C">
        <num>19.18-C</num>
        <heading>Corrections-based substance use disorder treatment and transition services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Alcohol, benzodiazepine, heroin and opioid withdrawal management;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At least one formulation of every form of medication assisted\ntreatments approved for the treatment of a substance use disorder by the\nFederal Food and Drug Administration necessary to ensure that each\nindividual participating in the program receives the particular form\nfound to be the most effective at treating and meeting their individual\nneeds. The commissioner may allow jails a limited exemption to providing\nopioid full agonist treatment medications where the commissioner\ndetermines that no providers that have received the required\naccreditation are located within a reasonable distance of the facility.\nJails that do not have the resources available to meet standards set\nforth herein may apply to the commissioner for a limited exception\nallowing such jail to enter into an agreement with a community- or\njail-based program offering substance use disorder treatment and\ntransition services to provide such services to individuals in such\njails. Any such determination shall be reviewed on a regular basis;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Group and individual counseling and clinical support;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Peer support;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Discharge planning; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Re-entry and transitional supports.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After a medical screening, incarcerated individuals who are\ndetermined to suffer from a substance use disorder for which medication\nassisted treatment exists shall be offered placement in the medication\nassisted treatment program. Placement in such program shall not be\nmandatory.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each participating incarcerated individual shall work with an\nauthorized specialist to develop an individualized treatment plan,\nincluding an appropriate level of counseling and planning for continuity\nof care upon return to the community.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Decisions regarding type, dosage, or duration of any medication\nregimen shall be made by a qualified health care professional licensed\nor certified under title eight of the education law who is authorized to\nadminister such medication in conjunction with the incarcerated\nindividual.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Participation in the medication assisted treatment program shall\nnot be unreasonably withheld from a qualified incarcerated individual.\nAn incarcerated individual using medication assisted treatment prior to\nsuch individual's incarceration shall be eligible to, upon request by\nsuch individual, continue such treatment in the medication assisted\ntreatment program for any period of time during the duration of such\nindividual's incarceration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be denied participation in the program on the\nbasis of a positive drug screening upon entering custody or upon intake\ninto the program; nor shall any person receive a disciplinary infraction\nfor such positive drug screening. No person shall be removed from, or\ndenied participation in the program on the basis of having received any\ndisciplinary infraction:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>before entry into the program; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_18_C__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nduring participation in the program.\n  4. Within amounts appropriated therefor, funding shall be made avail-\nable pursuant to criteria established by the office of addiction\nservices and supports in consultation with local governmental units,\nwhich shall take into consideration the local needs and resources as\nidentified by local governmental units, the average daily jail\npopulation, the average number of persons incarcerated in the jail that\nrequire substance use disorder services and such other factors as may be\ndeemed necessary.\n  5. Any jail-based substance use disorder treatment and transition\nservices program that is already in operation at the time this act shall\nhave become law and meets or exceeds the standards set forth in this\nsection shall be deemed to have met the requirements of subdivisions one\nand two of this section. Such programs shall certify annually in writing\nto the commissioner that they have met or exceeded the standards set\nforth herein.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>