<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.17"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.17"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19.17"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_17">
        <num>19.17</num>
        <heading>Programs, services, and operation of facilities in the office of alcoholism and substance abuse services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_17__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall establish policy and procedure for the\norganization, administration, and operation of facilities under his or\nher jurisdiction. He or she shall make provision for the efficient\nrendition of services to patients by such facilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_17__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall establish the areas which each facility\nunder his or her jurisdiction shall serve and the categories of patients\nwhich each such facility shall receive, retain, or treat. The\ncommissioner shall provide for priority of admission for persons whose\nchildren have been placed in foster care or are in jeopardy of being so\nplaced pursuant to article ten of the family court act or article six of\nthe social services law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_17__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may permit the other offices of the department\nand any public or private non-profit organization or political\nsubdivision of the state to operate programs for the mentally disabled\nnot inconsistent with the programs and objectives of the department, in\nany facility under his or her jurisdiction.  The commissioner may permit\nany facility under his or her jurisdiction to operate programs for the\nmentally disabled, not inconsistent with the programs and objectives of\nthe department, under contracts or agreements with other offices within\nthe department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_17__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall direct and carry on basic clinical,\nepidemiological, social science, evaluative, and statistical research in\nchemical abuse and dependence either individually or in conjunction with\nother agencies, public or private, and, within the amounts made\navailable by appropriation therefor, develop pilot programs. In\npursuance of the foregoing and notwithstanding any other provision of\nlaw, the office may establish, direct, and carry on experimental pilot\nclinical programs providing for early intervention and for treatment of\nchemical abuse and dependence. Such treatment may include the\nadministration, under medical supervision and control, of experimental\nsubstances.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_17__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office shall have the authority to gather information and\nmaintain statistical and other records relating to chemical abuse and\ndependence services in the state. Any person licensed or otherwise\npermitted to dispense, administer, or conduct research with respect to a\ncontrolled substance in the course of a licensed professional practice\nor research license pursuant to article thirty-three of the public\nhealth law and all public officials having duties to perform with\nrespect to controlled substances or users of such substances shall\nreport and supply such information to the office in relation thereto as\nthe office shall by rule, regulation, or order require consistent with\nappropriate state and federal law relative to the confidentiality of\npatient records.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_17__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be in the office the facilities named below for the\ncare, treatment and rehabilitation of the mentally disabled and for\nclinical research and teaching in the science and skills required for\nthe care, treatment and rehabilitation of such mentally disabled.\n  R.E. Blaisdell Addiction Treatment Center\n  Bronx Addiction Treatment Center\n  C.K. Post Addiction Treatment Center\n  Creedmoor Addiction Treatment Center\n  Dick Van Dyke Addiction Treatment Center\n  Kingsboro Addiction Treatment Center\n  McPike Addiction Treatment Center\n  Richard C. Ward Addiction Treatment Center\n  J.L. Norris Addiction Treatment Center\n  South Beach Addiction Treatment Center\n  St. Lawrence Addiction Treatment Center\n  Stutzman Addiction Treatment Center\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_17__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office shall have the authority to establish an information\npolicy and data reporting procedure for the collection, use, and\ndisclosure of data from providers of chemical dependence services,\nincluding procedures to ensure the protection of patient-identifying\ninformation and data gathered pursuant to section 19.16 of this article,\nwhich shall be deemed confidential except as otherwise provided by law\nincluding, but not limited to, articles six and six-A of the public\nofficers law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>