<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.28"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.28"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19.28"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.28/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.28/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.28/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.28/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_28">
        <num>19.28</num>
        <heading>Receipt and disbursement of federal funds</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_28__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may receive, use, or distribute federal financial\nor technical assistance to support construction of facilities, research,\nstaffing, or other programs or activities for alcoholism, substance\nabuse, or chemical dependence services, appropriated under federal\nlegislation or regulations or under other federal legislation or\nregulations which provide assistance to the mentally disabled, including\nbut not limited to vocational rehabilitation programs, alcoholism\nprograms, substance abuse programs, poverty programs, or special\nprograms for children or the aged.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_28__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may promulgate rules and regulations relating to\nthe commissioner's powers and duties to implement any provision of state\nor federal law involving the receipt, use or disbursement of federal\nfinancial or technical assistance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_28__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of taxation and finance shall be the custodian of\nfederal financial assistance granted or allocated to the office by the\nUnited States. These funds shall be paid out on the audit and warrant of\nthe comptroller on the certificate of the commissioner, or his or her\nauthorized representative.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_28__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the rules and regulations of the commissioner, any\nfunds made available to the office by the United States or by another\nstate agency as a federal allotment to be administered by the office may\nbe disbursed by it to a local government, voluntary nonprofit agency,\neducational agency, or other entity properly authorized to receive funds\nin fulfillment of the purposes of appropriate federal or state\nlegislation for the provision of services, construction of facilities,\nresearch, staffing, training or related programs or activities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>