<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.40"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.40"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19.40"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_40">
        <num>19.40</num>
        <heading>Provision of chemical dependence services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the office shall have\nthe authority to issue a single operating certificate for the provision\nof chemical dependence services to providers of alcoholism and/or\nsubstance abuse services previously certified or licensed pursuant to\narticles twenty-three and/or thirty-one of this chapter and who are\ndeemed by the commissioner to meet applicable requirements of article\nthirty-two of this chapter and operating regulations promulgated\nthereunder. The commissioner shall have the authority to waive any\nrequirements deemed to be duplicative or unnecessary to implement the\nprovisions of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certificates of approval and operating certificates previously\nissued under article twenty-three and/or thirty-one of this chapter\nshall remain in full force and effect until they are converted to\noperating certificates for the provision of chemical dependence services\npursuant to this chapter. Conversion shall occur upon promulgation of\napplicable chemical dependence operating regulations by the\ncommissioner, taking into consideration time which is reasonably needed\nby providers of services to come into compliance with such applicable\nregulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_40__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All providers of chemical dependence services issued operating\ncertificates pursuant to this section shall be subject to all provisions\nof this chapter applicable to providers of alcoholism services and to\nall provisions of this chapter applicable to providers of substance\nabuse services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_40__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Providers of chemical dependence services not previously certified\nor licensed pursuant to articles twenty-three and/or thirty-one of this\nchapter shall be certified for the provision of such services pursuant\nto article thirty-two of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>