<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.45*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.45*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-06-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19.45*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.45*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.45*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.45*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.45*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_45*2">
        <num>19.45*2</num>
        <heading>The council for treatment equity</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Council" shall mean the council for treatment equity, within the\noffice of addiction services and supports, created pursuant to this\nsection which shall consist of a director and any additional full or\npart-time staff the commissioner deems necessary to effectuate the\nprovisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Vulnerable populations" shall mean those who have experienced\ninjustices and disadvantages as a result of their race, ethnicity,\nsexual orientation, gender identity, disability status, age,\nsocioeconomic status and/or any other status which has caused a person\nto experience injustices and disadvantages.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Racially and ethnically diverse areas" shall mean counties where\nthe non-white population is forty percent or more or the service area of\nan agency, corporation, facility or individual providing substance use\ndisorder services where the non-white population of said area is forty\npercent or more.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Provider of services" shall mean any agency, corporation,\nfacility or individual providing substance use disorder services to\nvulnerable populations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Treatment disparities" shall mean measurable differences in\naccess to and quality of substance use disorder services as determined\nby race, ethnicity, sexual orientation, gender identity, disability\nstatus, age and socioeconomic status.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Treatment equity" shall mean achieving the highest level of\nsubstance use disorder services for all people and shall entail focused\nefforts to address avoidable inequalities by equalizing those conditions\nfor substance use disorder services for those that have experienced\ninjustices and socioeconomic disadvantages.\n  2. The council for treatment equity. There is hereby created, within\nthe office of addiction services and supports, a council for treatment\nequity. The council, in conjunction with the behavioral health services\nadvisory council, shall have the following powers and duties:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Work collaboratively with relevant state agencies, local\ngovernmental units as defined in article forty-one of this chapter and\nother affected stakeholders, including, but not limited to, providers to\nand representatives of vulnerable populations, in order to set\npriorities to achieve treatment equity in both racial and ethnically\ndiverse areas and for vulnerable populations throughout the state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Analyze collected data to determine the causes of treatment\ndisparities in both racially and ethnically diverse areas and for\nvulnerable populations throughout the state, including any economic,\nphysical, social or cultural barriers;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Develop and implement strategies aimed at achieving treatment\nequity in racially and ethnically diverse areas and among vulnerable\npopulations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Promote community involvement by conducting promotional and\neducational outreach programs regarding substance use disorders and\navailable services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_45*2__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Review the impact of current laws, rules, regulations, policies\nand programs that may be affecting the ability to achieve treatment\nequity.\n  3. Report. The council shall submit a written report to the governor,\nthe temporary president of the senate and the speaker of the assembly no\nlater than one year succeeding the effective date of this section and\nannually thereafter, setting forth the findings, recommendations and\nactivities of the council on matters within the scope of its powers and\nduties as set forth in this section.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 19.45's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>