<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.41"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.41"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19.41"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.41/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.41/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.41/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-19.41/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_41">
        <num>19.41</num>
        <heading>Facilities; receivership</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph eight of\nthis subdivision. During the interim period when such clients must\nremain in the facility, the receiver may correct or eliminate those\ndeficiencies in the facility that seriously endanger the life, health,\nor safety of such clients; provided that such correction or elimination\nof deficiencies does not include major alterations of the physical\nstructure of the facility. The receiver shall, during this period,\noperate the facility in such a manner as to guarantee safety and\nadequate care for such clients. The receiver shall have the power to let\ncontracts therefor or incur expenses in accordance with the provisions\nof applicable statutes, rules and regulations, and applicable guidelines\nestablished by the office. Any receiver who is an official or employee\nof the state of New York shall not be required to file any bond. Such\nreceiver shall collect incoming payments from all sources and apply them\nto the costs incurred in the performance of its functions as a receiver.\nThe receiver shall honor all existing leases, mortgages, and chattel\nmortgages that had previously been undertaken as obligations of the\nowners or operators of the facility. However, such receiver may make\napplication to the appointing court for recision, reformation, or such\nother relief as may be appropriate with respect to the executory\ncovenants or provisions of any contractual obligations of such owners or\noperators as may be necessary or appropriate to protect the best\ninterests of the clients served by such facility. No security interest\nin any real or personal property comprising the facility or contained\nwithin the facility shall be impaired or diminished in priority by the\nreceiver. The receiver shall compensate the owner or owners of any goods\nheld in inventory for those goods which it uses or causes to be used,\nexcept that no such compensation shall be made for any such goods for\nwhich the owner or operators of the facility have already been\n...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_41__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The appointing court, upon application of the receiver, may make\nsuch provision as justice may require for a reasonable compensation and\nreimbursement of the reasonable expenses of such receiver. The receiver\nshall be liable only in its official capacity for injury to person and\nproperty by reason of conditions of the facility in a case where an\nowner would have been liable; provided that it operates such facility in\ncompliance with the terms of its appointment, it shall not have any\nliability in its personal capacity, except for gross negligence and\nintentional acts.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_41__subsec_a__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall terminate the receivership only under any of\nthe following circumstances:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>eighteen months after the date on which it is ordered;\n  (ii) when the receiver, or other voluntary agency or not-for-profit\ncorporation satisfactory to the commissioner, has (A) agreed to continue\nthe operation of the facility, (B) entered into a satisfactory long-term\n(not less than two years) arrangement reached on a bona fide arm's\nlength basis with the owner or owners of land and/or structure on or in\nwhich the facility is or is to be located, and (C) applied for and\nreceived from the commissioner a new operating certificate or license,\nas appropriate, for the continued operation of the facility; or\n  (iii) at such times as all of the persons served by the facility have\nbeen provided alternative services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the time of termination, the receiver shall render a full and\ncomplete accounting to the court and shall make disposition of surplus\nmoney at the direction of the court.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_41__subsec_b__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who is served a copy of an order of the court\nappointing the receiver shall, upon being notified of the name and\naddress of the receiver, make all payments for goods supplied by the\nfacility, or services rendered by the facility, to the receiver. A\nreceipt shall be given for each such payment, and copies of all such\nreceipts shall be kept on file by the receiver. The amount so received\nshall be deposited by the receiver in a special account, which shall\nalso be used for all disbursements made by the receiver.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person refusing or omitting to make such a payment after such\nservice and notice may be sued therefor by the receiver. Such person\nshall not in such suit dispute the authority of the receiver to incur or\norder such expenses, or the right of the receiver to have such payments\nmade to it. The receipt of the receiver for any sum paid to it shall, in\nall suits and proceedings and for every purpose, be as effectual in\nfavor of any person holding the same as actual payment of the amount\nthereof to the owner or other person or persons who would, but for the\nprovisions of this subdivision, have been entitled to receive the sum to\nbe paid. No person shall be discharged, nor shall any contract or rights\nbe forfeited or impaired, nor any forfeiture or liability be incurred,\nby reason of any omission to pay any owner, contractor or other person\nany sum so paid to the receiver.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_41__subsec_b__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No provision contained herein shall be deemed to relieve the\nowner or operator of any civil or criminal liability incurred, or any\nduty imposed by law, by reason of acts or omissions of the owner or\noperator prior to the appointment of any receiver hereunder, nor shall\nanything contained herein be construed to suspend during the\nreceivership any obligation of the owner or operator for the payment of\nmortgages or liens.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The receiver shall not be responsible for any obligations incurred\nby the owner, operator, or prime lessor, if any, prior to the\nappointment of the receiver.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The receiver shall be entitled to use for operating and\nmaintenance expenses and the basic needs of persons served by the\nfacility a portion of the revenues due the operator during the month in\nwhich the receiver is appointed, which portion shall be established on\nthe basis of the amounts of the unpaid operating and maintenance\nexpenses for such month.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_41__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any sums determined to be due and owing by the receiver to the\nowner, operator, or prime lessor shall be off-set by any charges\ndetermined to be the obligations of the owner, operator, or prime\nlessor.\n  c.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_41__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to paragraph two of this subdivision, and subject to\nthe approval of the director of the budget, the commissioner is\nauthorized to make payments to receivers appointed pursuant to the\nprovisions of subdivision b of this section only if the receiver\ndemonstrates to the satisfaction of the commissioner that the facility's\nfunds which are available are insufficient to meet the operating and\nmaintenance expenses of the facility and the basic needs of those served\nby the facility.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_41__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of law, payments made\npursuant to this section shall be made from funds appropriated therefor\nand such payments shall be made only if a certificate of allocation and\na schedule of amounts to be available therefore shall have been issued\nby the director of the budget and a copy of such certificate filed with\nthe comptroller, the chairman of the senate fiance committee, and the\nchairman of the assembly ways and means committee. Such certificate may\nbe amended from time to time by the director of the budget, and a copy\nof each such amendment shall be filed with the comptroller, the chairman\nof the senate finance committee, and the chairman of the assembly ways\nand means committee.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>