<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-25.01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-25.01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="25.01"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-25.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-25.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-25.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-25.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_25_01">
        <num>25.01</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_25_01__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used herein:\n  1. "Local governmental unit" shall have the same meaning as that\ncontained in article forty-one of this chapter.\n  2. "Operating expenses" shall mean expenditures approved by the office\nand incurred for the maintenance and operation of substance use disorder\nand/or compulsive gambling programs, including but not limited to\nexpenditures for treatment, administration, personnel, and contractual\nservices. Operating expenses do not include capital costs and debt\nservice unless such expenses are related to the rent, financing or\nrefinancing of the design, construction, acquisition, reconstruction,\nrehabilitation or improvement of a substance use disorder and/or\ncompulsive gambling program facility pursuant to the mental hygiene\nfacilities finance program through the dormitory authority of the state\nof New York (DASNY; successor to the Facilities Development\nCorporation), or otherwise approved by the office.\n  3. "Debt service" shall mean amounts, subject to the approval of the\noffice, required to be paid to amortize obligations including principal\nand interest, assumed by or on behalf of a voluntary agency or a program\noperated by a local governmental unit.\n  4. "Capital costs" shall mean the costs of a program operated by a\nlocal governmental unit or a voluntary agency with respect to the\nacquisition of real property estates, interests, and cooperative\ninterests in realty, their design, construction, reconstruction,\nrehabilitation and improvement, original furnishings and equipment, site\ndevelopment, and appurtenances of a facility.\n  5. "State aid" shall mean financial support provided through\nappropriations of the office to support the provision of substance use\ndisorder treatment, compulsive gambling, prevention or other authorized\nservices, with the exclusion of appropriations for the purpose of\nmedical assistance.\n  6. "Voluntary agency contributions" shall mean revenue sources of\nvoluntary agencies exclusive of stat...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>