<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-30.01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-30.01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="30.01"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-30.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-30.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-30.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-30.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_30_01">
        <num>30.01</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 30.01 Legislative findings.\n  The legislature hereby finds that effective diagnosis and treatment\nfor citizens struggling with eating disorders, a complex and potentially\nlife-threatening condition, requires a continuum of interdisciplinary\nproviders and levels of care. Such effective diagnosis and treatment\nfurther requires the coordination and comprehensive management of an\nindividualized plan of care specifically oriented to the distinct needs\nof each individual.\n  The legislature further finds that, while there are numerous health\ncare providers in the state with expertise in eating disorder treatment,\nthere is no generally accessible, comprehensive system for responding to\nthese disorders. Due to the lack of such a system the legislature finds\nthat treatment, information/referral, prevention and research activities\nare fragmented and incomplete. In addition, due to the broad,\nmultifaceted needs of individuals with eating disorders, insurance\npayments for the necessary plan of care and providers is usually\nfragmented as well, leaving citizens with insufficient coverage for\nessential services and, therefore, at risk of incomplete treatment,\nrelapse, deterioration and potential death.\n  The legislature therefore declares that the state take positive action\nto facilitate the development and public identification of provider\nnetworks and care centers of excellence to provide a coordinated,\ncomprehensive system for the treatment of such disorders, as well as to\nconduct community education, prevention, information/referral and\nresearch activities. The legislature further declares that health\ncoverage by insurers and health maintenance organizations should include\ncovered services provided through such centers and that, to the extent\npossible and practicable, health plan reimbursement should be structured\nin a manner to facilitate the individualized, comprehensive and\nintegrated plans of care which such centers are required to provide.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>