<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="31.01"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31_01">
        <num>31.01</num>
        <heading>Evaluation of services for the mentally disabled</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_01__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall ensure that all services for the mentally\ndisabled, whether provided by the department, by a local governmental\nunit or by a provider of services, are periodically evaluated and that\ndepartmental budget requests reflect such evaluations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_01__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to ensure that such evaluations and the resulting reports\nand data generated are comparable for all services to the mentally\ndisabled throughout the state, the commissioner shall promulgate rules\nand regulations requiring the development of evaluation criteria and\nmethods which shall include, but not be limited to:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_31_01__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>uniform definitions of services for the mentally disabled;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_31_01__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>uniform financial and clinical reporting procedures;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_31_01__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>requirements for the generation and maintenance of uniform data\nfor all individuals receiving services from any provider of services;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_31_01__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>uniform criteria for evaluating categories of need; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_31_01__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>uniform standards for all comparable services and programs.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_01__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A timetable for development and implementation of evaluation\ncriteria and methods shall be included in such rules and regulations to\nensure the orderly and adequate compliance by the department and its\nfacilities, local governmental units and providers of services. Such\ntimetable shall also include specific dates by which such evaluation\ncriteria and methods, and the evaluation reports and data developed with\nsuch criteria and methods shall be included in the budget request\nsubmitted to the department by the department facilities, local\ngovernmental units and providers of services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_01__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_31_01__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the commissioner,\nor his designee, may require from any hospital, as defined under article\ntwenty-eight of the public health law, any information, report, or\nrecord necessary for the purpose of carrying out the functions, powers\nand duties of the commissioner related to the investigation of deaths\nand complaints of abuse, mistreatment, or neglect concerning mentally\ndisabled individuals who receive services, or had prior to death\nreceived services, in a facility as defined in section 1.03 of this\nchapter, and have been treated at such hospitals.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_31_01__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any information, report, or record requested by the commissioner\nor his designee pursuant to this subdivision shall be limited to that\ninformation that the commissioner determines necessary for the\ncompletion of his investigation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_31_01__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The information, report or record received by the commissioner or\nhis designee pursuant to this subdivision shall be subject to section\ntwo thousand eight hundred five-m, section eighteen, as added by chapter\nfour hundred ninety-seven of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-six and\narticle twenty-seven-F of the public health law, section 33.13 of this\nchapter, and any applicable federal statute or regulation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>