<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.26"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.26"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="31.26"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.26/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.26/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.26/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-31.26/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31_26">
        <num>31.26</num>
        <heading>Residential treatment facilities for children and youth</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_26__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may authorize the operation of residential\ntreatment facilities for children and youth. Such residential treatment\nfacilities may only be operated by not-for-profit organizations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_26__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall have the power to adopt rules and\nregulations governing the establishment and operation of residential\ntreatment facilities for children and youth. Such rules and regulations\nshall at least require, as a condition of issuance or retention of an\noperating certificate for a residential treatment facility for children\nand youth, that admission of children into such facilities be in\naccordance with priorities for admission of children most immediately in\nneed of such services in accordance with standards established by the\ncommissioner which shall be in accordance with federal regulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_26__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of\neducation and the commissioner of the office of children and family\nservices, shall adopt rules and regulations governing the standards for\nadmissions of individuals to residential treatment facilities required\nin section 9.51 of this chapter in accordance with federal regulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_26__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of mental health and the commissioner of social\nservices shall enter into a cooperative agreement to govern the\noperation of residential treatment facilities for children and youth by\nan authorized agency, visitation, inspection and supervision of such\nfacilities, enforcement of the conditions of operating certificates\nissued to such facilities by the department of social services and the\noffice of mental health, and protection of the confidentiality of\nclinical information regarding patients at such residential treatment\nfacilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_26__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office of mental health, the department of social services and\nthe department of education shall establish a uniform system by which\nauthorized agencies which operate residential treatment facilities for\nchildren and youth report the cost of operating such facilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31_26__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office of mental health shall, in accordance with the\nprovisions of section four thousand four of the education law, be\nresponsible for paying the tuition costs for children who are receiving\ncare in a residential treatment facility for children and youth if such\nchildren are residents of this state and such children were not placed\nin such a facility by a school district, social services district, the\ndivision for youth or the family court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>