<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-05-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="36.01"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_36_01">
        <num>36.01</num>
        <heading>Crisis stabilization centers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_01__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioners are authorized to jointly license crisis\nstabilization centers subject to the availability of state and federal\nfunding.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_01__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A crisis stabilization center shall serve as a voluntary and\nurgent service provider for persons at risk of a mental health or\nsubstance abuse crisis or who are experiencing a crisis related to a\npsychiatric and/or substance use disorder that are in need of crisis\nstabilization services. Each crisis stabilization center shall provide\nor contract to provide person centered and patient driven crisis\nstabilization services for mental health or substance use twenty-four\nhours per day, seven days per week, including but not limited to:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Engagement, triage and assessment;\n  (ii) Continuous observation;\n  (iii) Mild to moderate detoxification;\n  (iv) Sobering services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Therapeutic interventions;\n  (vi) Discharge and after care planning;\n  (vii) Telemedicine;\n  (viii) Peer support services; and\n  (ix) Medication assisted treatment.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_01__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioners shall require each crisis stabilization center\nto submit a plan. The plan shall be approved by the commissioners prior\nto the issuance of a license pursuant to this article. Each plan shall\ninclude:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the center's catchment area,\n  (ii) a description of the center's crisis stabilization services,\n  (iii) agreements or affiliations with hospitals as defined in section\n1.03 of this chapter,\n  (iv) agreements or affiliations with general hospitals or law\nenforcement to receive persons,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of local resources available to the center to\nprevent unnecessary hospitalizations of persons,\n  (vi) a description of the center's linkages with local police\nagencies, emergency medical services, ambulance services and other\ntransportation agencies,\n  (vii) a description of local resources available to the center to\nprovide appropriate community mental health and substance use disorder\nservices upon release,\n  (viii) written criteria and guidelines for the development of\nappropriate planning for persons in need of post community treatment or\nservices,\n  (ix) a statement indicating that the center has been included in an\napproved local services plan developed pursuant to article forty-one of\nthis chapter for each local government located within the center's\ncatchment area; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other information or agreements required by the commissioners.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_01__subsec_x__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Crisis stabilization centers shall participate in county and\ncommunity planning activities annually, and as additionally needed, in\norder to participate in local community service planning processes to\nensure, maintain, improve or develop community services that demonstrate\nrecovery outcomes. These outcomes include, but are not limited to,\nquality of life, socio-economic status, entitlement status, social\nnetworking, coping skills and reduction in use of crisis services.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each crisis stabilization center shall be staffed with a\nmultidisciplinary team capable of meeting the needs of individuals\nexperiencing all levels of crisis in the community, which shall include,\nbut not be limited to, at least one psychiatrist or psychiatric nurse\npractitioner, a credentialed alcoholism and substance abuse counselor\nand one peer support specialist on duty and available at all times.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioners shall promulgate regulations necessary to the\noperation of such crisis stabilization centers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a crisis stabilization center has been established prior to\nthe effective date of this article, the previously established center\nmay be issued a license where the provider can demonstrate substantial\ncompliance with minimum crisis service standards necessary for patient\nsafety and program efficacy.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purpose of addressing unique rural service delivery needs\nand conditions, the commissioners shall provide technical assistance for\nthe establishment of crisis stabilization centers otherwise approved\nunder the provisions of this section, including technical assistance to\npromote and facilitate the establishment of such centers in rural areas\nin the state or combinations of rural counties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioners shall develop guidelines for educational\nmaterials to assist crisis stabilization centers in educating local\npractitioners, community mental health and substance abuse programs,\nhospitals, law enforcement and peers. Such materials shall include\nappropriate education relating to de-escalation techniques, cultural\ncompetency, the recovery process, mental health, substance use, and\navoidance of aggressive confrontation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_01__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within the amounts appropriated, the commissioners shall arrange\nfor appropriate training to law enforcement entities, first responders,\nincluding but not limited to firefighters and emergency medical services\npersonnel, and any other entities deemed appropriate by the\ncommissioners, located within the catchment area of a crisis\nstabilization center. The training may include but not be limited to:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_01__subsec_g__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>crisis intervention team training;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_01__subsec_g__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>mental health first aid;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_01__subsec_g__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nimplicit bias training; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_01__subsec_g__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>naloxone training. Such training may be\nprovided in an electronic format or other format as deemed appropriate\nby the commissioners. The commissioners may contract with an\norganization with the knowledge and expertise in providing the training\nrequired under this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>