<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.04"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.04"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="36.04"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.04/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.04/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.04/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-36.04/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_36_04">
        <num>36.04</num>
        <heading>Certified community behavioral health clinics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_04__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioners are authorized to jointly certify community\nbehavioral health clinics, subject to the availability of state and\nfederal funding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_04__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certified community behavioral health clinics shall provide\ncoordinated, comprehensive behavioral health care, including mental\nhealth and addiction services, primary care screening, and case\nmanagement services, in accordance with certified community behavioral\nhealth clinic standards established by the United States department of\nhealth and human services substance abuse and mental health services\nadministration and the commissioners of the office of mental health and\nthe office of addiction services and supports.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioners shall require each proposed certified community\nbehavioral health clinic to submit a plan, which shall be approved by\nthe commissioners prior to the issuance of an operating certificate\npursuant to this article. Such plan shall include:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a description of the clinic's character and competency to provide\ncertified community behavioral health clinic services across the\nlifespan, including how the clinic will ensure access to crisis services\nat all times and accept all patients regardless of ability to pay;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a description of the clinic's catchment area;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a statement indicating that the clinic has been included in an\napproved local services plan developed pursuant to article forty-one of\nthis title for each local government located within the clinic's\ncatchment area;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>where executed, agreements establishing formal relationships with\ndesignated collaborating organizations to provide certain certified\ncommunity behavioral health clinic services, consistent with guidance\nissued by the United States department of health and human services\nsubstance abuse and mental health services administration and the office\nof mental health and the office of addiction services and supports;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a staffing plan driven by local needs assessment, licensing, and\ntraining to support service delivery;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a description of the clinic's data-driven approach to quality\nimprovement;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a description of how consumers are represented in governance of\nthe clinic;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>all financial information in the form and format required by the\noffice of mental health and the office of addiction services and\nsupports; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_36_04__subsec_c__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any other information or agreements required by the commissioners.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_04__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a certified community behavioral health clinic has been\nestablished and is participating on the effective date of this section\nin the federal certified community behavioral health clinic\ndemonstration awarded to the state by the United States department of\nhealth and human services substance abuse and mental health services\nadministration, the previously established clinic may be certified where\nthe clinic demonstrates compliance with the certification standards\nestablished pursuant to this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36_04__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioners shall promulgate any rule or regulation\nnecessary to effectuate this section.\n  * NB Effective November 3, 2023\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>