<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_15">
        <num>41.15</num>
        <heading>Approved plans and state aid</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Net operating costs of programs incurred pursuant to an approved\nlocal services plan in accordance with the regulations of the\ncommissioner or commissioners of the office or offices of the department\nhaving jurisdiction of the services and approved by the commissioner or\ncommissioners of the office or offices of the department having\njurisdiction of the services shall be eligible for state aid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Long range goals, intermediate range plans, and annual plans shall\nmeet requirements for comprehensive services set for each local\ngovernment by the commissioners of the offices of the department after\ntaking into consideration local needs and available resources. These\nservices shall be concerned with diagnosis, care, treatment, social and\nvocational rehabilitation, community residential services licensed by\nthe department of mental hygiene, research, consultation and public\neducation, education and training of personnel, control and prevention\nof mental disabilities, and the general furtherance of mental capability\nand health. As part of the local services plan required to establish\neligibility for state aid in accordance with the provisions herein, each\nlocal governmental unit shall submit a five-year plan and annual\nimplementation plans and budgets which shall reflect local needs and\nresources, including the needs and resources available for the provision\nof community support services, and the role of facilities in the\ndepartment in the provision of required services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to regulations for special circumstances as established by\nthe commissioner or commissioners of the office or offices of the\ndepartment having jurisdiction of the services, no annual plan or\nintermediate range plan of the local governmental unit shall be approved\nunless it indicates that reasonable efforts are being made to extend or\nimprove local services in each succeeding local fiscal year in\naccordance with the statewide long range goals and objectives of the\ndepartment for the development and integration of state, regional, and\nlocal services for the mentally disabled.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Beginning the first day of July, nineteen hundred seventy-eight,\nallocations of state aid for operating costs shall be made to eligible\nlocal governental units in advance no more than ten days after the\nbeginning of each quarter. Such quarterly payments shall be adjusted,\nwhen necessary, to reflect actual eligible net operating costs,\nprojected eligible net operating costs and appropriations available and\nshall be subject to audit and readjustment to comply with all applicable\nprovisions of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_15__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Capital costs incurred by a local government or by a voluntary\nagency, pursuant to an approved local services plan and in accordance\nwith the regulations of the commissioner or commissioners of the office\nor offices of the department having jurisdiction of the services and\nwith the approval of the commissioner or commissioners having\njurisdiction of the services, shall be eligible for state aid pursuant\nto the provisions of this article. Capital costs incurred by a voluntary\nagency shall be eligible for state aid only if incurred pursuant to an\nagreement between the voluntary agency and the local governmental unit\nwhere the construction is located. Such agreement shall contain the\napproval by the local governmental unit of such construction and an\nagreement by such unit to include the program of the voluntary agency in\nits plans and proposals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_15__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Services made available to or provided for children attending\npublic schools, for which aid is sought pursuant to this chapter, shall\nbe made available to or provided to all school children upon request by\nthe authorities of their schools.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>