<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.18"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.18"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41.18"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.18/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.18/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.18/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.18/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_18">
        <num>41.18</num>
        <heading>Local services plan; state aid</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A local services plan is a plan for the rendition of local\nservices.  Such a plan must have been developed by the local\ngovernmental unit with the involvement of consumers, consumer groups,\nvoluntary agencies and other providers of services, in accordance with\nthe regulations of the commissioner and must be approved by the\ncommissioner in order to be eligible for state aid. A local services\nplan shall contain a comprehensive proposal for annual and intermediate\nrange plans and expenditures by the local governmental unit and by\nvoluntary agencies pursuant to contract with such local governmental\nunit. A local services plan shall contain provisions to assure that\nthere is planning and coordination with the delivery of community\nsupport services to mentally ill persons, in accordance with section\n41.47 of this article. An annual plan must be supported by specific\nbudgets.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Local governments shall be granted state aid, in accordance\nwith the provisions of this subdivision, for approved net operating\ncosts pursuant to an approved local services plan at the rate of fifty\npercent of the amount incurred during the local fiscal year by such\nlocal governments and by voluntary agencies pursuant to contract with\nsuch local governments; provided, however, that a local government\nhaving a population of less than two hundred thousand shall be granted\nstate aid at the rate of seventy-five percent for the first one hundred\nthousand dollars of its approved net operating costs. Notwithstanding\nthe foregoing, local governments shall be granted state aid of one\nhundred percent of the net operating costs expended by such local\ngovernments and by voluntary agencies pursuant to contract with such\nlocal governments for services to people with developmental disabilities\nwho were patients in a state facility for a continuous period of five or\nmore years following the first day of January, nineteen hundred\nsixty-nine, provided that such services are rendered in accordance with\nan approved local services plan. Such one hundred percent state aid for\nservices to such persons shall be also provided to a voluntary agency\npursuant to a direct contract between such agency and an office of the\ndepartment whenever such services provided pursuant to such direct\ncontract are rendered in accordance with an approved local services plan\nfor servicing such clients. For purposes of determining whether a person\nhas been a patient in such a facility for a continuous period of five\nyears or more, if a person who has been discharged or released from such\na facility is thereafter returned to such a facility within ninety days\nof the discharge or release, the period of time between such discharge\nor release and such return shall not constitute an interruption of, and\nshall be counted as part of, the continuous period.\n  (ii) Notwithstanding the foregoin...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the foregoing, local governments and voluntary\nagencies may be granted state aid of up to one hundred percent of the\nnet operating costs expended by such localities and by voluntary\nagencies pursuant to contracts with the office of mental health for\nprograms transferred from the task force on integrated projects for\nyouth and chemical dependency established pursuant to chapter eight\nhundred twelve of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-seven. Such aid\nmay include funds transferred from such task force to the office of\nmental health.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Local governments and voluntary agencies shall be granted state\naid for capital costs pursuant to an approved local services plan at a\nrate not to exceed fifty percent of the amount eligible for state aid;\nprovided, however, that state aid for capital costs for that portion of\na general hospital which provides inpatient psychiatric services to the\nmentally ill pursuant to an approved local services plan shall be\nreimbursed at the rate of thirty-three and one-third percent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The liability of the state in any state fiscal year for state aid\npursuant to this section shall exclude chemical dependence services,\nwhich are subject to article twenty-five of this chapter, and shall be\nlimited to the amounts appropriated for such state aid by the\nlegislature for such state fiscal year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to qualify for the state aid available as described in\nsubdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, a local services plan must\ninclude provisions for the development of appropriate residential\naccommodations, consistent with the present and anticipated needs of the\nmentally disabled with the jurisdiction of the local governmental unit.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_18__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No voluntary agency receiving state funds pursuant to this article\nshall expend any state moneys except for value received and shall not\nmake any charitable contribution of state funds or use any state funds\nto pay above market value for any goods or services, except as\nauthorized by the offices of the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>