<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41.24"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_24">
        <num>41.24</num>
        <heading>Study on alternative to net deficit funding</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_24__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A cost-related funding methodology which adequately pays for\nservices necessary to provide appropriate care, which recognizes\ngeographic distinctions as they relate to cost and which ensures that\nproviders are reimbursed for the fixed or uncontrollable operational\ncosts such as interest, depreciation, property, capitalized development\ncosts, insurance and reasonable and necessary personnel costs.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_24__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A guarantee of minimum maintenance of local government tax levy\nfinancial participation at current levels.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_24__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A system of incentives to promote the maximization of alternative\nfunding sources including but not limited to contract income and\ncharitable contributions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_24__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An evaluation of the relationship between net deficit funded\nprograms and other non-residential programs, excluding day treatment,\nand a determination whether or not to incorporate the funding of all\nsuch programs into a unified funding methodology.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_24__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Information relating to a demonstration project undertaken by the\noffice in certain developmental disabilities services offices to examine\npossible modifications in the use of medical assistance funding for\nprograms and services pursuant to the provisions of a federal grant.\nSuch information shall include specific recommendations for applying the\nresults of such demonstration project to programs and services operated\nby voluntary providers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_24__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An examination of the implications of department of mental hygiene\nconsolidated fiscal reporting process and an incorporation, as\nappropriate, of such implications into the formulation of\nrecommendations.\n  Such study shall be prepared in conjunction with a council of not more\nthan ten persons which shall include not for profit provider\norganizations, parents of persons with developmental disabilities,\nrepresentatives of local government and others to be appointed by the\ncommissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>