<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.34"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.34"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41.34"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.34/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.34/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.34/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.34/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_34">
        <num>41.34</num>
        <heading>Site selection of community residential facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_34__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this section, the following definitions shall\napply:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Community residential facility for the disabled" means a\nsupportive living facility with four to fourteen residents or a\nsupervised living facility subject to licensure by the office of mental\nhealth or the office for people with developmental disabilities which\nprovides a residence for up to fourteen individuals with mental\ndisabilities, including residential treatment facilities for children\nand youth.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Sponsoring agency" means an agency or unit of government, a\nvoluntary agency or any other person or organization which intends to\nestablish or operate a community residential facility for the disabled.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Municipality" means an incorporated village if a facility is to\nbe located therein, a town if the facility is to be located therein and\nnot simultaneously within an incorporated village, or a city, except\nthat in the city of New York, the community board with jurisdiction over\nthe area in which such a facility is to be located shall be considered\nthe municipality.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the office of the\ndepartment responsible for issuance of license and operating certificate\nto the proposed community residential facility.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_34__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a sponsoring agency intends to establish a residential facility\nfor the disabled within a municipality but does not have a specific site\nselected, it may notify the chief executive officer of the municipality\nin writing of its intentions and include in such notice a description of\nthe nature, size and community support requirements of the program.\nProvided, however, nothing in this subdivision shall preclude the\nproposed establishment of a site pursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a site has been selected by the sponsoring agency, it\nshall notify the chief executive officer of the municipality in writing\nand include in such notice the specific address of the site, the type of\ncommunity residence, the number of residents and the community support\nrequirements of the program. Such notice shall also contain the most\nrecently published data compiled pursuant to section four hundred\nsixty-three of the social services law which can reasonably be expected\nto permit the municipality to evaluate all such facilities affecting the\nnature and character of the area wherein such proposed facility is to be\nlocated. The municipality shall have forty days after the receipt of\nsuch notice to:\n  (A) approve the site recommended by the sponsoring agency;\n  (B) suggest one or more suitable sites within its jurisdiction which\ncould accommodate such a facility; or\n  (C) object to the establishment of a facility of the kind described by\nthe sponsoring agency because...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prior to forwarding a response to the sponsoring agency and the\ncommissioner, the municipality may hold a public hearing pursuant to\nlocal law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the municipality approves the site recommended by the\nsponsoring agency, the sponsoring agency shall seek to establish the\nfacility at the approved site.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the site or sites suggested by the municipality are\nsatisfactory with regard to the nature, size and community support\nrequirements of the program of the proposed facility and the area in\nwhich such site or sites are located does not already include an\nexcessive number of community residential facilities for the mentally\ndisabled or similar facilities licensed by other state agencies, the\nsponsoring agency shall seek to establish its facility at one of the\nsites designated by the municipality.\n  If the municipality suggests a site or sites which are not\nsatisfactory to the sponsoring agency, the agency shall so notify the\nmunicipality which shall have fifteen days to suggest an alternative\nsite or sites for the proposed community residential facility.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the event the municipality objects to establishment of a\nfacility in the municipality because to do so would result in such a\nconcentration of community residential facilities for persons with\nmental disabilities or combination of such facilities and other\nfacilities licensed by other state agencies that the nature and\ncharacter of areas within the municipality would be substantially\naltered; or the sponsoring agency objects to the establishment of a\nfacility in the area or areas suggested by the municipality; or in the\nevent that the municipality and sponsoring agency cannot agree upon a\nsite, either the sponsoring agency or the municipality may request an\nimmediate hearing before the commissioner to resolve the issue. The\ncommissioner shall personally or by a hearing officer conduct such a\nhearing within fifteen days of such a request.\n  In reviewing any such objections, the need for such facilities in the\nmunicipality shall be considered as shall the existing concen...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_34__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Review of a decision rendered by a commissioner pursuant to this\nsection may be had in a proceeding pursuant to article seventy-eight of\nthe civil practice law and rules commenced within thirty days of the\ndetermination of the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_34__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A licensing authority shall not issue an operating certificate\nto a sponsoring agency for operation of a facility if the sponsoring\nagency does not notify the municipality of its intention to establish a\nprogram as required by subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section. Any operating\ncertificate issued without compliance with the provisions of this\nsection shall be considered null and void and continued operation of the\nfacility may be enjoined.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_34__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The office of mental health and the office for people with\ndevelopmental disabilities shall not issue an operating certificate for\nthe operation of a supportive living facility or a supervised living\nfacility of more than fourteen residents if the agency or unit of\ngovernment, voluntary agency or any other person or organization which\nintends to establish or operate such a facility does not notify the\nchief executive officer of the municipality in which that facility is to\nbe established in writing of the intention to establish such facility\nand include in such notice the specific address of the site, the type of\nresidence, the number of residents and the community support\nrequirements of the program; provided, however, that nothing contained\nin this paragraph shall either be construed to require facilities of\nmore than fourteen beds to meet any other requirement of this section,\nor to deem such facilities family units for the purposes of local laws\nand ordinances.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_34__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A community residence established pursuant to this section and\nfamily care homes shall be deemed a family unit, for the purposes of\nlocal laws and ordinances.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>