<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.40*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.40*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41.40*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.40*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.40*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.40*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.40*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_40*2">
        <num>41.40*2</num>
        <heading>Respite services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_40*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Definitions. When read in this article:\n  1. "Respite" shall mean the provision of intermittent temporary\nsubstitute care of mentally retarded or developmentally disabled persons\non behalf of and in the absence of the parent or legal guardian of the\nmentally retarded or developmentally disabled person, for the purpose of\nproviding relief from the stresses of responsibilities concommitant with\nproviding continued care. Respite shall not exceed forty-two days in any\ncalendar year for any individual except where authorized by the\ncommissioner, subject to the approval of the director of the budget.\n  2. "Provider" shall mean any person, firm, corporation, governmental\nsubdivision or state agency which renders respite services including,\nbut not limited to: individuals, family care providers and volunteers.\nIndividuals who are a parent or legal guardian of a disabled person\nreceiving the respite service may be providers only where respite\nservice is rendered as part of a voluntary in-kind program approved\nhereunder.\n  3. "Sponsor" shall mean any person, firm, corporation, governmental\nsubdivision or state agency approved by the commissioner which contracts\nwith the office for purposes of a demonstration project pursuant to this\nchapter and which is responsible for the recruitment, coordination and\narrangement of provider services in a manner which meets client needs,\nthe general supervision of the demonstration project, and the submission\nof such information or reports as may be required by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_40*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Respite demonstration programs. 1. The commissioner is hereby\nauthorized to establish respite demonstration projects for the purposes\nof establishing eligibility criteria for respite services; evaluating\nthe demand for respite services and the means of effectively,\nefficiently and economically meeting such demand; ascertaining the\nrespite services available and necessary to meet the demand; evaluating\nthe effectiveness of utilizing paid providers which are not state\nagencies for the provision of respite services; evaluating the viability\nof financing the provision of respite services through user fees and by\nlocal government units; evaluating the effectiveness and efficiency of\nutilizing a program of voluntary in-kind services for the provision of\nrespite; evaluating the relationship between respite and the need for\ninstitutionalization; identifying the costs of providing such services;\nand the effectiveness of continuing such projects. The commissioner\nshall establish regulations as may be necessary for the implementation\nof such demonstration projects.\n  2. The commissioner is authorized to demonstrate, where appropriate,\nthe viability of the provision of insurance coverage necessary to\nprotect and defend providers from liability for claims arising out of\nthe provision of voluntary in-kind respite services.\n  3. The commissioner, within four months after the effective date of\nthis section, shall publicize the existence of, and make available,\napplication forms for such demonstration projects.\n  4. Such application forms shall contain notification of the purposes\nof respite projects as set forth in paragraph one of this subdivision\nand shall require the submission of such information as the commissioner\ndeems necessary for the evaluation of such proposed demonstration\nprojects. This information shall include, but not be limited to:\n  i. the identity and qualifications of the sponsor and provider or\nproviders and a plan for the coordinat...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_40*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before the first day of January, nineteen hundred\neighty-four the commissioner shall issue a report to the governor, the\ndirector of the budget, the chairman of the senate finance committee,\nand the chairman of the assembly ways and means committee evaluating the\nappropriateness of continuing respite projects which shall include, but\nnot be limited to:\n  1. An analysis of the effectiveness of respite in promoting the\ncontinuance of quality care for such mentally retarded and\ndevelopmentally disabled persons.\n  2. A qualitative and quantitative analysis of respite services\nrendered by providers herein, together with demographic analysis of the\nfamilies and mentally retarded or developmentally disabled persons\nparticipating in the project and the degree of disability of\nparticipants.\n  3. An assessment of the nature and extent of the demands for respite\nservices and an analysis of accessibility and availability of services\nto meet this demand.\n  4. Specific identification of any factors which significantly enhance\nor inhibit the successful provision of respite.\n  5. A comparative assessment of the costs, efficiency and effectiveness\nof each type of service or combination of services provided either\npursuant to this section or otherwise existing.\n  6. Methods for funding respite services, including:\n  i. state financial support;\n  ii. federal funds;\n  iii. local funds;\n  iv. available third party reimbursement for qualified services;\n  v. user fees; and\n  vi. in-kind services for users of respite services.\n  7. A financial report for each project.\n  8. A qualitative and quantitative description of respite services\nprovided through developmental centers and the home care program and any\nother respite services provided through the office or any other provider\nas well as an analysis of the effectiveness and efficiency of such\nrespite services.\n  9. Recommendations for client eligibility criteria for all respite\nservices described ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_40*2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No funds shall be paid to any parent or guardian for the provision\nof respite services to his or her own child or dependent.\n  * NB Expired March 31, 1984\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 41.40\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>