<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.49*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.49*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41.49*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.49*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.49*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.49*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.49*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_49*2">
        <num>41.49*2</num>
        <heading>Community based mental health services for seriously emotionally disturbed children</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_49*2__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is caused by a medically determined mental illness as evidenced by\na primary psychiatric diagnosis by a physician, or is caused by other\nserious emotional disturbance as defined by regulations of the\ncommissioner of mental health;\n  (ii) has continued or is likely to continue for a period of at least\none year;\n  (iii) would cause substantial risk of psychiatric hospitalization in\nthe absence of community based mental health services; and\n  (iv) results in substantial functional limitations in two or more of\nthe following areas: (A) self-care at an appropriate developmental\nlevel, (B) receptive and expressive language, (C) learning, (D)\nself-direction, and (E) capacity for living in a family environment.\n  2. The commissioner of mental health is authorized, within\nappropriations made therefor, to make grants to local governmental units\nfor one hundred percent of the net operating costs of community based\nprograms approved by his office to serve seriously emotionally disturbed\nchildren. Grants provided under this section shall only be used to\nexpand existing services or to create new services for seriously\nemotionally disturbed children and shall not supplant existing services\nfor such individuals.  The commissioner shall promulgate rules and\nregulations for the operation and funding of such programs. Such rules\nand regulations shall include but not be limited to, eligibility and\nprogram requirements, and standards for reimbursement. Such programs\nshall be designed to provide mental health services to seriously\nemotionally disturbed children in the community who, absent such\nservices, would experience substantial risk of new or additional\npsychiatric hospitalization, or would experience substantial risk of\nserious functional disability as a result of their mental illness.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish the education\ndepartment's responsibility for the education of children with\nhandicapping conditions.\n  4. Notw...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>