<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.53"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.53"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41.53"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_53">
        <num>41.53</num>
        <heading>Community residence development grants for alcoholism services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_53__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of alcoholism and substance abuse services is\nauthorized, within appropriations made therefor, to make grants to local\ngovernmental units and voluntary nonprofit agencies developing an\nalcoholism community residence as defined in subdivision thirty-eight of\nsection 1.03 of this chapter. Such grants shall be limited to the\ndevelopment costs incurred prior to the operation of a community\nresidence. Development costs which may be eligible for up to one hundred\npercent reimbursement under this grant include:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_53__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>reasonable legal and other professional fees;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_53__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>initial staffing;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_53__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>up to six months rent;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_53__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>furniture; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_41_53__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>reasonable rehabilitation costs within guidelines established by\nthe division of the budget.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_53__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Application for grants shall be made in the manner and on forms\nprescribed by the commissioner. The commissioner shall establish a\nschedule, subject to the approval of the director of the division of the\nbudget, indicating the maximum development cost per bed for such\ncommunity residences. Such schedule may include varying rates for\ndistinct geographic areas of the state, if in the determination of the\ncommissioner the location of an eligible community residence has direct\nbearing on the level of development costs. The commissioner may also\nestablish varying rates based on the size of an eligible community\nresidence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_53__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No grant will be awarded by the commissioner if the projected per\nbed development cost for the community residence exceeds the schedule\nestablished in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_53__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_53__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No such grant will be awarded unless the community residence is\nconsistent with the local services plan, pursuant to this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_53__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state comptroller, or his legally authorized representative,\nis authorized and empowered to examine the books and accounts of the\noffices relating to program development grants and from time to time to\nexamine the books and accounts of each local governmental unit or\nvoluntary nonprofit agency receiving such grants, including its\nreceipts, disbursements, contracts, leases, loans and any other moneys\nrelating to its financial operation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_53__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payments pursuant to this section shall be made in lieu of state\naid for operating costs payable pursuant to any other provision of this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>