<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.51"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.51"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="41.51"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-41.51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_41_51">
        <num>41.51</num>
        <heading>State aid for costs of comprehensive psychiatric emergency programs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_51__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this article, local\ngovernments may be granted state aid, subject to appropriations made\ntherefor, for up to one hundred percent of the net operating costs\nincurred during the local fiscal year by such local governments, or by\nvoluntary agencies pursuant to contract with such local governments, for\nthe operation of comprehensive psychiatric emergency programs licensed\nby the commissioner of mental health.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_41_51__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of mental health may, subject to the approval of\nthe director of the budget, directly contract with general hospitals\nlicensed pursuant to article twenty-eight of the public health law, to\nreimburse approved operating and capital costs of comprehensive\npsychiatric emergency programs operated by such general hospitals.\nBefore entering into a direct contract with a general hospital, the\ncommissioner shall notify each local governmental unit located within\nthe program's catchment area and give the director of the local\ngovernmental unit an opportunity to appeal the need for such direct\ncontract. Such appeals shall be informal in nature and the rules of\nevidence shall not apply.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2027\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>