<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-61.01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-61.01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="61.01"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-61.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-61.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-61.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-61.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_61_01">
        <num>61.01</num>
        <heading>Receipt and disbursement of federal funds</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_61_01__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner or his authorized representative may receive,\nuse, or distribute federal financial or technical assistance to support\nconstruction, research, staffing, or other programs or activities in\nmental health, developmental disabilities, alcoholism, or drug addiction\nappropriated under federal health, mental health, or developmental\ndisabilities legislation or regulations or under other federal\nlegislation or regulations which provide assistance to the mentally\ndisabled, including but not limited to vocational rehabilitation\nprograms, alcoholism programs, drug addiction programs, poverty\nprograms, or special programs for children or the aged.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61_01__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may promulgate rules and regulations to implement\nany provision of state or federal law involving the receipt, use, or\ndisbursement of federal financial or technical assistance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61_01__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of taxation and finance shall be the custodian of\nfederal financial assistance granted or allocated to the department by\nthe United States. Funds shall be paid out on the audit and warrant of\nthe comptroller on the certificate of the commissioner or his authorized\nrepresentative.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_61_01__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the rules and regulations of the commissioner, any\nfunds made available to the department by the United States or by\nanother state agency as a federal allotment to be administered by the\ndepartment may be disbursed by it to a local government, voluntary\nnon-profit agency, educational agency, or person properly authorized to\nreceive funds in fulfillment of the purposes of appropriate federal or\nstate legislation for the provision of services, construction of\nfacilities, research, staffing, training, or related programs or\nactivities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>