<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.19"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.19"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7.19"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.19/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.19/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.19/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.19/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_19">
        <num>7.19</num>
        <heading>Personnel of the office</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_19__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner or his or her designee may, within the amounts\nappropriated therefor, appoint and remove in accordance with law and\napplicable rules of the state civil service commission, such officers\nand employees of the office of mental health as are necessary for\nefficient administration and shall administer the office's personnel\nsystem in accordance with such law and rules. In exercising the\nappointing authority, the commissioner shall take all reasonable and\nnecessary steps, consistent with article twenty-three-A of the\ncorrection law, to ensure that any such person so appointed has not\npreviously engaged in any act in violation of any law which could\ncompromise the health and safety of patients.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_19__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The director of a hospital or institute in the office shall have\nprofessional qualifications and experience to be prescribed by the\ncommissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_19__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the positions of\npsychiatrist III and deputy director in any office facility, in\nMatteawan state hospital, or in Dannemora state hospital may be filled\nby promotion open to employees of all such facilities who possess the\nminimum qualifications for the respective positions. Promotion lists\nwhich are established for those positions shall be general eligible\npromotion lists from which names are certified in the order of final\nearned ratings and from which certification shall not be subdivided by\nthe facility or department in which such persons are employed. Nothing\nin this subdivision shall prevent the use of open competitive\nexaminations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_19__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall establish regulations governing the\npersonnel administration of the department and its facilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_19__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The use of volunteers at facilities in the office of mental health\nshall be encouraged. The commissioner may establish regulations\ngoverning such volunteer services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_19__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where, and to the extent that, an agreement between the state and\nan employee organization entered into pursuant to article fourteen of\nthe civil service law so provides, the commissioner is authorized to\nimplement the provisions of such agreement relating to discipline\nconsistent with the terms thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>