<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.27"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.27"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7.27"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.27/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.27/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.27/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.27/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_27">
        <num>7.27</num>
        <heading>Facility services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_27__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Chapels. The commissioner may permit any religious or missionary\ncorporation or society or combination of such corporations and societies\nto erect a building on the grounds of any in-patient facility in the\noffice of mental health for the holding of religious service, to be used\nexclusively for the benefit of the patients and employees of such\nfacility, subject to such conditions as may be imposed by the\ncommissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_27__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fire mutual aid. In cooperation with the development and operation\nof plans for mutual aid in cases of fire and other public emergencies,\nthe director of an in-patient facility in the office of mental health,\nwith the approval of the commissioner of mental health, may authorize\nthe fire department of the facility to furnish aid to such territory\nsurrounding the facility as may be practical in cases of fire and such\nemergencies, having due regard to the safety of the patients and\nproperty of the facility and to engage in practice and training programs\nin connection with the development and operation of such mutual aid\nplans.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_27__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Community stores. The commissioner may authorize the director of\nany facility in the office of mental health to operate a community store\nor to lease space in any of its buildings not inconsistent with the\nrequirements of the facility for the operation of a community store for\nthe use and benefit of the patients, visitors, and personnel of such\nfacility. The moneys received by the director of such facility under or\npursuant to any such operation shall be deposited in a special fund to\nbe known as the community store fund and shall be used for the general\npurposes of the facility, subject to the provisions of section\nfifty-three of the state finance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_27__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Laboratory services. Subject to the regulations of the\ncommissioner, the director of a facility in the office of mental health\nmay agree to make the laboratory service of such facility available to\nadjacent local governments and may receive, apply, and spend money for\nthe extension of laboratory service according to the terms of the\nagreement as approved by such commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_27__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Special employment programs. The director of any facility operated\nby the office of mental health may purchase goods and services produced\nby special employment programs, sheltered workshop programs or supported\nwork programs, which are operated by any facility within such office,\nsubject to the provisions of section one hundred seventy-five-c of the\nstate finance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>