<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.41"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.41"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7.41"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.41/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.41/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.41/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-7.41/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_41">
        <num>7.41</num>
        <heading>Geriatric service demonstration program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_41__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office shall establish a geriatric service demonstration\nprogram to provide grants, within appropriations therefor, to providers\nof mental health care, substance use disorder services, compulsive\ngambling services, or any combination thereof, to the elderly, including\norganizations that provide health and aging services as well as mental\nhealth, substance use disorder, and compulsive gambling organizations.\nThe office is also authorized, under the demonstration program, to\nfoster and support collaboration between providers of home care services\nlicensed or certified under article thirty-six of the public health law\nand mental health providers for the integration of health and mental\nhealth care, and for all other enumerated goals of this section. Such\nprogram shall be administered by the office in cooperation with the\noffice of alcoholism and substance abuse services, the state office for\nthe aging and such other state agencies as the commissioner shall\ndetermine are necessary for the operation of the program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Grants may be awarded by the office to providers of care to older\nadults with mental disabilities, substance use disorder, compulsive\ngambling, or any combination thereof, for the purposes which may include\none or more of the following:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Community integration. Programs which enable older adults with\nmental disabilities or older adults suffering from substance use\ndisorder or compulsive gambling to age safely in the community and\nprevent the unnecessary use of institutional care;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Improved quality of treatment. Programs for older adults which\nimprove the quality of mental health care, substance use disorder or\ncompulsive gambling services in the community or in residential\nfacilities;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Integration of services. Programs which integrate mental health\nand aging services with alcohol, drug, health and other support\nservices;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Workforce. Programs which make more efficient use of mental\nhealth, substance use disorder, compulsive gambling, health and aging\nservices professionals by developing alternative service roles for\nparaprofessionals and volunteers, including peers, and programs more\neffective in recruitment and retention of bi-lingual, bi-cultural or\nculturally competent staff;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Family support. Programs which provide support for family\ncaregivers, to include the provision of care to older adults by younger\nfamily members and by older adults to younger family members;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Finance. Programs which have developed and implemented innovative\nfinancing methodologies to support the delivery of best practices;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Specialized populations. Programs which concentrate on outreach\nto, engagement of and effective treatment of cultural minorities or\nveterans as defined in section eighty-five of the civil service law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Information clearinghouse. Programs which compile, distribute and\nmake available information on clinical developments, program innovations\nand policy developments which improve the care to older adults with\nmental disabilities or suffering from substance use disorder or\ncompulsive gambling; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_41__subsec_b__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Staff training. Programs which offer on-going training initiatives\nincluding improved clinical and cultural skills, evidence based\ngeriatric mental health, substance use disorder and compulsive gambling\ntreatment skills, and the identification and management of mental,\nbehavioral and substance abuse disorders among older adults.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_41__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may adopt rules and regulations necessary to\nimplement the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>