<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.03"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.03"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-02-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75.03"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.03/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.03/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.03/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.03/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75_03">
        <num>75.03</num>
        <heading>Policy and purposes of article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 75.03 Policy and purposes of article.\n  It is hereby declared that the provision of new and improved community\nfacilities is necessary to care for the increasing number of persons\nafflicted with mental disability. Such facilities should be located\nclose to the people they serve in order to speed rehabilitation and\nrestoration and to provide for out-patient care, in-patient care,\nincluding after care, diagnostic and rehabilitative services, and\nresidential accommodations for operation as hostels. Such facilities\nshould supplement the services provided by the commissioner and the\ndepartment of mental hygiene and should be available to cities and\ncounties operating approved community services programs pursuant to the\nprovisions of article eleven of this chapter.\n  It is hereby further declared that non-profit corporations should be\ncreated to construct, acquire, reconstruct, rehabilitate, own, and\noperate such facilities and that provision should be made for mortgage\nloan participation by a lending institution or the New York state\nhousing finance agency in order to insure that the full resources of the\nprivate enterprise sector of the economy may be made available for this\npurpose; that there is a need for public assistance to such corporations\nby the granting of tax exemption; that it is the policy of the state to\npromote the provision of community facilities by such nonprofit\ncorporations; and that such provision is a public use and purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>