<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.17"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.17"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75.17"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-75.17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75_17">
        <num>75.17</num>
        <heading>Mortgage loans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_75_17__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any company formed under this article may, subject to the approval\nof the commissioner, borrow funds from the New York state housing\nfinance agency and secure the repayment thereof by bond or note and\nmortgage which shall contain such terms and conditions as may be deemed\nnecessary or desirable by the New York state housing finance agency or\nrequired by any agreement between the New York state housing finance\nagency and the holders of its notes and bonds with respect to such\ncompanies, including the right to assignment of rates and fees and entry\ninto possession in case of default, but the operation of such project,\nin the event of such entry, shall be subject to regulations promulgated\nby the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75_17__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The New York state housing finance agency may make a contract to\nmake loans to companies not to exceed the total project cost. Any such\nloan shall be secured by a first mortgage lien upon all the real\nproperty and improvements of which the project consists and upon all\nfixtures and articles of personal property attached to or used in\nconnection with the construction, acquisition, reconstruction,\nrehabilitation, improvement, or operation of the project.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75_17__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any inconsistent provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding,\nmortgages of a company shall be exempt from the mortgage recording taxes\nimposed by article eleven of the tax law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>