<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.07"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.07"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="79.07"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.07/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.07/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.07/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.07/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_79_07">
        <num>79.07</num>
        <heading>Petition; contents</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 79.07 Petition; contents.\n  A petition for the appointment of a guardian for an incompetent or\nconservatee ward may be filed in the supreme court or in the county\ncourt pursuant to jurisdiction given in the laws of the state, by or on\nbehalf of any person who, under the laws of the state, is entitled to\nfile such a petition. A petition for the appointment of a guardian for\nan infant ward may be filed in the surrogate's court pursuant to\njurisdiction given in the surrogate's court procedure act, by or on\nbehalf of any person who, under the provision of the surrogate's court\nprocedure act, is entitled to file such petition.\n  The petition for appointment of a guardian, whether the ward be a\nmental incompetent or an infant, shall set forth the name, age, place of\nresidence of the ward, the names and places of residence of the nearest\nrelative, if known, and the fact that such ward is entitled to receive\nmoneys payable by or through the administration and shall set forth the\namount of moneys then due and the amount of probable future payments.\n  The petition shall also set forth the name and address of the person\nor institution, if any, having actual custody of the ward.\n  In the case of a mentally incompetent ward the petition shall show\nthat such ward has been rated incompetent on examination by the\nadministration in accordance with the laws and regulations governing the\nadministration.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>