<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.29"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.29"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="79.29"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.29/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.29/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.29/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-79.29/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_79_29">
        <num>79.29</num>
        <heading>Admission and retention of mentally ill veterans</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 79.29 Admission and retention of mentally ill veterans.\n  Whenever it appears that a mentally ill veteran of any war, military\noccupation or expedition is eligible for treatment in a United States\nveterans' administration hospital or that a mentally ill seaman or other\nperson is eligible for treatment in a United States public health\nservice hospital and the official in charge of such hospital determines\nthat such person is suitable for voluntary admission to such hospital or\nthat an involuntary admission to such hospital is necessary for the\nproper care and treatment of such veteran, seaman, or other person, such\nofficial is authorized to admit and retain such veteran, seaman or other\nperson, provided, however, such official shall comply with all\napplicable provisions of article nine of this chapter relating to\nadmission and retention of patients. The officials in charge of such\nhospitals are also authorized to apply to the commissioner for approval\nto receive and retain such veterans, seamen or other eligible persons on\nan emergency basis, in accordance with the provisions of section 9.39 of\nthis chapter.  Such veteran, seaman, or other person, upon admission,\nshall be subject to the rules and regulations of such hospital to the\nextent that such rules and regulations do not conflict with the\nprovisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>