<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.05"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.05"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="82.05"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_82_05">
        <num>82.05</num>
        <heading>Duties, responsibilities, and authority of supporters</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supporter must:\n  1. respect the decision-maker's right to make a decision, even when\nthe supporter disagrees with the decision or believes it is not in the\ndecision-maker's best interests;\n  2. act honestly, diligently, and in good faith;\n  3. act within the scope set forth in the executed supported\ndecision-making agreement;\n  4. avoid conflicts of interest;\n  5. notify the decision-maker in writing, and in a manner the\ndecision-maker can understand, of the supporter's intent to resign as a\nsupporter; and\n  6. participate in facilitation and/or education programs developed\nunder regulations promulgated by the office for people with\ndevelopmental disabilities in order to enter a formal supported\ndecision-making agreement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supporter is prohibited from:\n  1. making decisions for the decision-maker, except to the extent\notherwise granted in an advance directive;\n  2. exerting undue influence upon the decision-maker;\n  3. physically coercing the decision-maker;\n  4. obtaining, without the consent of the decision-maker, information\nacquired for a purpose other than assisting the decision-maker in making\na decision authorized by the supported decision-making agreement;\n  5. obtaining, without the consent of the decision-maker, or as\nexpressly granted by the supported decision-making agreement, and\naccompanied by an appropriate release, nonpublic personal information as\ndefined in 15 U.S.C. § 6809</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_82_05__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A), or clinical records or information\nunder subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 33.13 of this chapter; and\n  6. communicating a decision-maker's decision to a third-party without\nthe participation and presence of the decision-maker.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The relationship between a decision-maker and a supporter is one\nof trust and confidence and serves to preserve the decision-making\nauthority of the decision-maker.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supporter shall not be considered a surrogate or substitute\ndecision maker for the decision-maker and shall not have the authority\nto sign legal documents on behalf of the decision-maker or bind the\ndecision-maker to a legal agreement, but may, if such authority is\nexpressly granted in the supported decision-making agreement, provide\nco-signature together with the decision-maker acknowledging the receipt\nof statements of rights and responsibilities in order to permit\nparticipation in such programs or activities that the decision-maker has\ncommunicated a choice to participate in.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If expressly granted by the supported decision-making agreement,\nand the decision-maker has signed an appropriate release, the supporter\nmay assist the decision-maker in obtaining educational records under the\nFamily Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (20 U.S.C. § 1232g),\nprotected health information under the Health Insurance Portability and\nAccountability Act of 1996 (45 CFR §§ 164.502, 164.508), clinical\nrecords and information under subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 33.13 of this\nchapter, or patient information under subdivisions two and three of\nsection eighteen of the public health law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supporter shall ensure the information obtained under\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_05__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section is kept privileged and confidential, as\napplicable, and is not subject to unauthorized access, use, or\ndisclosure.\n  * NB Effective 90 days from the date that the regulations issued in\naccordance with § 1 of chapter 481 of 2022 appear in the New York State\nRegister or the date such regulations are adopted, whichever is later.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>