<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.04"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.04"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="82.04"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.04/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.04/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.04/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.04/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_82_04">
        <num>82.04</num>
        <heading>Scope</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a decision-maker voluntarily enters into a supported\ndecision-making agreement with one or more supporters, the\ndecision-maker may, in the agreement, authorize the supporter to provide\nsupport to them in making their own decisions in areas they choose,\nincluding, but not limited to: gathering information, understanding and\ninterpreting information, weighing options and alternatives to a\ndecision, considering the consequences of making a decision or not\nmaking it, participating in conversations with third parties if the\ndecision-maker is present and requests their participation,\ncommunicating the decision-maker's decision to third parties if the\ndecision-maker is present and requests their participation, and\nproviding the decision-maker support in implementing the\ndecision-maker's decision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this article, nor the existence of an executed\nsupported decision-making agreement, shall preclude the decision-maker\nfrom acting independently of the supported decision-making agreement or\nexecuting, with or without the assistance of supporters under a\nsupported decision-making agreement, a power of attorney under title\nfifteen of article five of the general obligations law, health care\nproxy under article twenty-nine-C of the public health law, or other\nadvance directive.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the existence of a supported decision-making\nagreement, a decision-maker shall continue to have unrestricted access\nto their personal information without the assistance of a supporter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the existence of a supported decision-making\nagreement, a decision-maker may request and receive assistance in making\nany decision that is not covered under the supported decision-making\nagreement at any time and from any person, regardless of whether that\nperson is designated as a supporter in the supported decision-making\nagreement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supported decision-making agreement made pursuant to this\narticle may be evidence that the decision-maker has a less restrictive\nalternative to guardianship in place.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The availability of supported decision-making agreements is not\nintended to limit the informal use of supported decision-making, or to\npreclude judicial consideration of such informal arrangements as less\nrestrictive alternatives to guardianship.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Execution of a supported decision-making agreement may not be a\ncondition of participation in any activity, service, or program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a decision-maker seeks from any person professional advice that\nwould be otherwise covered by evidentiary privilege in accordance with\nsections forty-five hundred three, forty-five hundred four, forty-five\nhundred seven, forty-five hundred eight and forty-five hundred ten of\nthe civil practice law and rules, the inclusion in the conversation of a\nsupporter authorized by the supported decision-making agreement to\nprovide support in the area in which the decision-maker seeks the\nprofessional advice shall not constitute a waiver of that privilege.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary,\nnothing within this article shall be construed to prohibit eligibility\nof a decision-maker for receipt of services or supports that they would\nhave otherwise been entitled, including adult protective services,\nabsent entering into a supported decision-making agreement under the\nprovisions of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_04__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supported decision-making agreement made between a\ndecision-maker and his or her supporter or supporters after consultation\nand education, which is signed by a facilitator shall have the legal\nforce and effect authorized under section 82.11 of this article.\n  * NB Effective 90 days from the date that the regulations issued in\naccordance with ยง 1 of chapter 481 of 2022 appear in the New York State\nRegister or the date such regulations are adopted, whichever is later.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>