<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="82.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_82_10">
        <num>82.10</num>
        <heading>Form of agreement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supported decision-making agreement may be in any form\nconsistent with the requirements set forth in this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supported decision-making agreement must:\n  1. be in writing;\n  2. be dated;\n  3. designate the decision-maker, and at least one supporter;\n  4. list the categories of decisions with which a supporter is\nauthorized to assist the decision-maker;\n  5. list the kinds of support that each supporter may give for each\narea in which they are designated as a supporter;\n  6. contain an attestation that the supporters agree to honor the right\nof the decision-maker to make their own decisions in the ways and areas\nspecified in the agreement, respect the decision-maker's decisions, and,\nfurther, that they will not make decisions for the decision-maker;\n  7. state that the decision-maker may change, amend, or revoke the\nsupported decision-making agreement at any time for any reason, subject\nto the requirements of section 82.06 of this article;\n  8. be signed by all designated supporters; and\n  9. be executed or endorsed by the decision-maker in the presence of at\nleast two adult witnesses who are not also designated as supporters, or\nwith the attestation of a notary public.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supported decision-making agreement may:\n  1. appoint more than one supporter;\n  2. authorize a supporter to obtain personal information as described\nin subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_10__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 82.05 of this article;\n  3. authorize a supporter to share information with any other supporter\nor others named in the agreement; or\n  4. detail any other limitations on the scope of a supporter's role\nthat the decision-maker deems important.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to be subject to the provisions of section 82.11 and\nsubdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>through</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 82.12 of this article, a\nsupported decision-making agreement must also:\n  1. be signed by a facilitator or educator;\n  2. include a statement that the supported decision-making agreement\nwas made in accordance with a recognized facilitation and/or education\nprocess; and\n  3. include an attached attestation by the decision-maker that a\nparticular decision has been made in accordance with the support\ndescribed in the supported decision-making agreement.\n  * NB Effective 90 days from the date that the regulations issued in\naccordance with ยง 1 of chapter 481 of 2022 appear in the New York State\nRegister or the date such regulations are adopted, whichever is later.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>