<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="82.11"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-82.11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_82_11">
        <num>82.11</num>
        <heading>Legal effect of decisions made with support and third party obligations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_11__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This section shall apply only to decisions made pursuant to\nsupported decision-making agreements created in accordance with this\narticle and following a recognized supported decision-making\nfacilitation or education process, as prescribed by regulations\ngoverning the facilitation and education processes promulgated by the\noffice for people with developmental disabilities. Additionally, such\ndecisions shall be signed by a facilitator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_11__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A decision or request made or communicated by a decision-maker\nwith the assistance of a supporter in accordance with the provisions of\na supported decision-making agreement must, notwithstanding any other\nprovision of law, be recognized as the decision or request of the\ndecision-maker and may be enforced by the decision-maker in law or\nequity on the same basis as all others.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_11__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person, entity, or agency required to recognize and honor a\ndecision made pursuant to a supported decision-making agreement\nauthorized by this section may require the decision-maker to execute or\nendorse an attestation, as provided in paragraph three of subdivision\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_11__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 82.10 of this article, as a condition of recognizing and\nhonoring the decision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82_11__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person, entity, or agency that receives a supported\ndecision-making agreement must honor a decision made in accordance with\nthe agreement, unless the person, entity, or agency has substantial\ncause to believe the supported decision-making agreement has been\nrevoked, or the decision-maker is being abused, coerced, unduly\ninfluenced, or financially exploited by the supporter, or that the\ndecision will cause the decision-maker substantial and imminent physical\nor financial harm.\n  * NB Effective 90 days from the date that the regulations issued in\naccordance with ยง 1 of chapter 481 of 2022 appear in the New York State\nRegister or the date such regulations are adopted, whichever is later.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>