<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-84.05"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-84.05"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="84.05"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-84.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-84.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-84.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-84.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_84_05">
        <num>84.05</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the comptroller</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Financial stability and integrity of the financial organization;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The safety of the investment instrument being offered;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The ability of the investment instrument to track increasing costs\nof obtaining care for individuals with disabilities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The ability of the financial organization to satisfy recordkeeping\nand reporting requirements;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The financial organization's plan for promoting the program and\nthe investment it is willing to make to promote the program;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fees, if any, proposed to be charged to persons for opening or\nmaintaining accounts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The minimum initial deposit and minimum contributions that the\nfinancial organization will require;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The ability of banking organizations to accept electronic\nwithdrawals, including payroll deduction plans; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Other benefits to the state or its residents included in the\nproposal, including fees payable to the state to cover expenses of\noperation of the program.\n  3-a. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision three of this\nsection, the comptroller may, in his or her discretion, enter into a\ncontract with the existing third party administrator of the NYS college\nchoice tuition savings program for the purpose of administering the NY\nABLE savings account program and providing account depositories and\nmanagers. The term of such contract shall expire on the same date as the\ncontract for the administration of the NYS college choice tuition\nsavings program expires. Following such expiration, the comptroller may,\nin his or her discretion, solicit proposals for the purpose of\nadministering the NY ABLE savings account program and solicit proposals\nfor the purpose of administering the NYS college choice tuition savings\nprogram jointly or separately.\n  4. The comptroller may enter into a contract with a financial\norganization. Such financial organization management may provide one or\nmore types of investment instrument.\n  5. The comptroller may select more than one financial organization for\nthe program.\n  6. A management contract shall include, at a minimum, terms requiring\nthe financial organization to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Take any action required to keep the program in compliance with\nrequirements of section 84.09 of this article and any actions not\ncontrary to its contract to manage the program to qualify as a\n"Qualified ABLE account" under subsection</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_84_05__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection 529A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Keep adequate records of each account, keep each account\nsegregated from each other account, and provide the comptroller with\ninformation as required;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>compile and total information contained in statements required to\nbe prepared under section 84.09 of this article and provide such\ncompilations to the comptroller.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If there is more than one program manager, provide the comptroller\nwith such information necessary to determine compliance;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provide the comptroller or his or her designee access to the books\nand records of the program manager to the extent needed to determine\ncompliance with the contract;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Hold all accounts for the benefit of the account owner;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Be audited at least annually by a firm of certified public\naccountants selected by the program manager and that the results of such\naudit be provided to the comptroller; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provide the comptroller with copies of all regulatory filings and\nreports made by it during the term of the management contract or while\nit is holding any accounts, other than confidential filings or reports\nthat will not become part of the program. The program manager shall make\navailable for review by the comptroller the results of any periodic\nexamination of such manager by any state or federal banking, insurance,\nor securities commission, except to the extent that such report or\nreports may not be disclosed under applicable law or the rules of such\ncommission.\n  7. The comptroller may provide that an audit shall be conducted of the\noperations and financial position of the program depository and manager\nat any time if the comptroller has any reason to be concerned about the\nfinancial position, the recordkeeping practices, or the status of\naccounts of such program depository and manager.\n  8. During the term of any contract with a program manager, the\ncomptroller shall conduct an examination of such manager and its\nhandling of accounts. Such examination shall be conducted at least\nbiennially if such manager is not otherwise subject to periodic\nexamination by the superintendent of financial services, the federal\ndeposit insurance corporation or other similar entity.\n  9.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If selection of a financial organization as a program manager\nor depository is not renewed, after the end of its term:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Accounts previously established and held in investment instruments\nat such financial organization may be terminated;\n  (ii) Additional contributions may be made to such accounts;\n  (iii) No new accounts may be placed with such financial organization;\nand\n  (iv) Existing accounts held by such depository shall remain subject to\nall oversight and reporting requirements established by the comptroller.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_84_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the comptroller terminates a financial organization as a\nprogram manager or depository, he or she shall take custody of accounts\nheld by such financial organization and shall seek to promptly transfer\nsuch accounts to another financial organization that is selected as a\nprogram manager or depository and into investment instruments as similar\nto the original instruments as possible.\n  10. The comptroller may enter into such contracts as it deems\nnecessary and proper for the implementation of the program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>