<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.07"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.07"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9.07"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.07/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.07/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.07/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.07/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_07">
        <num>9.07</num>
        <heading>Notice to all patients of their rights and of the availability of the mental hygiene legal service</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_07__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Immediately upon the admission of any patient to a hospital or\nupon his conversion to a different status, the director shall inform the\npatient in writing of his status, including the section of this chapter\nunder which he is hospitalized, and of his rights under this article,\nincluding the availability of the mental hygiene legal service. At any\ntime thereafter, upon the request of the patient or of anyone on the\npatient's behalf, the patient shall be permitted to communicate with the\nmental hygiene legal service and avail himself of the facilities\nthereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_07__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The director of every hospital shall post copies of a notice, in a\nform and manner to be determined by the commissioner, at places\nthroughout the hospital where such notice will be conspicuous and\nvisible to all patients, stating the following:\n  1. the availability of the mental hygiene legal service.\n  2. a general statement of the rights of patients under the various\nadmission or retention provisions of this article.\n  3. the right of the patient to communicate with the director, the\nboard of visitors, the commissioner of mental health, and the mental\nhygiene legal service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>