<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.48"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.48"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9.48"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.48/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.48/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.48/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.48/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_48">
        <num>9.48</num>
        <heading>Duties of directors of assisted outpatient treatment programs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_9_48__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Directors of assisted outpatient treatment programs established\npursuant to section 9.60 of this article shall provide a written report\nto the program coordinators, appointed by the commissioner of mental\nhealth pursuant to subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 7.17 of this chapter,\nwithin three days of the issuance of a court order. The report shall\ndemonstrate that mechanisms are in place to ensure the delivery of\nservices and medications as required by the court order and shall\ninclude, but not be limited to the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a copy of the court order;\n  (ii) a copy of the written treatment plan;\n  (iii) the identity of the case manager or assertive community\ntreatment team, including the name and contact data of the organization\nwhich the case manager or assertive community treatment team member\nrepresents;\n  (iv) the identity of providers of services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the date on which services have commenced or will commence.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_9_48__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The directors of assisted outpatient treatment programs shall\nensure the timely delivery of services described in paragraph one of\nsubdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 9.60 of this article pursuant to any court\norder issued under such section. Directors of assisted outpatient\ntreatment programs shall immediately commence corrective action upon\nreceiving notice from program coordinators, that services are not being\nprovided in a timely manner. Such directors shall inform the program\ncoordinator of such corrective action.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Directors of assisted outpatient treatment programs shall submit\nquarterly reports to the program coordinators regarding the assisted\noutpatient treatment program operated or administered by such director.\nThe report shall include the following information:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the names of individuals served by the program;\n  (ii) the percentage of petitions for assisted outpatient treatment\nthat are granted by the court;\n  (iii) any change in status of assisted outpatients, including but not\nlimited to the number of individuals who have failed to comply with\ncourt ordered assisted outpatient treatment;\n  (iv) a description of material changes in written treatment plans of\nassisted outpatients;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any change in case managers;\n  (vi) a description of the categories of services which have been\nordered by the court;\n  (vii) living arrangements of individuals served by the program\nincluding the number, if any, who are homeless;\n  (viii) any other information as required by the commissioner of mental\nhealth; and\n  (ix) any recommendations to improve the program locally or statewide.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Directors of assisted outpatient treatment programs providing\nservices described in paragraph one of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 9.60\nof this article pursuant to any court order issued under such section\nshall evaluate the need for ongoing assisted outpatient treatment\npursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_48__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 9.60 of this article prior to the\nexpiration of any assisted outpatient treatment order; and shall notify\nthe director of community services of the new county of residence when\nhe or she has reason to believe that an assisted outpatient has or will\nchange his or her county of residence during the pendency of an assisted\noutpatient treatment order. Upon such change of residence, the director\nof the new county of residence shall become the appropriate director, as\nsuch term is defined in section 9.60 of this article.\n  * NB Repealed June 30, 2027\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>