<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MHY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.55"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.55"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9.55"/>
          <FRBRname value="MHY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mhy/section-9.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_55">
        <num>9.55</num>
        <heading>Emergency admissions for immediate observation, care and treatment; powers of qualified psychiatrists</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_55__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 9.39 of this article or to a comprehensive\npsychiatric emergency program, if he or she determines upon examination\nof such person that such person appears to have a mental illness for\nwhich immediate observation, care and treatment in a hospital is\nappropriate and which is likely to result in serious harm to himself or\nherself or others. Upon the request of such qualified psychiatrist,\npeace officers, when acting pursuant to their special duties, or police\nofficers, who are members of an authorized police department or force or\nof a sheriff's department shall take into custody and transport any such\nperson. Upon the request of a qualified psychiatrist an ambulance\nservice, as defined by subdivision two of section three thousand one of\nthe public health law, is authorized to transport any such person. Such\nperson may then be admitted to a hospital in accordance with the\nprovisions of section 9.39 of this article or to a comprehensive\npsychiatric emergency program in accordance with the provisions of\nsection 9.40 of this article.\n  * NB Effective until July 1, 2027\n* ยง 9.55 Emergency admissions for immediate observation, care and\n           treatment; powers of qualified psychiatrists.\n  A qualified psychiatrist shall have the power to direct the removal of\nany person, whose treatment for a mental illness he is either\nsupervising or providing in a facility licensed or operated by the\noffice of mental health which does not have an inpatient psychiatric\nservice, to a hospital approved by the commissioner pursuant to\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_55__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 9.39 of this article, if he determines upon\nexamination of such person that such person appears to have a mental\nillness for which immediate observation, care and treatment in a\nhospital is appropriate and which is likely to result in serious harm to\nhimself or others, as defined in section 9.39 of this article. Upon the\nrequest of such qualified psychiatrist, peace officers, when acting\npursuant to their special duties, or police officers, who are members of\nan authorized police department or force or of a sheriff's department\nshall take into custody and transport any such person. Upon the request\nof a qualified psychiatrist an ambulance service, as defined by\nsubdivision two of section three thousand one of the public health law,\nis authorized to transport any such person. Such person may then be\nadmitted in accordance with the provisions of section 9.39 of this\narticle.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2027\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>