<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="100"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_100">
        <num>100</num>
        <heading>Alcoholic beverages generally</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the parents or lawful guardian of such person expressly consent in\nwriting to such appearance;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the appearance is for a special function, occasion, or event;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the appearance is approved by and made under the sponsorship of a\nprimary or secondary school;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the appearance takes place in the presence and under the direct\nsupervision of a teacher of such school; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the appearance does not take place in a tavern. Failure to\nrestrain such a person from so appearing shall be deemed to constitute\npermission.\n  3. Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to require\nthat any food be sold or purchased with or in order to obtain any\nalcoholic beverage for consumption on the premises where sold.\n  4. Alcoholic beverages may be sold to be consumed on the premises at a\nbar, counter or similar contrivance. Only one such bar, counter or\ncontrivance shall be permitted in any licensed premises, except that not\nmore than two additional bars, counters or contrivances may be permitted\nby the liquor authority for good cause shown to it, and upon the payment\nto it of a fee, for each additional bar, equivalent to the amount of the\nannual license fee paid by the licensee or, in the case of an additional\nbar, counter or contrivance operated on a seasonal basis, a fee\nequivalent to the amount of the annual license fee paid by the licensee\nprorated for the number of months that the seasonal bar is in operation.\nProvided however that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the licensed premises is a legitimate theatre or concert hall,\nor contiguous to and used in conjunction with a legitimate theatre or\nconcert hall, additional bars, counters or contrivances may be permitted\nby the liquor authority upon payment to it of an annual fee of one\nhundred dollars for each such additional bar, counter or contrivance so\npermitted, in addition to the annual license fee paid by such licensee;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if such licensed premises be located at a baseball park, race\ntrack, or either outdoor or indoor athletic field, facility, arena or\nstadium, additional bars, counters or contrivances where beer shall be\nsold at retail for consumption on the premises may be permitted by the\nliquor authority, upon payment to it of the annual fee of thirty dollars\nfor each such additional bar, counter or contrivance so permitted, in\naddition to the amount of the annual license fee paid by the licensee;\nand\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>temporary portable bars, counters or contrivances shall be\npermitted in a ballroom, meeting room or private dining-room on the\nlicensed premises of a hotel, restaurant or club during such time as\nsaid ballroom, meeting room or private dining-room is used for a private\ndinner, entertainment, meeting or similar affair to which members of the\ngeneral public are not admitted.\n  4-a. At race meetings, authorized by the state gaming commission,\nnotwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, additional bars,\ncounters or contrivances where alcoholic beverages shall be sold at\nretail for consumption on the premises may be permitted by the liquor\nauthority, upon payment to it of a fee equivalent to the amount of the\nannual or summer license fee paid by the licensee for each such\nadditional bar, counter or contrivance so permitted in addition to the\namount of the annual or summer license fee paid by the licensee.\n  4-b. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, for venues\nbeing operated or to be operated under a license to sell alcoholic\nbeverages for consumption on the premises, and having a capacity for one\nthousand or more persons, the liquor authority may issue licenses for\nbars, counters, or similar contrivances in such numbers as the authority\nmay determine in the exercise of its discretion.\n  5. No retail licensee for off-premises consumption shall sell, deliver\nor give away, or cause, permit or procure to be sold, delivered or given\naway any alcoholic beverage, other than as provided herein, on credit: a\nretail licensee for off-premises consumption, except a winery licensee,\nmay accept third party credit cards for the sale of any alcoholic\nbeverage for which it is licensed; a winery licensee having the right to\nsell wine at retail for off-premises consumption may accept third party\ncredit cards for the sale of said beverages at the winery premises only;\nand any person duly authorized to sell wine at retail for consumption\noff t...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_100__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Elimination of fraudulent and deceptive transactions;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_100__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Protection of purchasers against defaults by sellers;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_100__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The delivery of the alcoholic beverages represented by such\nreceipts or documents, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_100__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The payment of all taxes due thereon to the state.\n  8. Within ten days after filing a new application to sell liquor at\nretail under section sixty-three of this chapter, a notice thereof, in\nthe form prescribed by the authority, shall be posted by the applicant\nin a conspicuous place at the entrance to the proposed premises. The\napplicant shall make reasonable efforts to insure such notice shall\nremain posted throughout the pendency of the application. The provisions\nhereof shall apply only where no retail liquor license has previously\nbeen granted for the proposed premise and shall, specifically, not be\napplicable to a proposed sale of an existing business engaged in the\nretail sale of liquor. The authority may adopt such rules as it may deem\nnecessary to carry out the purpose of this subdivision.\n  9.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within ten days after filing a new application or an\napplication for renewal to sell liquor under section sixty-four,\nsixty-four-a, sixty-four-b, sixty-four-c, sixty-four-d or sixty-four-e\nof this chapter, a notice thereof shall be posted by the applicant in a\nconspicuous place at the entrance to the establishment or proposed\nestablishment where it can be easily read by passers-by. Said notice\nshall be in a form prescribed by the authority, provided however that\nsaid notice shall be either printed or highlighted in a pink ink of a\nneon, luminous or fluorescent variety. The notice shall specify the\napplication date, the type of license, any identifying number assigned\nby the authority, if available at the time of posting such notice, and\nhow to contact the state liquor authority to give a response to the\napplication. The applicant shall make reasonable efforts to insure such\nnotice shall remain posted throughout the pendency of such application.\nAdditionally, within ten days of the applicant's receipt of a written\nrequest from the authority, the applicant shall re-post such notice. The\nauthority may adopt such rules as it may deem necessary to carry out the\npurpose of this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within ten days of the applicant's receipt of written notice of a\nhearing scheduled pursuant to section sixty-four, sixty-four-a or\nsixty-four-c of this chapter, the applicant shall post a copy of such\nnotice in a conspicuous place at the entrance to the establishment or\nproposed establishment where it can be easily read by passers-by. This\nnotice shall include in clear and concise language a statement of the\nuse and capacity of the establishment. The applicant shall make\nreasonable efforts to insure such notice shall remain posted until the\ndate of the hearing or public meeting specified in such notice.\nAdditionally, within ten days of the applicant's receipt of a written\nrequest from the authority, the applicant shall re-post such notice. The\nauthority may adopt such rules as it may deem necessary to carry out the\npurpose of this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>