<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="101"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_101">
        <num>101</num>
        <heading>Manufacturers and wholesalers not to be interested in retail places</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Be interested directly or indirectly in any premises where any\nalcoholic beverage is sold at retail; or in any business devoted wholly\nor partially to the sale of any alcoholic beverage at retail by stock\nownership, interlocking directors, mortgage or lien or any personal or\nreal property, or by any other means. The provisions of this paragraph\nshall not apply to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any such premises or business constituting the\novernight lodging and resort facility located wholly within the\nboundaries of the town of North Elba, county of Essex, township eleven,\nRichard's survey, great lot numbers two hundred seventy-eight, two\nhundred seventy-nine, two hundred eighty, two hundred ninety-eight, two\nhundred ninety-nine, three hundred, three hundred eighteen, three\nhundred nineteen, three hundred twenty, three hundred thirty-five and\nthree hundred thirty-six, and township twelve, Thorn's survey, great lot\nnumbers one hundred six and one hundred thirteen, as shown on the\nAdirondack map, compiled by the conservation department of the state of\nNew York - nineteen hundred sixty-four edition, in the Essex county\natlas at page twenty-seven in the Essex county clerk's office,\nElizabethtown, New York, provided that such facility maintains not less\nthan two hundred fifty rooms and suites for overnight lodging, (ii) (A)\nall that tract or parcel of land situate in the City of Canandaigua,\nCounty of Ontario, State of New York, all as shown on a map entitled\n"Meridian Automotive Systems Subdivision Plan", prepared by Costich\nEngineering, P.C., having drawn number 3203-01, last dated 8/4/2003, and\nis to be filed in the Ontario County Clerk's Office and being more\nparticularly bounded and described as follows:\nBeginning at a point on the east right-of-way line of North Bloomfield\nRoad said point also being the northwest corner of lands now or formerly\nowned by Donald and Jean Baier having T.A.  # 070.19-01-06; thence\n  1. N60Á57;16"W, along said east right-of -way of North Bloomfield Road\na distance of 1,266.75 feet to a point; thence\n  2. N50Á14'22"W, along said east right-of-way line of North Bloomfield\nRoad a distance of 143.38 feet to a point; thence\n  3. N31Á52'21"W, along said east right-of-way line of North Bloomfield\nRoad a distance of 187.27 feet to a point on the south right-of-way line\nof North Street; thence\n  4. N46Á08...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 70Á 25' 10" W, along the north line of\nBuffalo Street a distance of 516.06 feet to a point in the east line of\nthe Penn Central Railroad Batavia Branch; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>N 37Á 42' 55" W\nalong the easterly line of Batavia Branch of the railroad a distance of\n758.52 feet to a point; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>N 70Á 25' 10" E a distance of 743.79\nfeet to a point in the west line of the Auburn Branch of the railroad;\nthence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 19Á 36' 35" E along said west line of the Auburn Branch of\nthe railroad distance of 379.37 feet to a point; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>N 70Á 25'10"\nE a distance of 8.00 feet to a point; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 19Á 36' 35" E a\ndistance of 341.48 feet to a point on the north line of Buffalo Street\nand the place of beginning.\n  PARCEL 4\nALL THAT TRACT OR PARCEL OF LAND, situate in the City of Canandaigua,\nCounty of Ontario and State of New York, bounded and described as\nfollows:\nBeginning at a point at a corner in the general easterly line of land of\nCanandaigua Industries Co., Inc., distant 341.48 feet measured N 19Á 36'\n36" W along said easterly line, from the northerly line of Buffalo\nStreet at a point therein distant 1200 feet, more or less, measured\nwestwardly, along said line of Buffalo Street, from the westerly line of\nMain Street;\nExtending from said beginning point the following eight courses and\ndistances, the first four thereof being along said general easterly line\nof lands of Canandaigua Industries Co., Inc.:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 70Á 25' 10" W 8.00\nfeet to an iron;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>N 19Á 36' 35" W, 379.37 feet to a spike set in a\nrailroad tie;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 70Á 25' 10" W, 17.00 feet to an iron stake; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nN 19Á 38' 00" W, 164.00 feet to an iron stake; thence the following four\ncourses and distances by remaining land of Penn Central Transportation\nCompany:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>N 70Á 22' 00" E, 33.00 feet to an iron stake;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 19Á 38'\n00" E, 164.02 feet to an iron stake;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 19Á 36' 35" E, 379.37 feet to\nan iron stake; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 70Á 23' 25" W, 8.00 feet to the place of\nbeginning.\n  PARCEL 5\nALL THAT TRACT OR PARCEL OF LAND, situate in the City of Canandaigua,\nCounty of Ontario, State of New York, all as shown on a map entitled\n"8.512 acre parcel to be conveyed to Constellation Brands, Inc. by\nMeridian Automotive Systems, Inc.", prepared by Costich Engineering,\nP.C., having drawing number 3203-A, dated 6/18/2003, and being more\nparticularly bounded and described as follows:\nCommencing at a point on the south right-of-way line of North (66.0'\nR.O.W.) Street said point being the northwest corner of lands now or\nformerly owned by Cambridge Acquisition Corp, having T.A.  #\n070.19-01-04.2 and the northeast corner of lands now or formerly owned\nby Cambridge Acquisition Corp having T.A.   070.19-01-03; thence A.\nS38Á37'53"E, along the aforementioned common property line a distance of\n772.95 feet to the point and place of beginning; thence 1. S38Á37'53"E,\na distance of 772.95 feet to a point; thence 2...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any such\npremises or business located on that certain piece or parcel of land, or\nany subdivision thereof, situate, lying and being in the Town of\nPlattsburgh, County of Clinton, State of New York and being more\nparticularly bounded and described as follows: Starting at an iron pipe\nfound in the easterly bounds of the highway known as the Old Military\nTurnpike, said iron pipe being located 910.39 feet southeasterly, as\nmeasured along the easterly bounds of said highway, from the southerly\nbounds of the roadway known as Industrial Parkway West, THENCE running S\n31 Á 54' 33" E along the easterly bounds of said Old Military Turnpike\nExtension, 239.88 feet to a point marking the beginning of a curve\nconcave to the west; thence southerly along said curve, having a radius\nof 987.99 feet, 248.12 feet to an iron pipe found marking the point of\nbeginning for the parcel herein being described, said point also marked\nthe southerly corner of lands of Larry Garrow, et al, as described in\nBook 938 of Deeds at page 224; thence N 07Á 45' 4" E along the easterly\nbounds of said Garrow, 748.16 feet to a 3"x4" concrete monument marking\nthe northeasterly corner of said Garrow, the northwesterly corner of the\nparcel herein being described and said monument also marking the\nsoutherly bounds of lands of Salerno Plastic Corp. as described in Book\n926 of Deeds at Page 186; thence S 81Á 45' 28" E along a portion of the\nsoutherly bounds of said Salerno Plastic Corp., 441.32 feet to an iron\npin found marking the northeasterly corner of the parcel herein being\ndescribed and also marking the northwest corner of the remaining lands\nnow or formerly owned by said Marx and Delaura; thence S 07Á 45' 40" W\nalong the Westerly bounds of lands now of formerly of said Marx and\nDeLaura and along the easterly bounds of the parcel herein being\ndescribed, 560.49 feet to an iron pin; thence N 83Á 43' 21" W along a\nportion of the remaining lands of said Marx and DeLaura, 41.51 feet to...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_v__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet Southerly from the Southerly line of the new garage\nbuilt upon land adjoining on the North; thence Westerly parallel with\nsaid garage, Forty-six and Seven-tenths (46.7) feet; thence Southerly\nOne Hundred Forty and Eight-tenths (140.8) feet to the Northerly margin\nof Union Street; thence Easterly along the Northerly margin of Union\nStreet, about Forty-eight and three-tenths (48.3) feet to the point or\nplace of beginning.\n  The two above parcels are together more particularly described as\nfollows:\n  All that parcel of land in the City of Schenectady beginning at a\npoint in the northerly margin of Union Street at the southwesterly\ncorner of lands now or formerly of Friedman (Deed Book 636 at page 423)\nwhich point is about 60 feet westerly of the westerly line of North\nCollege Street and runs thence N. 86 deg. 42' 20" W. 92.30 feet to the\nsoutheasterly corner of other lands now or formerly of Friedman (Deed\nBook 798 at page 498); thence N. 04 deg. 06' 48" E. 140.50 feet...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_v__subsec_90">
            <num>(90)</num>
            <content>
              <p>degrees, one\nhundred ninety-one and seventy-five hundredths (191.75) feet to a point\nin the Northwesterly street line of Erie Boulevard thence southwesterly\nalong the Northwesterly street line of Erie Boulevard, one hundred\ntwenty-three and eight-tenths (123.8) feet to its intersection with the\nNortherly street line of Union Street; thence Westerly along the\nNortherly street line of Union Street, one hundred twenty-four and\nfifty-five hundredths (124.55) feet to the point or place of beginning.\n  The above described parcel of property includes the Blue Line parcel\nof land, which is a portion of the abandoned Erie Canal Lands, located\nin the First Ward of the City of Schenectady, New York, and which Blue\nLine parcel lies between the Northwesterly line of Erie Boulevard as set\nforth in the above described premises and the Northeasterly lot line of\nthe old Union Street School as it runs parallel with the Northwesterly\nline of Erie Boulevard as aforesaid.\n  The two above par...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances along said edge of pavement: Northeasterly on\na curve to the left having a radius of 2221.65 feet, a chord bearing of\nNorth 30Á-16'-39" East, a chord distance of 280.79, a central angle of\n07Á-14'-47", a length of 280.98 feet to a point of reverse curvature;\nthence, Northeasterly on a curve to the right having a radius of 843.42\nfeet, a chord bearing of North 45Á-25'-09" East, a chord distance of\n534.08, a central angle of 36Á-55'-01", a length of 543.43 feet to a\npoint; thence, South 30Á-04'-59" East, a distance of 18.28 feet to the\ncorner of the property acquired by Ontario County (Liber 766 of Deeds,\nPage 1112), as shown on a map recorded in the Ontario County Clerk's\nOffice as Map No. 6313; thence, the following four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and\ndistances along said property line: South 30Á-04'-59" East, a distance\nof 177.17 feet to a point; thence, South 02Á-20'-33" East, a distance of\n147.53 feet to a point; thence, South 41Á-31'-35" East, a distance of\n200.93 feet to a point; thence, South 23Á-48'-53" West, along said\nproperty line, and the projection thereof, through the first said lands\nof Ontario County - Finger Lakes Community College (Liber 698 of Deeds,\nPage 466), a distance of 517.96 feet to Point of Beginning. Said parcel\ncontaining 7.834 acres, more or less, as shown on a map entitled\n"Proposed Lease Area - Friends of the Finger Lakes Performing Arts\nCenter, Hopewell, NY", prepared by Bergmann Associates, drawing LM-01,\ndated June 10, 2005, last revised August 17, 2005. The related PAC\nProperties are shown on the Map denominated "FLCC Campus Property, FLPAC\nGround Lease, Parking, Vehicular &amp; Pedestrian Access", recorded in the\nOntario County Clerk's Office on December 10, 2009 in Book 1237...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of law to the contrary, the state liquor authority may issue a\nlicense under section fifty-one-a of this chapter to the owner and/or\noperator of the parcel described in this subparagraph. The legal\ndescription for the parcel so identified as the site is as follows:\n  ALL THAT TRACT OR PARCEL OF LAND situate in the city of Syracuse,\nCounty of Onondaga and State of New York being more particularly\ndescribed as follows:\n  Beginning at a point in the easterly line of North Clinton Street,\nsaid point being approximately 518.65 feet southerly along the easterly\nline of North Clinton Street from its intersection with the southerly\nline of Division Street; thence N. 76Á 43' 56" E. a distance of 133.65\nfeet to a point; thence N. 53Á 11' 01" E. a distance of 142.28 feet to a\npoint; thence N. 71Á 07' 02" E a distance of 16.99 feet to a point in\nthe westerly line of Genant Drive; thence southeasterly along the\nwesterly line of Genant Drive on a curve to the right with a radius of\n643.94 feet, an arc length of 77.63 feet and a chord of S. 16Á 43' 54"\nE. with a distance of 77.58' to the point of tangency; thence S. 13Á 17'\n52" E.  a distance of 265.92 feet to a point; thence on a curve to the\nright with a radius of 55 feet, an arc length of 57.02 feet and a chord\nof S.  16Á 23' 37" W. with a distance of 54.53 feet to the point of\ntangency; thence S. 59Á 31' 29" W. a distance of 24.64 feet to a point;\nthence S.  71Á 26' 56" W. a distance of 142.18 feet to a point in the\neasterly line of N. Clinton Street; thence N. 28Á 09' 10" W. a distance\nof 364.86 feet to the point and place of beginning. Said parcel being\napproximately 1.99 acres. The aforesaid described parcel is also shown\nas Lot "1B" (331 Genant Drive) according to a map entitled "A Map of\nResubdivision of a portion of Block D in the Original Village of\nSyracuse into Lots 1A and 1B, City of Syracuse, Onondaga County, State\nof New York, Known as 431 and 311 Gen...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>described in this deed, the\npermanent right-of-way and easement to operate, maintain, replace and/or\nremove any and all existing gas and electric facilities, and all\nappurtenant facilities thereto, as are now erected upon the premises\nabove described, including the full right, privileges and authority to\ncross lands of the party of the second part to gain access to said\nfacilities, and also including the full right, privileges and authority\nto cut and remove all trees, structures, and other obstructions within\nthe permanent right-of-way, together with the right to cut and remove\nany trees outside the permanent right-of-way which in the sole opinion\nof Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation, its successors and assigns, are\ndeemed likely to interfere with or pose a hazard to the facilities,\nprovided that the Multi-Story Brick Building, stairs and two air\nconditioning units shown on the Subdivision Map shall not be removed or\nmodified by Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation, its successors and\nassigns, pursuant to this Right-of-Way and Easement.\n  ALSO, EXCEPTING AND RESERVING to Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation, its\nsuccessors and assigns, the permanent right-of-way and easement to\noperate, maintain, build, construct, replace and/or remove electric and\ngas distribution facilities within ten</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_s__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet of the edge of any\nhighway</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>abutting the premises herein deemed necessary by said Niagara\nMohawk Power Corporation, its successors and assigns, said easement to\ninclude the full right, privilege and authority to cut and remove all\ntrees, structures, and obstructions within said easement deemed\nnecessary by Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation, provided that the\nMulti-Story Brick Building shown on the Subdivision Map shall not be\nremoved or modified by Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation, its successors\nand assigns, pursuant to this right-of-way and easement; or (xi) ALL\nthat certain plot, piece or parcel of land, situate, lying and being in\nthe Town of Greenburgh, County of Westchester and State of New York,\nbeing bounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point on the easterly side of Saw Mill River Road where\nthe same is intersected by the division line between premises\nhereinafter described and lands now or formerly of One Riverdale Ave.\nDevelopment Co., Inc., said point being North 11 Degrees 23' 24" West\n22.83 feet from the former North East corner of Saw Mill River Road and\nHunter Lane;\n  THENCE along said division line, North 82 Degrees 18' 00" East 647.08\nfeet to land now or formerly of One Riverdale Ave. Development Co.,\nInc.;\n  THENCE northerly along same, North 7 Degrees 42' 00" West 351.52 feet\nand North 10 Degrees 15' 00" West 282.50 feet to the southeast corner of\nlands now or formerly of Hodes Daniels;\n  THENCE westerly along same, South 80 Degrees 34' 00" West 85.00 feet,\nSouth 9 Degrees 26' 00" East 40.52 feet, South 80 Degrees 35' 00" West\n120.56 feet, and South 81 Degrees 15' 00" West 485.74 feet to the east\nside of Saw Mill River Road;\n  THENCE southerly along same, South 18 Degrees 17' 40" East 150.40 feet\nand South 11 Degrees 23' 24" East 431.17 feet to the point of BEGINNING;\nor\n  (xii) ALSO ALL THOSE TRACTS OR PARCELS OF LAND, situate in the Tenth\nWard of the City of Troy, County of Rensselaer and State of New York,\nknown as Lots Number ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_s__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, A Seven (A7), Six</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_s__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, A Six (A6), Five\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_s__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, A Five (A5) and the southerly portions of Lots Four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_s__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and A Four\n(A4), as the same are laid down and described on a certain Map made by\nFrederick W. Orr, dated August 15, 1918, filed in the Office of the\nClerk of the County of Rensselaer as Map No. 29 1/2, Drawer 18. The said\npremises hereby intended to be conveyed are bounded and described as\nfollows:\n  COMMENCING at an iron rod in the westerly side of River Street at the\nmost southeasterly corner of premises heretofore conveyed by Harry\nGoldberg and Norman Goldberg to Arthur E. Collins and another, by Deed\ndated November 8, 1940, recorded November 12, 1940 In the Office of the\nClerk of the County of Rensselaer in Book 633 of Deeds at page 400 and\nrunning thence southerly along the westerly line of River Street 215.6\nfeet to a pipe in the most southeasterly corner of Lot No. A7; thence\nwesterly along the southerly line of Lots Nos. A7 and 7, 163 feet more\nor less to the easterly shore of the Hudson River; thence northerly\nalong the easterly shore of the Hudson River 216 fe...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_s__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a manufacturer\nor wholesaler, if an individual, or a partner, of a partnership, or, if\na corporation, an officer or director thereof, from being an officer or\ndirector of a duly licensed charitable organization which is the holder\nof a license for on-premises consumption under this chapter, nor</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_s__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a\nmanufacturer from acquiring any such premises if the liquor authority\nfirst consents thereto after determining, upon such proofs as it shall\ndeem sufficient, that such premises is contiguous to the licensed\npremises of such manufacturer, and is reasonably necessary for the\nexpansion of the facilities of such manufacturer. After any such\nacquisition, it shall be illegal for a manufacturer acquiring any such\npremises to sell or deliver alcoholic beverages manufactured by him to\nany licensee occupying such premises; or\n  (xiii) any such premises or business located in the Town of Carmel,\nCounty of Putnam, State of New York, and being more particularly bounded\nand described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point on the westerly side of U.S. Route 6 where the\nsame is intersected by Lot No. 1 as shown on "Minor Subdivision Plat\nPrepared for Hinckley Holdings LLC Between Tax Lots 55.10-1-1, 55.10-1-3\n&amp; 55.6-1-53," filed in the Putnam County Clerks' office on July 18, 2018\nas fil...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>higher education institution chartered by the\nNew York state board of regents located at:\n                               SCHEDULE A\n  ALL that certain tract, lot and parcel of land lying and being in the\nTown of Hyde Park, County of Dutchess and State of New York, being more\nparticularly described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point on the easterly side of Albany Post Road (NYS\nRoute 9), said point being the southwesterly corner of the herein\ndescribed premises and the northwesterly corner of lands now or formerly\nof Traver; running thence along the said easterly side of Albany Post\nRoad the following four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances: North 03Á 15' 30"\nEast 68.91 feet, North 09Á 35' 20" East 31.09 feet, North 06Á 53' 00"\nEast 148.62 feet, and North 12Á 25' 00" East 62.03 feet to the corner\nformed by the intersection of the said easterly side of Albany Post Road\nand the Southerly side of West Dorsey Lane; running thence along the\nsaid southerly side of West Dorsey Lane North 38Á 26' 00" East 25.02\nfeet, North 63Á 13' 00" East 37.83 feet, and North 67Á 25' 00" East\n121.38 feet to the northwest corner of lands now or formerly of\nFirneiss; running thence along the westerly and southerly line of lands\nnow or formerly of Firneiss, South 03Á 16' 59" East 179.57 feet and\nSouth 79Á 13' 59" East 121.73 feet to lands now or formerly of Maidman;\nrunning thence along the westerly line of lands now or formerly of\nMaidman South 28Á 34' 00" West 105.08 feet, South 32Á 18' 00", East\n12.15 feet, and South 35Á 55' 00" West 193.04 feet to lands now or\nformerly of Traver; running thence along lands n...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 74Á 03'-27" West 68+ feet to a\npoint 101.00 feet distant easterly, measured at right angles, from\nstation H265+08.00 of said baseline; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>North 30Á 39' 40" West, 32+\nfeet to a point on the southerly boundary of said existing West Dorsey\nLane, the last mentioned point being 86± feet distant easterly, measured\nat right angles, from station H265+37+ of said baseline; thence\nnortheasterly along the last mentioned boundary of said existing West\nDorsey Lane, 83+ feet to the point of beginning; being 3,327 square feet\nor 0.076 acre more or less.\n  The above mentioned survey baseline is a portion of the 1988 survey\nbaseline for the reconstruction of the Poughkeepsie-Hyde Park, State\nHighway No. 453 as shown on a map and plan on file in the office of the\nState Department of Transportation and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a station H258+36.14; thence North 09Á 19'45" West to\nstation H267+62.73.\n  ALL bearings referred to TRUE NORTH at the 74' - 20' MERIDIAN OF WEST\nLONGITUDE.\n  SUBJECT to utility company agreements, easements, covenants,\nconditions and restrictions of record.\n  SUBJECT to the following res...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the premises may not be used, in whole or in part, for any form of\nlive entertainment including, but not limited to, bands or DJ's, at any\ntime; provided however, this restriction shall automatically terminate\nfive</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>years from the date of this deed; and\n  (ii) if the premises are used to serve any form of alcoholic beverage,\nthe premises must be closed for business no later than 11:59 o'clock\np.m. every day; provided, however, this restriction shall automatically\nterminate five</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>years from the date of this deed.\n  The party of the second part waives and releases any claim that said\nrestrictions are unenforceable for any reason, including the allegation\nthat such restrictions constitute a restraint upon alienation, are an\nunreasonable restriction or restraint on business or economic\ndevelopment, are a violation of any law, regulation or right, or that\nthey are not for the benefit of adjoining lands, or are not part of a\ncommon scheme or plan, it being clearly understood and expressly agreed\nby the parties that these restrictions are for the benefit of the party\nof the first part's other businesses and properties, for the term set\nforth above both now and hereafter, and that the lack of such\nrestrictions will damage and harm the grantor, its successors and\nassigns. Without all of these restrictions, the party of the first part\nwould not sell the premises to the party of the second part. In any\nproceeding to enforce said restrictions or prevent the ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\nthirteen of section one hundred six of this article and further\nidentified as Parcel A in such subparagraph may designate the\nmanufacturer licensee located at the premises described in this\nsubparagraph as owner of such brands for purposes of brand label\nregistration and price scheduling under this chapter.\n  * NB There are 3 sbpar (xiv)'s\n  (xv) any such premises located on that certain tract or parcel of\nland, situate in the City of Rochester, County of Monroe and State of\nNew York, bounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point on the northerly right-of-way line of East\nAvenue; said point being easterly 125.43 feet from the easterly\nright-of-way line of Alexander Street, as measured along said northerly\nright-of-way line of East Avenue; thence,\n  1. N 07Á 17' 46" E, a distance of 218.26 feet to a point; thence,\n  2. N 39Á 14' 18" W, a distance of 27.51 feet to a point; thence,\n  3. N 20Á 00' 35" E, a distance of 121.48 feet to a point; thence,\n  4. N 39Á 47' 19" W, a distance of 32.64 feet to a point; thence,\n  5. .S 74Á 12' 52" W, a distance of 30.93 feet to the point of\nintersection with the aforementioned easterly right-of-way line of\nAlexander Street; thence the following three</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses along said\neasterly right-of-way line.\n  6. N 20Á 04' 36" E, a distance of 210.80 feet to an angle point;\nthence;\n  7. N 20Á 23' 26" E, a distance of 48.84 feet to a point of\nintersection with the common line dividing lands at 390 East Avenue on\nthe south and lands of 350 Alexander Street on the north; thence,\n  8. N 20Á 23' 26" E, continuing along the easterly right-of-way line, a\ndistance of 141.65 feet to a point; thence,\n  9. S 68Á 41' 56" E, a distance of 81.10 feet to a point; thence,\n  10. S 21Á 46' 08" W, a distance of 142.27 feet to a point; thence,\n  11. S 68Á 13' 59" E, a distance of 92.32 feet to a point; thence,\n  12. S 20Á 04' 36" W, a distance of 600.00 feet to a point of\nintersection with the aforementioned northerly right-of-way line of East\nAvenue; thence,\n  13. N 71Á 32' 04" W, along said northerly right-of-way line, a\ndistance of 44.84 feet to the Point of Beginning,\n  TOGETHER WITH THE BENEFITS and subject of the burdens of a certain\nEasem...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>northerly at an angle in the northwest quadrant of\nninety</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_90">
            <num>(90)</num>
            <content>
              <p>degrees, sixteen</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>minutes with the northerly line of\nSeneca Street a distance of one hundred ninety-two and five-tenths\n(192.5) feet, more or less, to a point in the old line fence, which\npoint is the northeasterly corner of the premises; thence running</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nwesterly along said old line fence at an angle in the northwest quadrant\nof eighty-five</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_85">
            <num>(85)</num>
            <content>
              <p>degrees, fifty-two</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_52">
            <num>(52)</num>
            <content>
              <p>minutes with the line fence\nherein described a distance of seventy-eight and two-tenths (78.2) feet\nto a point; thence running</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>northerly at an angle in the northeast\nquadrant of ninety-four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_94">
            <num>(94)</num>
            <content>
              <p>degrees, four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>minutes with the last\ndescribed course and along a jog in said fence a distance of three and\nfive-tenths (3.5) feet, more or less, to a point; thence running</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nwesterly and continuing along said old fence line a distance of eleven\nand five-tenths (11.5) feet, more or less, to a point, which point is\nthe northwest corner of the premises, and running thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in a\nsoutherly direction a distance of two hundred two</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_202">
            <num>(202)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet, more or\nless, to the northerly line of said Seneca Street, as now monumented,\nwhich point is the southwest corner of the premises, and running thence\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>along the northerly line of said Seneca Street a distance of\neighty-nine and seven-tenths (89.7) feet to the point or place of\nbeginning.\nPARCEL 2\nAll that certain lot, piece or parcel of land situate in the city of\nGeneva, County of Ontario and state of New York, more particularly\nbounded and described as follows:\nCommencing at a point in the east line of lands of Agnes Dempsey Doxsee,\nsaid point being one foot south of the south wall of the present barn\nnow on said land, and running thence southerly about twenty-nine</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_29">
            <num>(29)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nfeet, more or less, to the north line of the lands of the S-G Theatre\nCorporation; thence westerly along the north line of the land of the S-G\nCorporation thirty-three</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_33">
            <num>(33)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet to a point; thence northerly and\nparallel with the first course hereof and along the westerly line of the\nlands of Agnes Dempsey Doxsee to a point; which point if measured in a\nstraight line east and west would be one</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>foot south of the south\nline of the present barn; thence easterly thirty-three</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_33">
            <num>(33)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet to the\nplace of beginning.\nBeing the same premises shown on a map of a survey prepared by William\nJ. Newton, L.S. dated January 15, 1975 (Survey No. 74-202-C) filed in\nthe Ontario County Clerk's office.\n  * NB There are 3 sbpar (xviii)'s\n  * (xviii) ALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, with the\nbuildings and improvements thereon erected, situate, lying and being in\nthe Town of East Hampton, County of Suffolk and State of New York, known\nand designated as Lots 81 through 86, inclusive in Block 2, as shown on\nthat certain map entitled, "Map of Montauk Manor, Section 1", which Map\nwas filed in the Office of the Clerk of the County of Suffolk on\nSeptember 1, 1911 as Map #518, said lots when taken together, are more\nparticularly bounded and described as follows:\nBEGINNING at a point of intersection of the easterly side of Washington\nStreet and the division line between lands now or formerly of B &amp; B\nPrecision Realty, Inc., and the premises herein described;\n...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirteen of section one hundred six of this article\nmay designate the importer licensee located at the premises described in\nthis subparagraph as owner of such brands for purposes of brand label\nregistration and price scheduling under this chapter.\n  * NB There are 3 sbpar (xviii)'s\n  * (xviii) ALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, situate,\nlying and being in the Borough of Manhattan, City, County and State of\nNew York, bounded and described as follows:\nParcel A\n  BEGINNING at the intersection of the southerly line of South Street,\n135 feet wide, and the westerly line of Block 2 Lot 3;\n  THENCE RUNNING the following seven</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Along said westerly line of Block 2 Lot 3, South 16 degrees 50\nminutes 39 seconds East a distance of 145.30 feet to a point;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE still along said westerly line of Block 2 Lot 3, North 73\ndegrees 09 minutes 21 seconds East a distance of 28.67 feet to a point;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE still along said westerly line of Block 2 Lot 3, South 16\ndegrees 50 minutes 39 seconds East a distance of 419.26 feet to a point\non the U.S. Pierhead Line approved by Secretary of War, February 25,\n1918;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE along said U.S. Pierhead Line, South 73 degrees 09 minutes\n21 seconds West a distance of 317.76 feet to a point;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE still along said U.S. Pierhead Line, South 87 degrees 11\nminutes 44 seconds West a distance of 36.57 feet to a point on the\neasterly line of Block 2 Lot 1;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE along the northerly line of Block 2 Lot 1, North 15 degrees\n30 minutes 29 seconds West a distance of 555.84 feet to a point on said\nsoutherly line of South Street; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE along said southerly line of South Street, North 73 degrees\n09 minutes 21 seconds East a distance of 311.61 feet to the point of\nBEGINNING.\n  EXCEPTING THEREFROM the slips, and those certain portions of the\nground floor as delineated on the diagrams annexed to the Sublease</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nwith the cross-hatching on the schematic drawing of the ground floor\ndepicted on page 1 of Annex 1 and (ii) with black shading or\ncross-hatching on the schematic drawing of Annex 2.\nParcel B\n  All that certain Lot, piece or parcel of land, with the buildings and\nimprovements thereon erected, situate, lying and being in the Borough of\nManhattan, County of New York, State of New York:\n  Borough of Manhattan, City, County and State of New York, bounded and\ndescribed as follows:\n  BEGINNING at the corner formed by the intersection of the westerly\nside of Broadway and the southerly side of Morris Street;\n  THENCE southerly along the westerly side of Broadway, 203 feet 1-3/4\ninches Survey (203 feet 2-1/4 inches Deed more or less), to the\nnortherly side of lands formerly belonging to Eve White;\n  THENCE westerly along the northerly side of said lands formerly\nbelonging to Eve White 201 feet 2 inches Survey (200 feet 8 inches Deed\nmore or less), to the easterly side of Greenwich Street;\n  THENCE northerly along the easterly side of Greenwich Street 231 feet\n1-3/4 inch Survey (231 feet 1-3/4 inches Deed) to the southeasterly\ncorner of Greenwich and Morris Streets; and\n  THENCE easterly along the southerly side of Morris Street, 248 feet 2\ninches Survey (248 feet 3 inches Deed) to the point or place of\nBEGINNING.\nParcel C\n  All that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, situate, lying and\nbeing in the Borough of Manhattan, City, County and State of New York,\nbounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at the corner formed by the intersection of the easterly\nside of William Street and the southerly side of Wall Street;\n  RUNNING THENCE easterly along the southerly side of Wall Street 198.11\nfeet to the corner formed by the intersection of the westerly side of\nHanover Street and the southerly side of Wall Street;\n  THENCE southerly along the westerly side of Hanover Street 52.33 feet\nto an angel point therein;\n  THENCE southerly still alon...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_125">
            <num>(125)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet westerly from the corner formed by the\nintersection of the southerly side of 42nd Street with the westerly side\nof Lexington Avenue; and running\n  THENCE Southerly and parallel with Lexington Avenue ninety-eight</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_98">
            <num>(98)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nfeet nine</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches;\n  THENCE Westerly and parallel with 42nd Street fifty</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_50">
            <num>(50)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet to a\npoint in the easterly line of premises conveyed by Pershing Square\nBuilding Corporation to The Bowery Savings Bank by deed dated January 4,\n1921 and recorded in the Office of the Register of the County of New\nYork on January 5, 1921 in Liber 3190 of Conveyances at Page 440;\n  THENCE Southerly along the easterly side of said premises on a line at\nright angles to the southerly side of 42nd Street ninety-eight</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_98">
            <num>(98)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet\nnine</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches to the northerly side of 41st Street;\n  THENCE westerly along the northerly side of 41st Street one hundred\nfour</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_104">
            <num>(104)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet six</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches more or less to a point from which a line\ndrawn northerly to the southerly side of 42nd Street and parallel with\nPark Avenue and at right angles with the northerly side of 41st Street\nwould run through the center of the seventh row (reading easterly from\nPark Avenue) of column locations as shown by circular indications\nthereof upon map entitled: "State of New York, Transit Construction\nCommissioner, Engineering Department, Route Number 43, Section Number 1,\nBorough of Manhattan, Map or Plan showing property for resale east side\nof Park Avenue between East 41st Street and East 42nd Street, signed by\nD. L. Turner, Chief Engineer, dated February 4, 1920 (as revised May 25,\n1920) and designated as drawing number 175, file number 3801", which map\nis annexed to the deed above mentioned;\n  THENCE Northerly along said line one hundred ninety-seven</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_197">
            <num>(197)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet\nsix</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches to the southerly side of 42nd Street; and\n  THENCE Easterly along the southerly side of 42nd Street one hundred\nfifty-four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_154">
            <num>(154)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet six</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches more or less to the point or place\nof BEGINNING.\nParcel F\n  ALL THAT CERTAIN plot, piece, or parcel of land, situate, lying and\nbeing in the Borough of Manhattan, New York County, City and State of\nNew York, bounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at the comer formed by the intersection of the southerly\nline of West 61st Street with the easterly line of Riverside Boulevard,\nas shown on the City Map;\n  RUNNING THENCE easterly, along to the southerly line of West 61st\nStreet, 423 feet 6 inches to a point;\n  THENCE southerly, at right angles to the previous course, 74 feet\n3-1/8 inches;\n  THENCE southwesterly, along a line forming an included angle of 169\ndegrees 40 minutes 47 seconds, 138 feet 7-3/4 inches;\n  THENCE westerly, along a line forming an included angle of 100 degrees\n19 minutes 13 seconds, 445 feet I 0-5/8 inches to a point on the\neasterly side of Riverside Boulevard;\n  THENCE northerly, along the easterly line of Riverside Boulevard which\nform...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Make, or cause to be made, any loan to any person engaged in the\nmanufacture or sale of any alcoholic beverage at wholesale or retail.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Make any gift or render any service of any kind whatsoever,\ndirectly or indirectly, to any person licensed under this chapter which\nin the judgment of the liquor authority may tend to influence such\nlicensee to purchase the product of such manufacturer or wholesaler. The\nprovisions of this paragraph shall not be construed to prevent a\nmanufacturer or wholesaler from entertaining a licensee at lunch or\ndinner, or to prevent a manufacturer or wholesaler from participating in\nor supporting bona fide retailer association activities such as, but not\nlimited to, associate memberships, dinners, conventions, trade shows,\nproduct tastings and product education where such participation is in\nreasonable amounts and does not reach proportions that indicate attempts\nto influence the purchase of products of contributing manufacturers and\nwholesalers by the members of such retailer associations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Enter into any contract with any retail licensee whereby such\nlicensee agrees to confine his sales to alcoholic beverages manufactured\nor sold by one or more such manufacturers or wholesalers. Any such\ncontract shall be void and subject the licenses of all parties concerned\nto revocation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The prohibitions and restrictions contained in paragraphs b, c and\nd above shall not apply to any contractual arrangements between a\nlicensed manufacturer or wholesaler and a licensed retailer where such\nmanufacturer or wholesaler has made a substantial investment, directly\nor through such retailer, in the construction, capitalization or\nfurnishing of any exhibit, facility or installation in the area leased\nby the city of New York to New York World's Fair 1964-1965 Corporation,\npursuant to chapter four hundred twenty-eight of the laws of nineteen\nhundred sixty, as amended, and such retailer is conducting his business\nas a part of such exhibit or installation or is responsible to such\ncorporation for the construction, operation or maintenance of such\nexhibit, facility or installation. This modification to the prohibitions\nand restrictions contained in this paragraph shall continue until\nNovember first, nineteen hundred sixty-five.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The prohibitions and restrictions contained in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall not apply to any contractual or other\nfinancial arrangements undertaken by the Culinary Institute of America\nfor the education purposes of such institute, including student\nscholarships, academic building sponsorships, and Culinary Institute of\nAmerica event sponsorships that further the academic mission of the\nCulinary Institute of America, where such contractual or other financial\narrangements are between a licensed manufacturer, wholesaler, or\nretailer for on-premises consumption, and the Culinary Institute of\nAmerica, operating within the metes and bounds established by\nsubparagraph (xiv) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n  1-a. The provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this\nsection shall not apply to any licensed manufacturer or wholesaler\nlocated on the 35th floor of premises in the borough of Manhattan, city,\ncounty and state of New York, bounded and described as follows:\nbeginning at the corner formed by the intersection of the easterly side\nof Washington Street and the southerly side of Barclay Street; running\nthence easterly along the southerly side of Barclay Street, the\nfollowing three</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 88 degrees 37\nminutes 20 seconds East 161.04 feet;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 88 degrees 39 minutes 01\nseconds East 67.81 feet; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 88 degrees 36 minutes 50 seconds\nEast 112.04 feet to the corner formed by the intersection of the\nsoutherly side of Barclay Street and the westerly side of West Broadway;\nthence southerly along the westerly side of West Broadway, the following\nthree</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 13 degrees 29 minutes 10\nseconds West 33.54 feet;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 88 degrees 37 minutes 31 seconds East\n7.16 feet; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 13 degrees 29 minutes 10 seconds West 172.20\nfeet to the corner formed by the intersection of the westerly side of\nWest Broadway and the northerly side of Vesey Street; thence westerly\nalong the northerly side of Vesey Street, North 88 degrees 37 minutes 31\nseconds West 233.48 feet to the corner formed by the intersection of the\nnortherly side of Vesey Street and the easterly side of Washington\nStreet; and thence northerly along the easterly side of Washington\nStreet, North 18 degrees 10 minutes 00 seconds West 213.45 feet to the\npoint or place of beginning. Provided, however that, with respect to\nsuch manufacturer's or wholesaler's interest in a retail licensee\nlocated at premises described in paragraph (a-1) of subdivision thirteen\nof section one hundred six of this article:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such interest must have\nbeen acquired prior to the effective date of the chapter of the laws of\ntwo thousand nineteen which added this subdivision; (ii) such\nmanufacturer or wholesaler may not sell alcoholic beverages directly to\nsuch retail licensee; and (iii) no more than fifteen percent of the\nannual dollar value of alcoholic beverages purchased by such retail\nlicensee for sale on the premises may be produced by any such\nmanufacturer.\n  2. Any lien, mortgage, or other interest or estate however, now held\nby a manufacturer or wholesaler on the real property of any licensee,\nwhich lien, mortgage, interest or estate was acquired on or before\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred and thirty-two, shall not be\nincluded within the provisions of this section but the burden of\nestablishing the time of the accrual of the interest comprehended by\nthis subdivision shall be upon the person who claims to be entitled to\nthe protection and exemption afforded hereby.\n  3. Any interest or estate mentioned in this section held by a\nmanufacturer or wholesaler in an office building located in a city\nhaving a population of five hundred thousand or more and in which is\nlocated the licensed premises of such manufacturer or wholesaler shall\nnot prohibit</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the issuance of licenses pursuant to section sixty-four\nof this chapter for restaurant premises located in such building or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nsaid manufacturer or wholesaler from being interested directly or\nindirectly in such restaurant premises, provided the building is not\nless than five stories in height, both the building and the interior of\nthe restaurant premise have been granted landmark status in accordance\nwith applicable state or local law and space within the building is also\noccupied by persons other than the manufacturer or wholesaler, and that\nthe rental for the retail premises applied for shall be comparable to\nthat for similar space in such building and similar buildings in the\nimmediate neighborhood; and provided further that the provisions of this\nparagraph shall apply solely with respect to restaurant premises in a\nbuilding located on a parcel of land wholly within the boundaries of the\nborough of Manhattan, city and county of New York, and bounded and\ndescribed as follows: beginning at a corner formed by the intersection\nof the northerly side of East Fifty-second Street and the easterly si...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\nstate liquor authority shall issue a license under section seventy-six-a\nof this chapter to the New York State Wine and Culinary Center, Inc.\n("center") situated at the premises known as: all that certain plot,\npiece or parcel of land, with the buildings and improvements thereon\nerected, situate, lying and being in the City of Canandaigua, County of\nOntario and State of New York and being more particularly described as\nfollows: Being at an iron stake located on the northerly line of Village\nLot No. 9 where the same intersects the westerly line of South Main\nStreet; thence south 19 degrees 30' east along the westerly street line\nof South Main Street a distance of 60 feet to an iron stake which is the\npoint and place of beginning; thence</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>south 69 degrees 54' west a\ndistance of 284.26 feet to an iron stake; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>south 19 degrees\n30' east a distance of 248 feet to an iron stake; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>south 17\ndegrees 21' 10" west a distance of 120.05 feet to an iron stake; thence\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>south 81 degrees 52' 20" east a distance of 236.63 feet to an iron\nstake; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>north 8 degrees 10' east a distance of 30 feet to an\niron stake; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>south 81 degrees 50' east a distance of 100 feet\nto an iron stake; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>north 8 degrees 10' east a distance of\n94.97 feet to an iron stake located on the westerly street line of South\nMain Street; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_a__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>north 19 degrees 30' west along the westerly\nstreet line of South Main Street a distance of 392.52 feet to an iron\nstake which is the point and place of beginning.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The center may, but shall not be required to, produce wine as a\ncondition of such license.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from acting as a director,\nofficer, or employee of, or purveyor to, the center by reason of such\nperson holding a license under this law, or being affiliated with a\nlicensee under this law as a shareholder, partner, officer, director, or\nemployee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from being a lender or lessor to\nthe center, or a donor, patron, contributor or sponsor from time to time\nof the center through contributions in cash or in kind, on terms agreed\nwith the board of directors of the center, by reason of such person\nholding a license under this law, or being affiliated with a licensee\nunder this law as a shareholder, partner, officer, director, or\nemployee. Such persons shall be entitled, regardless of their licensing\nstatus under this law, to obtain all the benefits generally approved by\nthe board of directors of the center and offered to donors of similar\namounts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\ncenter is expressly authorized to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sell New York state produced wines, beers, ciders and distilled\nspirits for both on and off premise consumption;\n  (ii) offer tastings on the premises of such products and charge the\ngeneral public such amounts as it deems fit for such tastings. For\npurposes of this section, tastings may be conducted in a common tasting\narea on the premises;\n  (iii) provide banquet and entertainment facilities for the general\npublic for private parties in consideration of such fees as are\nestablished by the board of directors of the center from time to time,\nand to sell and serve at such events wines, ciders, malt beverages and\ndistilled spirits selected by persons hiring the facilities; and\n  (iv) hold through a wholly owned subsidiary a branch office permit at\nthe Finger Lakes Welcome Center situated at the premises known as:\n  All that tract or parcel of land situate in the City of Geneva, County\nof Ontario, State of New York, all as shown on a map entitled "Existing\nBuilding Exhibit Finger Lakes Welcome Center" prepared by Costich\nEngineering D.P.C dated February 28, 2018 having dwg # 4750 VE110 and\nbeing more particularly bounded and described as follows:\n  Beginning at the existing northwest corner of the One Story Frame\nFinger Lakes Welcome Center having grid coordinates of N1046012.35 E\n714603.03 referenced to the New York State Plane Coordinate System of\n1983 Central Zone; thence Easterly, and along the existing building face\na distance of 52.3 feet to a point; thence Northerly, and along the\nexisting building face a distance of 5.3 feet to a point; thence\nEasterly, and along the existing building face a distance of 40.3 feet\nto a point; thence Southerly, and along the existing building face a\ndistance of 26.5 feet to a point; thence Easterly, and along the\nexisting building face a distance of 5.4 feet to a point; thence\nSoutherly, and along the existing building face a distance of 15.0 feet\nto a point; thence Easterly, and along the existing bu...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\nstate liquor authority shall issue a license under section seventy-six-a\nof this chapter to the Finger Lakes Wine Center, Inc. ("center")\nsituated at the premises known as:\n  All that tract or parcel of land situate in the City of Ithaca, County\nof Tompkins and State of New York, bounded and described as follows:\n  PARCEL A:\n  BEGINNING at a point at the intersection of the easterly street line\nof South Cayuga Street with the northerly street line of East Clinton\nStreet;\n  thence North 02 degrees 05 minutes 21 seconds West along the easterly\nstreet line of South Cayuga Street a distance of 273.47 feet to a point;\n  thence North 87 degrees 29 minutes 52 seconds East a distance of 77.84\nfeet to a point;\n  thence South 02 degrees 30 minutes 08 seconds East a distance of\n108.17 feet to a point;\n  thence North 87 degrees 29 minutes 52 seconds East a distance of 46.83\nfeet to a point;\n  thence South 02 degrees 30 minutes 08 seconds East a distance of\n107.31 feet to a point;\n  thence North 87 degrees 29 minutes 52 seconds East a distance of 12.17\nfeet to a point;\n  thence South 02 degrees 30 minutes 08 seconds East a distance of 24.70\nfeet to a point;\n  thence South 87 degrees 29 minutes 52 seconds West a distance of 12.17\nfeet to a point;\n  thence South 02 degrees 30 minutes 08 seconds East a distance of 33.50\nfeet to a point in the northerly street line of East Clinton Street;\n  thence South 87 degrees 35 minutes 39 seconds West a distance of\n126.65 feet to the point of beginning, containing 0.680 acres of land.\n  SUBJECT to the following:\n  Restrictive covenants running with the land, contained in a Deed from\nthe Ithaca Urban Renewal Agency to the City of Ithaca dated July 13,\n1976 and recorded in said Clerk's Office on July 13, 1977 in Liber 558\nof Deeds at page 672.\n  Restrictive covenants running with the land, contained in a Deed from\nthe Ithaca Urban Renewal Agency t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The center may, but shall not be required to, produce wine as a\ncondition of such license.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from acting as a director,\nofficer, or employee of, or purveyor to, the center by reason of such\nperson holding a license under this chapter, or being affiliated with a\nlicensee under this chapter as a shareholder, partner, officer,\ndirector, or employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from being a lender or lessor to\nthe center, or a donor, patron, contributor or sponsor from time to time\nof the center through contributions in cash or in kind, on terms agreed\nwith the board of directors of the center, by reason of such person\nholding a license under this chapter, or being affiliated with a\nlicensee under this chapter as a shareholder, partner, officer,\ndirector, or employee. Such persons shall be entitled, regardless of\ntheir licensing status under this chapter, to obtain all the benefits\ngenerally approved by the board of directors of the center and offered\nto donors of similar amounts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The center is expressly authorized to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>charge the general public such amounts as it sees fit for the\ntasting of New York state wines sold on the premises;\n  (ii) provide banquet and entertainment facilities for the general\npublic for private parties in consideration of such fees as are\nestablished by the board of directors of the center from time to time\nand to sell and serve at such events wines, malt beverages and distilled\nspirits selected by persons hiring the facilities; and\n  (iii) provide for wine related and other educational classes as deemed\nappropriate by the center, either alone or in conjunction with other\nentities that conduct educational classes, and charge the general public\nsuch amounts as it sees fit for the purpose of carrying out the\nprovisions of this subparagraph.\n  6. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\nstate liquor authority may issue a license under subdivision two-c of\nsection sixty-one of this chapter to the owner and/or operator of the\nparcels described in this paragraph. The legal descriptions for the\nthree parcels so identified as the site are as follows:\n                                PARCEL A\n  All that piece or parcel of property situate in the Village of Lake\nGeorge, County of Warren, State of New York and being bounded and\ndescribed as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point at the intersection of the southwesterly boundary\nof Beach Road with the southeasterly boundary of lands now or formerly\nof Holly RAJ Inc., and running thence southeasterly along the said\nsouthwesterly boundary of Beach Road and the southwesterly boundary of\nlands now or formerly of the Village of Lake George the following</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nnine courses and distances: 1) South 47Á 49' 51" East 49.20 feet to a\npoint; 2) South 41Á 08' 51" East 50.18 feet to a point; 3) South 34Á 19'\n51" East 20.62 feet to a point; 4) South 34Á 19' 51" East 29.38 feet to\na point; 5) South 28Á 23' 51" East 54.00 feet to a point; 6) South 23Á\n28' 51" East 75.29 feet to a point; 7) South 25Á 57' 51" East 130.22\nfeet to a point; 8) South 30Á 43' 21" East 109.09 feet to a point; and\n9) South 29Á 21' 51" East 140.00 feet to a point in the northwesterly\nboundary of the premises conveyed by The Counties of Warren and\nWashington Industrial Development Agency to The Fort William Henry\nCorporation by deed dated May 18, 1998 and recorded in the Warren County\nClerk's Office on May 28, 1998 in Liber 1066 of Deeds at Page 279;\nthence South 60Á 37' 18" West along the said northwesterly boundary of\nthe premises conveyed by The Counties of Warren and Washington\nIndustrial Development Agency to The Fort William Henry Corporation\n70.01 feet to a...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>five courses and distances: 1) North 29Á\n21' 51" West 139.17 feet to a point; 2) North 30Á 43' 21" West 111.17\nfeet to a point; 3) North 25Á 55' 51" West 130.20 feet to a point; 4)\nNorth 26Á 32' 41" West 145.00 feet to a point; and 5) North 42Á 42' 21"\nWest 120.00 feet to a point in the first mentioned southeasterly\nboundary of lands now or formerly of Holly RAJ Inc.; thence North 51Á\n01' 09" East along the said southeasterly boundary of lands now or\nformerly of Holly RAJ Inc. 70.00 feet to the point of beginning,\ncontaining 1.062 acres of land, being the same more or less.\n                                PARCEL B\n  All that piece or parcel of property situate in the Village of Lake\nGeorge, County of Warren, State of New York and being bounded and\ndescribed as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point at the intersection of the easterly boundary of\nNew York State Route 9N with the northerly boundary of lands now or\nformerly of Charles R. Wood Foundation, and running thence norther...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances: 1) North 03Á- 06'- 51" West\n54.12 feet to a point; 2) North 00Á- 54'- 09" East 281.77 feet to a\npoint; 3) North 01Á-45'- 09" East 59.83 feet to a point; and 4) North\n02Á- 47'- 35" West 51.87 feet to an iron pin in the southerly boundary\nof other lands now or formerly of Fort William Henry Corporation; thence\neasterly along the said southerly boundary of other lands now or\nformerly of Fort William Henry Corporation the following three</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\ncourses and distances: 1) North 88Á- 22'- 09" East 475.96 feet to a\npoint; 2) North 60Á- 07'- 09" East 66.22 feet to a point; and 3) North\n47Á- 47'- 09" East 315.47 feet to an iron pipe in the easterly boundary\nof lands now or formerly of the Village of Lake George; thence southerly\nalong the said easterly boundary of lands now or formerly of The Village\nof Lake George the following three</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances: 1) South\n32Á- 08'- 51" East 148.00 feet to a point; 2) South 37Á- 04'- 51" East\n221.91 feet to a point; and 3) South 32Á- 47'- 51" East 83.60 feet to a\npoint in the northerly boundary of the aforementioned lands now or\nformerly of Charles R. Wood Foundation; thence westerly along the said\nnortherly boundary of lands now or formerly of Charles R. Wood\nFoundation the following four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances: 1) South 55Á-\n39'- 09" West 188.00 feet to a square head bolt; 2) South 68Á- 08'- 09"\nWest 115.00 feet to a point; 3) South 81Á- 37'-09" West 240.84 feet to a\npoint; and 4) South 74Á- 08'- 09" West 546.05 feet to the point of\nbeginning, containing 8.558 acres of land, being the same more or less.\n  ALSO, ALL that certain piece or parcel of land situate lying and being\nin the Village of Lake George, County of Warren, State of New York,\nbeing more particularly described as follows:\n  COMMENCING at a point located on the westerly boundary of lands now or\nformerly of Warren County as described in Liber 281, Page 51, said point\nalso being on the division line between lands now or formerly of Warren\nCounty (Liber 4390 Page 154) on the south and lands now or formerly of\nFort William Henry Corp. (Liber 497 Page 222) on the north; thence along\nsaid division line South 40Á27'30" West, 188.00 feet to the Point of\nBeginning; thence through said lands of Warren ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances: 1) South 33Á45'28" West, 74.95 feet to\na point, 2) South 59Á52'14" West, 108.57 feet to a point, and 3) North\n75Á07'46" West, 41.87 feet to a point on the division line between said\nlands of Warren County on the south and lands now or formerly of Fort\nWilliam Henry Corp. (Liber 497 Page 222) on the north; thence along said\ndivision line North 66Á25'30" East, 91.92 feet to a point; thence North\n52Á56'30" East, 115.00 feet to the point or place of beginning.\n  EXCEPTING AND RESERVING THEREFROM, ALL that certain piece or parcel of\nland situate lying and being in the Village of Lake George, County of\nWarren, State of New York, being more particularly described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point located on the westerly boundary of lands now or\nformerly of Warren County as described in Liber 281, Page 51, said point\nalso being on the division line between lands now or formerly of Warren\nCounty (Liber 4390 Page 154) on the south and lands now or formerly of...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances northerly from the\nintersection of the easterly boundary of New York State Route 9N with\nthe northerly boundary of lands now or formerly of Charles R. Wood\nFoundation: 1) North 03Á- 06'- 51" West 54.12 feet; 2) North 00Á- 54'-\n09" East 281.77 feet; 3) North 01Á- 45'- 09" East 59.83 feet; and 4)\nNorth 02Á- 47'- 35" West 51.87 feet, and running thence from said point\nof beginning northerly along the said easterly boundary of New York\nState Route 9N the following seven</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances: 1) North\n03Á- 29'-09" East 105.00 feet to a point; 2) North 09Á- 11'- 09" East\n60.10 feet to a point; 3) North 05Á- 41'- 09" East 161.06 feet to a\npoint; 4) North 09Á- 28'-34" East 124.23 feet to an iron pin; 5) North\n14Á- 08'- 27" East 150.26 feet to a square monument; 6) North 22Á- 36'-\n14" East 111.15 feet to a point; and 7) North 17Á- 47'- 09" East 91.79\nfeet to an iron pipe in the southerly boundary of lands now or formerly\nof Adirondack Entertainment and Recreation, Inc.; thence South 59Á- 07'-\n51" East along the said southerly boundary of lands now or formerly of\nAdirondack Entertainment and Recreation, Inc. 40.70 feet to a point;\nthence North 51Á- 01'- 09" East along the southeasterly boundary of said\nlands now or formerly of Adirondack Entertainment and Recreation, Inc.\n167.30 feet to a point in the southwesterly boundary of lands now or\nformerly of The Adirondack Lakeview Corporation; thence southeasterly\nalong the said southwesterly bound...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and\ndistances: 1) South 42Á- 42'- 21" East 120.00 feet to a point; 2) South\n26Á- 32'- 41" East 145.00 feet to a point; 3) South 25Á-55'- 51" East\n130.20 feet to a point; 4) South 30Á- 43'- 21" East 111.17 feet to a\npoint; and 5) South 29Á- 21'- 51" East 139.17 feet to a point; thence\nNorth 60Á- 37'- 18" East along the southeasterly boundary of said lands\nnow or formerly of The Adirondack Lakeview Corporation 70.01 feet to a\npoint in the westerly boundary of lands now or formerly of the Village\nof Lake George; thence southerly along the said westerly boundary of\nlands now or formerly of The Village of Lake George the following two\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances: 1) South 29Á- 21'- 51" East 32.24 feet to a\npoint; and 2) South 30Á- 27'- 51" East 73.00 feet to an iron pipe in the\nnortherly boundary of other lands now or formerly of Fort William Henry\nCorporation; thence westerly along the said northerly boundary of other\nlands now or formerly of Fort William Henry Corporation the following\nthree</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_101__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances: 1) South 47Á- 47'- 09" West 315.47 feet\nto a point; 2) South 60Á- 07'- 09" West 66.22 feet to a point; and 3)\nSouth 88Á- 22'- 09" West 475.96 feet to the point of beginning,\ncontaining 9.398 acres of land, being the same more or less.\n  8.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\nstate liquor authority shall issue a license under section seventy-six-a\nof this chapter to the Concord Grape Belt Heritage Association Inc.\nGrape Discovery Center ("center") situated at the premises known as: all\nthat certain plot, piece or parcel of land, with the buildings and\nimprovements thereon erected, situated, lying and being in the Town of\nWestfield, County of Chautauqua and State of New York being parcels\n209.00-2-13 and 209.00-2-14 and being more particularly described as\nfollows:\n                                PARCEL A\n  All that tract or parcel of land, situate in the Town of Westfield,\nCounty of Chautauqua and State of New York, being part of Lot 13, Town 4\nand Range 14 of the Holland Land Company's Survey and further bounded\nand described as follows:\n  Beginning at a set "MAG" nail on the south bounds of U.S. Route 20\nalso know as Main Road, also known as the Buffalo and Erie Road, said\n"MAG" nail being N 60 degrees 17' 18" E, 264.87 feet as measured along\nthe south bounds of U.S. Route 20, from the northwest corner of premises\ndescribed in deed from David S. Neill to Sam F. Nixon, dated January 30,\n1916, and recorded in the Chautauqua County Clerk's Office in Liber 421\nof Deeds at page 165; thence N 60 degrees 17' 18" E, along the south\nbounds of U.S. Route 20, a distance of 195.88 feet to a set "MAG" nail\nin asphalt; thence N 64 degrees 0' 0" E, and still along the south\nbounds of U.S. Route 20, a distance 70 feet to a set "MAG" nail in\nasphalt; thence S 1 degree 55' 0" W, 250 feet to an existing iron pin at\nthe northwest corner of lands of Joanne W. Nixon, as described in a deed\nrecorded in the Chautauqua County Clerk's Office in Liber 2182 of Deeds\nat page 196; thence continuing along the same course, S 1 degree 55' 0"\nW along the west line of lands of said Nixon, 78.8 feet to an existing\niron stake at the northeast corner of lands of Joanne W. Nixon as\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The center may, but shall not be required to, produce wine as a\ncondition of such license.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from acting as a director,\nofficer, or employee of, or purveyor to, the center by reason of such\nperson holding a license under this chapter, or being affiliated with a\nlicensee under this chapter as a shareholder, partner, officer,\ndirector, or employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from being a lender or lessor to\nthe center, or a donor, patron, contributor or sponsor from time to time\nof the center through contributions in cash or in kind, on terms agreed\nwith the board of directors of the center, by reason of such person\nholding a license under this chapter, or being affiliated with a\nlicensee under this chapter as a shareholder, partner, officer,\ndirector, or employee. Such persons shall be entitled, regardless of\ntheir licensing status under this chapter, to obtain all the benefits\ngenerally approved by the board of directors of the center and offered\nto donors of similar amounts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\ncenter is expressly authorized to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sell New York state produced wines, beers and distilled spirits\nfor both on and off premise consumption;\n  (ii) offer tastings on the premises of such products and charge the\ngeneral public such amounts as it deems fit for such tastings. For\npurposes of this section, tastings may be conducted in a common tasting\narea on the premises; and\n  (iii) provide banquet and entertainment facilities for the general\npublic for private parties in consideration of such fees as are\nestablished by the board of directors of the center from time to time,\nand to sell and serve at such events wines, malt beverages and distilled\nspirits selected by persons hiring the facilities.\n  9.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\nstate liquor authority shall issue a license under section sixty-one-a\nof this chapter to Cornell university on behalf of the New York state\ncollege of agriculture and life sciences and the New York state\nagricultural experiment station as defined in sections fifty-seven\nhundred twelve and fifty-seven hundred thirteen of the education law.\nIssuance of such a license shall not preclude or nullify other licenses\ngranted to Cornell university, whether now or in the future, in all its\nlocations in New York state in accordance with the provisions of this\nchapter. Issuance of such a license shall not restrict the ability of\nCornell university, or the New York state college of agriculture and\nlife sciences and the New York state agricultural experiment station to\nconduct research, teaching, education, extension and outreach, and\neconomic development activities related to products that are not\nregulated by this chapter. For purposes of compliance with this chapter,\nthe New York state college of agriculture and life sciences and the New\nYork state agricultural experiment station as defined in sections\nfifty-seven hundred twelve and fifty-seven hundred thirteen of the\neducation law shall be considered to be located on a farm.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cornell university, acting on behalf of the New York state college\nof agriculture and life sciences and the New York state agricultural\nexperiment station may, but shall not be required to, produce wine,\nbeer, distilled spirits, distillates, cider, mead and other fermented\nproducts as a condition of such license.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from acting as a director,\nadvisory council member, officer, or employee of, or purveyor to,\nCornell university and the New York state college of agriculture and\nlife sciences and the New York state agricultural experiment station by\nreason of such person holding a license under this chapter, or being\naffiliated with a licensee under this chapter as a shareholder, partner,\nofficer, director, or employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from being a donor, patron,\ncontributor or sponsor from time to time of Cornell university and the\nNew York state college of agriculture and life sciences and the New York\nstate agricultural experiment station through contributions in cash or\nin kind, by reason of such person holding a license under this chapter,\nor being affiliated with a licensee under this chapter as a shareholder,\npartner, officer, director, or employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary,\nCornell university, acting through the New York state college of\nagriculture and life sciences and the New York state agricultural\nexperiment station is expressly authorized to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>manufacture New York state produced wines, beers, ciders, mead,\ndistilled spirits and other fermented products for educational,\nworkforce development and research purposes to include industrial\nproduct or non-consumable product research;\n  (ii) offer organoleptic tastings, on the premises, of such products\nonly for the purposes of education, workforce development, and research\nand analysis. No fees may be imposed for such tastings, other than as\npart of the general cost of an educational course, workshop, or other\ninstructional event;\n  (iii) provide educational courses, workforce development and\nexperiential learning opportunities within the New York state college of\nagriculture and life sciences and the New York state agricultural\nexperiment station and allow separately licensed entities to utilize\nfacilities and equipment located at such places for the production of\nsmall-scale, pilot batches of wine, distilled spirits, cider, mead, beer\nand other fermented products not for further retail sale and for\nresearch purposes only; and\n  (iv) conduct product testing and technical analysis including, but not\nlimited to, sensory analysis, of New York state and non-New York state\nmanufactured wine, distilled spirits, cider, mead, beer, and other\nfermented products in accordance with an internally established fee\nschedule.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary,\nCornell university may:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>offer educational courses, workshops or\nother instructional events on wine, distilled spirits, cider, mead, beer\nand other fermented products through any of its colleges, schools or\nunits, in accordance with internally established fee schedules and under\nappropriate licenses; and (ii) use its facilities, and provide the use\nof its facilities to third parties, for functions at which alcoholic\nbeverages may be sold and served provided the university or third\nparties, as applicable, have obtained the appropriate permit or license\nfrom the authority.\n  10.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary,\nthe state liquor authority shall issue a license under section\nsixty-one-a of this chapter to the community college in Broome county,\nestablished pursuant to article one hundred twenty-six of the education\nlaw, in the city of Binghamton, and the Broome county culinary and\nevents center on the premises described as follows:\n  ALL THAT TRACT OR PARCEL OF LAND, situate in the city of Binghamton,\nCounty of Broome, and State of New York, being more particularly\ndescribed as follows:\n  Beginning at a point in the east side of Exchange Street at the\nsouth-west corner of the stone front building known as "Pope Block;"\nthence,\n  1. Southerly, along the easterly line of Exchange Street, 107.41 feet\n(one hundred and seven feet and five inches) to a point where the\neasterly line of Exchange Street intersects the north line of Congdon\nPlace; thence,\n  2. Easterly, along the north line of Congdon Place, making a measured\ninterior angle of 93Á 01' 02" with the east line of Exchange Street, a\ndistance of 200.43 feet to a point, said point being 50 feet westerly\nfrom the west line of Myrtle Avenue; thence,\n  3. Northerly, along a line parallel with the west line Myrtle Avenue,\nmaking an interior angle of 88Á 59' 55" with the north line of Congdon\nPlace, a distance of 65.00 feet to a point; thence,\n  4. Westerly, along a line parallel with the north line of Congdon\nPlace, making an interior angle of 91Á 00' 05" with the last described\nline, a distance of 71.95 feet to a point; thence,\n  5. Northerly, along a line making an interior angle of 271Á 03' 58"\nwith the last described line a distance of 44.08 feet to a point;\nthence,\n  6. Westerly, along a line making an interior angle of 88Á 09' 38" with\nthe last described line, a distance of 133.93 feet to the Point of\nBeginning, said line forming a measured interior angle of 87Á 45' 22"\nwith the east line of Exchange street.\n  The above described ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The community college in Broome county and Broome county culinary\nand events center may, but shall not be required to, produce wine, beer,\ndistilled spirits, cider and mead as a condition of such license.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from acting as a director,\nadvisory council member, officer, or employee of, or purveyor to, the\ncommunity college in Broome county and Broome county culinary and events\ncenter by reason of such person holding a license under this chapter, or\nbeing affiliated with a licensee under this chapter as a shareholder,\npartner, officer, director, or employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be disqualified from being a donor, patron,\ncontributor or sponsor from time to time of the community college in\nBroome county and Broome county culinary and events center through\ncontributions in cash or in kind, by reason of such person holding a\nlicense under this chapter, or being affiliated with a licensee under\nthis chapter as a shareholder, partner, officer, director, or employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\ncommunity college in the Broome county and Broome county culinary and\nevents center is expressly authorized to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sell New York state produced wines, beers, ciders, meads and\ndistilled spirits for both on and off-premises consumption;\n  (ii) manufacture New York state produced wines, beers, ciders, meads\nand distilled spirits for educational, workforce development and\nresearch purposes to include industrial product or non-consumable\nproduct innovation research;\n  (iii) offer tastings, on the premises, of such products only for the\npurposes of education, workforce development, and research and analysis.\nFor purposes of this subdivision, tastings may only be conducted on the\npremises of the community college in Broome county and Broome county\nculinary and events center described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision. No fees may be imposed for such tastings, other than as\npart of the general cost of an educational course, workshop, or other\ninstructional event;\n  (iv) provide educational courses, workforce development and\nexperiential learning opportunities within the community college in\nBroome county and Broome county culinary and events center; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide banquet and entertainment facilities for the general\npublic for private parties in consideration of such fees as are\nestablished by the community college in Broome county and Broome county\nculinary and events center from time to time, and to sell and serve at\nsuch events wines, ciders, beers, mead and distilled spirits selected by\npersons hiring the facilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_101__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of compliance with this chapter, the community\ncollege in Broome county and the Broome county culinary and events\ncenter shall be considered to be located on a farm.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>