<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="106"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_106">
        <num>106</num>
        <heading>Provisions governing licensees to sell at retail for consumption on the premises</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No retail licensee for on-premises consumption, except\ncorporations operating railroad cars or aircraft being operated on\nregularly scheduled flights by a United States certificated airline or\npersons or corporations operating a hotel, as defined in subdivision\nfourteen of section three of this chapter, for exclusive use in the\nfurnishing of room service in the manner prescribed by rule or\nregulation of the state liquor authority, shall keep upon the licensed\npremises any liquors and/or wines in any cask, barrel, keg, hogshead or\nother container, except in the original sealed package as received from\nthe manufacturer or wholesaler. Such containers shall have affixed\nthereto such labels as may be required by the rules of the liquor\nauthority, together with all necessary federal revenue and New York\nstate excise stamps as required by law. No retail licensee for\non-premises consumption shall reuse, refill, tamper with, intentionally\nadulterate, dilute or fortify the contents of any container of alcoholic\nbeverages as received from the manufacturer or wholesaler.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, a retail licensee for on-premises consumption may prepare\nand keep drinks containing alcoholic beverages in dispensing machines,\nhaving capacities of not less than a gallon, which continually mix such\ndrinks or utilizing a pressurized mixing and dispensing system.\n  * 2-a.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, in\naddition to any other privilege provided under this chapter, any retail\nlicense that allows for liquor and/or wine sale for on-premises\nconsumption shall also include the privilege to sell for take-out and\ndelivery, any product it may otherwise sell at retail, subject to the\nfollowing conditions:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any purchase for take-out or delivery must be accompanied by a\npurchase of a substantial food item;\n  (ii) the alcoholic beverages are packaged in a container with a secure\nlid or cap sealed in a manner designed to prevent consumption without\nremoval of the lid or cap by breaking the seal;\n  (iii) beverages purchased for take-out or delivery are subject to any\napplicable state and municipal open container laws, rules, regulations,\nor ordinances;\n  (iv) takeout and delivery of alcoholic beverages may only occur during\nlicensed hours of operation of on premises retailers in the county in\nwhich the licensed premises are located or, if different, the hours of\noperation set forth in the licensee's method of operation with the\nauthority;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the price per serving shall be the same as if consumed on premises\nand shall not be sold as part of any promotion or special unless such\npromotion or special is also available for consumption on premises; and\nfurther provided each serving shall be available only in the same manner\nas available on premises;\n  (vi) the licensee shall not sell for take-out, or deliver, any bottles\nof liquor or bottles of wine;\n  (vii) the licensee shall not advertise or promote the sale of full\nbottles of wine or liquor for off-premises consumption; and\n  (viii) the licensee shall not display full bottles of wine or liquor\nfor the purpose of promoting the sale of such products for off-premises\nconsumption.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Deliveries made via motor vehicle shall only be made in</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a\nvehicle permitted by the authority pursuant to section ninety-four of\nthis chapter, or (ii) in a vehicle owned and operated, or hired and\noperated, by the licensee or its employee pursuant to section one\nhundred sixteen of this article; provided deliveries may be made\nutilizing the vehicle of an employee of the licensee, and provided\nfurther that a copy of the permit or license must be present in any\nvehicle while making deliveries. Delivery must be to a residential\naddress, and may not be delivered except to a person twenty-one years of\nage or older at that residence who is not at the time of delivery\nintoxicated. Delivery drivers shall require a recipient, at the delivery\naddress, upon delivery, to demonstrate that the recipient is at least\ntwenty-one years of age by providing a valid form of photographic\nidentification authorized by section sixty-five-b of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to change the\nexisting privilege of a retail licensee for on-premises consumption to\nsell beer, cider, or mead for consumption off the premises as currently\nprovided for in this chapter. Provided, further, that nothing contained\nin this subdivision shall be deemed to supersede the provisions of\nsection one thousand two hundred twenty-seven of the vehicle and traffic\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority may promulgate guidance, rules and regulations\nnecessary to implement the provisions of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority may, on its own initiative or on complaint of any\nperson, institute proceedings to suspend or revoke a licensee's ability\nto sell alcoholic beverages for takeout or delivery pursuant to this\nsubdivision after a hearing, in accordance with section one hundred\nnineteen of this article, at which such licensee shall be given an\nopportunity to be heard. Such proceedings and such hearing shall be held\nin such manner and upon such notice as may be prescribed by the rules of\nthe authority.\n  * NB Repealed April 9, 2030\n  * 2-b. Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter to the contrary,\na retail licensee for on-premises consumption shall be authorized to\npurchase up to six bottles of wine or liquor in the aggregate per week\nfrom an off-premises retail licensee, and may resell any wine and liquor\nso purchased for consumption on the premises licensed therefor.\n  * NB Effective March 5, 2026\n  3. No retail licensee for on-premises consumption shall sell, deliver\nor give away, or cause or permit or procure to be sold, delivered or\ngiven away any liquors and/or wines for consumption off the premises\nwhere sold. The provisions of this subdivision shall not prohibit a\nlicensed winery or farm winery from allowing a patron to leave the\nwinery or farm winery with a partially consumed bottle of wine provided\nthat the removal of the bottle is done in accordance with subdivision\nfour of section eighty-one of this chapter.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No liquors and/or wines shall be sold or served in premises\nlicensed under section sixty-four or clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision six of\nsection sixty-four-a of this chapter, except at tables where food may be\nserved and except as provided by subdivision four of section one\nhundred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No liquors and/or wines shall be sold or served in premises\nlicensed under clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision six of section sixty-four-a of\nthis chapter, except at such times and upon such conditions and by the\nuse of such facilities as the liquor authority, by regulation, may\nprescribe with due regard to the convenience of the public and the\nstrict avoidance of sales prohibited by this chapter.\n  4-a. No beer shall be sold or served at a bar, counter or other\nsimilar contrivance unless a card, sign or plate, visible to the\ncustomer, upon which the name of the brewer is conspicuously and legibly\ndisplayed, is annexed or affixed to the tap or faucet from which the\nbeer is drawn.\n  5. No alcoholic beverages shall be sold, offered for sale or given\naway upon any premises licensed to sell alcoholic beverages at retail\nfor on-premises consumption, during the following hours:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, on\nSunday, from four ante meridiem to ten o'clock a.m., except pursuant to\na permit issued under section ninety-nine-h or subdivision five of\nsection ninety-seven of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, on any\nother day between four ante meridiem and eight ante meridiem.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On any day between three ante meridian and six ante meridian, for\na premises located within an international airport owned or operated by\nthe Port Authority of New York and New Jersey. The provisions of this\nparagraph shall not be subject to change pursuant to subdivision eleven\nof section seventeen of this chapter.\n  Unless otherwise approved by the authority pursuant to subdivision\neleven of section seventeen of this chapter, where any rule has been\nadopted in a county on or before April first, nineteen hundred\nninety-five, further restricting the hours of sale for alcoholic\nbeverages, such restricted hours shall be the hours, during which the\nsale of alcoholic beverages at retail for on-premises consumption shall\nnot be permitted within such county.\n  Nor shall any person be permitted to consume any alcoholic beverages\nupon any such premises later than one-half hour after the start of the\nprohibited hours of sale provided for in this section.\n  6. No person licensed to sell alcoholic beverages shall suffer or\npermit any gambling on the licensed premises, or suffer or permit such\npremises to become disorderly. The use of the licensed premises, or any\npart thereof, for the sale of lottery tickets, playing of bingo or games\nof chance, or as a simulcast facility or simulcast theater pursuant to\nthe racing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law, when duly authorized\nand lawfully conducted thereon, shall not constitute gambling within the\nmeaning of this subdivision.\n  6-a. No retail licensee for on-premises consumption shall suffer or\npermit any person to appear on licensed premises in such manner or\nattire as to expose to view any portion of the pubic area, anus, vulva\nor genitals, or any simulation thereof, nor shall suffer or permit any\nfemale to appear on licensed premises in such manner or attire as to\nexpose to view any portion of the breast below the top of the areola, or\nany simulation thereof.\n  6-b. No retail licensee for on-pre...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No retail licensee for on-premises consumption shall suffer,\npermit or promote an event on its premises wherein the contestants\ndeliver, or are not forbidden by the applicable rules thereof from\ndelivering kicks, punches or blows of any kind to the body of an\nopponent or opponents, whether or not the event consists of a\nprofessional match or exhibition, and whether or not the event or any\nsuch act, or both, is done for compensation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The prohibition contained in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision,\nhowever, shall not be applied to any authorized combative sport.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any other penalty provided by law, a violation of\nthis subdivision shall constitute an adequate ground for instituting a\nproceeding to suspend, cancel or revoke the license of the violator in\naccordance with the applicable procedures specified in section one\nhundred nineteen of this article.\n  7. Except where a permit to do so is obtained pursuant to section\n405.10 of the penal law, no retail licensee for on-premises consumption\nshall suffer, permit, or promote an event on its premises wherein any\nperson shall use, explode, or cause to explode, any fireworks or other\npyrotechnics in a building as defined in paragraph e of subdivision one\nof section 405.10 of the penal law, that is covered by such retail\nlicense or possess such fireworks or pyrotechnics for such purpose. In\naddition to any other penalty provided by law, a violation of this\nsubdivision shall constitute an adequate ground for instituting a\nproceeding to suspend, cancel, or revoke the license of the violator in\naccordance with the applicable procedures specified in section one\nhundred nineteen of this article. Provided however, if more than one\nretail licensee is participating in a single event, upon approval by the\nauthority, only one retail licensee must obtain such permit.\n  8. A club or a luncheon club licensed to sell alcoholic beverages for\non-premises consumption shall be permitted to sell such beverages only\nto its members and to their guests accompanying them.\n  9. No restaurant and no premises licensed to sell liquors and/or wines\nfor on-premises consumption under clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision six of\nsection sixty-four-a of this chapter shall be permitted to have any\nopening or means of entrance or passageway for persons or things between\nthe licensed premises and any other room or place in the building\ncontaining the licensed premises, or any adjoining or abutting premises,\nunless such licensed premises are in a building used as a hotel and\nserves as a dining room for guests of such hotel, or unless such\npremises are a bona fide restaurant with such access for patrons and\nguests from any part of such building or adjoining or abutting premises\nas shall serve public convenience in a reasonable and suitable manner;\nor unless such licensed premises are in a building owned or operated by\nany county, town, city, village or public authority or agency, in a park\nor other similar place of public accommodation. All glass in any window\nor door on said licensed premises shall be clear and shall not be\nopaque, colored, stained or frosted.\n  10. A vessel licensed to sell liquors and/or wines for on-premises\nconsumption shall not be permitted to sell any liquors and/or wines,\nwhile said vessel is moored to a pier or dock, except that vessels\nsailing on established schedules shall be permitted to sell liquors\nand/or wines for a period of three hours prior to the regular advertised\nsailing time.\n  11. A railroad car or aircraft being operated on regularly scheduled\nflights by a United States certificated airline licensed to sell liquors\nand/or wines for on-premises consumption shall be permitted to sell\nliquors and/or wines only to passengers and while in actual transit,\nexcept that a railroad operating licensed cars shall be allowed to sell\nliquors and/or wines from portable carts located on station platforms\nlocated at Penn Station, Grand Central Station, Jamaica, Hunterspoint\nAvenue or Flatbush from which such licensed railroad cars depart.\n  12. Each retail licensee for on-premises consumption shall keep and\nmaintain upon ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No retail licensee for on-premises consumption shall be\ninterested, directly or indirectly, in any premises where liquors, wines\nor beer are manufactured or sold at wholesale, by stock ownership,\ninterlocking directors, mortgage or lien on any personal or real\nproperty or by any other means, except that liquors, wines or beer may\nbe manufactured or sold wholesale by the person licensed as a\nmanufacturer or wholesaler thereof:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on real property owned by an interstate railroad corporation or a\nUnited States certificated airline with a retail license for on-premises\nconsumption; or\n  (ii) on premises or with respect to a business constituting an\novernight lodging and resort facility located wholly within the\nboundaries of the town of North Elba, county of Essex, township eleven,\nRichard's survey, great lot numbers two hundred seventy-eight, two\nhundred seventy-nine, two hundred eight, two hundred ninety-eight, two\nhundred ninety-nine, three hundred, three hundred eighteen, three\nhundred nineteen, three hundred twenty, three hundred thirty-five and\nthree hundred thirty-six, and township twelve, Thorn's survey, great lot\nnumbers one hundred six and one hundred thirteen, as shown on the\nAdirondack map, compiled by the conservation department of the state of\nNew York - nineteen hundred sixty-four edition, in the Essex county\natlas at page twenty-seven in the Essex county clerk's office,\nElizabethtown, New York, provided that such facility maintains not less\nthan two hundred fifty rooms and suites for overnight lodging; or\n  (iii) on premises or with respect to the operation of a restaurant in\nan office building located in a city having a population of five hundred\nthousand or more and in which is located the licensed premises of such\nmanufacturer or wholesaler, provided that the building, the interior of\nthe retail premise and the rental therefor fully comply with the\ncriteria set forth in paragraph two of subdivision three of section one\nhundred one of this article; or\n  (iv) any such premises or business located on that tract or parcel of\nland, or any subdivision thereof, situate in the Village of Lake Placid,\nTown of North Elba, Essex County, New York; it being also a part of Lot\nNo. 279, Township No. 11, Old Military Tract, Richard's Survey; it being\nalso all of Lot No. 23 and part of Lot No. 22 as shown and designated on\na certain map entitled "Map of Building S...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any such premises or business located on that certain piece or\nparcel of land, or any subdivision thereof, situate, lying and being in\nthe Town of Plattsburgh, County of Clinton, State of New York and being\nmore particularly bounded and described as follows: Starting at an iron\npipe found in the easterly bounds of the highway known as the Old\nMilitary Turnpike, said iron pipe being located 910.39 feet\nsoutheasterly, as measured along the easterly bounds of said highway,\nfrom the southerly bounds of the roadway known as Industrial Parkway\nWest, THENCE running S 31Á 54' 33" E along the easterly bounds of said\nOld Military Turnpike Extension, 239.88 feet to a point marking the\nbeginning of a curve concave to the west; thence southerly along said\ncurve, having a radius of 987.99 feet, 248.12 feet to an iron pipe found\nmarking the point of beginning for the parcel herein being described,\nsaid point also marked the southerly corner of lands of Larry Garrow, et\nal, as described in Book 938 of Deeds at page 224; thence N 07Á 45' 4" E\nalong the easterly bounds of said Garrow, 748.16 feet to a 3"x4"\nconcrete monument marking the northeasterly corner of said Garrow, the\nnorthwesterly corner of the parcel herein being described and said\nmonument also marking the southerly bounds of lands of Salerno Plastic\nCorp. as described in Book 926 of Deeds at Page 186; thence S 81Á 45'\n28" E along a portion of the southerly bounds of said Salerno Plastic\nCorp., 441.32 feet to an iron pin found marking the northeasterly corner\nof the parcel herein being described and also marking the northwest\ncorner of the remaining lands now or formerly owned by said Marx and\nDelaura; thence S 07Á 45' 40" W along the Westerly bounds of lands now\nof formerly of said Marx and DeLaura and along the easterly bounds of\nthe parcel herein being described, 560.49 feet to an iron pin; thence N\n83Á 43' 21" W along a portion of the remaining lands of said Marx and\nDeLaura, 41.51 feet to ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet Southerly from the Southerly line of the new garage\nbuilt upon land adjoining on the North; thence Westerly parallel with\nsaid garage, Forty-six and Seven-tenths (46.7) feet; thence Southerly\nOne Hundred Forty and Eighty-tenths (140.8) feet to the Northerly margin\nof Union Street; thence Easterly along the Northerly margin of Union\nStreet, about Forty-eight and three-tenths (48.3) feet to the point or\nplace of beginning.\n  The two above parcels are together more particularly described as\nfollows:\n  All that parcel of land in the City of Schenectady beginning at a\npoint in the northerly margin of Union Street at the southwesterly\ncorner of lands now or formerly of Friedman (Deed Book 636 at page 423)\nwhich point is about 60 feet westerly of the westerly line of North\nCollege Street and runs thence N. 86 deg. 42' 20" W. 92.30 feet to the\nsoutheasterly corner of other lands now or formerly of Friedman (Deed\nBook 798 at page 498); thence N. 04 deg. 06' 48" E. 140.50 fee...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_90">
            <num>(90)</num>
            <content>
              <p>degrees, one\nhundred ninety-one and seventy-five hundredths (191.75) feet to a point\nin the Northwesterly street line of Erie Boulevard thence southwesterly\nalong the Northwesterly street line of Erie Boulevard, one hundred\ntwenty-three and eight-tenths (123.8) feet to its intersection with the\nNortherly street line of Union Street; thence Westerly along the\nNortherly street line of Union Street, one hundred twenty-four and\nfifty-five hundredths (124.55) feet to the point or place of beginning.\n  The above described parcel of property includes the Blue Line parcel\nof land, which is a portion of the abandoned Erie Canal Lands, located\nin the First Ward of the City of Schenectady, New York, and which Blue\nLine parcel lies between the Northwesterly line of Erie Boulevard as set\nforth in the above described premises and the Northeasterly lot line of\nthe old Union Street School as it runs parallel with the Northwesterly\nline of Erie Boulevard as aforesaid.\n  The two above par...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\ncourses and distances along said edge of pavement: Northeasterly on a\ncurve to the left having a radius of 2221.65 feet, a chord bearing of\nNorth 30Á-16'-39" East, a chord distance of 280.79, a central angle of\n07Á-14'-47", a length of 280.98 feet to a point of reverse curvature;\nthence, Northeasterly on a curve to the right having a radius of 843.42\nfeet, a chord bearing of North 45Á-25'-09" East, a chord distance of\n534.08, a central angle of 36Á-55'-01", a length of 543.43 feet to a\npoint; thence, South 30Á-04'-59" East, a distance of 18.28 feet to the\ncorner of the property acquired by Ontario County (Liber 766 of Deeds,\nPage 1112), as shown on a map recorded in the Ontario County Clerk's\nOffice as Map No. 6313; thence, the following four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and\ndistances along said property line: South 30Á-04'-59" East, a distance\nof 177.17 feet to a point; thence, South 02Á-20'-33" East, a distance of\n147.53 feet to a point; thence, South 41Á-31'-35" East, a distance of\n200.93 feet to a point; thence, South 23Á-48'-53" West, along said\nproperty line, and the projection thereof, through the first said lands\nof Ontario County - Finger Lakes Community College (Liber 698 of Deeds,\nPage 466), a distance of 517.96 feet to Point of Beginning. Said parcel\ncontaining 7.834 acres, more or less, as shown on a map entitled\n"Proposed Lease Area - Friends of the Finger Lakes Performing Arts\nCenter, Hopewell, NY", prepared by Bergmann Associates, drawing LM-01,\ndated June 10, 2005, last revised August 17, 2005. The related PAC\nProperties are shown on the Map denominated "FLCC Campus Property, FLPAC\nGround Lease, Parking, Vehicular &amp; Pedestrian Access", recorded in the\nOntario County Clerk's Office on December 10, 2009 in Book 1237...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_35">
            <num>(35)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:\n  1) Thence North 40 deg. 22 min. 15 sec. East 191.79 feet to a point;\n  2) Thence South 82 deg. 04 min. 58 sec. East 294.58 feet to a point;\n  3) Thence North 07 deg. 52 min. 16 sec. East 314.89 feet to a point;\n  4) Thence South 82 deg. 07 min. 45 sec. East 53.96 feet to a point;\n  5) Thence North 07 deg. 52 min. 16 sec. East 70.18 feet to a point;\n  6) Thence South 82 deg. 07 min. 44 sec. East 40.81 feet to a point;\n  7) Thence North 07 deg. 52 min. 16 sec. East 35.49 feet to a point;\n  8) Thence South 82 deg. 07 min. 50 sec. East 1.52 feet to a point;\n  9) Thence North 07 deg. 52 min. 16 sec. East 45.53 feet to a point;\n  10) Thence South 82 deg. 07 min. 44 sec. East 92.67 feet to a point;\n  11) Thence North 07 deg. 52 min. 16 sec. East 194.00 feet to a point;\n  12) Thence North 82 deg. 07 min. 44 sec. West 121.00 feet to a point;\n  13) Thence North 07 deg. 52 min. 14 sec. East 408.67 feet to a point;\n  14) Thence South 82 deg. 07 min. 44 sec. E...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses\nand distances:\n  1) Thence South 18 deg. 26 min. 44 sec. East 44.24 feet to a point;\n  2) Thence South 31 deg. 26 min. 40 sec. East 70.85 feet to a point;\n  3) Thence South 37 deg. 56 min. 38 sec. East 377.51 feet to a point;\n  4) Thence South 33 deg. 48 min. 10 sec. East 129.69 feet to a point;\n  5) Thence South 32 deg. 22 min. 13 sec. East 213.26 feet to a point;\n  6) Thence South 42 deg. 27 min. 42 sec. East 58.65 feet to a point;\nand\n  7) Thence South 40 deg. 20 min. 45 sec. East 77.11 feet to its\nintersection with lands appropriated by the People of the State of New\nYork described as Map 1401 Parcel 1831 in Book 5256 of Deeds at Page 686\nand Book 5274 of Deeds at Page 836; Thence along the bounds of said Map\n1401 Parcel 1831 the following fifteen</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:\n  1) South 07 deg. 30 min. 19 sec. East 39.16 feet to a point; thence\n  2) South 03 deg. 25 min. 41 sec. West 30.00 feet to a point; thence\n  3) South 12 deg. 49 min. 21 sec. West 30.00 feet to a point; thence\n  4) South 22 deg. 11 min. 30 sec. West 30.00 feet to a point; thence\n  5) South 31 deg. 35 min. 08 sec. West 30.00 feet to a point; thence\n  6) South 40 deg. 57 min. 25 sec. West 30.01 feet to a point; thence\n  7) South 48 deg. 44 min. 51 sec. West 20.00 feet to a point; thence\n  8) South 55 deg. 01 min. 19 sec. West 19.99 feet to a point; thence\n  9) South 65 deg. 30 min. 44 sec. West 8.49 feet to a point; thence\n  10) North 75 deg. 22 min. 31 sec. West 38.92 feet to a point; thence\n  11) North 29 deg. 08 min. 26 sec. West 25.83 feet to a point; thence\n  12) North 07 deg. 58 min. 33 sec. West 20.27 feet to a point; thence\n  13) North 07 deg. 40 min. 45 sec. East 100.00 feet to a point; thence\n  14) North 82 deg. 23 min. 04 sec. West 1.00 fee...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:\n  1) South 07 deg. 40 min. 17 sec. West 70.35 feet to a point; thence\n  2) South 82 deg. 09 min. 26 sec. East 1.00 feet to a point; and\n  3) North 07 deg. 40 min. 37 sec. East 70.35 feet to its intersection\nwith the bounds of the hereinabove described Map 1401 Parcel 1831;\nThence along the bounds of said Map 1401 Parcel 1831 the following ten\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:\n  1) North 07 deg. 40 min. 37 sec. East 100.00 feet to a point; thence\n  2) North 40 deg. 32 min. 01 sec. East 61.06 feet to a point; thence\n  3) North 50 deg. 26 min. 34 sec. East 110.76 feet to a point; thence\n  4) North 55 deg. 51 min. 53 sec. East 43.02 feet to a point; thence\n  5) North 66 deg. 11 min. 17 sec. East 30.00 feet to a point; thence\n  6) North 79 deg. 28 min. 24 sec. East 30.00 feet to a point; thence\n  7) South 87 deg. 12 min. 02 sec. East 30.00 feet to a point; thence\n  8) South 73 deg. 54 min. 22 sec. East 30.00 feet to a point; thence\n  9) South 59 deg. 56 min. 49 sec. East 33.00 feet to a point; and\n  10) South 47 deg. 06 min. 38 sec. East 95.11 feet to its intersection\nwith the division line between Lot 11J on the Northwest and the lands\nnow or formerly of Woodstead Enterprises Co. as described in Book 3530\nof Deeds at Page 257 on the Southeast (formerly lands of Rome Watertown\nand Oswego Railroad Company via Letters Patent, B...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses:\n1) South 30 deg. 39 min. 30 sec. West 599.46 feet to a point; thence 2)\nSouth 30 deg. 30 min. 42 sec. West 62.49 feet to a point; and 3) South\n23 deg. 40 min. 55 sec. West 220.04 feet to its point of intersection\nwith Southwesterly boundary of West Hiawatha Boulevard; thence South 49\ndeg. 30 min. 46 sec. East along said Southwesterly boundary, 0.30 feet\nto its point of intersection with the first hereinabove described\nNorthwesterly boundary of West Hiawatha Boulevard; thence South 40 deg.\n26 min. 20 sec. West, along said Northwesterly boundary, 98.08 feet to\nits point of intersection with the division line between Lot 11J on the\nNortheast and Lot 11H of the Carousel Center Subdivision on the\nSouthwest; thence North 50 deg. 25 min. 12 sec. West, along said\ndivision line, 147.85 feet to the Northwest corner of Lot 11H; thence\nSouth 40 deg. 26 min. 20 sec. West 217.47 feet to the Southwest corner\nof lot 11H; thence South 49 deg. 49 min. 16 sec. East 147.83 feet to a...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses: 1) South 40 deg. 26\nmin. 20 sec. West 17.66 feet to a point; and 2) South 43 deg. 01 min. 50\nsec. West 468.25 feet to the point of beginning.\n  Excepting the following piece or parcel of land appropriated by the\nPeople of the State of New York described as Map 1401 Parcel 1832 in\nBook 5256 of Deeds at Page 686 and Book 5274 of Deeds at Page 836:\nCommencing at the southwest corner of herein above described Map 1402\nParcel 1836 said point having a proceeding course of South 07 deg. 40\nmin. 17 sec. West 70.35 feet in the premises describe hereinabove;\nthence North 13 deg. 18 min. 48 sec. West 138.17 feet to the southeast\ncorner of Map 1401 Parcel 1832; thence along the bounds of said Map 1401\nParcel 1832 the following four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:\n  1) North 82 deg. 09 min. 26 sec. West 1.00 feet to a point; thence\n  2) North 07 deg. 53 min. 50 sec. East 353.36 feet to a point; thence\n  3) South 81 deg. 54 min. 58 sec. East 1.00 feet to a point, and\n  4) South 07 deg. 53 min. 54 sec. West 353.36 feet to the point of\nbeginning; or such premises or businesses located on that tract or\nparcel of land situate lying and being in the Town of Oneonta, County of\nOtsego and State of New York and being a portion of Otsego County Tax\nMap Department Parcel Number 287.00-1-33 and bounded and described as\nfollows: Beginning at a point 2.12 feet off the northeasterly corner of\na one story building on the lands, now or formerly, of Abner Doubleday,\nLLC, aka Cooperstown All Star Village, LLC, as owned by Martin and\nBrenda Patton, which point lies N 87Á55'13" W a distance of 149.37' from\nthe northeast corner of the Patton lands; thence N 74Á30'18" W a\ndistance of 51.50 feet to a point; thence S 15Á29'42" W a di...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on such premises or business located on any of the following four\nparcels:\n  Parcel A\n  any such premises or business constituting the overnight lodging and\nresort facility located wholly within the boundaries of the Village of\nAltmar, County of Oswego, Great Lot 19 beginning at a point on\ncenterline of Pulaski Street at its intersection with the division line\nbetween the lands now or formerly of Altmar Parish Williamstown Central\nSchool District (APW CSD) as described in Book 378 of Deeds at Page 118\non the northwest and the lands now or formerly of Tostanoski as\ndescribed in Book 1356 of Deeds at Page 55 on the southeast; Thence\nalong said centerline the following two</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses: 1) North 37 deg. 35\nmin. 00 sec. West, a distance of 803.88 ft. to a point and 2). North 45\ndeg. 48 min. 13 sec. West, a distance of 132.33 ft. to its intersection\nwith the division line between the said lands of APW CSD on the\nsoutheast and the lands now or formerly of Hayward as described in Book\n894 of Deeds at Page 211 &amp; Doc. #2006-9318 on the northwest; Thence\nNorth 23 deg. 48 min. 43 sec. East along said division, a distance of\n131.66 ft. to its intersection with the division line between the said\nlands of APW CSD on the north and the said lands of Hayward on the\nsouth; Thence South 73 deg. 16 min. 17 sec. West along the said division\nline, a distance of 131.66 ft. to its intersection with the division\nline between the said lands of APW CSD and the lands now or formerly of\nNational Grid as described in Book 282 of Deeds at Page 552; Thence\nalong said division line to the following six</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses: 1) North 23\ndeg. 43 min. 38 sec. East, a distance of 158.73 ft. to a point; thence\n2) North 83 deg. 39 min. 24 sec. West, a distance of 190.48 ft. to a\npoint; thence 3) North 25 deg. 39 min. 08 sec. East, a distance of 24.15\nft. to a point; thence 4) North 53 deg. 32 min. 01 sec. East, a distance\nof 265.18 ft. to a point; thence 5) North 81 deg. 24 min. 54 sec. East a\ndistance of 475.00 ft. to a point; and 6) North 81 deg. 24 min. 54 sec.\nEast, a distance of +/- 522 ft. to its intersection with the center of\nSalmon River; Thence upstream along said center, and in a generally\nsoutherly direction, a distance of +/- 1,455 ft. to its intersection\nwith the division line between the said lands of APW CSD on the\nnorthwest and the lands now or formerly of Bennett as described in Book\n927 of Deeds at Page 65 on the southeast; Thence South 52 deg. 19 min.\n00 sec. West along said division line, a distance of +/- 170 ft. to a\npoint; Thence South 52 deg. 19 min. 00 sec. West,...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_y">
          <num>(y)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n  East 607401.00</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n  of the New York State Coordinate System, East Zone and which point is\ndistant, the following courses from the southerly corner of the Parcel\nshown on Map No. 20407 that occupies coordinate position\n  North 463520.804</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_y">
          <num>(y)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n  East 608470.681</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n  of the aforesaid New York State Coordinate System, East Zone:\n  North 47 degrees 30' 36" West 856.60 feet,\n  North 77 degrees 10' 53" West 488.18 feet,\n  North 41 degrees 17' 53" West 113.32 feet and\n  North 41 degrees 50' 16" East 169.08 feet;\n  THENCE from the said point of beginning along the said easterly\nshoreline (high water mark) of the east bank of the Hudson River:\n  Due North 16.17 feet,\n  North 53 degrees 58' 22" West 13.60 feet,\n  North 73 degrees 04' 21" West 24.04 feet,\n  North 63 degrees 26' 06" West 22.36 feet,\n  North 82 degrees 18' 14" West 37.34 feet,\n  North 64 degrees 47' 56" West 37.58 feet,\n  South 82 degrees 52' 30" West 16.12 feet,\n  North 61 degrees 41' 57" West 14.76 feet and\n  South 21 degrees 48' 05" West 9.71 feet;\n  THENCE leaving the high water mark and running across a peninsula of\nland and along the division line between Parcel I and Parcel II as shown\non said Filed Map No. 20407, North 65 degrees 32' 43" West 30.18 feet to\nanother point on the said easterly shoreline (high water mark) of the\nEast Bank of the Hudson River;\n  THENCE northerly along the said high water mark, the following\ncourses:\n  North 3 degrees 00' 46" West 17.54 feet,\n  North 13 degrees 45' 39" West 50.45 feet,\n  North 10 degrees 49' 23" West 69.23 feet,\n  North 0 degrees 47' 22" West 52.48 feet to a point which is the point\nof beginning of the hereinafter described 40 foot easement which point\noccupies coordinate position\n  North 464676.48</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_y">
          <num>(y)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n  East 607189.28</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n  of the New York State Coordinate System, East Zone;\n  THENCE continuing along the aforesaid easterly shoreline (high water\nmark) of the East Bank of the Hudson, the following courses:\n  North 10 degrees 18' 17" West 23.91 feet,\n  North 39 degrees 04' 58" West 21.39 feet,\n  North 20 degrees 13' 30" West 21.74 feet,\n  North 39 degrees 02' 08" West 95.27 feet,\n  North 13 degrees 08' 02" West 30.81 feet,\n  North 18 degrees 26' 06" West 53.76 feet,\n  North 28 degrees 10' 43" West 63.53 feet,\n  North 18 degrees 26' 06" West 50.60 feet,\n  North 37 degrees 14' 05" West 31.40 feet,\n  North 21 degrees 15' 02" West 96.57 feet,\n  North 32 degrees 00' 19" West 47.17 feet,\n  North 1 degree 18' 07" West 44.01 feet and\n  North 17 degrees 14' 29" East 29.32 feet to a point on the southerly\nline of lands under lease to the County of Westchester (Resco Site);\n  THENCE along the said County of Westchester (Resco Site) lands: Due\nEast 432.31 feet to a point on the westerly line of an easement and a\nright-of-way leading to Charles Point Avenue;\n  THENCE along the said westerly and southwesterly line of the said\nright-of-way leading to Charles Point Avenue: Due South 241.16 feet and\nSouth 27 degrees 13' 00" East 406.90 feet to a point;\n  THENCE leaving the said easement and running along other lands now or\nformerly of The City of Peekskill Industrial Development Agency, South\n41 degrees 50' 16" West 270.01 feet to the aforementioned easterly\nshoreline (high water mark) of the East Bank of the Hudson River and the\npoint or place of beginning.\n  TOGETHER with an easement over all that parcel of land situate in the\nCity of Peekskill, County of Westchester and State of New York that is\nmore particularly bounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point on the westerly line of Charles Point Avenue with\nthe said westerly line is intersected by the line dividing the easement\nherein described on the south from lands under lease to the County of\nWestche...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_y">
          <num>(y)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n  East 608004.15</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n  of the New York State Coordinate System, East Zone;\n  THENCE from the said point of beginning southerly along the said\nwesterly line of Charles Point Avenue, South 14 degrees 54' 00" West\n103.48 feet to a point;\n  THENCE westerly along other lands of the City of Peekskill Industrial\nDevelopment Agency: Due West 396.44 feet to a point which is the\neasterly most corner of the lands of Point Associates, the grantee\nherein;\n  THENCE along the northeasterly line of the said Point Associates'\nland, North 27 degrees 13' 00" West 406.90 feet and Due North 241.16\nfeet to a point on the southerly line of the aforementioned lands leased\nto the County of Westchester (Resco Site);\n  THENCE easterly along the said southerly line Due East 75.00 feet to a\npoint;\n  THENCE southeasterly and easterly still along the said lands leased to\nthe County of Westchester (Resco Site) the following courses:\n  Due South 223.00 feet,\n  South 27 degrees 13' 00" East 314.87 feet and\n  Due East 390.14 feet to the aforementioned westerly line of Charles\nPoint Avenue and the point or place of BEGINNING.\n  TOGETHER WITH a non-exclusive easement for utilities, and ingress and\negress over that certain right of way leading from Charles Point Avenue,\nnow known as John E. Walsh Boulevard, in a westerly and northwesterly\ndirection to the above described premises and as more fully described in\nthe Declaration of Easement recorded in Liber 8888 cp 35; or\n  (xii) all those tracts or parcels of land, situate in the Tenth Ward\nof the City of Troy, County of Rensselaer and State of New York, known\nas Lots Number Seven</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, A Seven (A7), Six</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, A Six (A6), Five</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, A\nFive (A5) and the southerly portions of Lots Four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and A Four (A4),\nas the same are laid down and described on a certain Map made by\nFrederick W. Orr, dated August 15, 1918, filed in the Office of the\nClerk of the County of Rensselaer as Map No. 29 1/2, Drawer 18. The said\npremises hereby intended to be conveyed are bounded and described as\nfollows:\n  COMMENCING at an iron rod in the westerly side of River Street at the\nmost southeasterly corner of premises heretofore conveyed by Harry\nGoldberg and Norman Goldberg to Arthur E. Collins and another, by Deed\ndated November 8, 1940, recorded November 12, 1940 In the Office of the\nClerk of the County of Rensselaer in Book 633 of Deeds at page 400 and\nrunning thence southerly along the westerly line of River Street 215.6\nfeet to a pipe in the most southeasterly corner of Lot No. A7; thence\nwesterly along the southerly line of Lots Nos. A7 and 7, 163 feet more\nor less to the easterly shore of the Hudson River; thence northerly\nalong the easterly shore of the Hudson River 216 fe...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_55">
            <num>(55)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet, more or less, to the west line of property now or\nformerly owned by one Desidora; thence southerly one hundred ten</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_110">
            <num>(110)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nfeet, more or less, to the northerly line of property now or formerly\nowned by one Gutierresl thence westerly fifty-five</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_55">
            <num>(55)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet, more or\nless to the easterly line of an alley; thence northerly one hundred ten\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_x__subsec_110">
            <num>(110)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet, more or less to the point or place of beginning. Be the\naforesaid dimensions in this clause more or less and encompassing lands\nconsidered to be a single contiguous parcel; or\n  (xiv) any such premises or business located on that certain piece or\nparcel of land, or any subdivision thereof, situate, lying and being in\nthe Village of Suffern, Town of Ramapo, County of Rockland and State of\nNew York, addressed as 97-99 Lafayette Avenue, Suffern, New York,\nidentified for tax purposes by the Town of Ramapo - 2000 County/Town Tax\nBill, Tax Map No. 07/016-B-0239-B-0000 and New Parcel Tax Identification\nNo. 54.35-2-54, bounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point on the Westerly side of Washington Avenue, where\nthe same is intersected by the Northerly line of lands now or formerly\nof the Village of Suffern (Sect. 168, Lot 284), said point also being\nthe Southeasterly corner of the premises herein intended to be\ndescribed.\n  RUNNING THENCE North 76 degrees 15 mi...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such interest must have been acquired\nprior to the effective date of chapter two hundred ninety-nine of the\nlaws of two thousand twenty-one; (ii) such retail licensee may not\npurchase alcoholic beverages directly from any such manufacturer or\nwholesaler; and (iii) no more than fifteen percent of the annual dollar\nvalue of alcoholic beverages purchased by such retail licensee for sale\non the premises may be produced by any such manufacturer; or\n  * NB Repealed upon certain provisions (see chapter 299 of 2021 § 2)\n  * (xviii) Real property in the Town of East Hampton, County of\nSuffolk, State of New York, described as follows:\n  ALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, situate, lying and\nbeing at Montauk, Town of East Hampton, County of Suffolk and State of\nNew York, bounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at the corner formed by the intersection of the northeast\nside of Surfside Place with the southeast side of Ocean view Terrace;\n  RUNNING THENCE from said point of beginning along the southeasterly\nside of Oceanview Terrace North 68 degrees 18 minutes 15 seconds East,\n265.64 feet to land formerly of Montauk Improvement Inc.;\n  THENCE along said land South 24 degrees 34 minutes 52 seconds East,\n321.71 feet to the northerly line of boardwalk easement;\n  THENCE still along said course, 82 feet, more and less (114.76 feet\nper survey), to the high water mark of the Atlantic Ocean;\n  THENCE southwesterly and along the high water mark of the Atlantic\nOcean, 267 feet more or less (265,41 feet per survey) to the northeast\nside of the Surfside Place;\n  THENCE along the northeast side of Surfside Place North 24 degrees 34\nminutes 52 seconds West, 425 feet, more or less, (448.98 feet per\nsurvey) to the point or place of BEGINNING.\n  Provided, however, that with respect to such retail licensee's\ninterest in a business engaged in the manufacture or sale at wholesale\nof alcoholic beverages described in subdivision one-a of section one\nhu...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such interest must have been acquired\nprior to the effective date of chapter two hundred eighty-eight of the\nlaws of two thousand twenty-two; (ii) such retail licensee may not\npurchase alcoholic beverages directly from any such manufacturer or\nwholesaler; and (iii) no more than fifteen percent of the annual dollar\nvalue of alcoholic beverages purchased by such retail licensee for sale\non the premises may be produced by any such manufacturer; or\n  (xix) on real property located on that certain tract or parcel of land\nsituated in the Town of Shelby, County of Orleans and State of New York,\nbeing part of Great Lot No. 32 in Township 14, Range 3 of the Holland\nLand Purchase and bounded and described as follows:\nBeginning at the point of intersection of the centerline of Maple Ridge\nRoad, a/k/a New York State Route No. 31A (66 foot wide right-of-way)\nwith the centerline of Bates Road;\nthence</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>North 00Á 12' 14" West and along the centerline of said Bates\nRoad a distance of 225.00 feet to a point; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>North 89Á 47' 46"\nEast and along the south line of lands now or formerly owned by Joyce\nand Raymond Cook, Jr. (See Liber 392 of Deeds at page 246 and Tax\nAccount No. 080.00 - 03 - 15.3) a distance of 200.00 feet to a point;\nthence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>North 00Á 12' 14" West and along the westerly line of lands\nnow or formerly of said Joyce and Raymond Cook, Jr. and also along the\nwesterly line of lands now or formerly owned by Mark G. and Evon C.\nNavarra (See Liber 498 of Deeds at page 88 and Tax Account No. 080.00 -\n03 - 15.2) and lands now or formerly owned by John E. Harris, Jr. (See\nLiber 452 of Deeds at page 207 and Tax Account No. 080.00 - 03 - 16.0) a\ndistance of 300.00 feet to a point; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 89Á 47' 46" West\nand along the north line of lands now or formerly of said John E.\nHarris, Jr. a distance of 200.00 feet to a point in the centerline of\nBates Road;\nthence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>North 00Á 10' 30" West and along the centerline of said Bates\nRoad a distance of 1414.14 feet to a point; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>North 89Á 46' 17"\nEast and along the south line of lands now or formerly owned by Harry R.\nand Lois A. Deyarmin (See Liber 466 of Deeds at page 322 and Tax Account\nNo. 080.00 - 03 - 17.00) and also along the south line of lands now or\nformerly owned by Michael J. Healy and Vincent J. Licata (See Liber 391\nof Deeds at page 1077 and Tax Account No. 080.00 - 03 - 01.4) a distance\nof 398.06 feet to a point on the westerly line of lands now or formerly\nowned by the Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation (See Liber 360 of Deeds at\npage 186 and Tax Account No. 080.00 - 03 - 23.0); thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 02Á\n21' 51" East and continuing along the westerly line of lands now or\nformerly owned by the said Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation a distance\nof 1932.39 to a point in the centerline of Maple Ridge Road, a/k/a New\nYork State Route No. 31A; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 88Á 47' 20" West and along\nthe centerline of said Maple Ridge Road, a/k/a New York State Route No.\n31A, a distance of 471.69 feet to the point of beginning.\nHereby intending to describe a parcel of land shown on a Survey Map made\nby Clark Patterson Associates, dated August 7, 2006, being Project No.\n9418.00 and Drawing Number BNDY - 2. Together with the right, privilege\nand easement for use of one or more of four road crossings not to exceed\n20 feet in width, as reserved in the Warranty Deed made by Glenn L. Hill\nand Nola A. Hill to the Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation, dated November\n2, 1972 and recorded November 3, 1972 in the Orleans County Clerk's\nOffice in Liber 360 of Deeds at page 186. ALSO ALL THAT TRACT OR PARCEL\nOF LAND situate in the Town of Shelby, County of Orleans and State of\nNew York, being part of Great Lot No. 32 in Township 14, Range 3 of the\nHolland Land Purchase and bounded and described as follows:\nCommencing at the point of intersection of the...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>North 02Á 21' 51" West and along the easterly line of lands\nnow or formerly owned by the Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation (See Liber\n360 of Deeds at page 186 and Tax Account No. 080.00 - 03 - 23.0) a\ndistance of 1931.96 feet to a point;\nthence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>North 89Á 45' 02" East and along the south line of lands now\nor formerly owned by Douglas A. Holka (See Liber 545 of Deeds at page 43\nand Tax Account No. 080.00 - 03 - 1.1) a distance of 1378.90 feet to a\npoint; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 00Á 12' 37" East and along the westerly line of\nlands now or formerly owned by Franklin Tower (See Liber 489 of Deeds at\npage 185 and Tax Account No. 080.00 - 03 - 14.0) a distance of 1908.72\nfeet to a point in the centerline of said Maple Ridge Road, a/k/a New\nYork State Route No. 31A; thence</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>South 88Á 47' 20" West and along\nthe centerline of said Maple Ridge Road, a/k/a New York State Route No.\n31A, a distance of 1306.49 feet to the point of beginning.\nHereby intending to describe a parcel of land shown on a Survey Map made\nby Clark Patterson Associates, dated August 7, 2006, being Project No.\n9418.00 and Drawing Number BNDY - 2. Together with the right, privilege\nand easement for use of one or more of four road crossings not to exceed\n20 feet in width, as reserved in the Warranty Deed made by Glenn L. Hill\nand Nola A. Hill to the Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation, dated November\n2, 1972 and recorded November 3, 1972 in the Orleans County Clerk's\nOffice in Liber 360 of Deeds at page 186; or\n  * (xx) ALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, with the\nbuildings and improvements thereon erected, situate, lying and being in\nthe Town of East Hampton, County of Suffolk and State of New York,\nbounded and described as follows:\n  Beginning at a point on the nort...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision one of section one hundred one of this article as owner\nof such brands for purposes of brand label registration and price\nscheduling as required under this chapter; or\n  * NB Repealed upon certain conditions (see chapter 328 of 2022 § 3)\n  * (xxi) Parcel A:  ALL THAT CERTAIN plot, place or parcel of land,\nwith the buildings and improvements thereon erected, situate, lying and\nbeing in the Borough of Manhattan, City, County and State of New York,\nbounded and described as follows:  BEGINNING at the corner formed by the\nintersection of the northerly side of Grove Street with the easterly\nside of Bleecker Street; THENCE easterly along the northerly side of\nGrove Street 117 feet 9 1/2 inches to the center of a party wall between\nNos. 53 and 55 Grove Street; THENCE northerly parallel with or nearly so\nwith Bleecker Street and partly through the center of said party wall 47\nfeet; THENCE westerly parallel with or nearly so with Grove Street 36\nfeet 7 inches to a point distant 82 feet 5 inches from Bleecker Street;\nTHENCE northerly at right angles to Christopher Street 29 feet 1 1/2\ninches; THENCE westerly parallel with Grove Street 88 feet 6 inches to\nthe easterly side of Bleecker Street; THENCE southerly along the\neasterly side of Bleecker Street 73 feet 3 inches to the point or place\nof beginning. Notwithstanding section one hundred seven-a of this\narticle, the retail licensee and brand owner located at the premises\ndescribed in this subparagraph and further identified as Parcel A may\ndesignate the manufacturer licensee located at the premises described in\nsubparagraph (xiv) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section one\nhundred one of this article as owner of such brands for purposes of\nbrand label registration and price scheduling as required under this\nchapter.\n  Parcel B:\nALL that lot of land in the borough of Manhattan, County of New York,\nCity and State of New York, bounded and described as follows:\nBEGINNING on the southwesterly corner of Commence and Barrow Streets;\nRUNNING THENCE westerly along the southerly side of Barrow Street twenty\nfeet, seven and One-half inches to the easterly face of the easterly\nwall of the premises known as seventy-seven Barrow Street;\nRUNNING THENCE southerly in a straight line along the easterly face of\nsaid wall and the line to continuation thereof eighty feet, eleven\ninches;\nRUNNING THENCE northeasterly in a straight line and past of the distance\nalong the northerly wall of the three story basement, brick building\nknown as 48 Commerce Street fifty-five feet, eight and three fourths\ninches to the westerly side of Commerce Street;\nTHENCE northerly along the westerly side of Commerce Street sixty feet,\nnine and one half inches to the point or place of BEGINNING.\n  Parcel C:\nALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land with the buildings and\nimprovements thereon erected, situate, lying, and being in the Borough\nof Manhattan, City, County and State of New York, bounded and described\nas follows:\nBEGINNING at a point on the northerly side of Christopher Street,\ndistant 125 feet westerly from the corner formed by the intersection of\nthe northerly side of Christopher Street with the westerly side of\nBleecker Street;\nRUNNING THENCE northerly parallel with Bleecker Street, 90 feet;\nTHENCE westerly in the rear parallel with Christopher Street, 25 feet;\nTHENCE southerly parallel with Bleecker Street 90 feet to the northerly\nside of Christopher Street;\nTHENCE easterly along the northerly side of Christopher Street, 25 feet\nto the point or place of BEGINNING.\n  Parcel D:\nALL that piece o...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 44Á 33'\n20" W, 11.45 feet to a point,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>N 45Á 26' 40" W, 4 feet to a point,\nand</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>45Á 20' 30" W, 109.27 feet to a point in the northerly line of\nCherry Alley; thence along said Cherry Alley N 45Á 52' 40" W 23.40 feet\nto an iron pin, which iron pin marks the southwesterly corner of the\npremises here in described; thence along lands now or formerly of\nMichael Martin N 44Á 37' 20" E, 120.67 feet to a point in the southerly\nline of Warren Street; thence along the southerly line of Warren Street\nthe following two courses and distances:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 45Á 52' 40" E, 23.39\nfeet, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>S 45Á 51' 30" E, 5.37 feet to the point or place beginning\nas shown on a map entitled "Survey update of Lands of Richman's Apparel\nof Hudson, New York, Inc." dated January 11, 1982, made by M. Chazen, P.\nE. &amp; L. S., and recorded in the Columbia County Clerk's Office as Micro\n7469.\nTOGETHER WITH the Temporary Easement granted by The City of Hudson to\nBread and Roses, LLC dated 3/10/2003 recorded 3/14/2003 in Cartridge 441\nFrame 1222.\n  Parcel E:\nALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, situate, lying, and\nbeing in the Borough of Manhattan, City, County and State of New York,\nbounded and described as follows:\nBEGINNING at a point on the southerly side of Grove Street, distant 83\nfeet westerly from the corner formed by the intersection of the said\nsoutherly side of Grove Street with the westerly side of Bleecker\nStreet;\nRUNNING THENCE westerly along the southerly side of Grove Street, 42\nfeet;\nTHENCE southerly parallel with the westerly side of Bleecker Street, 10...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such retail licensees may not purchase alcoholic\nbeverages directly from any such manufacturer or wholesaler; and (ii) no\nmore than fifteen percent of the annual dollar value of alcoholic\nbeverages purchased by any such individual retail licensee for sale on\nthe premises may be produced by any such manufacturer; or\n  * NB Repealed upon certain conditions (see chapter 348 of 2022 § 3)\n  * (xxii) Parcel A\n  ALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land with the buildings and\nimprovements thereon erected, situated, lying and being in the Town of\nWilmington, County of Essex and State of New York, being part of lot No.\n32 of Mallory's Grant and more particularly described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at a point in the Wilmington-Lake Placid State Highway\n(Route 86) said point being located 600 feet North Easterly from the\npoint where the division line between lots Nos. 31 and 32 of Mallory's\nGrant intersects the center of said Highway and which point of beginning\nis the most Easterly corner of a parcel of land conveyed by Bernard J.P.\nComiskey to Marjorie B. Wilkins by deed dated July 7, 1950 and recorded\nin the Essex County Clerk's Office on July 10, 1950 in Book 279 of Deeds\nat page 293, and from said point of beginning running thence in a\nNorthwesterly direction along the Northeasterly line of said parcel a\ndistance of 550 feet to the most Northerly corner thereof; thence\nSouthwesterly along the Northeasterly line of said parcel (described as\nparallel to the center of said highway) and continuing in the same\ncourse along the Northwesterly line of a parcel of land conveyed by said\nComiskey to Walter N. Zywan and Marylyn V. Zywan a total distance on\nthis course of 600 feet to a point in the division line between said\nlots Nos. 31 and 32; thence Northwesterly along said division line a\ndistance of 1985 feet more or less to the most Westerly corner of lot\nNo. 32; thence Northeasterly along the Westerly boundary of Mallory's\nGrant a distance of 169...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses from a 3/4 inch iron pipe in the southeast bounds of New\nYork State Route 86 which lies 304.52 feet southwest of White Brook:\n  1. South 49Á 25' 55" East, 395.00 feet;\n  2. South 49Á 27' 22" East, 349.45 feet;\n  Thence, South 49Á 27' 22" East, 450.00 feet along the southwest line\nof certain lands of Richard M. Sibalski and Jane F. Sibalski, Deed Book\n772/Page 4, to a point on the west bank of the West Branch of the\nAuSable River, said course passing through a 1/2 inch iron pipe line\nmarker at a distance of 440.00 feet;\n  Thence, Southerly 130 feet more or less along the west bank of the\nWest Branch of the AuSable River on the following three</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses to a\npoint at the southerly corner:\n  1. South 29Á 37' 10" West, 32.66 feet to a point:\n  2. South 32Á 53' 59" East, 40.69 feet to a point;\n  3. South 55Á 14' 56" West, 65.59 feet to a point;\n  Thence, North 48Á 23' 02" West, 246.21 feet along the southwesterly\nline to 5/8 inch iron rod with cap, said course passing through a 5/8\ninch iron rod line marker at a distance of 51.00 feet;\n  Thence, North 56Á 25' 45" West, 95, 11 feet along the southwesterly\nline to 5/8 inch iron rod with cap;\n  Thence, North 09Á 51' 36" West, 179.07 feet along the west line to the\nPoint-of-Beginning.\n  Together with a right of way for all normal purposes of ingress and\negress over the existing drive from the southwest line of the premises\nsouthwest and northwest to the New York State Route 86 and also the\nright to maintain, repair and replace the existing utility lines\nproviding service to the premises hereinabove described in their present\nlocations.\n  Parcel D\n  ALL THAT TRACT, ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses from a 3/4 inch iron pipe in the southeast bounds of New\nYork State Route 86 which lies 304.52 feet southwest of White Brook:\n  1. South 49Á 25' 55" East, 395.00 feet:\n  2. South 49Á 27' 22" East, 349.45 feet;\n  Thence, South 49Á 27' 22" East, 450.00 feet along the southwest line\nof certain lands of Richard M. Sibalski and Jane F. Sibalski, Deed Book\n772/Page 4, to a point on the west bank of the West Branch of the\nAuSable River, said course passing through a 1/2 inch iron pipe line\nmarker at a distance of 440.00 feet;\n  Thence, Southerly 130 feet more or less along the west bank of the\nWest Branch of the AuSable River on the following three</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses to a\npoint at the southerly corner:\n  1. South 29Á 37' 1 O" Well, 32.66 feet to a point;\n  2. South 32Á 53' 59" East, 40.69 feet to a point;\n  3. South 55Á 14' 56" West, 65.59 feet to a point;\n  Thence, North 48Á 23' 02" West, 246.21 feet along the southwesterly\nline to a 5/8 inch iron rod with cap, said course passing through a 5/8\ninch iron rod line marker at a distance of 51.00 feet;\n  Thence, North 56Á 28' 45" West, 95.11 feet along the southwesterly\nline to a 5/8 inch iron rod with cap;\n  Thence, North 09Á 51' 36" West, 179.07 feet along the west line to the\nPoint-of Beginning. Together with a right of way for all normal purposes\nof ingress and egress over the existing drive from the southwest line of\nthe premises southwest and northwest to New York State Route 86.\n  Parcel F\n  ALL THAT TRACT OR PARCEL OF LAND situate in the Town of Grand Island,\nCounty of Erie and State of New York, being part of Lot No. 66, on said\nIsland, bounded and described as follow...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such interest\nshall have been acquired prior to the effective date of this\nsubparagraph;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such retail licensee may not purchase alcoholic\nbeverages directly from any such manufacturer or wholesaler; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>no\nmore than fifteen percent of the annual dollar value of alcoholic\nbeverages purchased by such retail licensee for sale on the premises may\nbe produced by any such manufacturer.\n  * NB There are 3 sbpar (xxiii)'s\n  * NB Repealed upon certain provisions (see chapter 412 of 2024 § 2)\n  * (xxiii) ALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, situate,\nlying and being in the Borough of Manhattan, City, County and State of\nNew York, bounded and described as follows:\nParcel A\n  BEGINNING at the intersection of the southerly line of South Street,\n135 feet wide, and the westerly line of Block 2 Lot 3;\n  THENCE RUNNING the following seven</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses and distances:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Along said westerly line of Block 2 Lot 3, South 16 degrees 50\nminutes 39 seconds East a distance of 145.30 feet to a point;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE still along said westerly line of Block 2 Lot 3, North 73\ndegrees 09 minutes 21 seconds East a distance of 28.67 feet to a point;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE still along said westerly line of Block 2 Lot 3, South 16\ndegrees 50 minutes 39 seconds East a distance of 419.26 feet to a point\non the U.S. Pierhead Line approved by Secretary of War, February 25,\n1918;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE along said U.S. Pierhead Line, South 73 degrees 09 minutes\n21 seconds West a distance of 317.76 feet to a point;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE still along said U.S. Pierhead Line, South 87 degrees 11\nminutes 44 seconds West a distance of 36.57 feet to a point on the\neasterly line of Block 2 Lot 1;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE along the northerly line of Block 2 Lot 1, North 15 degrees\n30 minutes 29 seconds West a distance of 555.84 feet to a point on said\nsoutherly line of South Street; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>THENCE along said southerly line of South Street, North 73 degrees\n09 minutes 21 seconds East a distance of 311.61 feet to the point of\nBEGINNING.\n  EXCEPTING THEREFROM the slips, and those certain portions of the\nground floor as delineated on the diagrams annexed to the Sublease</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nwith the cross-hatching on the schematic drawing of the ground floor\ndepicted on page 1 of Annex 1 and (ii) with black shading or\ncross-hatching on the schematic drawing of Annex 2.\nParcel B\n  All that certain Lot, piece or parcel of land, with the buildings and\nimprovements thereon erected, situate, lying and being in the Borough of\nManhattan, County of New York, State of New York:\n  Borough of Manhattan, City, County and State of New York, bounded and\ndescribed as follows:\n  BEGINNING at the corner formed by the intersection of the westerly\nside of Broadway and the southerly side of Morris Street;\n  THENCE southerly along the westerly side of Broadway, 203 feet 1-3/4\ninches Survey (203 feet 2-1/4 inches Deed more or less), to the\nnortherly side of lands formerly belonging to Eve White;\n  THENCE westerly along the northerly side of said lands formerly\nbelonging to Eve White 201 feet 2 inches Survey (200 feet 8 inches Deed\nmore or less), to the easterly side of Greenwich Street;\n  THENCE northerly along the easterly side of Greenwich Street 231 feet\n1-3/4 inch Survey (231 feet 1-3/4 inches Deed) to the southeasterly\ncorner of Greenwich and Morris Streets; and\n  THENCE easterly along the southerly side of Morris Street, 248 feet 2\ninches Survey (248 feet 3 inches Deed) to the point or place of\nBEGINNING.\nParcel C\n  All that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, situate, lying and\nbeing in the Borough of Manhattan, City, County and State of New York,\nbounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at the corner formed by the intersection of the easterly\nside of William Street and the southerly side of Wall Street;\n  RUNNING THENCE easterly along the southerly side of Wall Street 198.11\nfeet to the corner formed by the intersection of the westerly side of\nHanover Street and the southerly side of Wall Street;\n  THENCE southerly along the westerly side of Hanover Street 52.33 feet\nto an angel point therein;\n  THENCE southerly still alon...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_125">
            <num>(125)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet westerly from the corner formed by the\nintersection of the southerly side of 42nd Street with the westerly side\nof Lexington Avenue; and running\n  THENCE Southerly and parallel with Lexington Avenue ninety-eight</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_98">
            <num>(98)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nfeet nine</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches;\n  THENCE Westerly and parallel with 42nd Street fifty</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_50">
            <num>(50)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet to a\npoint in the easterly line of premises conveyed by Pershing Square\nBuilding Corporation to The Bowery Savings Bank by deed dated January 4,\n1921 and recorded in the Office of the Register of the County of New\nYork on January 5, 1921 in Liber 3190 of Conveyances at Page 440;\n  THENCE Southerly along the easterly side of said premises on a line at\nright angles to the southerly side of 42nd Street ninety-eight</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_98">
            <num>(98)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet\nnine</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches to the northerly side of 41st Street;\n  THENCE westerly along the northerly side of 41st Street one hundred\nfour</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_104">
            <num>(104)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet six</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches more or less to a point from which a line\ndrawn northerly to the southerly side of 42nd Street and parallel with\nPark Avenue and at right angles with the northerly side of 41st Street\nwould run through the center of the seventh row (reading easterly from\nPark Avenue) of column locations as shown by circular indications\nthereof upon map entitled: "State of New York, Transit Construction\nCommissioner, Engineering Department, Route Number 43, Section Number 1,\nBorough of Manhattan, Map or Plan showing property for resale east side\nof Park Avenue between East 41st Street and East 42nd Street, signed by\nD. L. Turner, Chief Engineer, dated February 4, 1920 (as revised May 25,\n1920) and designated as drawing number 175, file number 3801", which map\nis annexed to the deed above mentioned;\n  THENCE Northerly along said line one hundred ninety-seven</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_197">
            <num>(197)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet\nsix</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches to the southerly side of 42nd Street; and\n  THENCE Easterly along the southerly side of 42nd Street one hundred\nfifty-four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_154">
            <num>(154)</num>
            <content>
              <p>feet six</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_106__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inches more or less to the point or place\nof BEGINNING.\nParcel F\n  ALL THAT CERTAIN plot, piece, or parcel of land, situate, lying and\nbeing in the Borough of Manhattan, New York County, City and State of\nNew York, bounded and described as follows:\n  BEGINNING at the comer formed by the intersection of the southerly\nline of West 61st Street with the easterly line of Riverside Boulevard,\nas shown on the City Map;\n  RUNNING THENCE easterly, along to the southerly line of West 61st\nStreet, 423 feet 6 inches to a point;\n  THENCE southerly, at right angles to the previous course, 74 feet\n3-1/8 inches;\n  THENCE southwesterly, along a line forming an included angle of 169\ndegrees 40 minutes 47 seconds, 138 feet 7-3/4 inches;\n  THENCE westerly, along a line forming an included angle of 100 degrees\n19 minutes 13 seconds, 445 feet I 0-5/8 inches to a point on the\neasterly side of Riverside Boulevard;\n  THENCE northerly, along the easterly line of Riverside Boulevard which\nform...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall not\napply to the holder of a retail on-premises consumption license issued\nfor a premises located in the borough of Manhattan, city, county and\nstate of New York, bounded and described as follows: Beginning at a\npoint on the northerly side of 52nd Street, distant 375 feet westerly\nfrom the northwesterly corner of 52nd Street and Fifth Avenue; running\nthence northerly parallel with Fifth Avenue and part of the way through\na party wall, 75 feet 5 inches; thence westerly parallel with the\nnortherly side of 52nd Street, 11 feet 2-3/4 inches; thence northerly\nparallel with Fifth Avenue, 25 feet to the center line of the block;\nthence easterly along said center line of the block, 71 feet 2-3/4\ninches; thence southerly parallel with Fifth Avenue and part of the way\nthrough a party wall, 100 feet 5 inches to the northerly side of 52nd\nStreet; thence westerly along the northerly side of 52nd Street, 60 feet\nto the point or place of beginning. Provided, however, that with respect\nto such retail licensee's interest in a business engaged in the\nmanufacture or sale at wholesale of alcoholic beverages described in\nsubdivision 1-a of section one hundred one of this article: such\ninterest must have been acquired prior to the effective date of the\nchapter of the laws of two thousand nineteen which added this paragraph;\n(ii) such retail licensee may not purchase alcoholic beverages directly\nfrom any such manufacturer or wholesaler; and (iii) no more than fifteen\npercent of the annual dollar value of alcoholic beverages purchased by\nsuch retail licensee for sale on the premises may be produced by any\nsuch manufacturer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any lien, mortgage or other interest or estate now held by said\nretail licensee on or in the personal or real property of such\nmanufacturer or wholesaler, which mortgage, lien, interest or estate was\nacquired on or before December thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nthirty-two, shall not be included within the provisions of this\nsubdivision; provided, however, the burden of establishing the time of\nthe accrual of the interest, comprehended by this subdivision shall be\nupon the person who claims to be entitled to the protection and\nexemption afforded hereby.\n  14. No retail licensee for on-premises consumption shall make or cause\nto be made any loan to any person engaged in the manufacture or sale of\nliquors, wines or beer at wholesale.\n  15. All retail licensed premises shall be subject to inspection by any\npeace officer, acting pursuant to his or her special duties, or police\nofficer and by the duly authorized representatives of the liquor\nauthority, during the hours when the said premises are open for the\ntransaction of business.\n  * 16. A person holding a retail on-premises license for a movie\ntheatre, other than a license for a movie theatre that meets the\ndefinitions of restaurant and meals, and where all seating is at tables\nwhere meals are served, shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for every purchase of an alcoholic beverage, require the purchaser\nto provide written evidence of age as set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision two of section sixty-five-b of this chapter; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>allow the purchase of only one alcoholic beverage per transaction;\nand\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_106__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not commence the sale of alcoholic beverages until one hour prior\nto the start of the first motion picture, and cease all sales of\nalcoholic beverages after the conclusion of the final motion picture.\n  * NB Repealed April 20, 2027\n  17. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a retail licensee for\non-premises consumption that is a person or corporation operating a\nhotel shall be permitted to sell liquors, beer, and/or wines through a\nmechanical device or vending machine placed in the lodger's rooms and to\nwhich access to such device or machine is restricted by means of a\nlocking device which requires the use of a key, magnetic card or similar\ndevice provided, however, that no such key, card or similar device shall\nbe provided to any person under the age of twenty-one or to any person\nwho is visibly intoxicated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>