<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-114"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-114"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="114"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_114">
        <num>114</num>
        <heading>Licenses, publication, general provisions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_114__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Name of person to whom\nlicense is issued;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_114__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>kind of license and what kind of traffic in\nalcoholic beverages is thereby permitted;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_114__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>description by street and\nnumber, or otherwise, of licensed premises;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_114__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement in substance\nthat such license shall not be deemed a property or vested right, and\nthat it may be revoked at any time pursuant to law.\n  5. There shall be printed and furnished by the liquor authority to\neach licensee a statement of the causes for which licenses may be\nrevoked. Such statement shall be prepared by the liquor authority and\ndelivered to the licensee with his license or as soon thereafter as may\nbe practicable. Any amendments thereto shall also be sent by the liquor\nauthority to all licensees as soon as may be practicable after such\namendments. Failure to send such statements or changes therein, or\nfailure to receive the same, or any misstatement or error contained in\nsuch statements or amendments shall, however, not be an excuse or\njustification for any violation of law, or prevent, or remit, or\ndecrease any penalty or forfeiture therefor.\n  6. Before commencing or doing any business for the time for which a\nlicense has been issued said license shall be enclosed in a suitable\nwood or metal frame having a clear glass space and a substantial wood or\nmetal back so that the whole of said license may be seen therein, and\nshall be posted up and at all times displayed in a conspicuous place in\nthe room where such business is carried on, so that all persons visiting\nsuch place may readily see the same. It shall be unlawful for any person\nholding a license to post such license or to permit such license to be\nposted upon premises other than the premises licensed, or upon premises\nwhere traffic in alcoholic beverages is being carried on by any person\nother than the licensee, or knowingly to deface, destroy or alter any\nsuch license in any respect. Whenever a license shall be lost or\ndestroyed without fault on the part of the licensee or his agents or\nemployees, a duplicate license in lieu thereof may be issued by the\nliquor authority in its discretion and in accordance with such rules and\nregulations and the payment of suc...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>