<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-119"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-119"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="119"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_119">
        <num>119</num>
        <heading>Procedure for revocation or cancellation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this subdivision shall apply in all cases of\nlicensee or permittee failure after receiving appropriate notice, to\ncomply with a summons, subpoena or warrant relating to a paternity or\nchild support proceeding and arrears in payment of child support or\ncombined child and spousal support referred to the authority by a court\npursuant to the requirements of section two hundred forty-four-c of the\ndomestic relations law or pursuant to section four hundred fifty-eight-b\nor five hundred forty-eight-b of the family court act.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receipt of an order from the court based on arrears in\npayment of child support or combined child and spousal support pursuant\nto one of the foregoing provisions of law, the authority, if it finds\nsuch person to have been issued a license or permit, shall within thirty\ndays of receipt of such order from the court, provide notice to the\nlicensee or permittee of, and initiate, a hearing which shall be held at\nleast twenty days and no more than thirty days after the sending of such\nnotice to the licensee or permittee.  The hearing shall be solely held\nfor the purpose of determining whether there exists as of the date of\nthe hearing proof that full payment of all arrears of support\nestablished by the order of the court to be due from the licensee or\npermittee have been paid.  Proof of such payment shall be a certified\ncheck showing full payment of established arrears or a notice issued by\nthe court or the support collection unit, where the order is payable to\nthe support collection unit designated by the appropriate social\nservices district.  Such notice shall state that full payment of all\narrears of support established by the order of the court to be due have\nbeen paid.  The licensee or permittee shall be given full opportunity to\npresent such proof of payment at the hearing in person or by counsel.\nThe only issue to be determined by the authority as a result of the\nhearing is whether the arrears have been paid.  No evidence with respect\nto the appropriateness of the court order or ability of the respondent\nparty in arrears to comply with such order shall be received or\nconsidered by the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this article or of\nany other provision of law to the contrary, such license or permit shall\nbe suspended if at the hearing, provided for by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, the licensee or permittee fails to present proof of payment\nas required by such subdivision.  Such suspension shall not be lifted\nunless the court or the support collection unit, where the court order\nis payable to the support collection unit designated by the appropriate\nsocial services district, issues notice to the authority that full\npayment of all arrears of support established by the order of the court\nto be due have been paid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receipt of an order from the court based on failure to\ncomply with a summons, subpoena, or warrant relating to a paternity or\nchild support proceeding, the authority, if it finds such person has\nbeen issued a license or permit, shall within thirty days of receipt of\nsuch order from the court, provide notice to the licensee or permittee\nthat his or her license shall be suspended in sixty days unless the\nconditions in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision are met.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this article or of\nany other provision of law to the contrary, such license or permit shall\nbe suspended in accordance with the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision unless the court terminates its order to commence suspension\nproceedings.  Such suspension shall not be lifted unless the court\nissues an order to the authority terminating its order to commence\nsuspension proceedings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall inform the court of all actions taken\nhereunder as required by law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This subdivision applies to support obligations paid pursuant to\nany order of child support or child and spousal support issued under\nprovisions of article three-A or section two hundred thirty-six or two\nhundred forty of the domestic relations law, or article four, five or\nfive-A of the family court act.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this article or of\nany other provision of law to the contrary, the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall apply to the exclusion of any other requirements of\nthis article and to the exclusion of any other requirement of law to the\ncontrary.\n  5. Where a licensee is convicted of two or more qualifying offenses\nwithin a five year period, the authority, upon receipt of notification\nof such second or subsequent conviction pursuant to the provisions of\nsubdivision two of section one hundred six-a of this article, shall, in\naddition to any other sanction or civil or criminal penalty imposed\npursuant to this chapter, impose on such licensee a civil penalty not to\nexceed five hundred dollars. For purposes of this subdivision, a\nqualifying offense shall mean</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the offense defined in subdivision one\nof section sixty-five of this chapter; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the offense defined in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section sixty-five-b of this\nchapter. For purposes of this subdivision, a conviction of a licensee or\nan employee or agent of such licensee shall constitute a conviction of\nsuch licensee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>