<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-04-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15">
        <num>15</num>
        <heading>Officers; employees; offices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 15. Officers; employees; offices. Investigators employed by the\nauthority shall be deemed to be peace officers for the purpose of\nenforcing the provisions of this chapter or judgements or orders\nobtained for violation thereof, with all the powers set forth in section\n2.20 of the criminal procedure law. The counsel, secretary, chief\nexecutive officer, assistant chief executive officers, confidential\nsecretaries to commissioners and deputies shall be in the exempt class\nof the civil service. The other assistants, investigators and employees\nof the authority shall all be in the competitive class of the civil\nservice. The authority shall continue to have its principal office in\nthe city of Albany, and may maintain a branch office in the cities of\nNew York and Buffalo and such other places as the chairman may deem\nnecessary.\n  * NB Effective until July 18, 2027\n  * ยง 15. Officers; employees; offices. The authority shall have power\nto appoint any necessary deputies, counsels, assistants, investigators,\nand other employees within the limits provided by appropriation.\nInvestigators so employed by the Authority shall be deemed to be peace\nofficers for the purpose of enforcing the provisions of the alcoholic\nbeverage control law or judgements or orders obtained for violation\nthereof, with all the powers set forth in section 2.20 of the criminal\nprocedure law. The counsel, secretary, chief executive officer,\nassistant chief executive officers, confidential secretaries to\ncommissioners and deputies shall be in the exempt class of the civil\nservice. The other assistants, investigators and employees of the\nauthority shall all be in the competitive class of the civil service.\nThe authority shall continue to have its principal office in the city of\nAlbany, and may maintain a branch office in the cities of New York and\nBuffalo and such other places as it may deem necessary.\n  The authority shall establish appropriate procedures to insure that\nhearing officers are shielded from ex parte communications with alleged\nviolators and their attorneys and from other employees of the authority\nand shall take such other steps as it shall deem necessary and proper to\nshield its judicial processes from unwarranted and inappropriate\ncommunications and attempts to influence.\n  * NB Effective July 18, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>