<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3">
        <num>3</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Internal Revenue Code\nof the United States.\n  3-c. "Braggot" shall mean a malt alcoholic beverage made primarily\nfrom honey, water, and malt and/or hops; it may also contain fruits,\nspices, herbs, grain or other agricultural products. Honey shall\nrepresent at least fifty-one percent of the starting fermentable sugars\nby weight of the finished product. For the purposes of this chapter,\nbraggot shall be designated and sold as a beer.\n  4. "Brewery" means and includes any place or premises where beer is\nmanufactured for sale; and all offices, granaries, mashrooms,\ncooling-rooms, vaults, yards, and storerooms connected therewith or\nwhere any part of the process of manufacture of beer is carried on, or\nwhere any apparatus connected with such manufacture is kept or used, or\nwhere any of the products of brewing or fermentation are stored or kept,\nshall be deemed to be included in and to form part of the brewery to\nwhich they are attached or are appurtenant.\n  5. "Brewer" means any person who owns, occupies, carries on, works, or\nconducts any brewery, either by himself or by his agent.\n  6. "Board" or "local board" or "appropriate board" or "board having\njurisdiction" shall mean the state liquor authority.\n  7. "Building containing licensed premises" shall include the licensed\npremises and also any part of a building in which such premises is\ncontained and any part of any other building connected with such\nbuilding by direct access or by a common entrance.\n  7-a.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Catering establishment" means and includes any premises\nowned or operated by any person, firm, association, partnership or\ncorporation who or which regularly and in a bona fide manner furnishes\nfor hire therein one or more ballrooms, reception rooms, dining rooms,\nbanquet halls, dancing halls or similar places of assemblage for a\nparticular function, occasion or event and/or who or which furnishes\nprovisions and service for consumption or use at such function, occasion\nor event. Such premises must have suitable and adequate facilities and\naccommodations to provide food and service for not less than fifty\npersons at any one function, occasion or event and shall in no event be\ndeemed to include any taxi dance hall or any other premises at which\npublic dances are regularly scheduled to be held daily, weekly or\nmonthly and to which the general public is invited.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Off-premises catering establishment" means and includes any\npremises owned or operated by any person, firm, association, partnership\nor corporation who or which regularly and in a bona fide manner\nfurnishes for hire at a site remote from the premises for a particular\nfunction, occasion, or event provisions and service for consumption or\nuse at such function, occasion or event. Such premises must have\nsuitable and adequate facilities to provide food for not less than fifty\npersons. On-premises consumption shall not be allowed at such premises.\n  7-b.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Cider" means the partially or fully fermented juice of\nfresh, whole apples or other pome fruits, containing more than three and\ntwo-tenths per centum but not more than eight and one-half per centum\nalcohol by volume:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to which nothing has been added to increase the\nalcoholic content produced by natural fermentation; and (ii) with the\nusual cellar treatments and necessary additions to correct defects due\nto climate, saccharine levels and seasonal conditions. Nothing contained\nin this subdivision shall be deemed to preclude the use of such methods\nor materials as may be necessary to encourage a normal alcoholic\nfermentation and to make a product that is free of microbiological\nactivity at the time of sale. Cider may be sweetened or flavored after\nfermentation with fruit juice, fruit juice concentrate, sugar, maple\nsyrup, honey, spices or other agricultural products, separately or in\ncombination. Cider may contain retained or added carbon dioxide.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that an alcoholic beverage meets the definition of\nboth a cider, as defined in this subdivision, and a wine, as defined in\nsubdivision thirty-six of this section, the brand or trade name label\nowner of such alcoholic beverage shall designate whether such alcoholic\nbeverage shall be sold as a cider or a wine for all purposes under this\nchapter.\n  7-c. "Cidery" means and includes any place or premises wherein cider\nis manufactured for sale.\n  7-d. "Farm cidery" means and includes any place or premises, located\non a farm in New York state, in which New York state labelled cider is\nmanufactured, stored and sold, or any other place or premises in New\nYork state in which New York state labelled cider is manufactured,\nstored and sold.\n  8. "Convicted" and "conviction" include and mean a finding of guilt\nresulting from a plea of guilty, the decision of a court or magistrate\nor the verdict of a jury, irrespective of the pronouncement of judgment\nor the suspension thereof.\n  9. "Club" shall mean an organization of persons incorporated pursuant\nto the provisions of the not-for-profit corporation law or the\nbenevolent orders law, which is the owner, lessee or occupant of a\nbuilding used exclusively for club purposes, and which does not traffic\nin alcoholic beverages for profit and is operated solely for a\nrecreational, social, patriotic, political, benevolent or athletic\npurpose but not for pecuniary gain; except that where such club is\nlocated in an office or business building, or state armory, it may be\nlicensed as such provided it otherwise qualifies as a "club" within the\nmeaning of this subdivision. A "luncheon club" shall mean a club which\nis open only on week days during the hours between eleven o'clock in the\nmorning and three o'clock in the afternoon. A "member" of a club shall\nmean a person who whether a charter member or admitted in agreement with\nthe by-laws of the club, has become a bona fide member thereof, who\nmaintains...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3__subsec_c__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or\n501</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3__subsec_c__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the United States internal revenue code, a member of\nanother chapter or lodge of such not-for-profit corporation or\nbenevolent order who has in his or her possession an identification card\nor other proof of membership shall be deemed to be a member. A club and\na luncheon club shall appoint an alcoholic beverage officer from among\nits members who shall be responsible for filing all applications and\nother documents required to be submitted to the authority. The person\nappointed alcoholic beverage officer shall be subject to approval by the\nauthority.\n  9-a. "Custom crush facility" means a licensed winery or farm winery\nwhich obtains grapes, fruits and other plants grown exclusively in New\nYork state from, or on behalf of, other licensed wineries or farm\nwineries and crushes, processes, ferments, bottles or conducts any\ncombination of such services for such other licensed wineries or farm\nwineries.\n  10. "Distiller" means any person who owns, occupies, carries on,\nworks...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>from the effective date of this subdivision until December\nthirty-first, two thousand eighteen, beer made with no less than twenty\npercent, by weight, of its hops grown in New York state and no less than\ntwenty percent, by weight, of all of its other ingredients, excluding\nwater, grown in New York state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>from January first, two thousand nineteen until December\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty-eight, beer made with no less than\nsixty percent, by weight, of its hops grown in New York state and no\nless than sixty percent, by weight, of all of its other ingredients,\nexcluding water, grown in New York state; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>from January first, two thousand twenty-nine and thereafter, beer\nmade with no less than ninety percent, by weight, of its hops grown in\nNew York state and no less than ninety percent, by weight, of all of its\nother ingredients, excluding water, grown in New York state.\n  20-e. "New York state labelled cider" means cider made exclusively\nfrom apples or other pome fruits grown in New York state.\n  20-f. "New York state labelled braggot" means braggot made exclusively\nfrom honey produced in New York state.\n  20-g. "New York state labelled mead" means mead made exclusively from\nhoney produced in New York state.\n  21. "Permittee" means any person to whom a permit has been issued\npursuant to this chapter.\n  22. "Person" includes an individual, copartnership, corporations,\nsociety, joint stock company, alcoholic beverage officer appointed by a\nclub or a luncheon club or limited liability company.\n  23. "Population" means the number of inhabitants as determined by the\nlast preceding federal census.\n  24. "Rectifier" means and includes any person who rectifies, purifies\nor refines distilled spirits or wines by any process other than as\nprovided for on distillery premises and every person who, without\nrectifying, purifying or refining distilled spirits, shall, by mixing\nsuch spirits, wine or other liquor with water or any materials,\nmanufactures any imitation of or compounds liquors for sale under the\nname of whiskey, brandy, gin, rum, wine, spirits, cordials, bitters or\nany other name.\n  25. "Retail sale" or "sale at retail" means a sale to a consumer or to\nany person for any purpose other than for resale.\n  26. "Retailer" means any person who sells at retail any beverage for\nthe sale of which a license is required under the provisions of this\nchapter.\n  27. "Restaurant" shall mean a place which is regularly and in a bona\nfide manner used and kept open for the serving of meals to guests for\ncompensation and which has suitable kitchen faciliti...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>