<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-32"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-32"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-03-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="32"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_32">
        <num>32</num>
        <heading>Authorization for sale of mead and braggot by retail licensees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 32. Authorization for sale of mead and braggot by retail licensees.\n1. Each retail licensee under this chapter shall have the right, by\nvirtue of his or her license and without being required to pay any\nadditional fee for the privilege, to sell at retail for consumption on\nor off the premises, as the case may be, mead which has not been\ndesignated as a wine pursuant to subdivision nineteen-a of section three\nof this chapter and has been purchased from a person licensed to produce\nor sell mead at wholesale under this chapter.\n  2. Each retail licensee authorized to sell wine under this chapter\nshall have the right, by virtue of his or her license and without being\nrequired to pay any additional fee for the privilege, to sell at retail\nfor consumption on or off the premises, as the case may be, mead which\nhas been designated as a wine pursuant to subdivision nineteen-a of\nsection three of this chapter and which has been purchased from a person\nlicensed to produce or sell mead at wholesale under this chapter.\n  3. Each retail licensee authorized to sell beer under this chapter\nshall have the right, by virtue of his or her license and without being\nrequired to pay any additional fee for the privilege, to sell at retail\nfor consumption on or off the premises, as the case may be, braggot\nwhich has been purchased from a person licensed to produce or sell\nbraggot at wholesale under this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>