<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-52"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-52"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-05-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="52"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-52/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-52/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-52/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-52/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52">
        <num>52</num>
        <heading>Custom beermakers' center</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision eleven of section fifty-one-a of this\narticle.\n  3. A custom beermakers' center license shall authorize the holder\nthereof to operate a facility for individuals to rent space, equipment,\nand storage facilities and, if necessary, to purchase beer making\nsupplies to manufacture beer for personal household use provided that\nthe manufacture and production of beer for personal household\nconsumption and use is done in accordance with state and federal laws\nand regulations. Such a license shall also authorize the licensee,\nprovided such activities are permitted by the federal Alcohol and\nTobacco Tax and Trade Bureau for the manufacture of tax exempt beer for\npersonal household use, to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conduct training classes on how to manufacture beer; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conduct beer tastings for those individuals taking such classes\nand/or using such facility for brewing purposes at the licensed facility\nprovided that the tastings shall be subject to the following\nlimitations:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>tastings shall be conducted by the licensee or by an official\nagent of the licensee. Such licensee or agent shall be physically\npresent at all times during the conduct of the tastings; and\n  (ii) any liability stemming from a right of action resulting from a\ntasting of beer as authorized herein and in accordance with the\nprovisions of sections 11-100 and 11-101 of the general obligations law,\nshall accrue to the custom beermakers' center.\n  4. The custom beermakers' center licensee shall be subject to the\nsupervision of the authority to ensure that the licensee and the\nindividuals utilizing such center are in compliance with the provisions\nof this chapter, state laws, rules, and regulations, and the laws,\nrules, and regulations of the federal Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade\nBureau.\n  5. The licensee or an official agent of the licensee shall be\nphysically present at all times during the facility's hours of\noperations.\n  6. The annual aggregate production of beer at any such center for all\nindividuals making beer at such premises, pursuant to a custom\nbeermakers' center license, shall not exceed the production limits set\nby the authority that are commensurate with a non-commercial production\nfacility. Provided that such aggregate production limit shall not be\noffset by beer produced at such facility under a brewer's license or\nfarm brewery license.\n  7. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the authority\nmay issue a custom beermakers' center license to the holder of a farm\nbrewery or brewery license for use at such licensee's existing licensed\npremises.\n  8. The authority is hereby authorized to promulgate rules and\nregulations to effectuate the purposes of this section.\n  9. The licensee must maintain a record of the name, address, and\ncontact information of the individuals that have used such facility and\nthe annual amount of beer produced by each individual at the facility\npursuant to the rules of the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>