<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-01-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="53-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53_A">
        <num>53-A</num>
        <heading>Vendor's license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 53-a. Vendor's license. In cities having a population of one million\nor more, any individual person may apply for a license to sell beer as a\nvendor. Such application shall be in writing, and verified, and shall\ncontain such information as the liquor authority shall require. Such\napplication shall be accompanied by a check or draft for the amount\nrequired by this article for such license. If the liquor authority shall\ngrant the application it shall issue a license in such form as shall be\ndetermined by its rules. Such a license shall contain a description of\nthe licensed premises and in form and in substance shall be a license to\nthe person therein specifically designated to sell beer as a vendor in\ncities having a population of one million or more only, from the\npremises therein specifically licensed. A vendor's license shall\nauthorize the holder thereof to sell beer at retail to be delivered by\nsuch vendor to a person for consumption in his home and shall authorize\nthe holder thereof to operate one vehicle for the delivery of beer, but\nshall not authorize the sale to any person or licensee for resale.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>