<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-01-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="53"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53">
        <num>53</num>
        <heading>Wholesaler's license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 53. Wholesaler's license. Any person may apply to the liquor\nauthority for a license to sell beer at wholesale. Such application\nshall be in writing and verified and shall contain such information as\nthe liquor authority shall require. Such application shall be\naccompanied by a check or draft for the amount required by this article\nfor such license.  If the liquor authority shall grant the application\nit shall issue a license in such form as shall be determined by its\nrules. Such a license shall contain a description of the licensed\npremises and in form and in substance shall be a license to the person\ntherein specifically designated to sell beer at wholesale in the\npremises therein specifically licensed to duly licensed wholesalers,\nretailers and permittees in this state, and to sell or deliver beer to\npersons outside the state pursuant to the laws of the place of such sale\nor delivery. A wholesaler's license issued or renewed prior to July\nfirst, nineteen hundred sixty, and thereafter renewed or transferred,\nshall authorize the holder thereof to sell beer at retail to a person\nfor consumption in his home; provided, however, that regardless of the\ndate issued, renewed or transferred, a wholesaler's license issued to a\nbrewer or to the wholly-owned subsidiary of a brewer, shall authorize\nthe holder thereof to sell beer at retail to a person for consumption in\nhis home.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>