<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-58-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-58-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-05-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="58-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-58-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-58-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-58-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-58-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_58_D">
        <num>58-D</num>
        <heading>Custom cidermakers' center</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_58_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conduct training classes on how to manufacture cider; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_58_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conduct cider tastings for those individuals taking such classes\nand/or using such facility for the production of cider at the licensed\nfacility provided that the tastings shall be subject to the following\nlimitations:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_58_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>tastings shall be conducted by the licensee or by an official\nagent of the licensee. Such licensee or agent shall be physically\npresent at all times during the conduct of the tastings; and\n  (ii) any liability stemming from a right of action resulting from a\ntasting of cider as authorized herein and in accordance with the\nprovisions of sections 11-100 and 11-101 of the general obligations law,\nshall accrue to such center.\n  4. The custom cidermakers' center licensee shall be subject to the\nsupervision of the authority to ensure that the licensee and the\nindividuals utilizing such center are in compliance with the provisions\nof this chapter, state laws, rules, and regulations, and the laws,\nrules, and regulations of the federal Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade\nBureau.\n  5. The licensee or an official agent of the licensee shall be\nphysically present at all times during the facility's hours of\noperations.\n  6. The annual aggregate production of cider at any such center for all\nindividuals making cider at such premises, pursuant to a custom\ncidermakers' center license, shall not exceed the production limits set\nforth by the authority that are commensurate with a non-commercial\nproduction facility. Provided that such aggregate production limit shall\nnot be offset by cider produced at such facility under a cidery license\nor farm cidery license.\n  7. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the authority\nmay issue a custom cidermakers' center license to the holder of a farm\ncidery or cidery license or farm winery or winery license for use at\nsuch licensee's existing licensed premises.\n  8. The authority is hereby authorized to promulgate rules and\nregulations to effectuate the purposes of this section.\n  9. The licensee must maintain a record of the name, address, and\ncontact information of the individuals that have used such facility and\nthe annual amount of cider produced by each individual at the facility\npursuant to the rul...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>