<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="65-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_65_D">
        <num>65-D</num>
        <heading>Posting of signs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 65-d. Posting of signs. 1. The authority shall prepare, have printed\nand distribute across the state to all persons with a license to sell\nalcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises or a license to sell\nalcoholic beverages for consumption off the premises a sign or poster\nwith conspicuous lettering that states the following:\n  "No person shall sell or give away any alcoholic beverages to:\n  1. any person under the age of twenty-one years; or\n  2. any visibly intoxicated person.\n  IT IS A VIOLATION PUNISHABLE UNDER LAW FOR ANY PERSON UNDER THE AGE OF\nTWENTY-ONE TO PRESENT ANY WRITTEN EVIDENCE OF AGE WHICH IS FALSE,\nFRAUDULENT OR NOT ACTUALLY HIS OWN FOR THE PURPOSE OF ATTEMPTING TO\nPURCHASE ANY ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGE".\n  Such sign or poster shall be captioned with the word "warning" in at\nleast two inch lettering.\n  2. All persons with a license to sell alcoholic beverages for\nconsumption on the premises or a license to sell alcoholic beverages for\nconsumption off the premises shall display, in an upright position and\nin a conspicuous place, where it can be easily read by the clientele of\nthe establishment, the sign or poster upon receiving it from the\nauthority.\n  3. Any person with such license who violates the provisions of this\nsection shall be subject to a civil penalty, not to exceed one hundred\ndollars for each day of violation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>