<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="65-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-65-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_65_E">
        <num>65-E</num>
        <heading>Posting of signs relating to human trafficking</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_E__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section one hundred ten of this\nchapter, that topless entertainment and/or exotic dancing, whether\ntopless or otherwise, including but not limited to, pole dancing and lap\ndancing, would occur at the establishment, to display one or more signs\nor posters designated by the authority. Any sign or poster so designated\nshall meet the following specifications:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each sign or poster shall include information on human trafficking\nand the toll free telephone number of the National Human Trafficking\nhotline. The authority shall make any designated sign or poster\navailable for download from its website or from one or more links posted\non its website or on the website of the office of temporary and\ndisability assistance as provided in section four hundred\neighty-three-ff of the social services law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any sign or poster must be at least eight and one-half inches\nwide and eleven inches high.\n  (ii) If the National Human Trafficking hotline toll free number\nchanges, the authority shall notify each licensee that is subject to the\nposting requirement of this section of the change and shall require the\ndisplay of one or more signs or posters with the new toll free number\nwithin thirty days of such notification.\n  (iii) At a minimum, the licensee shall be required to display a\nbilingual version of the sign or poster in English and Spanish or to\ndisplay one sign or poster in English and one sign or poster in Spanish.\nA licensee may be required to display signs or posters in other\nlanguages as determined by the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_65_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person with a license to sell alcoholic beverages for\nconsumption on the premises that is subject to the posting requirement\nof this section shall display, in an upright position and in a\nconspicuous place where it can be easily read by clientele and employees\nof the establishment, any sign or poster required by the authority.\n  2. Any person with a license to sell alcoholic beverages for\nconsumption on the premises that is subject to the posting requirement\nof this section who violates the provisions of this section shall be\nsubject to a civil penalty, not to exceed one hundred dollars for each\nday of violation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>