<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-66"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-66"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="66"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-66/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-66/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-66/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-66/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_66">
        <num>66</num>
        <heading>License fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 66. License fees. 1. The annual fee for a distiller's license, class\nA, shall be twelve thousand dollars.\n  1-a. The annual fee for a distiller's license, class A-1, shall be two\nhundred fifty dollars.\n  2. The annual fee for a distiller's license, class B, shall be eight\nthousand dollars.\n  2-a. The annual fee for a distiller's license, class C, shall be one\nhundred twenty-eight dollars.\n  2-b. The annual fee for a distiller's license, class B-1, shall be\nthree hundred twenty dollars.\n  2-c. The annual fee for distiller's license, class D, shall be one\nhundred twenty-eight dollars.\n  3. The annual fee for a license to sell liquor at wholesale shall be\nsixty-four hundred dollars.\n  3-a. The annual fee for an importer's license shall be one hundred\ntwenty-five dollars.\n  3-b. The annual fee for a brand owner's license shall be one hundred\ntwenty-five dollars.\n  4. The annual fee for a license, under section sixty-four or\nsixty-four-a of this article, to sell liquor at retail to be consumed on\nthe premises where sold shall be twenty-one hundred seventy-six dollars\nin the counties of New York, Kings, Bronx and Queens; fifteen hundred\nthirty-six dollars in the county of Richmond and in cities having a\npopulation of more than one hundred thousand and less than one million;\ntwelve hundred sixteen dollars in cities having a population of more\nthan fifty thousand and less than one hundred thousand; and the sum of\neight hundred ninety-six dollars elsewhere; except that the license fees\nfor catering establishments and off-premises catering establishments\nshall be two-thirds the license fee specified herein and for clubs,\nexcept luncheon clubs and golf clubs, shall be seven hundred fifty\ndollars in counties of New York, Kings, Bronx and Queens; five hundred\ndollars in the county of Richmond and in cities having a population of\nmore than one hundred thousand and less than one million; three hundred\nfifty dollars in cities having a population of more than fifty thousand\nand less than one hundred thousand; and the sum of two hundred fifty\ndollars elsewhere. The annual fees for luncheon clubs shall be three\nhundred seventy-five dollars, and for golf clubs in the counties of New\nYork, Kings, Bronx, Queens, Nassau, Richmond and Westchester, two\nhundred fifty dollars, and elsewhere one hundred eighty-seven dollars\nand fifty cents. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the\ncontrary, there shall be no annual fee for a license, under section\nsixty-four, to sell liquor at retail to be consumed on the premises\nwhere the applicant is an organization organized under section two\nhundred sixty of the military law and incorporated pursuant to the\nnot-for-profit corporation law. Provided, however, that where any\npremises for which a license is issued pursuant to section sixty-four or\nsixty-four-a of this article remain open only within the period\ncommencing April first and ending October thirty-first of any one year,\nor only within the period commencing October first and ending the\nfollowing April thirtieth, the liquor authority may, in its discretion,\ngrant a summer or winter license effective only for such appropriate\nperiod of time, for which a license fee shall be paid to be pro-rated\nfor the period for which such license is effective, at the rate provided\nfor in the city, town or village in which such premises are located,\nexcept that no such license fee shall be less than one-half of the\nregular annual license fee; provided further that where the premises to\nbe licensed are a race track or a golf course or are licensed pursuant\nto section sixty-four or sixty-four-a of this article, the period of\nsuch summer license may commence March first and end November thirtieth.\n  Where a hotel, restaurant, club, golf course or race track is open\nprior to April first and/or subsequent to October thirty-first by reason\nof the issuance of a caterer's permit or permits issued by the\nauthority, such fact alone shall not affect the eligibility of the\npremises or the person owning or operating such hotel, restaurant, club,\ngolf course or race track for a summer license.\n  5. The annual fee for a license to sell liquor at retail not to be\nconsumed on the premises where sold shall be thirteen hundred sixty-six\ndollars in the counties of New York, Kings, Bronx and Queens; eight\nhundred fifty-four dollars in the county of Richmond and in cities\nhaving a population of more than one hundred thousand and less than one\nmillion; and elsewhere the sum of five hundred twelve dollars.\n  6. The annual fee for a license to sell liquor upon any railroad car\nto be consumed on such car or any car connected therewith shall be one\nhundred ninety-two dollars for each railroad car licensed.\n  7. The annual fee for a license to sell liquor upon any vessel in this\nstate to be consumed upon such vessel shall be sixteen hundred dollars\nfor each vessel licensed, provided, however, that where a vessel is\noperated only within the period commencing April first and ending\nOctober thirty-first of any one year, the liquor authority may, in its\ndiscretion, grant for such vessel a summer license effective only for\nsuch period of time, for which a license fee of four hundred forty-eight\ndollars shall be paid.\n  8. The annual fee for a license to sell liquor upon an aircraft being\noperated on regularly scheduled flights by a United States certificated\nairline in this state shall be nineteen hundred twenty dollars per annum\nfor an airline company operating up to and including twenty such\naircraft and twenty-five hundred sixty dollars for such an airline\noperating more than twenty such aircraft.\n  9. The annual fee for a license for a bottle club shall be the same as\nthe annual fee for a special license to sell liquor at retail to be\nconsumed on the premises, as set forth in subdivision four of this\nsection.\n  10. Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, the annual fee for\na license for an establishment defined as an owner-occupied residence\nproviding at least three but no more than five rooms for temporary\ntransient lodgers with sleeping accommodations and a meal in the\nforenoon of the day, known as a "bed and breakfast dwelling" as\nauthorized by subdivision five-a of section sixty-four of this article,\nshall be two hundred dollars plus fifteen dollars per each available\nbedroom.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>