<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-83"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-83"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="83"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-83/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-83/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-83/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-83/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_83">
        <num>83</num>
        <heading>License fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_83__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section seventy-six of this article shall be\nforty dollars.\n  2. The annual fee for a license to sell wine at wholesale shall be\neight hundred dollars.\n  3. The annual fee for a license to sell wine at retail, not to be\nconsumed on the premises, shall be six hundred forty dollars for each\nsuch place where such business is carried on in cities having a\npopulation of one million or more; in cities having less than one\nmillion population and more than one hundred thousand, three hundred\ntwenty dollars; and elsewhere, the sum of one hundred forty-five\ndollars.\n  4. The annual fee for selling wine at retail, to be consumed on the\npremises where sold, shall be as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_83__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In cities having a population of one hundred thousand or over the\nsum of four hundred eighty dollars per year; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_83__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Elsewhere, the sum of two hundred forty dollars per year.\n  4-a. The annual fee for a license to sell wine at retail to be\nconsumed on the premises where sold where the premises to be licensed\nremain open only within the period commencing April first and ending\nOctober thirty-first of any one year or only within the period\ncommencing October first and ending the following April thirtieth, the\nliquor authority, in its discretion, may grant a summer or winter\nlicense effective only for such appropriate period of time, for which an\nannual fee of one hundred twelve dollars shall be paid.\n  5. The annual fee for a special license to sell wine at retail, to be\nconsumed on the premises where sold, shall be as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_83__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In cities having a population of one hundred thousand or over, the\nsum of five hundred seventy-six dollars per year; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_83__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Elsewhere, the sum of two hundred seventy dollars per year.\n  6. The annual fee for a special winery license shall be six hundred\ntwenty-five dollars.\n  7. The annual fee for a special farm winery license shall be one\nhundred twenty-five dollars.\n  8. The annual fee for a roadside farm market license shall be one\nhundred dollars.\n  9. The annual fee for a license to operate a custom winemakers' center\nshall be three hundred twenty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>