<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-96-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-96-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="96-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-96-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-96-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-96-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-96-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_A">
        <num>96-A</num>
        <heading>Bottling permit</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 96-a. Bottling permit. 1. No liquor or wine may be bottled in this\nstate except by the manufacturer thereof or as hereinafter provided.\n  2. The liquor authority is hereby authorized to issue a bottling\npermit to a wholesale wine or liquor licensee to bottle, recask, filter\nor clarify wine or liquor, respectively, imported in bulk from a foreign\ncountry, on the premises of a United States customs bonded warehouse for\nwhich a warehouse permit has been issued under this chapter or in a\nforeign trade zone established pursuant to federal law. Such permit and\nthe exercise of the privileges granted thereunder shall be subject to\nthe laws of the United States and the rules of the federal agency having\njurisdiction thereunder, and such other rules as the state liquor\nauthority deems necessary.\n  3. The liquor authority is hereby authorized to issue a bottling\npermit to a person to bottle, on the premises designated in the permit\nor in a United States customs bonded warehouse for which a warehouse\npermit has been issued under this chapter, liquor manufactured outside\nof the state of New York or wine produced in a foreign country and\nreceived in this state in bulk. Such bottling may be performed for or on\nbehalf of wholesale liquor or wine licensees or for persons authorized\nto sell liquor or wine at wholesale pursuant to the laws and regulations\nof any other state, territorial possession of the United States or\nforeign country. Such permit shall also authorize the holder thereof to\nrebottle or recondition liquors and wines manufactured outside of the\nstate of New York and received in this state, for or on behalf of\nwholesale liquor or wine licensees, or for persons authorized to sell\nliquor or wine at wholesale pursuant to the laws and regulations of any\nother state, territorial possession of the United States or foreign\ncountry.  Such permit and the exercise of the privileges granted\nthereunder shall be subject to the laws of the United States and the\nrules of the federal agency having jurisdiction thereunder, and such\nother rules as the state liquor authority deems necessary.\n  4. Such permit shall be issued in the form prescribed by the liquor\nauthority and shall be issued for the calendar year and the fee for a\npermit issued under subdivision two of this section shall be at the rate\nof four hundred eighty dollars per annum, except that where the\napplication shall be filed after July first in any year the fee shall be\ntwo hundred forty dollars for the remainder of such period. The fee for\na permit under subdivision three of this section shall be at the rate of\nsixteen hundred dollars per annum, except that where the application\nshall be filed after July first in any year the fee shall be eight\nhundred dollars for the remainder of such period.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>