<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-08-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="97-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_97_B">
        <num>97-B</num>
        <heading>Sale of alcoholic beverages at the New York state fair</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such permit shall allow for the sale of alcoholic beverages by\nthe permit holder for consumption upon the premises known as the New\nYork state fairgrounds during the annual New York state fair for the\ncalendar year such permit is issued.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such a permit shall also allow the holder thereof to store\nalcoholic beverages upon the New York state fairgrounds, in areas\ndesignated by the concessionaire's license, during the seven days\nimmediately preceding and the seven days immediately following the state\nfair for which the permit has been issued.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such permit holder must display its permit at all locations as\nauthorized by the concessionaire's license and the authority.\n  4. The holder of an on-premises license issued for a premises located\nupon the New York state fairgrounds may exercise the privileges of a\npermit issued under this section without the need to obtain such permit.\nProvided, however, that the licensee may only sell such alcoholic\nbeverages as may be sold under the terms of its license.\n  5. The holder of a manufacturing license issued pursuant to section\nthirty-one, fifty-one, fifty-one-a, fifty-eight, fifty-eight-c,\nseventy-six or seventy-six-a of this chapter or subdivision two-c of\nsection sixty-one of this chapter may exercise the privileges of a\npermit issued under this section without need to obtain such permit.\nProvided, however, that the licensee:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>holds a concessionaire's\nlicense issued by the division of the New York state fair in the\ndepartment of agriculture and markets; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>may only sell such\nalcoholic beverages as may be sold for on-premises consumption at its\nlicensed premises under the terms of its license.\n  6. The exercise of the privileges of a permit under this section shall\nbe subject to:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such rules of the liquor authority as it deems\nnecessary; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the provisions of a concessionaire's agreement\nbetween the permit holder or licensee and the division of the New York\nstate fair in the department of agriculture and markets.\n  7. The fee for such permit shall be two hundred sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>