<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-04-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="97-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-97-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_97_D">
        <num>97-D</num>
        <heading>Temporary wholesale permit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant has a wholesale license application at the same\npremises pending before the liquor authority, together with all required\nfiling and license fees;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant has obtained and provided evidence of all permits,\nlicenses and other documents necessary for the operation of such a\nbusiness; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any current license in effect at the premises has been surrendered\nor placed in safekeeping, or has been deemed abandoned by the authority.\n  3. The liquor authority in granting such permit shall ensure that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>issuance of the permit will not inordinately hinder the operation\nor effective administration of this chapter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant would in all likelihood be able to ultimately obtain\nthe wholesale license being applied for; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_97_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant has substantially complied with the requirements\nnecessary to obtain such license.\n  4. The application for a permit shall be approved or denied by the\nliquor authority within forty-five days after the receipt of such\napplication.\n  5. A temporary permit shall authorize the permittee to operate a\nwholesale facility for the purchase, warehousing, and sale of alcoholic\nbeverages according to the laws applicable to the type of wholesale\nlicense being applied for.\n  6. Such temporary permit shall remain in effect for six months or\nuntil the wholesale license being applied for is approved and the\nlicense granted, whichever is shorter. Such permit may be extended at\nthe discretion of the liquor authority for additional three-month\nperiods of time upon payment of an additional fee of fifty dollars for\neach such extension.\n  7. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a temporary\nwholesale permit may be summarily cancelled or suspended at any time if\nthe liquor authority determines that good cause for cancellation or\nsuspension exists. The liquor authority shall promptly notify the\npermittee in writing of such cancellation or suspension and shall set\nforth the reasons for such action.\n  8. The liquor authority in reviewing such application shall review the\nentire record and grant the temporary permit unless good cause is\notherwise shown. A decision on an application shall be based on\nsubstantial evidence in the record and supported by a preponderance of\nthe evidence in favor of the applicant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>