<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ABC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-99-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-99-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="99-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="ABC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-99-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-99-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-99-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/abc/section-99-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_99_F">
        <num>99-F</num>
        <heading>Special permits for minors to entertain</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 99-f. Special permits for minors to entertain. The liquor authority\nis hereby authorized to issue special permits to any person under the\nage of eighteen years for the purpose of enabling such person to appear\nas an entertainer on any premises licensed for retail sale hereunder.\nThe provisions of this section shall apply to persons under the age of\neighteen years who are not otherwise eligible to act as an entertainer\npursuant to the provisions of subdivision two-b of section one hundred\nof this chapter. Such special permit shall be issued, in the discretion\nof the authority, upon the application of such minor. No such special\npermit shall be granted unless the written consent of both parents or\nthe lawful guardian or guardians of such minor shall appear upon such\napplication. The liquor authority may require the personal appearance at\nan office of the authority of such applicant and his parents or legal\nguardians at the time such application is made or at any other time\nprior to the consideration of such application by the authority upon\nwritten notice to the applicant and/or his parents or legal guardians.\nSuch personal appearance, if requested, shall be for the purpose of\nenabling the authority to establish that the entertainment that the\napplicant is intending to perform is not contrary to the best interests\nof the minor. The liquor authority is hereby authorized and directed to\npromulgate rules and regulations for the orderly implementation and\nadministration of the provisions of this section. Such rules and\nregulations shall provide for a reasonable limitation upon the types of\nentertainment for which an application for a special permit shall be\ngranted and may provide for conditions or limitations which may be\nattached to the granting of such special permit. In addition to any\nconditions or limitations as may be so imposed, such rules or\nregulations shall impose as a condition for the granting of such special\npermit that a parent or legal guardian of the minor shall be present\nduring such minor's appearance as an entertainer. Such special permit\nshall be subject to revocation, after a hearing upon a determination by\nthe authority that the conditions or limitations attached upon such\nspecial permit have been violated. Such special permits shall be issued\nfor limited periods not to exceed one year. The liquor authority may\nimpose a fee for the issuance of such special permit. Such fee shall not\nexceed sixty-four dollars if issued for an annual period nor shall such\nfee exceed six dollars per month or any lesser period thereof for which\na special permit has been issued. The liquor authority may waive such\nfee. The liquor authority shall revoke any special permit upon the\nwritten request of the parents or legal guardians of such minor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>