<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1100"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1100">
        <num>1100</num>
        <heading>Rules and regulations of the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1100. Rules and regulations of the department.  1. The department\nmay make rules and regulations for the protection from contamination of\nany or all public supplies of potable waters and water supplies of the\nstate or United States, institutions, parks, reservations or posts and\ntheir sources within the state, and the commissioner of environmental\nprotection of the city of New York and the board of water supply of the\ncity of New York may make such rules and regulations subject to the\napproval of the department for the protection from contamination of any\nor all public supplies of potable waters and their sources within the\nstate where the same constitute a part of the source of the public water\nsupply of said city.\n  2. Every such rule or regulation shall be published at least once in\neach week for two consecutive weeks, in at least one newspaper of the\ncounty where the waters to which it relates are located. The cost of\nsuch publication shall be paid by the corporation, municipality, state\nor United States or state or United States institution, park,\nreservation or post benefited by the protection of the water supply to\nwhich the rule or regulation published relates.\n  3. The affidavit of the printer, publisher or proprietor of the\nnewspaper in which such rule or regulation is published shall be filed,\ntogether with the rule or regulation published, in the county clerk's\noffice of such county, and such affidavit and rule and regulation shall\nbe conclusive evidence of such publication, and of all the facts therein\nstated in all courts and places.\n  4. All rules and regulations heretofore duly made and published for\nthe sanitary protection of public water supplies, pursuant to chapter\nfive hundred forty-three of the laws of eighteen hundred eighty-five,\nand chapter six hundred sixty-one of the laws of eighteen hundred\nninety-three, as amended, are hereby legalized, ratified, confirmed and\ncontinued in force, until new rules and regulations become operative.\n  5. This section shall not be construed to repeal or affect any of the\nprovisions of chapter three hundred seventy-eight of the laws of\neighteen hundred ninety-seven, or its amendments.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>