<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1102"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1102">
        <num>1102</num>
        <heading>Violation; injunction and abatement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1102__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon being notified of any violation as herein provided, the\ndepartment shall examine immediately into such violation; and if the\ndepartment finds such rule or regulation to have been violated, the\ncommissioner shall order the local board of health of the health\ndistrict wherein the violation or noncompliance occurs, to convene and\nenforce compliance with such rule or regulation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1102__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the local board of health of the health district wherein the\nviolation or noncompliance occurs, fails to enforce the order of the\ncommissioner within ten days after its receipt, the corporation\nfurnishing such water supply or the municipality, state, or United\nStates or state or United States institution, park, reservation or post\nderiving its water supply from the waters to which such rule or\nregulation relates, or the commissioner, or the local board of health of\nthe health district wherein the water supply protected by these rules is\nused, or any person interested in the protection of the purity of the\nwater supply, may maintain an action in a court of record which shall be\ntried in the county where the cause of action arose against such person,\nfor the recovery of the penalties incurred by such violation, and for an\ninjunction restraining the person violating such rule or regulation from\nthe continued violation thereof.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1102__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the person served with notice of violation does not comply\nwithin five days with the rule or regulation violated, in case such rule\nor regulation relates to a temporary or permanent source or act of\ncontamination affecting the potable water supply of the city of New\nYork, the commissioner of environmental protection of said city, or the\nboard of water supply of the city of New York, may summarily enforce\ncompliance with such rule or regulation and may summarily abate or\nremove the cause of the violation of such rule or regulation or the\nnuisance so created, and to that end may employ such force as may be\nnecessary and proper; provided, however, that no building or improvement\nshall be removed, disturbed or destroyed by the said commissioner of\nenvironmental protection or the said board of water supply until he or\nthey shall cause measurements to be made of the buildings and\nphotographs of the exterior views thereof, which measurements and\nphotographs shall be at the disposition thereafter of the owners or\ntheir attorneys, and failure to exercise such right of abatement shall\nnot be deemed a waiver thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1102__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Failure to comply within five days with such rule or regulation\nshall further entitle the city of New York to maintain an action in any\ncourt having jurisdiction thereof for the recovery of the penalties\nincurred by such violation in an amount authorized by section one\nthousand one hundred three of this title and for an injunction\nrestraining the person from violating such rule or regulation, or\ncreating or continuing such nuisance. The remedy by abatement herein\nprovided for shall not be construed to be exclusive.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>