<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1112"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1112"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-03-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1112"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1112">
        <num>1112</num>
        <heading>Emerging contaminant monitoring</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1112__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a public water system\nthat serves at least five service connections used by year-round\nresidents or regularly serves at least twenty-five year-round residents;\nor (ii) a public water system that regularly serves at least twenty-five\nof the same people, four hours or more per day, for four or more days\nper week, for twenty-six or more weeks per year.\n  3. a. The commissioner shall promulgate regulations to identify and\nlist substances as emerging contaminants that meet the following\ncriteria:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1112__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are not subject to any other substance-specific drinking water\nregulation of the department that establishes a maximum contaminant\nlevel, maximum residual disinfectant level, or action level;\n  (ii) are known or anticipated to occur in public water systems; and\n  (iii) because of their quantity, concentration, or physical, chemical\nor infectious characteristics, may cause physical injury or illness, or\notherwise pose a potential hazard to human health when present in\ndrinking water.\n  b. In determining what substances shall be listed as emerging\ncontaminants the commissioner shall, at a minimum, consider:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1112__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>unregulated contaminants monitored pursuant to the federal Safe\nDrinking Water Act (42 U.S.C. ยง 300g-1) as amended from time to time;\n  (ii) substances that require regulation or monitoring when present in\ndrinking water in other jurisdictions outside the state of New York;\n  (iii) pesticide chemicals for which the United States environmental\nprotection agency has set human health benchmarks for drinking water;\n  (iv) substances found at sites in remedial programs located inside and\noutside the state of New York, including but not limited to inactive\nhazardous waste sites; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1112__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>recommendations from the drinking water quality council\nestablished pursuant to section eleven hundred thirteen of this title.\n  c. The commissioner shall, at a minimum, include the following\nchemicals identified as emerging contaminants in the first list of\nemerging contaminants: perfluorononanoic acid (PFNA);\nperfluorohexanesulfonic acid (PFHxS); perfluoroheptanoic acid (PFHpA);\nperfluorobutanesulfonic acid (PFBS); hexafluoropropylene oxide dimer\nacid (HFPO-DA); Perfluorodecanoic acid (PFDA); Perfluorododecanoic acid\n(PFDoA); Perfluorohexanoic acid (PFHxA); Perfluoroundecanoic acid\n(PFUnA); 11-chloroeicosafluoro-3-oxaundecane-1-sulfonic acid\n(11Cl-PF3OUdS); 9-chlorohexadecafluoro-3-oxanonane-1-sulfonic acid\n(9Cl-PF3ONS); 4,8-dioxa-3H-perfluorononanoic acid (ADONA);\nNonafluoro-3,6-dioxaheptanoic acid (NFDHA); Perfluorobutanoic acid\n(PFBA); 1H, 1H, 2H, 2HPerfluorodecane sulfonic acid (8:2FTS);\nPerfluoro(2-ethoxyethane)sulfonic acid (PFEESA);\nPerfluoroheptanesulfonic acid (PFHpS); 1H,1H, 2H, 2H-Perfluorohexane\nsulfonic acid (4:2FTS); Perfluoro-3-methoxypropanoic acid (PFMPA);\nPerfluoro-4-methoxybutanoic acid (PFMBA); 1H,1H, 2H, 2H-Perfluorooctane\nsulfonic acid (6:2FTS); Perfluoropentanoic acid (PFPeA);\nPerfluoropentanesulfonic acid (PFPeS).\n  d. The commissioner shall make regulations to list the following\nadditional substances as emerging contaminants; provided however the\ncommissioner may, upon review and recommendation by the drinking water\nquality council pursuant to section eleven hundred thirteen of this\ntitle determine not to include such chemicals as emerging contaminants\nby January first, two thousand twenty-four: 1,2,3-trichloropropane;\nchloromethane (methylchloride); 1,1-dichloroethane; bromomethane (methyl\nbromide); chlorodifluoromethene (HCFC-22); vanadium; molybdenum; cobalt;\nstrontium; chromium-6; N-ethyl perfluorooctanesulfonamidoacetic acid\n(NEtFOSAA); N-methyl perfluorooctanesulfonamidoacetic acid (NMeFOSAA);\nPerfluorot...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1112__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such substance poses or has the potential to pose a\nsignificant hazard to human health when present in drinking water; (ii)\nsuch substance was recently detected in a public water system and has\nthe potential to be present in other public water systems; and (iii) it\nappears to be prejudicial to the interests of the people to delay action\nby preparing and filing regulations. The commissioner shall, however,\npromulgate regulations adding such new emerging contaminant or\nestablishing such notification level within one year of such\ndeclaration. Such declaration shall clearly state where and the date by\nwhich such testing must occur. After the commissioner promulgates\nregulations adding such emerging contaminant, such regulations shall\nsupersede the declaration issued pursuant to this subdivision. Until\nsuch notification levels are posted on the department's website pursuant\nto subdivision six of this section, the commissioner shall post the\nnotification levels established by declaration on such website so that\nthey are easily accessible through a link to the public.\n  8. Whenever one or more emerging contaminants is confirmed to be\npresent in drinking water at concentrations at or above a notification\nlevel established pursuant to this section:\n  a. the covered public water system shall notify the department within\ntwenty-four hours;\n  b. the covered public water system shall notify all owners of real\nproperty served by the covered public water system in a time and manner\nto be prescribed by the department, provided that in no event shall\nnotification occur more than ninety days after the presence of an\nemerging contaminant at concentrations at or above a notification level\nestablished pursuant to this section is confirmed;\n  c. the commissioner may directly notify such owners of real property\nif it is determined that the public's interest would be best served by\nsuch notification, or if the commissioner determines that the covered\npublic wa...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>