<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1114-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1114-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1114-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1114-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1114-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1114-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1114-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1114_B">
        <num>1114-B</num>
        <heading>Service line inventories and mapping</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Service line" means any piping connecting a water main to a\nbuilding inlet.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Gooseneck, pigtail, or connector" means a short section of\npiping, typically not exceeding two feet, which can be bent and used for\nconnections between rigid portions of a service line, as defined in 40\nCFR 141.2.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Galvanized service line" means iron or steel piping that has been\ndipped in zinc to prevent corrosion and rusting.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Covered public water system" means</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a public water system that\nserves at least fifteen service connections used by year-round residents\nor regularly serves at least twenty-five year-round residents; or (ii) a\npublic water system that regularly serves at least twenty-five of the\nsame people, four hours or more per day, for four or more days per week,\nfor twenty-six or more weeks per year.\n  2. Each covered public water system shall submit a service line\ninventory, in a format to be developed by the department, that\nidentifies the location, material composition, and other details of all\nservice lines connected to its distribution system. Each covered public\nwater system shall also submit an inventory summary form, in a format to\nbe developed by the department, summarizing the data identified in the\nservice line inventory. Notwithstanding subdivisions three and four of\nthis section, the development of service line inventories and inventory\nsummary forms shall comply with requirements promulgated by the United\nStates environmental protection agency.\n  3. Each service line shall be listed in service line inventories. Each\ncovered public water system shall include for each service line the\ninformation listed in this subdivision. The covered public water system\nmay mark "unknown" where documented evidence is not currently available:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>street address;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>town;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>zip code;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if known, whether a gooseneck, pigtail, or connector made of lead\nis present;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if known, the material composition of both the public portion and\ncustomer portion of the service line;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if known, whether the public portion or customer portion of the\nservice line was ever made of lead;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the verification method used to determine the material composition\nof both the public portion and customer portion of the service line;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if known, the installation or replacement date of both the public\nportion and customer portion of the service line;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if known, the diameter of both the public portion and customer\nportion of the service line;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if known, whether lead solder is present;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if known, the building type; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if known, whether a point of use or point of entry treatment\nsystem is present.\n  4. Inventory summary forms shall include, but not be limited to, the\nfollowing information about each covered water system:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>water system name and identification number;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contact information for the owner or licensed operator of record\ncompleting the form;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of service lines in the distribution system;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of lead service lines, including the total number\nof lead public service line portions and the total number of lead\ncustomer service line portions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of galvanized service lines requiring replacement\nas defined in 40 CFR 141.84, including the total number of galvanized\npublic service line portions requiring replacement and the total number\nof galvanized customer service line portions requiring replacement;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of non-lead service lines, including the total\nnumber of non-lead public service line portions and the total number of\nnon-lead customer service line portions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of service lines of unknown material, including\nthe total number of unknown public service line portions and the total\nnumber of unknown customer service line portions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of public service line portions identified by\nhistorical records, field inspections, customer identification with\nphoto or other verification, excavation, sequential sampling,\nstatistical analysis/predictive modeling, or other method determined by\nthe covered public water system to accurately identify service line\nmaterials;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of customer service portions identified by\nhistorical records, field inspections, customer identification with\nphoto or other verification, excavation, sequential sampling, and\nstatistical analysis/predictive modeling, or other method determined by\nthe covered public water system to accurately identify service line\nmaterials;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of how the service line inventory will be accessible\nto the public; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a certification verifying the accuracy of the information.\n  5. Each covered public water system shall electronically submit to the\ndepartment an initial service line inventory and an initial inventory\nsummary form no later than October sixteenth, two thousand twenty-four.\nThe department may prescribe data management means and methods for\nelectronic submissions by covered public water systems for uniformity\npurposes.\n  6. Covered public water systems whose inventories contain any service\nlines classified as lead, galvanized requiring replacement as defined in\n40 CFR 141.84, or unknown shall electronically submit updated service\nline inventories and inventory summary forms to the department at least\nannually. Updated service line inventories and inventory summary forms\nshall reflect information gathered during any service line replacements\nor service line material inspections that may have been conducted.\nUpdated inventory summary forms shall additionally include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description detailing the steps being taken to determine the\nmaterial composition of unknown service lines;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of service lines classified as lead, galvanized\nrequiring replacement, or unknown that were replaced over the course of\nthe previous year; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total number of service lines classified as unknown that were\ndetermined to be lead, galvanized requiring replacement, or other\nmaterial over the course of the previous year.\n  7. Each covered public water system which operates its own website\nshall make its most recent service line inventory and inventory summary\nform available to the public on its website.\n  8. No later than one hundred twenty days after receiving initial and\nupdated service line inventories and inventory summary forms, the\ndepartment shall make such inventories and inventory summary forms\navailable to the public through the department's website. Each local\nhealth department shall include a link on its website to the website\nmaintained by the department for hosting service line inventories and\ninventory summary forms.\n  9. No later than October sixteenth, two thousand twenty-six, the\ndepartment shall make the information from the service line inventories\nof covered public water systems serving more than ten thousand people\nand fewer than two million people available to the public on the\ndepartment's website in the form of an interactive map or maps. Such\ninteractive map or maps shall include, for each service line:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>material classification, including the material classification of\nboth the public and customer portions of a service line;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>street address; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1114_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the verification method for the service line classification.\n  10. The department's interactive map or maps shall be searchable by\naddress, and color-coded where applicable to designate material\nclassification. The department's interactive map or maps shall be\nupdated at least annually, in conjunction with the submission of updated\nservice line inventories by covered public water systems. The department\nmay choose not to create an interactive map when a covered public water\nsystem certifies that it maintains and updates its own interactive map,\nand shall include a link to such interactive map on the department's\nwebsite.\n  11. The department shall adopt such rules and regulations as it deems\nnecessary and proper to implement the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>