<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1151"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1151"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1151"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1151/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1151/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1151/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1151/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1151">
        <num>1151</num>
        <heading>Annual water supply statement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1151. Annual water supply statement. Each water works corporation\nshall prepare and provide an annual water supply statement to the\ncustomers it serves. Such statement shall contain such information as is\nrequired in this title as well as any additional information required by\nthe commissioner. Additionally, the statement shall provide a section\nwhich explains, in plain language, the information required in the\nstatement. The department may prepare or prescribe a format or model\nupon which all such statements shall be produced. The annual water\nsupply statement shall include, but not be limited to, the following\nitems of information:\n  1. A brief description on the source or sources of the water supply\nand the general qualitative and quantitative condition of the water\nsource.\n  2. The population served.\n  3. For water works corporations that calculate water use of all\ncustomers with meters, an accounting of the total annual amount of water\nwithdrawn, delivered, and lost from the system.\n  4. The analytical testing results for those constituents required to\nbe tested for under part five of the state sanitary code or as required\nby appropriate local health units, except for microbiological results,\nfor each source of water.\n  Where more than one analysis per year is conducted on a specific\nconstituent, the water works corporation shall list the range of results\nfrom highest to lowest during the reporting period. The applicable state\nguideline, standard, or MCL for each constituent present shall be listed\nand any instance where a state guideline, standard, or MCL is violated\nshall be noted.\n  For microbiological analyses as required by part five of the state\nsanitary code, the water works corporation shall indicate any instance\nwhere the water supply violated the MCL. The date or dates of violation,\nthe location where the violation occurred, and the response of the water\nworks corporation shall be listed.\n  5. A brief description of the types of treatment that the water\nreceives before entering the distribution system.\n  6. Any water sources restricted, removed from service, or otherwise\nlimited in their use and any actions taken to secure new supplies or\nreplace lost capacity. For the purposes of this subdivision, "water\nsources" shall include surface water sources, such as, but not limited\nto, lakes, ponds, rivers, streams, reservoirs and impoundments and for\ngroundwater sources, supply wells. For the purposes of this subdivision,\n"water sources" shall not include water mains or other types of\nconveyance infrastructure.\n  7. Information on water conservation measures customers can implement\nsuch as, but not limited to, retrofitting plumbing fixtures, altering\nirrigation timing, using irrigation sensors, leak detection, proper use\nof water-conserving appliances, daily conscientious use of water, and\nthe estimated savings in water and energy or money from the use of such\nmeasures.\n  8. A description of the risks associated with exposure to\ncryptosporidium parvum or giardia lamblia for specific at-risk\npopulations and the general public and measures that at-risk populations\ncan take to protect themselves according to recommendations by the\ndepartment or other governmental public health or environmental\nagencies. In addition, for water works corporations that test for\ncryptosporidium parvum or giardia lamblia, a summary of the following:\nsampling sites; number of tests per year; testing results and actions\ntaken in response to those results.\n  9. General information regarding lead pipes reasonably known to be\nlocated within the water system, as that term is defined in subdivision\ntwenty-six of section two of the public service law.\n  The commissioner may add such additional requirements as he determines\nto be appropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>