<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1160"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1160"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1160"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1160">
        <num>1160</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is necessary for the objectives and goals of the state sanitary\ncode or the federal safe drinking water act to assure safe public\ndrinking water;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>represents a reasonable effort to develop a viable water supply\nthat can consistently meet drinking water standards;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>takes into consideration the water resources management strategy\npursuant to title twenty-nine of article fifteen of the environmental\nconservation law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is a project for which financial assistance is available from the\nfund; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conforms with applicable state rules and regulations.\n  5. "Financial assistance to a recipient" has the same meaning as set\nforth in subdivision four of section twelve hundred eighty-five-m of the\npublic authorities law.\n  6. "Financing agreement" means an agreement between the corporation\nand one or more recipients meeting the requirements of section eleven\nhundred sixty-three of this title.\n  7. "Fund" means the drinking water revolving fund established under\nsection twelve hundred eighty-five-m of the public authorities law.\n  8. "Intended use plan" means a plan identifying the intended uses of\nthe amounts available in the fund, including but not limited to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a list of those projects for construction of water supply\nfacilities on the priority list developed pursuant to section eleven\nhundred sixty-one of this title;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the short and long term goals and objectives of\nthe fund;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>information on the activities to be supported, including a\ndescription of project categories, terms of financial assistance and\ncommunities served; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the criteria and method established for the distribution of\nfinancial assistance from the fund.\n  9. "Municipality" means any county, city, town, village, district\ncorporation, county or town improvement district, school district,\nIndian nation or tribe recognized by the state or the United States with\na reservation wholly or partly within the boundaries of New York state,\nany public benefit corporation or public authority established pursuant\nto the laws of New York or any agency of New York state which is\nempowered to construct and operate an eligible project, or any two or\nmore of the foregoing which are acting jointly in connection with an\neligible project.\n  10. "Recipient" means any municipality, public utility, or person,\nincluding any individual, firm, partnership, association, not-for-profit\ncorporation or other corporation organized and existing under the laws\nof the state or any other state which is empowered to construct and\noperate an eligible project, or any two or more of the foregoing which\nare acting jointly in connection with an eligible project.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>