<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1311"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1311">
        <num>1311</num>
        <heading>Hand washing facilities at certain public establishments featuring animals</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1311. Hand washing facilities at certain public establishments\nfeaturing animals. 1. All public establishments including, but not\nlimited to, carnivals, fairs and amusement parks, as such terms are\ndefined in section eight hundred seventy-c of the labor law, farms, and\nfarmers' markets, as such term is defined in section two hundred sixty\nof the agriculture and markets law, which feature displays of live\nanimals that patrons may reasonably be expected to come into physical\ncontact with for the purpose of touching, holding or petting shall\nprovide hand washing or hand cleansing facilities for such patrons. Hand\nwashing or hand cleansing facilities may be temporary or permanent\nfixtures and shall include one or more of the following: soap and\nrunning water; anti-bacterial fluids, foams or gels; or anti-bacterial\nor antiseptic wipes or towels.\n  2. Signs shall be conspicuously posted and shall state in a clear and\nlegible typeface, the following: "Animals may carry germs and bacteria\nthat can cause disease to people. It is strongly recommended that\npersons wash or cleanse their hands after touching, holding or petting\nthe animals." Such signs shall also indicate where the hand washing or\nhand cleansing facility is located.\n  3. The commissioner may make rules guarding against the spread of\nbacteria and viruses at public establishments that feature animals as\nprovided in subdivision one of this section, to persons employed at or\nto patrons of such establishments where such establishments are located\noutside the city of New York, and where such establishments are located\nwithin the city of New York, the commissioner of public health of the\ncity of New York may make and enforce such rules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>