<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1360"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1360"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1360"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1360/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1360/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1360/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1360/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1360">
        <num>1360</num>
        <heading>Location and disposition of radioactive gold jewelry</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1360. Location and disposition of radioactive gold jewelry.  1.\nThe commissioner is hereby authorized and directed to establish a\nprogram, which shall include the use of such investigations and\npersonnel as may be necessary, to identify gold jewelry which has been\ncontaminated by radioactive material which is, or may be, possessed by\nresidents of this state. Such program shall be publicized by the\ncommissioner, as may be practicable, to encourage residents to have such\nsuspected radioactive gold jewelry tested free of charge, except that\njewelers, manufacturers or distributors of gold jewelry may be charged a\nreasonable fee for the cost of such tests, as determined by the\ncommissioner.\n  2. Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of law, in any case where\nsuch gold jewelry is so identified as radioactive, the commissioner is\nhereby authorized and empowered to purchase from a resident on behalf of\nthe state such radioactive gold jewelry presented by such resident at\nthe commercial value of the gold content of the radioactive gold\njewelry, upon such terms and conditions as the commissioner deems\nnecessary and proper, and within the amount appropriated by the\nlegislature for this purpose.\n  3. Any such gold jewelry, purchased pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection, shall be held decontaminated or disposed of in such a manner as\nshall be determined necessary and proper by the commissioner which\ndisposition, however, may include, but not be limited to, the\ndestruction thereof.\n  4. Any person, firm, association or corporation who learns that they\npossess radioactive gold jewelry shall immediately notify the\ncommissioner or his designee of the existence of such radioactive gold\njewelry.\n  * NB Expired July 21, 1982\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>