<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1375"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1375"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1375"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1375/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1375/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1375/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1375/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1375">
        <num>1375</num>
        <heading>Enforcement agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1375. Enforcement agencies.  1. The commissioner's designee having\njurisdiction, county and city commissioners of health and local housing\ncode enforcement agencies designated by the commissioner's designee\nhaving jurisdiction or county or city commissioner of health shall have\nthe same authority, powers and duties within their respective\njurisdictions as has the commissioner under the provisions of this\ntitle.\n  2. The commissioner or his representative and an official or agency\nspecified in subdivision one of this section may request and shall\nreceive from all public officers, departments and agencies of the state\nand its political subdivisions such cooperation and assistance as may be\nnecessary or proper in the enforcement of the provisions of this title.\n  3. Nothing contained in this title shall be construed to alter or\nabridge any duties and powers now or hereafter existing in the\ncommissioner, county boards of health, city and county commissioners of\nhealth, the New York City department of housing preservation and\ndevelopment and the department of health, local boards of health or\nother public agencies or public officials, or any private party.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>