<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1528"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1528"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1528"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1528">
        <num>1528</num>
        <heading>County mosquito control commission; estimate and approval of annual requirements; power and duty of commissioner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1528. County mosquito control commission; estimate and approval of\nannual requirements; power and duty of commissioner.  1. Each county\nmosquito control commission shall, on or before the first day of October\nin each year, file with the commissioner and with the board of\nsupervisors of its county, a detailed estimate of the moneys required\nfor the ensuing year and a plan of the work to be done and the methods\nto be employed, together with a general description of such lands.\n  2. The board of supervisors shall have power to approve, modify or\nalter such estimates, plans and methods, and it shall be the duty of the\nboard of supervisors in the county in which a commission is appointed at\nits annual or other meeting held in the month of October of each year\nand on receipt of the said report from the county commission, to cause\nto be included in the annual budget of such county for the succeeding\nyear the amount of money included in such estimate of moneys, as\napproved, modified or altered by it for the use and purposes of the\nmosquito control commission, in its said county.\n  3. Provided, however, that any district which at the time when this\nsection, as hereby amended, take effect, shall have been legally\nestablished under chapter two hundred forty-six of the laws of nineteen\nhundred sixteen, as amended by chapter thirteen of the laws of nineteen\nhundred twenty-six, shall be exempted from the provisions of this\nchapter and from taxation under it.\n  4. The county treasurer of such county shall pay from time to time to\nthe mosquito control commission, on the requisition of such commission,\nduly signed and approved by the president and secretary thereof such\nsums as may be needed within the appropriation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>