<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1603"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1603"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1603"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1603/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1603/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1603/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1603/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1603">
        <num>1603</num>
        <heading>Creation of pesticide control board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1603. Creation of pesticide control board.  1. There is hereby\ncreated within the department of health a pesticide control board. Such\nboard shall have seven voting members, who shall be the commissioners of\nagriculture and markets, commerce, conservation, education and health,\nthe industrial commissioner and the commissioner of transportation. In\naddition, as advisory members, there shall be the dean of the New York\nstate college of agriculture at Cornell university, the dean of the New\nYork state college of forestry at Syracuse university, the dean of the\nNew York state veterinary college, the director of the New York state\nagricultural experiment station at Geneva, and, to be appointed by the\ngovernor, six members at least one of whom shall be the dean of a state\nuniversity college of medicine, one an ecologist, one a representative\nof the pesticide manufacturing industry, one a representative of custom\napplicators of pesticides and one a representative of organized\nconservationists.\n  2. Advisory members appointed by the governor shall serve for terms of\nthree years, such terms to commence on July first and to expire on June\nthirtieth; provided, however, that of the advisory members first\nappointed, two shall be appointed for a one year term expiring on June\nthirtieth, nineteen hundred sixty-five, and two shall be appointed for a\ntwo year term expiring on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred sixty-six.\nEach such advisory member shall hold office until his successor shall\nhave been appointed and qualified.\n  3. Each voting member and each ex-officio advisory member of such\nboard may, by official order filed in the office of the board, designate\na deputy or other representative in his department to perform his duties\nunder this article, except as provided in subdivision one of section\nsixteen hundred six of this article.\n  4. The members of the board or their respective designees shall\nreceive no additional compensation for their services as members of the\nboard, but shall be allowed their actual and necessary expenses incurred\nin the performance of their duties under this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>