<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-18*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-18*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="18*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-18*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-18*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-18*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-18*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_18*2">
        <num>18*2</num>
        <heading>Registration and notification of boards of directors or trustees of certain voluntary, not-for-profit facilities or corporations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 18. Registration and notification of boards of directors or\ntrustees of certain voluntary, not-for-profit facilities or\ncorporations. 1.  Notwithstanding any other law, rule or regulation, the\nexecutive director, chairperson or president of a voluntary,\nnot-for-profit corporation or facility which is subject to the\njurisdiction of the department shall furnish annually to the\ncommissioner a list of the names and addresses of the current members of\nthe board of directors or trustees of such facility or corporation.\nFailure to furnish such annual list shall remove such facility from\nconsideration for recertification.\n  2. In the event that such facility or corporation is found to be in\nviolation of the provisions of this chapter or of rules and regulations\npromulgated pursuant to this chapter which could result in the\nrevocation, cancellation, limitation or suspension of the operating\ncertificate of such facility and if notice of such violation is provided\nto the facility pursuant to such regulations, a copy of such notice\nshall be provided to each of the current members of the board of\ndirectors or trustees of such facility or corporation by the\ncommissioner.\n  3. The commissioner is authorized to promulgate such rules and\nregulations as are necessary to implement the provisions of this\nsection.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 18's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>