<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2003"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2003"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2003"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2003">
        <num>2003</num>
        <heading>Duties of department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2003. Duties of department.  1. Alzheimer's disease reports and data\nshall be maintained by the department in a manner suitable for research\npurposes, and shall be made available to persons as set forth in\nsubdivision two of this section.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, all information\ncollected pursuant to this article shall be confidential insofar as the\nidentity of the individual patient is concerned and shall be used solely\nfor the purposes as provided in this article. Access to the information\nshall be limited to the authorized employees of the department and\npersons with a valid scientific interest and qualifications, as defined\nby the commissioner, who are engaged in demographic, epidemiological or\nother similar studies related to health, and who agree, in writing, to\nmaintain confidentiality as established by the commissioner.\n  3. The department shall maintain an accurate record of all persons who\nare given access to the information contained in the Alzheimer's disease\nreports. The record shall include the name of the person authorizing\naccess, the name, title and organizational affiliation of persons given\naccess, dates of access, and the specific purpose for which information\nis to be used. The record of access shall be open to public inspection\nduring normal operating hours of the department.\n  4. Any person who, in violation of a written agreement to maintain\nconfidentiality, discloses any information provided pursuant to this\nsection, or who uses information provided pursuant to this section in a\nmanner other than that prescribed by the commissioner, may be denied\nfurther access to any confidential information maintained by the\ndepartment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>