<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2018"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2018"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-10-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2018"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2018/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2018/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2018/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2018/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2018">
        <num>2018</num>
        <heading>Duties of the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2018. Duties of the department. 1. FTD disorders reports and data\nshall be maintained by the department in a manner suitable for research\npurposes, and shall be made available to persons as set forth in section\ntwo thousand seventeen of this article.\n  2. All information collected under this article shall be confidential\ninsofar as the identity of individual patients is concerned and shall be\nsolely for the purposes as provided in this article. Access to such\ninformation shall be limited to authorized employees of the department\nas well as persons and organizations specified in section two thousand\nseventeen of this article with valid scientific interest and\nqualifications, as determined by the commissioner, who are engaged in\ndemographic, epidemiological, or other similar studies related to public\nhealth.\n  3. The department shall maintain an accurate record of all persons who\nare given access to the information contained in the frontotemporal\ndegeneration registry. Such record shall include the name of the person\nauthorizing access, the name, title and organizational affiliation of\npersons given access, dates of access, and the specific purposes for\nwhich information is to be used.\n  4. Any person who, in violation of a written agreement to maintain\nconfidentiality, discloses any information provided under this section,\nor who uses information provided under this section in a manner other\nthan that prescribed by the commissioner, may be denied further access\nto any confidential information maintained by the department.\n  * NB Effective January 14, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>