<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2164"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2164"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-09-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2164"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2164/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2164/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2164/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2164/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2164">
        <num>2164</num>
        <heading>Definitions; immunization against poliomyelitis, mumps, measles, diphtheria, rubella, varicella, Haemophilus influenzae type b (Hib), per...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2164__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No principal, teacher, owner or person in charge of a school\nshall permit any child to be admitted to such school, or to attend such\nschool, in excess of fourteen days, without the certificate provided for\nin subdivision five of this section or some other acceptable evidence of\nthe child's immunization against poliomyelitis, mumps, measles,\ndiphtheria, rubella, varicella, hepatitis B, pertussis, tetanus, and,\nwhere applicable, Haemophilus influenzae type b (Hib), meningococcal\ndisease, and pneumococcal disease; provided, however, such fourteen day\nperiod may be extended to not more than thirty days for an individual\nstudent by the appropriate principal, teacher, owner or other person in\ncharge where such student is transferring from out-of-state or from\nanother country and can show a good faith effort to get the necessary\ncertification or other evidence of immunization.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2164__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A parent, a guardian or any other person in parental relationship\nto a child denied school entrance or attendance may appeal by petition\nto the commissioner of education in accordance with the provisions of\nsection three hundred ten of the education law.\n  8. If any physician licensed to practice medicine in this state\ncertifies that such immunization may be detrimental to a child's health,\nthe requirements of this section shall be inapplicable until such\nimmunization is found no longer to be detrimental to the child's health.\n  8-a. Whenever a child has been refused admission to, or continued\nattendance at, a school as provided for in subdivision seven of this\nsection because there exists no certificate provided for in subdivision\nfive of this section or other acceptable evidence of the child's\nimmunization against poliomyelitis, mumps, measles, diphtheria, rubella,\nvaricella, hepatitis B, pertussis, tetanus, and, where applicable,\nHaemophilus influenzae type b (Hib), meningococcal disease, and\npneumococcal disease, the principal, teacher, owner or person in charge\nof the school shall:\n  a. forward a report of such exclusion and the name and address of such\nchild to the local health authority and to the person in parental\nrelation to the child together with a notification of the responsibility\nof such person under subdivision two of this section and a form of\nconsent as prescribed by regulation of the commissioner, and\n  b. provide, with the cooperation of the appropriate local health\nauthority, for a time and place at which an immunizing agent or agents\nshall be administered, as required by subdivision two of this section,\nto a child for whom a consent has been obtained. Upon failure of a local\nhealth authority to cooperate in arranging for a time and place at which\nan immunizing agent or agents shall be administered as required by\nsubdivision two of this section, the commissioner shall arrange for such\nadministration and may recover t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>