<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2171"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2171"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2171"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2171/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2171/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2171/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2171/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2171">
        <num>2171</num>
        <heading>Required offering of hepatitis C screening testing</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the individual is being treated for a life threatening emergency;\nor\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the individual has previously been offered or has been the subject\nof a hepatitis C screening test (except that a test shall be offered if\notherwise indicated); or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the individual lacks capacity to consent to a hepatitis C\nscreening test.\n  2. If an individual accepts the offer of a hepatitis C screening test\nand the screening test is reactive, an HCV RNA test must be performed,\non the same specimen or a second specimen collected at the same time as\nthe initial HCV screening test specimen, to confirm diagnosis of current\ninfection. The health care provider shall either offer all persons with\na detectable HCV RNA test follow-up HCV health care and treatment or\nrefer the individual to a health care provider who can provide follow-up\nHCV health care and treatment.\n  3. The offering of hepatitis C screening testing under this section\nshall be culturally and linguistically appropriate in accordance with\nrules and regulations promulgated by the commissioner.\n  4. This section shall not affect the scope of practice of any health\ncare practitioner or diminish any authority or legal or professional\nobligation of any health care practitioner to offer a hepatitis C\nscreening test or hepatitis C diagnostic test or to provide services or\ncare for the subject of a hepatitis C screening test or hepatitis C\ndiagnostic test.\n  5. Definitions. As used in this section, the following terms shall\nhave the following meanings:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Hepatitis C diagnostic test" shall mean any laboratory test or\ntests that detect the presence of hepatitis C virus in the blood and\nprovides confirmation of whether the individual has a hepatitis C virus\ninfection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Hepatitis C screening test" shall mean any laboratory screening\ntest or tests that detect the presence of hepatitis C virus antibodies\nin the blood.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Primary care" means the medical fields of family medicine,\ngeneral pediatrics, primary care, internal medicine, primary care\nobstetrics, or primary care gynecology, without regard to board\ncertification.\n  * NB Repealed January 1, 2030\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>