<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2183"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2183"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2183"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2183/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2183/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2183/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2183/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2183">
        <num>2183</num>
        <heading>Immunity passports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2183. Immunity passports. 1. Any covered entity that requires proof\nof COVID-19 immunization shall permit the use of physical immunity\npassports. No covered entity may require digital, electronic, or\nsmartphone-based proof of immunity. Notwithstanding this section, anyone\nrequiring an immunization passport shall accept a valid COVID-19\nVaccination Record Card allocated to COVID-19 vaccine providers by the\nCenters for Disease Control and Prevention for that purpose. The\nprovisions of this section shall apply to valid COVID-19 Vaccination\nRecord Cards allocated to COVID-19 vaccine providers by the Centers for\nDisease Control and Prevention.\n  2. Nothing in this section requires a covered entity to require proof\nof COVID-19 immunity or to independently verify the information\ncontained in an immunity passport.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit a covered\nentity's obligations under the Americans with Disabilities Act, article\nfifteen of the executive law, the civil rights law, or any other\nfederal, state, or local anti-discrimination law.\n  4. Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the practices\nof a health care provider, as defined in section eighteen of this\nchapter, a hospital or nursing home as defined in article twenty-eight\nof this chapter, a health practitioner as defined in section twenty-one\nhundred sixty-four of this chapter, a facility, as defined in section\n33.13 of the mental hygiene law, or a correctional health service\ngoverned by the department of corrections and community supervision, the\nrules of the board of correction in the city of New York, or a county\nboard of correction, with respect to records concerning their patients'\nvaccinations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>