<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2194"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2194"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2194"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2194/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2194/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2194/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2194/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2194">
        <num>2194</num>
        <heading>Employee immunization</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2194. Employee immunization. 1. Every long-term care facility shall\nnotify every employee of the immunization requirements of this article\nand request that the employee agree to be immunized against influenza\nvirus and pneumococcal disease.\n  2. The long-term care facility shall require documentation of annual\nimmunization against influenza virus and immunization against\npneumococcal disease for each employee. Upon finding that an employee is\nlacking such immunization or the long-term care facility or individual\nis unable to provide documentation that the individual has received the\nappropriate immunization, the long-term care facility must provide or\narrange for immunization. Immunization and the documentation thereof\nshall take place no later than November thirtieth of each year.\n  3. An individual who is newly employed as an employee after November\nthirtieth but before April first shall have his or her status for\ninfluenza and pneumococcal immunization determined by the facility, and\nif found to be deficient, the facility shall provide or arrange for the\nnecessary immunization.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>