<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2200"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2200">
        <num>2200</num>
        <heading>Tuberculosis; definitions and explanation of terms</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nState residence. Under the conditions hereinafter specified, any person\nwho has resided in the state of New York continuously for at least one\nyear immediately preceding the date of admission to a hospital for the\ncare and treatment of tuberculosis shall be deemed to have state\nresidence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>State residence so acquired shall continue until such person shall\nhave removed from the state and remained therefrom for one year;\nprovided, however, that no person shall lose state residence by absence\nfrom the state while serving in the armed forces of the United States or\nin the United States merchant marine, or while attached to and serving\nwith the armed forces of the United States and, provided, further, that\nno member of the family of any such person shall lose state residence by\nabsence from the state while living with or near such person during the\nperiod of such service and on account thereof.\n  2. Local residence. Under the conditions hereinafter specified, any\nperson with state residence as herein defined who has also resided\nwithin a county of the state or in the city of New York continuously for\nat least six months preceding the date of admission to a hospital for\nthe care and treatment of tuberculosis shall be deemed to have local\nresidence in such county or in the city of New York, as the case may be.\n  3. Qualification on residence. The continuous residence required to\nacquire either state residence or local residence shall not include any\nperiod during which the person was</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a patient in a hospital, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nan incarcerated individual of any public institution, incorporated\nprivate institution, or private tuberculosis home, cottage or hospital,\nor</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>residing on any military reservation. If, however, the periods of\nresidence immediately prior and subsequent to the periods specified in\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall together equal the required period of residence,\nsuch person shall be deemed to have the required continuous residence.\n  4. State charge. State charge shall mean any person suffering from\ntuberculosis or suspected of having tuberculosis and in need of\ntuberculosis hospital care and treatment therefor who is:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>without state residence;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>with state residence but without local residence;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2200__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an Indian or member of his family residing upon any Indian\nreservation in the state.\n  5. Local charge. Local charge shall mean any person suffering from\ntuberculosis or suspected of having tuberculosis and in need of\ntuberculosis hospital care and treatment therefor who has acquired local\nresidence, as defined in this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>