<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2204"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2204">
        <num>2204</num>
        <heading>Tuberculosis; removal of patients to another state or country; costs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2204. Tuberculosis; removal of patients to another state or country;\ncosts.  1. When any state charge, as defined in this article, who has\nnot acquired state residence has settlement or residence or otherwise\nbelongs to or in any other state or country, has legally responsible\nrelatives or friends willing to undertake the obligations to support him\nor to aid in supporting him in such other state or country, the\ndepartment may furnish him with transportation to such state or country,\nprovided, in the judgment of the commissioner the interest of the state\nand the welfare of such person will be promoted thereby.\n  2. The commissioner shall designate or employ nurses or attendants to\naccompany such persons being removed out of the state unless it appears\nthat such persons are in suitable condition to travel alone with safety.\n  3. The expense of such removal shall be paid from the state treasury\non the audit and warrant of the comptroller pursuant to a verified\naccount submitted by the department, and the commissioner shall\nthereupon seek reimbursement for such expense from the state or country\nof residence.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>