<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2332"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2332"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2332"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2332/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2332/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2332/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2332/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2332">
        <num>2332</num>
        <heading>Houses of prostitution; abatement; release of property on filing bond</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2332. Houses of prostitution; abatement; release of property on\nfiling bond.  1. If the owner of the premises in which a nuisance, as\ndefined in this article, has been maintained appears and pays all costs\nof the proceeding and files a bond with sureties to be approved by the\ncourt in the full value of the property, to be ascertained by the court,\nor in vacation by the judge thereof, conditioned that he will\nimmediately abate said nuisance and prevent the same from being\nestablished, or kept therein within a period of one year thereafter, the\ncourt, or in vacation the judge, if satisfied of his good faith, may\norder the premises, closed or sought to be closed under the order of\nabatement, delivered to said owner, and said order of abatement\ncancelled so far as the same may relate to said real property.\n  2. The release of the property under the provisions of this section\nshall not release it from the injunction herein provided against the\nproperty nor any of the defendants nor from any judgment, lien, or\nliability to which it may be subject by law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>