<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-11-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2404-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2404_A">
        <num>2404-A</num>
        <heading>Prostate cancer; duty to inform</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2404_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the symptoms and risk factors for prostate cancer;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2404_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the available methods for the detection and diagnosis of prostate\ncancer, including information on the relative accuracy of the available\ndetection and diagnostic techniques;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2404_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the availability of insurance coverage for diagnostic screening\nfor prostate cancer without cost sharing pursuant to subparagraph (B) of\nparagraph eleven-a of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2404_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three thousand two\nhundred sixteen, subparagraph (B) of paragraph eleven-a of subsection\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2404_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section three thousand two hundred twenty-one and paragraph two\nof subsection (z-1) of section four thousand three hundred three of the\ninsurance law; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2404_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the alternative medically viable methods of treating prostate\ncancer, including but not limited to hormonal, radiological,\nchemotherapeutic or surgical treatments, or combinations thereof. The\nsummary shall contain information on prostate post-treatment risks and\nother pertinent information to aid a person in deciding a course of\ntreatment. The summary shall be updated as is necessary.\n  2. The summary shall be provided to any health care provider or\npractitioner providing medical treatment to adult men without charge or\nfee for distribution in accordance with subdivision three of this\nsection.\n  3. The standardized written summary provided for by subdivision one of\nthis section may be provided by a health care provider to each person\nunder his or her care who is or may be at risk for prostate cancer or\nwho has been diagnosed to be afflicted with prostate cancer upon said\ndiagnosis, or as soon thereafter as practicable.\n  4. Nothing in this section shall be construed to create a cause of\naction for lack of informed consent in any instance in which such cause\nof action would be limited by section twenty-eight hundred five-d of\nthis chapter.\n  5. The commissioner shall have the written summary, required by this\nsection, completed and prepared for distribution on or before January\nfirst, nineteen hundred ninety-eight.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>