<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2404-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2404-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2404_C">
        <num>2404-C</num>
        <heading>Breast cancer; duty of providers of mammography services to notify and inform</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2404-c. Breast cancer; duty of providers of mammography services to\nnotify and inform. Every provider of mammography services shall, if a\npatient's mammogram demonstrates dense breast tissue, provide\nnotification to such patient that shall include, but not be limited to,\nthe following information, in any summary of the mammography report\nsent, pursuant to the federal mammography quality standards act, to the\npatient:\n  Your mammogram shows that your breast tissue is dense. Dense breast\ntissue is very common and is not abnormal. However, dense breast tissue\ncan make it harder to find cancer on a mammogram and may also be\nassociated with an increased risk of breast cancer.\n  This information about the result of your mammogram is given to you to\nraise your awareness. Use this information to talk to your doctor about\nyour own risks for breast cancer. At that time, ask your doctor if more\nscreening tests might be useful, based on your risk. A report of your\nresults was sent to your physician.\n  For the purposes of this section dense breast tissue shall mean\nheterogeneously dense or extremely dense tissue as defined in nationally\nrecognized guidelines or systems for breast imaging reporting of\nmammography screening, including, but not limited to, the breast imaging\nreporting and data system of the American College of Radiology, and any\nequivalent new terms, as such guidelines or systems are updated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>