<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2409-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2409-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2409-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2409-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2409-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2409-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2409-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2409_A">
        <num>2409-A</num>
        <heading>Advisory council</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2409_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make recommendations to the\ndepartment regarding the promotion and implementation of programs under\nsections twenty-four hundred six and twenty-four hundred nine of this\ntitle; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2409_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>prior to the department providing grants from the New\nYork State prostate and testicular cancer research and education fund,\ncreated pursuant to section ninety-five-e of the state finance law,\nadvise the department on various components of the department's\nsolicitation to distribute such funds, including but not limited to, the\npotential uses of the funds, the entities that may be eligible to apply\nfor the funds, the recommended contract deliverables for entities\nreceiving the funds, the recommended geographic distribution of the\nfunds, and the recommended award amounts.\n  3. The commissioner shall appoint twenty-one voting members, which\nshall include representation of health care professionals, consumers,\npatients, one voting member who shall be a person who has or has had\nprostate or testicular cancer, one voting member who shall be a person\nwho has or has had breast, cervical or ovarian cancer and other\nappropriate interests reflective of the diversity of the state, with\nexpertise in breast, cervical, prostate, testicular and/or ovarian\ncancer. The commissioner shall appoint one member as a chairperson. The\nmembers of the council shall receive no compensation for their services,\nbut shall be allowed their actual and necessary expenses incurred in\nperformance of their duties.\n  4. A majority of the appointed voting membership of the board shall\nconstitute quorum.\n  5. The advisory council shall meet at least twice a year, at the\nrequest of the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>