<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-241*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-241*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="241*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-241*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-241*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-241*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-241*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_241*2">
        <num>241*2</num>
        <heading>Office of health equity created</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 241. Office of health equity created. There is hereby created an\noffice of health equity within the state department of health. Such\noffice shall:\n  1. Work collaboratively with other state agencies and affected\nstakeholders, including providers and representatives of underserved\npopulations, in order to set priorities, collect and disseminate data,\nand align resources within the department and across other state\nagencies. The office shall also conduct health promotion and educational\noutreach, as well as develop and implement interventions aimed at\nachieving health equity among underserved populations by implementing\nstrategies to address the varying complex causes of health disparities,\nincluding the economic, physical, and social environments.\n  2. Integrate and coordinate selected state health care grant and loan\nprograms established specifically for promoting health equity in New\nYork state. As part of this function, the office shall develop a\ncoordinated application process for use by providers, municipalities and\nothers in seeking funds and/or technical assistance on pertinent\nprograms and services targeted to address health equity among\nunderserved populations.\n  3. Apply for grants, and accept gifts from private and public sources\nfor research to improve and enhance health equity. The office shall also\npromote health equity research in universities and colleges.\n  4. Together with the health equity council, serve as liaison and\nadvocate for the department on health equity matters. This function\nshall include the provision of staff support to the health equity\ncouncil and the establishment of appropriate program linkages with\nrelated federal, state, and local agencies and programs such as the\noffice of health equity of the public health service, the agricultural\nextension service and migrant health services.\n  5. Assist medical schools and state agencies to develop comprehensive\nprograms to improve the diversity of health personnel workforce by\npromoting health equity clinical training and curriculum improvement,\nand disseminating health career information to high school and college\nstudents.\n  6. Promote community strategic planning to address the complex causes\nof health disparities, including the social determinants of health and\nhealth care delivery systems and networks, in order to improve health\nequity. Strategic network planning and development may include such\nconsiderations as healthful foods, quality housing, economic\nopportunity, social relationships, transportation, and education, as\nwell as health care systems, including associated personnel, capital\nfacilities, reimbursement, primary care, long-term care, acute care,\nrehabilitative, preventive, and related services on the health\ncontinuum.\n  7. Review the impact of programs, regulations, and policies on health\nequity.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 241's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>