<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2411"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2411"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2411"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2411/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2411/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2411/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2411/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2411">
        <num>2411</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the board</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Survey state agencies, boards, programs and other state\ngovernmental entities to assess what, if any, relevant data has been or\nis being collected which may be of use to researchers engaged in breast\ncancer research;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Consistent with the survey conducted pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, compile a list of data collected by state agencies\nwhich may be of assistance to researchers engaged in breast cancer\nresearch as established in section twenty-four hundred twelve of this\ntitle;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Consult with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the\nNational Institutes of Health, the Federal Agency For Health Care Policy\nand Research, the National Academy of Sciences and other organizations\nor entities which may be involved in cancer research to solicit both\ninformation regarding breast cancer research projects that are currently\nbeing conducted and recommendations for future research projects;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Review requests made to the commissioner for access to information\npursuant to paragraph b of subdivision one of section 33-1203 and\nparagraph c of subdivision two of section 33-1205 of the environmental\nconservation law for use in human health related research projects. Such\ndata shall only be provided to researchers engaged in human health\nrelated research. The request made by such researchers shall include a\ncopy of the research proposal or the research protocol approved by their\ninstitution and copies of their institution's Institutional Review Board\n(IRB) or equivalent review board approval of such proposal or protocol.\nIn the case of research conducted outside the auspices of an institution\nby a researcher previously published in a peer-reviewed scientific\njournal, the board shall request copies of the research proposal and\nshall deny access to the site-specific and nine-digit zip code pesticide\ndata if the board determines that such proposal does not follow accepted\nscientific practice for the design of a research project. The board\nshall establish guidelines to restrict the dissemination by researchers\nof the name, address or other information that would otherwise identify\na commercial applicator or private applicator or any person who receives\nthe services of a commercial applicator;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Solicit, receive, and review applications from public and private\nagencies and organizations and qualified research institutions for\ngrants from the breast cancer research and education fund, created\npursuant to section ninety-seven-yy of the state finance law, to conduct\nresearch or educational programs which focus on the causes, prevention,\nscreening, treatment and cure of breast cancer and may include, but are\nnot limited to mapping of breast cancer, and basic, behavioral,\nclinical, demographic, environmental, epidemiologic and psychosocial\nresearch. The board shall make recommendations to the commissioner, and\nthe commissioner shall, in his or her discretion, grant approval of\napplications for grants from those applications recommended by the\nboard. The board shall consult with the Centers for Disease Control and\nPrevention, the National Institutes of Health, the Federal Agency For\nHealth Care Policy and Research, the National Academy of Sciences,\nbreast cancer advocacy groups, and other organizations or entities which\nmay be involved in breast cancer research to solicit both information\nregarding breast cancer research projects that are currently being\nconducted and recommendations for future research projects. As used in\nthis section, "qualified research institution" may include academic\nmedical institutions, state or local government agencies, public or\nprivate organizations within this state, and any other institution\napproved by the department, which is conducting a breast cancer research\nproject or educational program. If a board member submits an application\nfor a grant from the breast cancer research and education fund, he or\nshe shall be prohibited from reviewing and making a recommendation on\nthe application;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Consider, based on evolving scientific evidence, whether a\ncorrelation exists between pesticide use and pesticide exposure. As part\nof such consideration the board shall make recommendations as to\nmethodologies which may be utilized to establish such correlation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After two years of implementation of pesticide reporting pursuant\nto section 33-1205 of the environmental conservation law, the board\nshall compare the percentage of agricultural crop production general use\npesticides being reported to the total amount of such pesticides being\nused in this state as estimated by Cornell University, Cornell\nCooperative Extension, the department of environmental conservation, and\nthe Environmental Protection Agency;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Meet at least six times in the first year, at the request of the\nchair and at any other time as the chair deems necessary. The board\nshall meet at least two times a year and as needed thereafter. Provided,\nhowever, that at least one such meeting a year shall be a public\nhearing, at which the general public may question and present\ninformation and comments to the board with respect to the operation of\nthe health research science board, the breast cancer research and\neducation fund, and pesticide reporting established pursuant to sections\n33-1205 and 33-1207 of the environmental conservation law. At such\nhearing, the commissioner of the department of environmental\nconservation or his or her designee shall make a report to the board\nwith respect to the efficiency and utility of pesticide reporting\nestablished pursuant to sections 33-1205 and 33-1207 of the\nenvironmental conservation law. Should the existing bylaws be amended by\nthe board, any such amendments shall be consistent with the revisions of\nthis paragraph;\n  2. The commissioner shall request that the department of environmental\nconservation compile information pursuant to paragraph b of subdivision\none of section 33-1203 of the environmental conservation law as\nnecessary to fulfill board approved requests, pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2411__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision one of this section.\n  3. The commissioner shall provide the board with such staff assistance\nand support services as are necessary for the board to perform the\nfunctions required of it under this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>