<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2413"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2413"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2413"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2413/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2413/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2413/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2413/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2413">
        <num>2413</num>
        <heading>Biennial report</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2413. Biennial report. The commissioner shall submit a report on or\nbefore January first commencing in nineteen hundred ninety-nine, and\nbiennially thereafter, to the governor, the temporary president of the\nsenate and the speaker of the assembly concerning the operation of the\nhealth research science board. Such report shall include recommendations\nfrom the health research science board including, but not limited to,\nthe types of data that would be useful for breast cancer researchers and\nwhether private citizen use of residential pesticides should be added to\nthe reporting requirements. The report shall also include a summary of\nresearch requests granted or denied. In addition, such report shall\ninclude an evaluation by the commissioner, the commissioner of the\ndepartment of environmental conservation and the health research science\nboard of the basis, efficiency and scientific utility of the information\nderived from pesticide reporting pursuant to sections 33-1205 and\n33-1207 of the environmental conservation law and recommend whether such\nsystem should be modified or continued. The report shall include a\nsummary of the comments and recommendations presented by the public at\nthe board's public hearings.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>