<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2475"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2475"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2475"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2475/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2475/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2475/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2475/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2475">
        <num>2475</num>
        <heading>Special policies with respect to dioxin exposure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2475__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish, promote and maintain a public information program on\ndioxin. Such program shall include, but may not be limited to, an effort\nto contact Vietnam era veterans and employees of the public and private\nsectors within the state who were exposed to an herbicide containing\ndioxin;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2475__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>initiate an epidemiological study of the health effects of\nexposure to herbicides containing dioxin;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2475__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>maintain a central data bank within the department for information\ncollected on the health effects of exposure to dioxin and for the\ncataloguing of existing scientific and medical literature on the health\neffects of this exposure; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2475__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>initiate education for health professionals to assist them in\nunderstanding the potential risks and state-of-the-art knowledge with\nregard to detection, diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic\nsymptoms associated with dioxin exposure.\n  2. The commissioner may request and shall receive from any department,\ndivision, board, bureau, commission or agency of the state or of any\npolitical subdivision thereof such assistance and data as will enable\nhim to properly carry out his activities hereunder and effectuate the\npurposes herein set forth. The commissioner may also enter into any\ncontract for services as he deems necessary with a private agency or\nconcern upon said terms and conditions as he deems appropriate.\nInformation concerning patient and medical data provided to the\ncommissioner pursuant to this subdivision shall be kept confidential\naccording to the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2475__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsection two hundred six of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>