<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2500-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2500_I">
        <num>2500-I</num>
        <heading>Child food choking prevention</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2500-i. Child food choking prevention. 1. The department shall\nestablish criteria for determining which foods and food products may\npose a significant choking risk for children in various age groups.\n  2. The department shall conduct an ongoing public awareness and\neducation program under section two hundred seven of this chapter on\nchoking risks, precautions and life-saving procedures, including, but\nnot limited to, listing on its internet website information that assists\nmembers of the public in locating infant and child cardiopulmonary\nresuscitation classes.\n  3. The department shall produce and distribute educational materials\non food choking risks, precautions and life-saving procedures. Such\nmaterials shall be made available to child care centers, pediatricians\nand nursery, elementary and secondary schools for distribution to\npersons in parental relation to children, and to hospitals, birthing\ncenters and other appropriate health care providers for distribution to\nmaternity patients. In addition, such materials shall be provided to\nhealth care professionals engaged in the care and treatment of children\nfor distribution to such children and persons in parental relation. The\ndepartment shall also provide information on food choking risks,\nprecautions and life-saving procedures on the department's internet\nwebsite. No provision of this subdivision shall be deemed to prohibit\nthe utilization and distribution of educational materials relating\nthereto produced by any public, private or governmental entity, in lieu\nof the department's production of such materials.\n  4. The department shall periodically review available data on choking\nincidents in children and update the information on choking risks,\nprecautionary measures and life-saving procedures provided in its\neducational materials and on its internet website, as appropriate.\n  5. The department shall report every three years, commencing January\nfirst, two thousand eighteen, to the governor, the temporary president\nof the senate and the speaker of the assembly on the implementation of\nthis section and any recommendations for furthering the purpose of this\nsection.\n  6. Implementation of this section shall be contingent upon and shall\nbe conducted within appropriations made therefor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>