<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2500-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2500_H">
        <num>2500-H</num>
        <heading>Statewide perinatal data system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2500-h. Statewide perinatal data system. 1. In order to support\nquality care at all hospitals with obstetric services, the department is\nauthorized to provide de-identified information for all births at each\naffiliate hospital in each regional perinatal center's network to the\nregional perinatal center and the affiliate, except that such\ninformation shall include zip code and a unique identifier such as\nmedical record number.\n  2. The information when received by the department shall be used\nsolely for the purpose of improving quality of care and shall not be\nsubject to release under article six of the public officers law, and\nwhere applicable, shall be subject to the confidentiality provisions of\nsection twenty-eight hundred five-m of this chapter, except that the\nrelease of birth certificate information shall be subject to section\nforty-one hundred seventy-four of this chapter.\n  3. The commissioner may release information collected through the\nstatewide perinatal data system to his or her designees, including\npersons or entities under contract with the department to review quality\nof care issues, as required to monitor regional perinatal centers and\naffiliate hospitals and conduct quality improvement initiatives as\nneeded to monitor, evaluate and improve patient care and outcomes. Such\ndesignee or person or entity under contract with the department to\nreview quality of care issues shall maintain the confidentiality of all\nsuch information and shall use it only to improve quality of care, as\napproved by the department.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 2500-h's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>