<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2500-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2500_E">
        <num>2500-E</num>
        <heading>Pregnant women, blood test for hepatitis B; follow-up care</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2500-e. Pregnant women, blood test for hepatitis B; follow-up care.\n1. At the time that a blood sample is taken to be tested for syphilis\npursuant to section twenty-three hundred eight of this chapter, every\nphysician or other authorized practitioner attending a pregnant woman in\nthe state shall, in addition, submit or cause to be submitted such\nsample to an approved laboratory for a standard serological test for\nhepatitis B surface antigen.\n  2. The term "approved laboratory" means a laboratory approved for the\npurpose as herein provided by the department, or in the city of New York\nby the department of health of such city.\n  3. A standard serological test for hepatitis B surface antigen is one\nrecognized as such by the department or in the city of New York by the\ndepartment of health of such city.\n  4. The physician or other authorized practitioner attending a pregnant\nwoman shall record the hepatitis B surface antigen test results\nprominently in the pregnant woman's medical record at or before the time\nof hospital admission for delivery.\n  5. If, at the time of hospital admission for delivery, hepatitis B\nsurface antigen test results are not available, the hospital shall\narrange immediate testing of the mother with results available within\ntwenty-four hours, or as soon thereafter as practicable, but in no event\nlonger than forty-eight hours.\n  6. It shall be the duty of the administrative officer or other person\nin charge of each institution caring for infants twenty-eight days of\nage or less to report the hepatitis B surface antigen test results of\nall mothers of newborn children to the department in such a manner as\nmay be required by the commissioner.\n  7. If the mother of a newborn infant has tested positive for hepatitis\nB surface antigen, the physician or other authorized practitioner\nattending the infant shall offer or cause to be offered immunizing doses\nof hepatitis B vaccine and hepatitis B immune globulin to the newborn\nwithin twelve hours of birth or whenever the infant is stable\nphysiologically and immunizing doses of hepatitis B vaccine and\nfollow-up vaccine in accordance with the schedule specified by the\ncommissioner. If the mother's hepatitis B surface antigen test results\nwere unavailable when the mother was admitted to a hospital for\ndelivery, the physician or other authorized practitioner attending the\ninfant shall offer or cause to be offered immunizing doses of hepatitis\nB vaccine and hepatitis B immune globulin for the newborn immediately\nupon receiving results showing that the mother has tested positive for\nhepatitis B surface antigen and offer immunizing doses of hepatitis B\nvaccine and follow-up vaccine in accordance with the schedule specified\nby the commissioner.\n  8. The parent or guardian of any child born to a mother positive for\nhepatitis B surface antigen shall have administered to such child\nimmunizing doses of hepatitis B immune globulin at birth and hepatitis B\nvaccine as well as follow-up hepatitis B vaccine in accordance with the\nschedule specified by the commissioner.\n  9. If the parent or guardian of such child is unable to pay for the\nservices of a private physician or other authorized practitioner, such\nperson shall present such child to the health officer of the county in\nwhich the child resides, who shall then administer the follow-up\nhepatitis B vaccine without charge.\n  10. If any licensed physician or nurse practitioner certifies that a\nfollow-up dose of hepatitis B vaccine may be detrimental to a child's\nhealth, the requirements of this section shall be inapplicable until\nsuch immunization is found no longer to be detrimental to such child's\nhealth.\n  11. The provision of this section relating to immunization shall not\napply in the case of any newborn infant whose parent or guardian holds\ngenuine and sincere religious beliefs which prohibit immunization and\nwho notifies the person charged with administering such immunization of\nthe religious objection thereto.\n  12. The commissioner of health shall promulgate such rules and\nregulations as are necessary to carry out the requirements of this\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>