<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-10-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2500-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2500_A">
        <num>2500-A</num>
        <heading>Test for phenylketonuria and other diseases and conditions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Phenylketonuria.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Homozygous sickle cell disease.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Hypothyroidism.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Branched-chain ketonuria.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Galactosemia.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Homocystinuria.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Critical congenital heart defects through pulse oximetry\nscreening.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>With regard to any newborn infant who is identified as, or\nsuspected of, having a hearing impairment as a result of a screening\nconducted pursuant to section twenty-five hundred-g of this title, a\nurine polymerase chain reaction (PCR) test for cytomegalovirus, unless\nthe parent of the infant objects thereto; provided that if the\ncommissioner determines that another test for cytomegalovirus is\ndiagnostically equivalent to or better than the urine polymerase chain\nreaction test, the commissioner may, by regulation under this section,\nallow or require the use of that other test.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adrenoleukodystrophy.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency using a quantitative\nenzymatic test or other diagnostic test in cases where: the newborn\ninfant presents with hemolytic anemia, hemolytic jaundice, or\nearly-onset increasing neonatal jaundice, that is, jaundice (bilirubin\nlevel greater than fortieth percentile for age in hours) persisting\nbeyond the day of birth through the week after birth; the newborn infant\nhas been admitted to the hospital for jaundice following birth; or the\nbiological parent of the newborn infant indicates a family, racial, or\nethnic risk of glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency, including\nhaving significant African, Asian, Mediterranean, or Middle Eastern\nancestry.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2500_A__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Duchenne muscular dystrophy using a test validated by the\nWadsworth center for laboratories and research.\n  2. Testing, the recording of the results of such tests, tracking,\nfollow-up reviews and educational activities shall be performed at such\ntimes and in such manner as may be prescribed by the commissioner. The\ncommissioner shall promulgate regulations setting forth the manner in\nwhich information describing the purposes of the requirements of this\nsection shall be disseminated to parents or a guardian of the infant\ntested.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not apply in the case of any\ninfant or child whose parent or guardian is a member of a recognized\nreligious organization whose teachings and tenets are contrary to the\ntesting herein required and who notifies the person charged with having\nsuch test administered of his objection thereto.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>