<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2508"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2508"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-04-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2508"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2508">
        <num>2508</num>
        <heading>Newborn health and safe sleep study</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2508. Newborn health and safe sleep study. There shall be\nestablished in the department, by the commissioner, a newborn health and\nsafe sleep study designed to reduce infant mortality rates across the\nstate and enhance existing strategies to improve safe sleep practices.\nThe department, in consultation with health care providers, hospitals,\nsafe sleep product manufacturers, provider groups, the New York state\noffice of children and family services, and any other person or entity\nthe commissioner deems necessary, shall conduct a study on the\neffectiveness of existing safe sleep practices and identify additional\nsafe sleep practices that reduce infant mortality rates. The study shall\ninclude a review of baby boxes and other products aimed at encouraging\nsafe and healthy sleep practices. The department shall report to the\nlegislature within twelve months of the effective date of this section\non the results of this study. Within twelve months after the completion\nof the study, the department shall conduct a pilot program aimed at\nimproving caregiver education and continued safe sleep practices in\ncounties or areas with high infant mortality rates, and also shall\npursue available funding options and make efforts to establish a\npublic-private partnership with organizations that promote such causes\nor manufacture such products in order to seek to obtain donations for\nthese purposes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>