<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2530-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2530_A">
        <num>2530-A</num>
        <heading>Payment for prenatal care special services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2530_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the pregnant woman, at the time of the receipt of the health\nstatus data form by the department, is enrolled in a managed care health\nplan, the department shall send the form to the plan for triage and\nappropriate care management interventions, which shall include available\nplan services and referrals for other services available in the\ncommunity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2530_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the pregnant woman, at the time of the receipt of the health\nstatus data form by the department, is not enrolled in a managed care\nhealth plan, the department shall send the form to an entity described\nin subdivision five of this section for triage and appropriate care\nmanagement services, which shall include, but not be limited to, needed\nhome visits and referrals to community based services for high risk\npregnant women. If the pregnant woman subsequently becomes enrolled in a\nmanaged care health plan, the designated entity and the plan shall\nassure continuity of care.\n  5. Patient health status data collected under this section shall be\nmaintained as confidential by the department and by any person or entity\nto whom the department discloses the data. Such data may only be\ndisclosed by the department under this section.\n  6. For purposes of the activities described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2530_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision four of this section, the department is authorized to enter\ninto agreements with and, within amounts appropriated therefor, provide\nfunding to, local health departments or not-for-profit organizations to\npromote positive pregnancy outcomes, optimal child health, growth and\ndevelopment, and safe home environments.\n  7. The department is authorized to operate the program authorized by\nthis section in a subset of counties in the state.\n  8. Within amounts appropriated therefor, the commissioner is\nauthorized to develop fees to reimburse enrolled fee-for-service\nproviders for the collection and transmittal of clinical data authorized\nby this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>