<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2531"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2531"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-04-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2531"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2531/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2531/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2531/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2531/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2531">
        <num>2531</num>
        <heading>Children and recovering mothers program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2531. Children and recovering mothers program. Subject to\nappropriation, the commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner\nof alcoholism and substance abuse services, is authorized to establish\nthe children and recovering mothers program, a program aimed at\nproviding health care providers, hospitals and midwifery birth centers\nwith guidance, education and assistance when providing care to expectant\nmothers with a substance use disorder. Such program shall:\n  1. Provide information to both health care providers as well as\nexpectant mothers regarding use of medication assisted treatment for\npregnant women, which shall include information regarding buprenorphrine\ntraining, tools for providers on effective management of women with a\nsubstance use disorder during pregnancy, and a referral list of\nproviders in the area;\n  2. Provide guidance and referral information for substance use\ndisorder services, home visiting services and other benefits and\nservices that they may be eligible for while expecting and after birth;\n  3. Develop a system for rapid consultation and referral linkage\nservices for obstetricians and primary care providers statewide who\nprovide care for expectant mothers with substance use disorders;\n  4. Provide guidance on the identification of signs and symptoms of\nsubstance use disorder in expectant mothers; and\n  5. Anything else deemed necessary to implement the program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>