<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2552"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2552"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2552"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2552/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2552/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2552/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2552/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2552">
        <num>2552</num>
        <heading>Responsibility of municipality</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2552. Responsibility of municipality. 1. Each municipality shall be\nresponsible for ensuring that the early intervention services contained\nin an IFSP are provided to eligible children and their families who\nreside in such municipality. A municipality may monitor, which may\ninclude site visitation, evaluators and providers of such services\nwithin the municipality in accordance with this title and regulations\npromulgated hereunder, including making the determinations specified in\nthis section. The service coordinator shall report, in a manner and\nformat as determined by the municipality, on the delivery of services to\nan eligible child in accordance with the eligible child's IFSP. A\nmunicipality may request that the parent select a new service\ncoordinator or require that the service coordinator select a new\nprovider of services if the municipality finds that the service\ncoordinator has not been performing his or her responsibilities as\nrequired by this title or that services have not been provided in\naccordance with the eligible child's IFSP. If the early intervention\nofficial determines that the evaluator has not followed the requirements\nin this title or regulations promulgated hereunder, the early\nintervention official may require that the evaluator immediately submit\nadditional documentation to support the eligibility determination. If\nthe evaluator does not provide the requested documentation, or the\ndocumentation provided continues to be inconsistent with the\nrequirements of this title or regulations, the early intervention\nofficial can require that the parent select another evaluator to conduct\na multidisciplinary evaluation to determine whether the child meets\neligibility for program services.\n  2. The early intervention official shall require an eligible child's\nparent to furnish the parents' and eligible child's social security\nnumbers for the purpose of the department's and municipality's\nadministration of the program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>