<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2557"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2557"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2557"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2557/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2557/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2557/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2557/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2557">
        <num>2557</num>
        <heading>Financial responsibility and reimbursement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2557__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, in his or her discretion, is authorized to\ncontract with one or more entities to act as the fiscal agent for the\ndepartment and municipalities with respect to fiscal management and\npayment of early intervention claims. Municipalities shall grant\nsufficient authority to the fiscal agent to act on their behalf.\nMunicipalities, and individual and agency providers as defined by the\ncommissioner in regulation shall utilize such fiscal agent for payment\nof early intervention claims as determined by the department and shall\nprovide such information and documentation as required by the department\nand necessary for the fiscal agent to carry out its duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2557__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of section one hundred\ntwelve or one hundred sixty-three of the state finance law, sections one\nhundred forty-two and one hundred forty-three of the economic\ndevelopment law, or any other contrary provision of law, the\ncommissioner is authorized to enter into a contract or contracts under\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2557__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision without a competitive bid or request\nfor proposal process, provided, however, that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2557__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department shall post on its website, for a period of no less\nthan thirty days:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2557__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A description of the proposed services to be provided pursuant to\nthe contract or contracts;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2557__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The criteria for selection of a contractor or contractors;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2557__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The period of time during which a prospective contractor may seek\nselection, which shall be no less than thirty days after such\ninformation is first posted on the website; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2557__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The manner by which a prospective contractor may seek such\nselection, which may include submission by electronic means;\n  (ii) All reasonable and responsive submissions that are received from\nprospective contractors in a timely fashion shall be reviewed by the\ncommissioner; and\n  (iii) The commissioner shall select such contractor or contractors\nthat, in his or her discretion, are best suited to serve the purposes of\nthis section.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2557__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2557__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall apply only to the initial\ncontract or contracts necessary to obtain the services of a fiscal agent\nfor early intervention program fiscal management and payment of early\nintervention claims and shall not apply to subsequent contracts needed\nto maintain such services, as determined by the commissioner in his or\nher discretion.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>