<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2584"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2584"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2584"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2584/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2584/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2584/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2584/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2584">
        <num>2584</num>
        <heading>Children with physical disabilities; transportation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2584. Children with physical disabilities; transportation.  1. The\ndepartment shall on its own initiative provide, within the limits of the\nappropriations made therefor, such transportation for such children with\nphysical disabilities as in the judgment of the commissioner is needed\nto such places wherein the medical services outlined in section two\nthousand five hundred eighty-one of this chapter are administered or\nprovided to such children.\n  2. When the commissioner of health of any county or part-county health\ndistrict or the medical director of the program for children with\nphysical disabilities, or the department of health of the city of New\nYork, in pursuance of section two thousand five hundred eighty-two of\nthis chapter, shall issue an authorization for medical service for any\nchild with physical disabilities, including among the expenses thereof\ntransportation necessary to obtain such services, the commissioner, if\nhe approves such order, shall issue a certificate to such effect, copies\nof which shall be filed with the clerk of the board of supervisors or\nother governing elective body of the county or chief fiscal officer of\nthe city of New York and one in the office of the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>