<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2602"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2602"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2602"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2602">
        <num>2602</num>
        <heading>Helen Hayes Hospital; charges for service and reimbursement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2602. Helen Hayes Hospital; charges for service and reimbursement.\n1. The commissioner shall establish the rates to be paid for the\nmaintenance, care and treatment of all patients admitted to the Helen\nHayes Hospital.\n  2. The commissioner shall require that the director of the hospital\nshall render bills at suitable intervals and a final bill as soon as\npracticable on discharge of a patient, to the person or agency in each\ninstance who guarantees payment or, if payment is to be made from public\nfunds, to the proper fiscal officer of the agency or county or\nmunicipality indicated.\n  3. The commissioner may in his discretion, in proper cases, where\nsubstantial justice will best be served thereby, waive such bills or\ncompromise any portion of such bills for the maintenance, care and\ntreatment received or furnished to patients in the hospital. Such waiver\nor compromise shall be made only upon prior approval of the comptroller\nand the attorney general when they deem it to be for the best interest\nof the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>