<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="265-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_265_A">
        <num>265-A</num>
        <heading>Empire state stem cell board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 265-a. Empire state stem cell board. 1. The empire state stem cell\nboard ("board"), comprised of a funding committee and an ethics\ncommittee, both of which shall be chaired by the commissioner, is hereby\ncreated within the department for the purpose of administering the\nempire state stem cell trust fund ("fund"), created pursuant to section\nninety-nine-p of the state finance law. The board is hereby empowered,\nsubject to annual appropriations and other funding authorized or made\navailable, to make grants to basic, applied, translational or other\nresearch and development activities that will advance scientific\ndiscoveries in fields related to stem cell biology; provided, however,\nthat the board shall not make any grants on or after April first, two\nthousand twenty-one.\n  2. No grants made available in the fund from any source shall be\ndirectly or indirectly utilized for research involving human\nreproductive cloning.\n  3. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the board shall have\nthe authority to adopt by laws to govern its proceedings including but\nnot limited to rules respecting quorums and the number of votes needed\nto require the award of grants. No grants may be awarded by the board\nprior to the establishment of bylaws that must include merit based peer\nreview application guidelines. Such bylaws must be approved by the\nfunding committee.\n  4. Grants may be made for one or more years, provided, however, that\nno grant shall be made for which the annual commitment is more than\nfifteen percent of the total funds available in any year. However, no\nsingle institution shall be awarded more than twenty-five percent of the\ntotal amount appropriated. This limitation shall be considered\nseparately for each new proposal without aggregating any prior year\napprovals that may fund research activities. This requirement shall be\ndeterminative, unless two-thirds of the funding committee approves a\nhigher limit for a particular grantee.\n  5. The existence of the empire state stem cell board shall continue\nuntil there are no longer any assets or money available for\ndistribution.\n  * NB Repealed December 31, 2025\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>