<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-267"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-267"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="267"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-267/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-267/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-267/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-267/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_267">
        <num>267</num>
        <heading>Menstrual products in schools</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 267. Menstrual products in schools. All elementary and secondary\npublic schools in the state serving students in any grade from grade six\nthrough grade twelve shall provide menstrual products in the restrooms\nof such school building or buildings. Such products shall be provided at\nno charge to students.\n  * NB Effective until July 1, 2024\n  * ยง 267. Menstrual products in schools. 1. All elementary and\nsecondary public schools and non-public schools in the state serving\nstudents in any grade from grade six through grade twelve shall provide\nmenstrual products in the restrooms of such school building or\nbuildings. Such products shall be provided at no charge to students.\n  2. A non-public school may be granted an exemption from the\nrequirements of subdivision one of this section upon a demonstration\nsufficient to the commissioner of education that the school does not\nserve students who need such products and that menstrual products are\navailable in a manner that ensures the privacy of any student seeking\nthem within the school building or buildings, including but not limited\nto within any gender-neutral restroom. Such exemption may be revoked\nshould the circumstances change on which the exemption is granted.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2024\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>