<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2701"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2701">
        <num>2701</num>
        <heading>Purpose and functions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Carry on programs of professional education and training of\nmedical students, physicians and nurses in the prevention,\nrehabilitation, medical and nursing care of diseases of older people.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Plan and carry out the Alzheimer's disease assistance program to\nenhance support services for people with Alzheimer's disease and their\ncaregivers. Services to be provided by the program may include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2701__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>education and training for health care practitioners, caregivers,\nvolunteers and informal caregivers regarding services for or the\ntreatment of persons with Alzheimer's disease;\n  (ii) counseling for families of persons with Alzheimer's disease;\n  (iii) respite services for informal caregivers of persons with\nAlzheimer's disease; and\n  (iv) technological assistance for persons with Alzheimer's disease.\n  The commissioner shall make grants under this paragraph within amounts\nappropriated therefore to public and not-for-profit entities including\nlocal health agencies, health care providers, higher educational\ninstitutions affiliated with medical facilities, community-based\norganizations and other organizations with demonstrated expertise in\nserving persons with Alzheimer's disease. The commissioner may\ncoordinate grants under this paragraph with the availability of grants\nfrom other sources. The commissioner may also accept or seek grants from\nother sources to enhance amounts appropriated to this program.\n  7. Plan and carry out programs to stimulate the prevention,\nrehabilitation and control of chronic illnesses and the promotion of the\nhealth of adult, middle-aged and older persons, through "day hospital"\nand a "meals on wheels" demonstration projects.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>