<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-273"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-273"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="273"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-273/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-273/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-273/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-273/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_273">
        <num>273</num>
        <heading>Preferred drug program prior authorization</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a patient's health care provider prescribes a\nprescription drug that is not on the preferred drug list or the\nstatewide formulary of opioid dependence agents and opioid antagonists\nestablished pursuant to subparagraph (vii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision seven of section three hundred sixty-seven-a of the social\nservices law, the prescriber shall consult with the program to confirm\nthat in his or her reasonable professional judgment, the patient's\nclinical condition is consistent with the criteria for approval of the\nnon-preferred drug. Such criteria shall include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the preferred drug has been tried by the patient and has failed to\nproduce the desired health outcomes;\n  (ii) the patient has tried the preferred drug and has experienced\nunacceptable side effects;\n  (iii) the patient has been stabilized on a non-preferred drug and\ntransition to the preferred drug would be medically contraindicated; or\n  (iv) other clinical indications identified by the drug utilization\nreview board established pursuant to section three hundred sixty-nine-bb\nof the social services law, which shall include consideration of the\nmedical needs of special populations, including children, elderly,\nchronically ill, persons with mental health conditions, and persons\naffected by HIV/AIDS, pregnant persons, and persons with an opioid use\ndisorder.\n  * NB Effective until March 31, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a patient's health care provider prescribes a prescription\ndrug that is not on the preferred drug list, the prescriber shall\nconsult with the program to confirm that in his or her reasonable\nprofessional judgment, the patient's clinical condition is consistent\nwith the criteria for approval of the non-preferred drug. Such criteria\nshall include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the preferred drug has been tried by the patient and has failed to\nproduce the desired health outcomes;\n  (ii) the patient has tried the preferred drug and has experienced\nunacceptable side effects;\n  (iii) the patient has been stabilized on a non-preferred drug and\ntransition to the preferred drug would be medically contraindicated; or\n  (iv) other clinical indications identified by the committee for the\npatient's use of the non-preferred drug, which shall include\nconsideration of the medical needs of special populations, including\nchildren, elderly, chronically ill, persons with mental health\nconditions, and persons affected by HIV/AIDS.\n  * NB Effective March 31, 2026\n  * (a-1) When a patient's health care provider prescribes a\nprescription drug that is on the statewide formulary of opioid\ndependence agents and opioid antagonists established pursuant to\nsubparagraph (vii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision seven of section\nthree hundred sixty-seven-a of the social services law, the department\nshall not require prior authorization unless required by the\ndepartment's drug use review program established pursuant to section\n1927</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Social Security Act.\n  * NB Repealed March 31, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that the patient does not meet the criteria in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the prescriber may provide additional\ninformation to the program to justify the use of a prescription drug\nthat is not on the preferred drug list. The program shall provide a\nreasonable opportunity for a prescriber to reasonably present his or her\njustification of prior authorization. If, after consultation with the\nprogram, the prescriber, in his or her reasonable professional judgment,\ndetermines that the use of a prescription drug that is not on the\npreferred drug list is warranted, the prescriber's determination shall\nbe final.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a prescriber meets the requirements of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, the prescriber shall be granted prior authorization\nunder this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the instance where a prior authorization determination is not\ncompleted within twenty-four hours of the original request, solely as\nthe result of a failure of the program (whether by action or inaction),\nprior authorization shall be immediately and automatically granted with\nno further action by the prescriber and the prescriber shall be notified\nof this determination. In the instance where a prior authorization\ndetermination is not completed within twenty-four hours of the original\nrequest for any other reason, a seventy-two hour supply of the\nmedication shall be approved by the program and the prescriber shall be\nnotified of this determination.\n  4. When, in the judgment of the prescriber or the pharmacist, an\nemergency condition exists, and the prescriber or pharmacist notifies\nthe program that an emergency condition exists, a seventy-two hour\nemergency supply of the drug prescribed shall be immediately authorized\nby the program.\n  5. In the event that a patient presents a prescription to a pharmacist\nfor a prescription drug that is not on the preferred drug list and for\nwhich the prescriber has not obtained a prior authorization, the\npharmacist shall, within a prompt period based on professional judgment,\nnotify the prescriber. The prescriber shall, within a prompt period\nbased on professional judgment, either seek prior authorization or shall\ncontact the pharmacist and amend or cancel the prescription. The\npharmacist shall, within a prompt period based on professional judgment,\nnotify the patient when prior authorization has been obtained or denied\nor when the prescription has been amended or cancelled.\n  6. Once prior authorization of a prescription for a drug that is not\non the preferred drug list is obtained, prior authorization shall not be\nrequired for any refill of the prescription.\n  7. No prior authorization under the preferred drug program shall be\nrequired when a prescriber prescribes a drug on the preferred drug list;\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>