<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2761"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2761"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2761"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2761/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2761/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2761/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2761/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2761">
        <num>2761</num>
        <heading>Function, powers and duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2761__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>physical or mental condition that interferes with or is\nsignificantly likely to interfere with the worker's ability to perform\nassigned tasks or regular duties;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2761__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lack of compliance with established guidelines to prevent\ntransmission of disease and/or documentation or evidence of previous\ntransmission of bloodborne pathogens;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2761__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the appropriateness of techniques as related to performance of\nprocedures; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2761__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any health condition that would pose a significant risk to others.\n  3. When the panel recommends training, monitoring, reassignment, any\nsimilar action, or practice restrictions, the health care worker shall\nprovide written assurance to the panel that he/she has informed\nfacilities licensed by the department where the worker provides patient\ncare of the panel's recommendations and shall identify the person or\npersons at the facilities so informed. If the health care worker fails\nto inform facilities licensed by the department where he/she provides\npatient care of the panel's recommendations, the panel shall so notify\nsuch facilities. If the health care worker fails to comply with the\npanel's recommendations or compliance cannot be determined by the panel\nafter reasonable effort, the panel shall disclose the nature of its\nrecommendations to the professional licensing, registration or\ncertification boards relevant to the health care worker. The panel may\nperiodically monitor and reevaluate the worker, with the worker's\nconsent, at a frequency and through a mechanism to be determined by\nagreement between the worker and the panel.\n  4. The information received by the panel, the record of deliberations\nof the panel, and the decisions of the panel are not disclosable\npursuant to article six of the public officers law. If the health care\nworker fails to comply with the recommendations of the panel or\ncompliance cannot be determined by the panel after reasonable effort,\ninformation held by the panel, the panel's deliberations and\nrecommendations may be disclosed to and utilized by the office of\nprofessional medical conduct, the office of professional discipline and\nappropriate disciplinary bodies. The meetings of the panel are not\nsubject to article seven of the public officers law. The members of the\npanel are bound by article six-A of the public officers law (personal\nprivacy protection law).\n  5. A health care worker's petition to the panel ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>