<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2781"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2781"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2781"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2781/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2781/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2781/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2781/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2781">
        <num>2781</num>
        <heading>HIV related testing</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>HIV causes AIDS and can be transmitted through sexual activities\nand needle-sharing, by pregnant women to their fetuses, and through\nbreastfeeding infants;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>there is treatment for HIV that can help an individual stay\nhealthy;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>individuals with HIV or AIDS can adopt safe practices to protect\nuninfected and infected people in their lives from becoming infected or\nmultiply infected with HIV;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>testing is voluntary and can be done anonymously at a public\ntesting center;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the law protects the confidentiality of HIV related test results;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the law prohibits discrimination based on an individual's HIV\nstatus and services are available to help with such consequences; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the law requires that an individual be notified before an\nHIV-related test is performed, and that no test shall be performed over\ntheir objection; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pre- and post-exposure prophylaxis medications (PrEP and PEP) are\navailable to protect persons at risk of HIV infection.\n  Protocols shall be in place to ensure compliance with this section.\n  4. A health care provider who is not authorized by the commissioner to\nprovide HIV related tests on an anonymous basis shall refer a person who\nrequests an anonymous test to a test site which does provide anonymous\ntesting. The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to a health\ncare provider ordering the performance of an HIV related test on an\nindividual proposed for insurance coverage.\n  5. At the time of communicating the test result to the subject of the\ntest, a person ordering the performance of an HIV related test shall,\ndirectly or through a representative:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of a test indicating evidence of HIV infection,\nprovide the subject of the test or, if the subject lacks capacity to\nconsent, the person authorized pursuant to law to consent to health care\nfor the subject with counseling or referrals for counseling:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for\ncoping with the emotional consequences of learning the result; (ii)\nregarding the discrimination problems that disclosure of the result\ncould cause; (iii) for behavior change to prevent transmission or\ncontraction of HIV infection; (iv) to inform such person of available\nmedical treatments; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>regarding the need to notify his or her\ncontacts; and (vi) regarding pre- and post-exposure prophylaxis\nmedications available to sexual partners to prevent HIV infection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of a test not indicating evidence of HIV infection,\nprovide (in a manner which may consist of oral or written reference to\ninformation previously provided) the subject of the test, or if the\nsubject lacks capacity to consent, the person authorized pursuant to law\nto consent to health care for the subject, with information concerning\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the risks of participating in high risk sexual or needle-sharing\nbehavior; and (ii) regarding pre- and post-exposure prophylaxis\nmedications available to prevent HIV infection.\n  5-a. With the consent of the subject of a test indicating evidence of\nHIV infection or, if the subject lacks capacity to consent, with the\nconsent of the person authorized pursuant to law to consent to health\ncare for the subject, the person who ordered the performance of the HIV\nrelated test, or such person's representative, shall provide or arrange\nwith a health care provider for an appointment for follow-up medical\ncare for HIV for such subject.\n  6. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the performance\nof an HIV related test:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a health care provider or health facility in relation to the\nprocuring, processing, distributing or use of a human body or a human\nbody part, including organs, tissues, eyes, bones, arteries, blood,\nsemen, or other body fluids, for use in medical research or therapy, or\nfor transplantation to individuals provided, however, that where the\ntest results are communicated to the subject, post-test counseling, as\ndescribed in subdivision five of this section, shall nonetheless be\nrequired; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the purpose of research if the testing is performed in a\nmanner by which the identity of the test subject is not known and may\nnot be retrieved by the researcher; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on a deceased person, when such test is conducted to determine the\ncause of death or for epidemiological purposes; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conducted pursuant to section twenty-five hundred-f of this\nchapter; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in situations involving occupational exposures which create a\nsignificant risk of contracting or transmitting HIV infection, as\ndefined in regulations of the department and pursuant to protocols\nadopted by the department,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2781__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provided that:\n  (A) the person who is the source of the occupational exposure is\ndeceased, comatose or is determined by his or her attending health care\nprofessional to lack mental capacity to consent to an HIV related test\nand is not reasonably expected to recover in time for the exposed person\nto receive appropriate medical treatment, as determined by the exposed\nperson's attending health care professional who would order or provide\nsuch treatment;\n  (B) there is no person available or reasonably likely to become\navailable who has the legal authority to consent to the HIV related test\non behalf of the source person in time for the exposed person to receive\nappropriate medical treatment; and\n  (C) the exposed person will benefit medically by knowing the source\nperson's HIV test results, as determined by the exposed person's health\ncare professional and documented in the exposed person's medical record;\n  (ii) in which case\n  (A) a provider shall order an anonymous HIV test of the source person;\nand\n  (B) the results of such anonymous test, but not the identity of the\nsource person, shall be disclosed only to the attending health care\nprofessional of the exposed person solely for the purpose of assisting\nthe exposed person in making appropriate decisions regarding\npost-exposure medical treatment; and\n  (C) the results of the test shall not be disclosed to the source\nperson or placed in the source person's medical record.\n  7. In the event that an HIV related test is ordered by a physician or\ncertified nurse practitioner pursuant to the provisions of the education\nlaw providing for non-patient specific regimens, then for the purposes\nof this section the individual administering the test shall be deemed to\nbe the individual ordering the test.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>