<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2802-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2802-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2802-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2802-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2802-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2802-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2802-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2802_A">
        <num>2802-A</num>
        <heading>Transitional care unit demonstration program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2802_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall act upon such applications in a manner\nconsistent with section twenty-eight hundred two of this article\nprovided that the commissioner may not waive review and recommendation\nby the public health and health planning council. In the public health\nand health planning council's evaluation of applications and the\ncommissioner acting upon such applications, priority shall be given to\napplicants who have a memorandum of understanding or other cooperative\nagreement with one or more skilled nursing facilities located within\ntheir service area. Further, in the public health and health planning\ncouncil evaluating applications and the commissioner acting upon such\napplications, consideration shall also be given to the geographic\ndistribution of applicants throughout the state, so that applications\nmay be approved from the various geographic regions of the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2802_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The care provided in a transitional care unit shall be limited in\nduration and designed to resolve a patient's sub acute care medical\nproblems and result in the timely and appropriate discharge of such a\npatient to a home, residential health care facility or other appropriate\nsetting.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2802_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to be approved to operate a transitional care unit and to\nprovide transitional care services, an applicant must comply with and\nmeet all applicable requirements of and conditions of participation\nunder title XVIII of the federal Social Security Act (Medicare).\n  3. The commissioner shall report to the governor and the legislature\nconcerning the implementation of this section and the operation of\ntransitional care units within three years after the effective date of\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>