<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2803-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2803_E">
        <num>2803-E</num>
        <heading>Residential health care facilities; return and redistribution of unused medication</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2803-e. Residential health care facilities; return and\nredistribution of unused medication. 1. Notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovision of law, rule or regulation to the contrary, the commissioner\nis hereby authorized and directed to permit either a resident or\nconsultant pharmacist in a residential health care facility to return to\nthe pharmacy from which it was purchased any unused medication provided\nthat such medication is sealed in unopened, individually packaged units\nand within the recommended period of shelf life, and provided that such\nmedication is not a controlled substance as defined in section\nthirty-three hundred six of the public health law.\n  2. The pharmacy to which such medication as described in subdivision\none of this section is returned shall be permitted to receive, restock\nand redistribute that medication.\n  3. The pharmacy to which such medication as described in subdivision\none of this section is returned shall be required to reimburse or credit\nthe purchaser of that medication for the unused medication that is\nrestocked and redistributed. No pharmacy shall be required to accept any\nmedication returned under subdivision one of this section.\n  4. Neither an individual patient or the state, if a patient is a\nrecipient of a state funded program, shall be charged for unused\nmedication which according to the provisions of this law is returned for\nreimbursement or credit.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 2803-e's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>