<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2803-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2803_J">
        <num>2803-J</num>
        <heading>Information for maternity patients</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual rate of cesarean sections, primary, repeat and total,\nperformed at such facility;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of women with previous cesarean sections who\nhave had a subsequent successful vaginal birth;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of deliveries by midwives;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of births utilizing electronic fetal\nmonitoring listed on the basis of external and internal;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of births utilizing forceps, listed on the\nbasis of low forceps delivery and mid forceps delivery;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of breech births delivered vaginally;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of births utilizing analgesia;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of births utilizing anesthesia including\ngeneral, spinal, epidural, and paracervical listed on the basis of\nvaginal and cesarean births;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of births utilizing induction of labor;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of births utilizing augmentation of labor;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the annual percentage of vaginal births utilizing episiotomies;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether birthing rooms are available for use in the facility;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether rooming-in is available in the facility, on the basis of\ntwenty-four hours a day or daytime;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the facility conducts safety drills to prepare for\nobstetric emergencies;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the facility participates in quality improvement\ninitiatives;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_p">
          <num>(p)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the facility has an agreement and policy to arrange for\nemergent transfer of care for critically ill pregnant people/infants to\nhigher levels of care (applicable only for those facilities that are not\nthe designated regional perinatal center or a quaternary or tertiary\ncare center with Level III-IV NICU);\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_q">
          <num>(q)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the facility has a written community needs assessment plan\nto reduce racial disparities and address community needs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_r">
          <num>(r)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the facility offers, upon patient request, an autopsy for\nstillbirth; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the facility offers bereavement support for patients that\nhave suffered a stillbirth or third trimester fetal loss.\n  3. Compilation of the statistics set out in subdivision two of this\nsection shall be the responsibility of the commissioner.\n  4. Statistical information shall be presented in the most recent one\nyear aggregate.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall establish an immunization schedule for\nnewborn children. The immunization schedule shall chart out recommended\nimmunizations against certain diseases and illnesses and age-appropriate\ntimes for the administration of each immunization. The immunization\nschedule shall also include information on the importance of getting\nchildren immunized at the recommended ages. The immunization schedule\nshall also include the toll-free telephone number operated by the\ndepartment as part of its immunization education efforts. The\nimmunization schedule shall be in accordance with recommendations\nestablished by the New York state department of health and the\nimmunization practices advisory committee of the United States\ndepartment of health and human services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall provide the immunization schedule to the\nlocal registrars for distribution pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section four thousand one hundred thirty-seven of\nthis chapter.\n  6. Every hospital and birth center shall request that a parent and/or\nparents, which shall mean and include biological and adoptive parents,\nguardians, or other persons in parental relationship to a newborn child,\nif available, view</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a video presentation, approved by the\ncommissioner, on the dangers of shaking infants and young children, and\nthe symptoms of shaken baby syndrome, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2803_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a video presentation,\napproved by the commissioner, on the dangers of drowning for infants and\nyoung children. After viewing such video presentations or upon refusal\nto view such video presentations, the hospital or birth center shall\nrequest that such parent and/or parents sign a form stating that they\nhave viewed or refused to view such video presentations. All training\nmaterials and forms required to implement the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall be provided by the commissioner.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 2803-j's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>