<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2804-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2804-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2804-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2804-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2804-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2804-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2804-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2804_A">
        <num>2804-A</num>
        <heading>State task force on clinical practice guidelines and medical technology assessment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2804_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"clinical practice guidelines" shall mean\nsystematically developed statements to assist physician and patient\ndecisions about appropriate health care for specific clinical\ncircumstances; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2804_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"medical technology" shall mean an instrument or unit of equipment\nor technique for use as a health related treatment, testing or\ndiagnostic tool.\n  3. Task force members shall receive no compensation but shall be\nreimbursed for travel expenses incurred in the performance of their\nduties.\n  4. The task force may establish medical specialty advisory committees\nto assist in carrying out its responsibilities pursuant to this section.\n  5. The task force shall solicit the cooperation and participation of\nmedical specialty organizations recognized by the American Board of\nMedical Specialties with clinical practice guideline experience. The\nstate task force shall meet as necessary to fulfill its\nresponsibilities.\n  6. The task force, in consultation with the commissioner, shall\nsolicit specific research and/or project proposals from medical\nspecialty societies recognized by the American Board of Medical\nSpecialties to promote the development and application of clinical\npractice guidelines and appropriate use of medical technology.\nSpeciality societies, at their option, may incorporate the involvement\nof any other organization which they deem appropriate into their\nproposal. The task force shall then recommend to the commissioner\nspecific research projects to be undertaken by such specialty society\ncandidates for grants and contracts pursuant to subdivision fifteen of\nsection two hundred six of this chapter. The task force shall not\nrecommend any projects for the purpose of developing clinical practice\nguideline-based reimbursement methodologies or any other regulations.\n  7. The task force in cooperation with the medical specialty\norganizations recognized by the American Board of Medical Specialties\nshall issue a report to the governor and legislature by May first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-five which shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2804_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>describe the current status of practice guidelines, their uses and\ntheir impact on health care delivery and outcomes;\n  (ii) identify appropriate uses of practice guidelines and medical\ntechnology for purposes of improving health care quality and efficiency;\n  (iii) identify inappropriate uses or applications of practice guide-\nlines and medical technology;\n  (iv) identify by what means the uses of practice guidelines should be\nfacilitated, if appropriate or warranted; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2804_A__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>identify what role, if any, state government should have relative\nto practice guidelines.\n  8. Staff of the department shall be made available to provide\ntechnical assistance to the task force as necessary.\n  * NB Expired June 30, 1996\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>