<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-Y"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-Y"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-11-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2805-Y"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2805_Y">
        <num>2805-Y</num>
        <heading>Identification and assessment of human trafficking victims</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2805_Y__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"human trafficking victim" shall have the meaning set forth in\nsection four hundred eighty-three-aa of the social services law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2805_Y__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"subject facility" shall mean a general hospital, public health\ncenter, diagnostic center, treatment center or outpatient department;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2805_Y__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"subject facility personnel" shall mean nursing, medical, social\nwork and other clinical care personnel, and security personnel in the\nsubject facility service units; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2805_Y__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"subject facility service units" shall mean the service units of\nthe subject facility that include the following areas:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2805_Y__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>emergency\nservices; (ii) pediatrics; (iii) obstetrics and gynecology; (iv)\northopedics;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2805_Y__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>internal medicine; (vi) family medicine; (vii)\nradiology; (viii) surgery; (ix) psychiatry; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2805_Y__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>dental services to\nthe extent the subject facility maintains a dental clinic, center or\ndepartment on site of the subject facility.\n  2. Every subject facility shall provide for the identification,\nassessment, and appropriate treatment or referral of persons suspected\nas human trafficking victims, and in the case of persons under eighteen\nyears old, the reporting of such persons as an abused or maltreated\nchild if required under title six of article six of the social services\nlaw. The subject facility shall establish and implement written policies\nand procedures under this section which shall apply to all subject\nfacility service units.\n  3. Every subject facility shall provide, on an ongoing basis, to all\nsubject facility personnel training regarding the policies and\nprocedures established under this section, including training in the\nrecognition of indicators of a human trafficking victim and the\nresponsibilities of such personnel in dealing with persons suspected as\nhuman trafficking victims. Such training may be incorporated as part of\nthe subject facility's existing training programs, provided that the\ntraining includes all of the requirements of this section.\n  4. The commissioner may identify organizations or providers for\nconsideration by subject facilities to provide training under this\nsection. The commissioner may, in consultation with the office of\ntemporary and disability assistance and the office of children and\nfamily services, make regulations under this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>