<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2805-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2805-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2805_O">
        <num>2805-O</num>
        <heading>Identification of veterans and their spouses by nursing homes, residential health care facilities, and adult care facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2805-o. Identification of veterans and their spouses by nursing\nhomes, residential health care facilities, and adult care facilities. 1.\nEvery nursing home and residential health care facility as defined in\nsubdivisions two and three of section two thousand eight hundred one of\nthis article and every adult care facility licensed and certified by the\ndepartment pursuant to title two of article seven of the social services\nlaw or article forty-six-B of this chapter, including all adult homes,\nenriched housing programs, residences for adults, assisted living\nprograms, and assisted living residences shall keep and maintain\naccurate records identifying veterans and their spouses residing within\nsuch facilities. Such information shall be solicited by nursing home\nand/or residential health care facility staff upon a patient's\nadmission, noted on the admission form, and included with the patient's\nfile by asking the question "Have you or your spouse ever served in the\nUnited States military?". In the case of patients currently residing at\nsuch nursing homes or residential health care facilities, staff shall\nsolicit such information by asking the question "Have you or your spouse\never served in the United States military?" from each patient residing\nat such institution and update the patient's file to indicate veteran\nstatus.\n  2. Every nursing home, residential health care facility and every\nadult care facility licensed and certified by the department pursuant to\ntitle two of article seven of the social services law or article\nforty-six-B of this chapter, including all adult homes, enriched housing\nprograms, residences for adults, assisted living programs, and assisted\nliving residences shall in writing advise all individuals identifying\nthemselves as veterans or spouses of veterans that the department of\nveterans' services and local veterans' service agencies established\npursuant to section fourteen of the veterans' services law to provide\nassistance to veterans and their spouses regarding benefits under\nfederal and state law. Such written information shall include the name,\naddress and telephone number of the New York state department of\nveterans' services, the nearest department of veterans' services office,\nthe nearest county or city veterans' service agency and the nearest\naccredited veterans' service officer.\n  3. Every nursing home, residential health care facility and every\nadult care facility licensed and certified by the department pursuant to\ntitle two of article seven of the social services law or article\nforty-six-B of this chapter, including all adult homes, enriched housing\nprograms, residences for adults, assisted living programs, and assisted\nliving residences, with the permission of individuals identifying\nthemselves as veterans or spouses of veterans, shall transmit such\nveteran status information to the division of veterans' services.\n  4. Any person who violates the provisions of this section shall be\nsubject to a civil fine not to exceed fifty dollars per violation but in\nno event shall any fine exceed one thousand dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>