<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-X"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-X"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2807-X"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2807_X">
        <num>2807-X</num>
        <heading>Grants for long term care demonstration projects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_X__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The following factors shall be considered in approving each\ndemonstration project respectively:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_X__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Residential health care demonstration project. (A) the extent to\nwhich there is a reduction in the need for skilled nursing beds for a\nfacility that is eligible to replace its existing skilled nursing\nfacility; (B) the potential to design and develop more appropriate\nsmaller residential health care facilities as an alternative to\nreplacing an existing skilled nursing facility; (C) the extent to which\nthe quality, efficiency and continuity of care will be promoted and\nprovided for by the development of integrated long-term care services in\nthe community; (D) the extent to which the project will provide training\nto health care workers to appropriately staff new community based models\nof long term care; (E) demonstrate the involvement and support of\nworkforce in the program redesign; (F) the development of a new\nlong-term care reimbursement methodology that encourages care in the\nleast restrictive setting and adequately reflects the resources needed\nto serve consumers in each level of long term care; (G) and the\nincorporation of a research component designed to evaluate the project.\n  (ii) Community based care demonstration project. (A) the extent to\nwhich there is a reduction in the need for skilled nursing facility beds\non a countywide basis; (B) the development of a new system to inform\nrecently admitted residents of skilled nursing facilities of the\navailability of community long-term care options; (C) the extent to\nwhich the discharge planning program from skilled nursing facilities\nwill inform, assist and maximize freedom of choice to consumers who\nchoose to move back to the community; (D) the extent to which the\nproject will develop community based long term care services, including\nfunding for the recruitment and retention of direct care health care\nworkers necessary to increase community based services; (E) the extent\nto which the project will provide training to health care staff; and (F)\nthe incorporation of a research component d...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_X__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this\nsection, the method for setting the capitated rate of payment under\ntitle 19 of the federal social security act shall be consistent with the\nmethod used for all managed long term care plans authorized under\nsubdivision eight of section forty-four hundred three-f of the public\nhealth law.\n  3. The commissioner is authorized to seek federal waivers pursuant to\ntitles XVIII and XIX of the federal social security act when such\nwaivers are necessary to develop cost-effective long term care\ndemonstration projects.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>