<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-D-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-D-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2807-D-1"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-D-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-D-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-D-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-D-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2807_D_1">
        <num>2807-D-1</num>
        <heading>Hospital quality contributions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_D_1__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of section\ntwenty-eight hundred seven-d of this article, provided, however, that in\nthe event the commissioner, in consultation with the director of the\nbudget, determines that such quality contribution shall raise less than\nor more than the total quality collection amount set forth in\nsubdivision two of this section, the commissioner, in consultation with\nthe director of the budget, may promulgate regulations, and may\npromulgate emergency regulations, increasing or decreasing such quality\ncontributions by amounts sufficient to ensure the collection of such\nannual quality contribution amount.\n  2. The annual quality contribution amount referenced in subdivision\none of this section shall be thirty million dollars for the state fiscal\nyear beginning April first, two thousand eleven, and for each subsequent\nstate fiscal year thereafter it shall be the amount of the preceding\nyear as increased by the ten year rolling average of the medical\ncomponent of the consumer price index as published by the United States\ndepartment of labor, bureau of labor statistics, for the preceding ten\nyears.\n  3. The quality contributions described in this section shall be\nadministered in accordance with and subject to the provisions of\nsubdivisions four, five, six, seven, eight and twelve of section\ntwenty-eight hundred seven-d of this article, provided, however, that\nsuch quality contributions shall be deposited in the HCRA resources fund\nas established pursuant to section ninety-two-dd of the state finance\nlaw; and provided further, however, that such contributions shall not be\nan allowable cost in the determination of reimbursement rates of payment\ncomputed pursuant to this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>