<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2815-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2815-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2815-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2815-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2815-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2815-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2815-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2815_A">
        <num>2815-A</num>
        <heading>Community health care revolving capital fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2815_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>held by the authority pursuant to this\nsection as custodian pursuant to an agreement with the commissioner\nuntil transferred to the administrator pursuant to this section, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2815_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ninvested by the authority in accordance with the investment guidelines\nof the authority during said custodial period. All investment income\nshall be credited to, and shall be deposited in, the revolving capital\nfund.\n  3. Administration agreement. The commissioner and the authority shall\nenter into an agreement, subject to the approval of the director of the\nbudget, for the purpose of administering the funds in the revolving\ncapital fund through an administrator. A copy of such agreement, and any\namendments thereto, shall be provided to the chair of the senate finance\ncommittee, the director of the division of budget, and the chair of the\nassembly ways and means committee. The agreement shall specify that the\nadministrator shall administer the community health care revolving\ncapital fund in a manner that will benefit the public health by\nencouraging improvements in the community health care delivery system in\nthe state, in compliance with all applicable laws, rules, regulations\nand other requirements.\n  4. Agreement with the administrator. The dormitory authority shall, in\nconsultation with the commissioner, enter into an agreement with the\nadministrator. Such agreement shall provide for the administration of\nthe revolving capital fund administrator, in accordance with the\nrequirements of this section, the commissioner and dormitory authority\nand all applicable laws, rules, regulations and other requirements. Upon\nthe effective date of the agreement, custody of, and responsibility for,\nthe revolving capital fund shall be transferred from the dormitory\nauthority to the administrator, subject to the requirements of the\nagreement. Such agreement shall include, but not be limited to, the\nfollowing provisions:\n  a. That the administrator shall be responsible for the receipt,\nmanagement and expenditure of monies held in the revolving capital fund;\n  b. That the administrator shall maintain books and records pertaining\nto all monies received...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2815_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>eligible costs as described in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2815_A__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, attributable to the proposed\nconstruction, reconstruction, renovation, rehabilitation, refurbishing,\nexpansion, upgrading and equipping of a participating borrower's\ncommunity-based health care facility; (ii) reserves for credit\nenhancement including loan guarantees; (iii) loan loss and debt service\nreserves and subordinated loans; and (iv) facility financing, including\nloans for predevelopment, acquisition and construction, permanent\nfinancing and bridge loans;\n  f. That eligible costs under this section shall include, but not be\nlimited to, all hard construction costs and associated professional and\nother costs, furniture, fixtures and equipment, including health\ninformation technology, acquisition, predevelopment due diligence,\ninitial operating expenses and working capital;\n  g. That the administrator administering the revolving capital fund\nshall report quarterly on the transactions in the revolving capital fund\nin a form and manner specified by the authority in consultation with the\ncommissioner, including but not limited to: receipts or deposits to the\nfund, disbursements, loans or credit enhancement made from the fund,\ninvestment income, and the balance on hand as of the end of the month\nfor each such quarter;\n  h. That the administrator shall be required to invest monies on\ndeposit in the fund in accordance with investment guidelines meeting the\nrequirements of the department and dormitory authority, and all\ninvestment income shall be credited to, and any repayment of loans as\nhereinafter provided shall be deposited in, the revolving capital fund,\nand spent therefrom only for the purposes set forth in this section;\n  i. That only the reasonable expenses of the administrator, as\ndetermined by the commissioner and president of the authority, incurred\nin the establishment and administration of the revolving capital loan\nprogram (including the retention of professionals and consultants, if\nany) may be paid or r...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>