<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2823"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2823"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2823"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2823/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2823/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2823/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2823/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2823">
        <num>2823</num>
        <heading>Supportive housing development program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a unit of local\ngovernment, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a not-for-profit corporation that has been in\nexistence for a period of at least one year prior to application and has\nbeen engaged in supportive housing programs for vulnerable populations.\n  2. Grants provided pursuant to this section shall be used only to fund\nhousing development activities and other general programmatic activities\nto help ensure a stable system of supportive housing for vulnerable\npersons in the community. Reinvestment funds for supportive housing for\nvulnerable populations, which are general fund savings directly related\nto inpatient hospital and nursing home bed decertification and/or\nfacility closure, shall be allocated annually by the commissioner based\nupon the following criteria:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the efficiency and effectiveness of the use of funding for the\ndevelopment of adequate and accessible housing to support vulnerable\npersons in the community and to ensure access to supports necessary to\nmaximize expected outcomes; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>other relevant factors relating to the maintenance of existing\nsupportive housing and the development of new supportive housing and\nassociated services.\n  3. The commissioner shall establish an application process by which\neligible applicants may apply for a grant under this section. The\napplication shall include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the geographic area in which the housing/services shall be\nprovided;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a detailed description of the housing/services to be provided;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a plan for the efficient and effective use of funding for the\ndevelopment of adequate and accessible housing to support vulnerable\npersons in the community;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>other relevant factors relating to the need for maintenance of\nexisting supportive housing and the development of new supportive\nhousing and associated services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2823__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other information that the commissioner deems relevant and\nappropriate.\n  4. Grantees under this section shall file an annual report with the\ncommissioner, in such form and with such information and data as the\ncommissioner prescribes detailing the expenditure of grant funds. In\naddition, the commissioner is authorized and empowered to make\ninspections and examine records of any entity funded pursuant to\nsubdivision two of this section. Such examination shall include all\nmedical, service and financial records, receipts, disbursements,\ncontracts, loans and other moneys relating to the financial operation of\nthe provider.\n  5. The amount of supportive housing development reinvestment funds for\nthe department shall be subject to annual appropriation. The\nmethodologies used to calculate the savings shall be developed by the\ncommissioner and the director of the budget. In no event shall the full\nannual value of supportive housing development reinvestment programs\nattributable to inpatient hospital and nursing home bed decertification\nand/or facility closure exceed the twelve month value of the department\nof health general fund reductions resulting from such decertification\nand/or facility closure.\n  6. The annual supportive housing development reinvestment\nappropriation shall reflect a proportion of the amount of general fund\nsavings resulting from subdivision five of this section. Within any\nfiscal year where appropriation increases are recommended for the\nsupportive housing development reinvestment program, insofar as\nprojected bed decertification and/or facility closures do not occur as\nestimated, and general fund savings do not result, then the reinvestment\nappropriations may be reduced in the next year's annual budget\nitemization.\n  7. No provision in this section shall create or be deemed to create\nany right, interest or entitlement to services or funds that are subject\nto this section, or to any other services or funds, whether t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>