<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2851"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2851"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2851"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2851/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2851/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2851/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2851/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2851">
        <num>2851</num>
        <heading>Policy and purposes of article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2851. Policy and purposes of article. It is hereby declared that a\nserious shortage of safe and sanitary nursing home accommodations for\npersons of low income, whose need for combined nursing care, lodging and\nboard cannot readily be provided by the ordinary unaided operations of\nprivate enterprise, exists in many communities throughout the state;\nthat there is need for non-profit corporations to construct, acquire,\nreconstruct, rehabilitate and improve, with loan participation by the\nNew York state housing finance agency or the New York state medical care\nfacilities finance agency, as the case may be, low cost nursing home\naccommodations, including such other facilities as may be incidental and\nappurtenant thereto, to meet such needs in furtherance of articles\nseventeen and eighteen of the constitution, and for public assistance to\nsuch companies by the granting of tax exemptions; that it is the policy\nof the state to promote the provision of such nursing home\naccommodations and that such provision is a public use and purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>