<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2871"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2871"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2871"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2871/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2871/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2871/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2871/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2871">
        <num>2871</num>
        <heading>Policy and purposes of article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2871. Policy and purposes of article. Many hospitals and other\nhealth facilities throughout the state are becoming obsolete and are no\nlonger adequate to meet the needs of modern medicine. As a result of\nrapid technological changes, such facilities require substantial\nstructural or functional changes.  Others are unsuited for continued use\nby virtue of their location and the physical characteristics of their\nexisting plants and should be replaced. Such inadequate and outmoded\nfacilities deny to the people of the state the benefits of health care\nof the highest quality, efficiently and promptly provided at a\nreasonable cost.  Their replacement and modernization is essential to\nprotect and prolong the lives of the state's population and cannot\nreadily be accomplished by the ordinary unaided operation of private\nenterprise.\n  It is the purpose of this article to encourage the timely construction\nand modernization, including the equipment, of hospital and other health\nfacilities, which are necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of human\ndisease, pain, injury, disability, deformity or physical condition, and\nof facilities incidental or appurtenant thereto, with mortgage loan\nparticipation by the New York state housing finance agency, all in\nfurtherance of article seventeen of the constitution. It is hereby\ndeclared to be the policy of the state to encourage the provision of\nmodern, well-equipped health facilities, and such provision is hereby\ndeclared to be a public use and purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>