<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2896-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2896_A">
        <num>2896-A</num>
        <heading>Board of examiners of nursing home administrators</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2896-a. Board of examiners of nursing home administrators. 1.  There\nshall be within the department a board of examiners of nursing home\nadministrators consisting of thirteen members appointed by the\ncommissioner, all of whom shall be citizens of the United States and\nresidents of the state of New York. The board shall be composed of one\nphysician, one hospital administrator, one professional registered\nnurse, three nursing home administrators employed in proprietary nursing\nhomes and three nursing home administrators employed in voluntary\nnursing homes, each of whom shall have not less than five years'\nexperience in the care of chronically ill or infirm aged patients. Three\nmembers shall be representative of the public and one member shall be\nappointed from a college providing training for nursing home\nadministrators. A member's term shall expire upon a change of status.\nEach member appointed from a profession requiring licensure or\nregistration to practice in the state shall be licensed or registered\nexcept for those nursing home administrators first appointed to the\nboard who shall be required only to possess the qualifications and be\neligible for licensure as required by this article.\n  2. The term of office of the members shall be three years; provided\nhowever, that of the members first appointed, three shall be appointed\nfor a term which shall expire on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred\nseventy-one; four for a term which shall expire on June thirtieth,\nnineteen hundred seventy-two; and four for a term which shall expire on\nJune thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-three; and provided however,\nthat of the members first appointed on the expansion of the board to\nthirteen members, one shall be appointed for a term which shall expire\non June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-four; and one for a term\nwhich shall expire on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-six.  No\nmember shall serve for more than two consecutive terms.  Before entering\nupon his term of office every board member shall file with the secretary\nof state the constitutional oath of office.  Vacancies in the membership\nof the board, however created, shall be filled in the manner of the\noriginal appointment by the commissioner for the unexpired term. Any\nmember may be removed by the commissioner for misconduct, incapacity,\nincompetence, or neglect of duty.\n  3. Each member of the board shall receive a per diem allowance as\ndetermined by the commissioner for the time spent in the performance of\nhis official duties and shall be reimbursed for all proper traveling and\nincidental expenses in carrying out the provisions of this article.\n  4. The commissioner shall designate an officer or employee of the\ndepartment to act as secretary to the board, who shall not be a member\nof the board.\n  5. The board at its first meeting to be held within thirty days after\nappointment, and annually thereafter at its first meeting in each year,\nshall organize and elect from its members a chairman.\n  6. The board, for the purpose of transacting its business, shall meet\nat least once every six months at times and places designated by\nresolution. Special meetings also may be held at such times as the board\nmay elect, or on the call of the commissioner. A written notice of the\ntime, place and purpose of any special meeting shall be mailed by the\nsecretary to all members of the board at least fifteen days before the\ndate of the meeting.\n  7. A majority of the members of the board shall constitute a quorum\nfor the transaction of business at any meeting.\n  8. The commissioner shall establish an advisory council, broadly\nrepresentative of the health professions and the public, to provide such\ntechnical assistance as the board or the commissioner shall request.\nMembers shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for\nexpenses actually and necessarily incurred in the performance of their\nduties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>