<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2896-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2896-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2896_G">
        <num>2896-G</num>
        <heading>Registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2896-g. Registration. 1. Every licensee must register biennially\nwith the department. The department shall mail to every person who has\nreceived a license under this article an application form for\nregistration requesting such information as the board and the\ncommissioner may require. Such licensee shall promptly fill out, sign\nand forward such application to the department, together with a fee of\nforty dollars; however, initial registration shall not require such fee.\nUpon receipt and approval of such application and fee, the department\nshall issue a certificate of biennial registration. The commissioner\nshall establish by rule and regulation the beginning date of the\nbiennial registration period.  In the event that a change in the\nestablished beginning date of the biennial registration period requires\nan adjustment in the duration of a registration period, there shall be a\nproportionate adjustment in the prescribed fee.\n  2. Licensees who apply for registration subsequent to the first year\nof any biennial registration period shall pay a fee of twenty dollars;\nhowever, initial registration shall not require such fee; upon receipt\nand approval of such application and fee, the department shall issue a\ncertificate of registration for the balance of the biennial registration\nperiod.\n  3. Registration subsequent to the thirty-first day of December,\nnineteen hundred seventy-three, shall require satisfactory completion of\nsuch continuation education programs or courses of study as the board\nshall determine are required to assure the licensee's retention of\nprofessional competence in nursing home administration and development\nof necessary different, new or advanced nursing home administration\nskills and techniques.\n  4. A nursing home administrator who fails or neglects to apply for\nregistration before the first day of the next ensuing biennial\nregistration period as required by the provisions of this section shall\nbe required to pay for registration an additional fee of five dollars\nfor each month or part thereof that he is in default, provided, however,\nthat the additional fee shall not be more than one hundred twenty\ndollars.\n  5. A practicing nursing home administrator who fails to apply and\nqualify for registration before the first day of the next ensuing\nbiennial registration period, shall be an illegal practitioner whose\nlicense may be suspended or revoked and who may be subjected to a civil\npenalty, censured or reprimanded by the board in accordance with the\nprovisions of this article.\n  6. No person shall be entitled to register as a nursing home\nadministrator unless he shall hold a license as provided for in this\narticle. Every unrevoked certificate of registration issued as provided\nin this article shall be presumptive evidence in all courts and places\nthat the person named therein is legally registered.\n  7. A nursing home administrator who has been heretofore duly licensed\nand registered to practice in this state whose license shall not have\nbeen revoked or suspended, and who either before or after registration,\nas required by this section, shall have temporarily abandoned the\npractice of nursing home administration and surrendered his registration\ncertificate, may reregister within this state upon complying with the\nprovisions of this section for registration, including payment of any\nfees due as of the date of surrender.\n  8. Upon receipt of satisfactory evidence that a certificate of\nregistration has been lost, mutilated or destroyed, the department may\nissue a duplicate certificate upon such terms and conditions as the\nboard shall prescribe with the approval of the commissioner, and upon\nthe payment of a fee of ten dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>