<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-290"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-290"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="290"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-290/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-290/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-290/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-290/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_290">
        <num>290</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person, company, corporation or\nother entity that is registered with the United States Drug Enforcement\nAdministration to collect controlled substances for the purposes of safe\ndisposal and destruction;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a law enforcement agency; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person,\ncompany, corporation or other entity authorized by the department to\nprovide alternative collection methods for covered drugs that are not\ncontrolled substances.\n  2. "Covered drug" means any substance recognized as a drug under 21\nUSC ยง 321</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_290__subsec_g__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, as amended, and any regulations promulgated thereunder\nthat is sold, offered for sale or dispensed in the state, whether\ndirectly or through a wholesaler, in any form including prescription and\nnonprescription drugs, drugs in medical devices and combination\nproducts, brand and generic drugs and drugs for veterinary use; provided\nhowever, covered drug shall not include:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>vitamins or supplements;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>herbal-based remedies and homeopathic drugs, products or remedies;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>cosmetics, soap (with or without germicidal agents), laundry\ndetergent, bleach, household cleaning products, shampoos, sunscreens,\ntoothpaste, lip balm, antiperspirants or other personal care products\nthat are regulated as both cosmetics and nonprescription drugs under the\nFederal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pet pesticide products\ncontained in pet collars, powders, shampoos, topical applications, or\nother forms;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>drugs that are biological products as defined in\nsubdivision twenty-seven of section sixty-eight hundred two of the\neducation law if the manufacturer already provides a take back program;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>drugs for which a manufacturer provides a take back program as part\nof a Federal Food and Drug Administration managed risk evaluation and\nmitigation strategy;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>emptied injector products or emptied medical\ndevices and their component parts or accessories; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_290__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>drugs that are\nused solely in a clinical setting.\n  3. "Manufacturer" means a person, company, corporation or other entity\nengaged in the manufacture of covered drugs sold in the state.\nManufacturer does not include a repackager or wholesaler.\n  4. "Pharmacies" means all pharmacies registered under section\nsixty-eight hundred eight of the education law that are part of a group\nof ten or more establishments that conduct business under the same name,\nor operate under a common ownership or management, or pursuant to a\nfranchise agreement with the same franchisor, and all nonresident\npharmacies registered pursuant to section sixty-eight hundred eight-b of\nthe education law that provide covered drugs to state residents by mail.\n  5. "Drug take back organization" means an organization designated by a\nmanufacturer or a group of manufacturers to act as an agent on behalf of\nthe manufacturer or group of manufacturers to operate and implement a\ndrug take back program as authorized by this article.\n  6. "Wholesaler" means any person, company, corporation or other entity\nthat sells or distributes drugs and covered drugs for resale to an\nentity in the state other than a consumer.\n  7. "Repackager" means an entity that owns or operates an establishment\nthat repacks and relabels a product or package containing a covered drug\nfor further sale or for distribution without further transaction.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>