<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2904-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2904-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2904-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2904-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2904-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2904-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2904-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2904_C">
        <num>2904-C</num>
        <heading>Regional nominating committees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2904-c. Regional nominating committees. 1. There are hereby\ncreated eight regional nominating committees. The eight regional\nnominating committees shall operate within defined geographic boundaries\nconsistent with the eight health systems agencies established pursuant\nto section two thousand nine hundred four-b of this article.\n  2. Each nominating committee shall consist of eleven members who shall\nbe residents of each respective region and who have demonstrated an\ninterest in regional health affairs. The members shall be appointed as\nfollows: five shall be appointed by the governor; two by the temporary\npresident of the senate; two by the speaker of the assembly; one by the\nminority leader of the senate; and one by the minority leader of the\nassembly. Two of the members initially appointed by the governor, shall\neach serve an initial term ending December thirty-first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-eight. One of the members initially appointed by the\ntemporary president of the senate and one of the members initially\nappointed by the speaker of the assembly shall each serve for an initial\nterm ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight. The\nseven remaining members, shall each serve an initial term ending\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-nine.\n  3. The members shall designate one of their number to serve as chair\nfor a period of two years or until his term of office expires, whichever\nperiod is shorter. A vacancy occurring for any reasons other than by\nexpiration of term shall be filled by the appointing officer for the\nremainder of the unexpired term. Six members of a committee shall\nconstitute a quorum.\n  4. A regional nominating committee shall approve members of the board\nof directors to the health systems agency as submitted by such health\nsystems agency pursuant to section twenty-nine hundred four-b of this\narticle as members' terms expire or vacancies occur on or after January\nfirst, nineteen hundred ninety-four. Approval for membership on the\nboard of directors of such agency shall require the concurrence of six\nmembers of a committee. Nominations submitted by the health systems\nagencies to such nominating committee and subsequent approvals of such\nnominations to the health systems agencies shall be released to the\npublic by the committee at the time of such submission or approval. A\nregional nominating committee shall take no longer than forty-five days\nto approve or disapprove agency board of director nominations. Such\napproval shall be in writing, and shall include the findings of the\ncommittee relating to the experience and aptitude for the agency\nposition of each candidate. The committee shall notify the governor, the\ntemporary president of the senate, and the speaker of the assembly and\nthe commissioner concerning all approvals to the agencies including the\naptitude and experience of the agency members.\n  5. Health systems agencies shall provide administrative support to the\nrespective regional nominating committee.\n  6. The committee shall undertake such other activities as are\nnecessary to carry out their functions pursuant to this article.\n  * NB Expired June 30, 1996\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>