<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-291"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-291"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="291"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-291/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-291/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-291/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-291/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_291">
        <num>291</num>
        <heading>Drug take back</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>operate a drug take back program approved by the department\nindividually or jointly with other manufacturers;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>enter into an agreement with a drug take back organization which\nshall operate a drug take back program approved by the department; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>enter into an agreement with the department to operate a drug take\nback program on its behalf.\n  2. Any manufacturer of a covered drug, individually or jointly, or a\ndrug take back organization contracted by a manufacturer of a covered\ndrug shall within one hundred eighty days from the effective date of\nthis section submit to the department, in a manner and form determined\nby the department, a proposed drug take back program that meets, at a\nminimum, the following requirements:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certifies the drug take back program will accept all covered drugs\nregardless of who produced them;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provides contact information for the person submitting the planned\ndrug take back program with whom the department shall direct all\ninquiries;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Details a collection system to provide convenient, ongoing\ncollection services to all persons seeking to dispose of covered drugs\npursuant to section two hundred ninety-two of this article that is\ngeographically distributed in a way to ensure access in rural and\nunderserved areas;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Describes other collection methods by which covered drugs will be\ncollected by authorized collectors;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Explains how covered drugs will be safely and securely tracked and\nhandled from collection through final disposal and destruction, policies\nto ensure security and compliance with all applicable laws and\nregulations including disposal and destruction at a permitted waste\ndisposal facility meeting federal requirements;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Describes the public education and outreach activities that will\nbe undertaken which shall include advertising of collection locations on\na website and through use of signage and other written materials, and\nhow effectiveness will be evaluated;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Details how the costs of pharmacy collection and other authorized\ncollectors will be reimbursed which shall include costs retroactive to\nthe effective date of this article, and where more than one manufacturer\nwill be involved in the planned drug take back program, a plan for the\nfair and reasonable manner of allocated costs among the participants in\nsuch program such that the costs paid by each manufacturer is reasonably\nrelated to the volume or value of covered drugs sold in the state; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_291__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provides any further information deemed appropriate by the\ndepartment.\n  3. Within thirty days of the effective date of this section, each\nwholesaler that sells covered drugs in or into the state shall provide\nthe department with a list of manufacturers that produce covered drugs.\nThe department may request updated lists at its discretion.\n  4. A manufacturer, individually or jointly, must pay all\nadministrative and operational fees associated with the drug take back\nprogram, including the cost of collecting, transporting and disposing of\ncovered drugs from pharmacies and other authorized collectors and the\nrecycling or disposal, or both, of packing collected with the covered\ndrug.  Manufacturers shall also pay costs incurred by the state in the\nadministration and enforcement of the drug take back program. Exclusive\nof fines and penalties, the state shall only recover its actual cost of\nadministration and enforcement. In instances where manufacturers jointly\nconduct a drug take back program, the costs of administration and\nenforcement shall be fairly and reasonably allocated such that the\nportion of costs is reasonably related to the volume or value of covered\ndrugs the manufacturers sell in the state. No manufacturer may charge a\npoint-of-sale or other fee to consumers, or a fee that could be passed\non to consumers, to recoup the cost of their drug take back program.\n  5. Within sixty days of receipt of a proposed drug take back program,\nthe department, in consultation with the department of environmental\nconservation, shall determine whether such proposed drug take back\nprogram complies with the requirements of this article and notify the\napplicant. The department may conduct a noticed public hearing prior to\napproval. If the drug take back program is approved, the department\nshall notify the applicant in writing. If the drug take back program is\nnot approved, the department shall notify the applicant in writing and\nthe applicant shall...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>