<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-292"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-292"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="292"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-292/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-292/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-292/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-292/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_292">
        <num>292</num>
        <heading>Collection</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Offering drug collection by one or more of the following methods:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On-site collection, dropbox, or receptacle meeting federal\nstandards;\n  (ii) Mail-back collection by prepaid envelopes as authorized by\nfederal law and regulation; or\n  (iii) Other federal drug enforcement agency approved methods of\ncollection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Signage prominently displayed advertising such drug collection to\nconsumers.\n  2. All drug take back program operators shall notify other potential\nauthorized collectors of the opportunity to serve as an authorized\ncollector for the drug take back program. Participation of authorized\ncollectors besides pharmacies shall be voluntary.\n  3. All costs of pharmacies and other authorized collectors shall be\npaid or reimbursed by the manufacturer, jointly or individually, as part\nof the drug take back programs required by this article.\n  4. For any city with a population of one hundred twenty-five thousand\nor more as of the last decennial census, the commissioner shall\nestablish by regulation a distribution plan that ensures that on-site\ncollection receptacle or dropbox placement shall be reasonably\naccessible to all residents and that provides for program cost\nefficiency.\n  5. Pharmacies providing for mail-back collection as part of the drug\ntake back program shall provide a voucher for a prepaid envelope upon\ndispensing a covered drug. Such voucher shall include information on\ndrug take back and safe drug disposal methods.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>