<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2958"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2958"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2958"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2958/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2958/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2958/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2958/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2958">
        <num>2958</num>
        <heading>Rural health care access development program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2958__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The hospital shall be at substantial risk of financial failure,\nusing a combination of generally accepted standard measures of financial\nviability and which is:\n  A. a federally designated sole community hospital or a rural referral\ncenter and is both a federally designated rural hospital and is\nclassified as a state rural hospital;\n  B. a federally designated sole community hospital or a rural referral\ncenter and is a federally designated rural hospital;\n  C. both a federally designated rural hospital and is classified as a\nstate rural hospital, but is not a sole community hospital or a rural\nreferral center;\n  D. either a federally designated rural hospital or is classified as a\nstate rural hospital; or\n  E. the hospital is either a federally defined sole community hospital\nor rural referral center.\n  (ii) The hospital is a sole community hospital or a rural referral\ncenter and is both a federally designated rural hospital and is\nclassified as a state rural hospital;\n  (iii) The hospital is a sole community hospital or a rural referral\ncenter and is a federally designated rural hospital, but is not\nclassified as a state rural hospital;\n  (iv) The hospital is both a federally designated rural hospital and is\nclassified as a state rural hospital but is not a sole community\nhospital or a rural referral center;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2958__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The hospital is either a federally designated rural hospital or is\nclassified as a state rural hospital; or\n  (vi) The hospital is either a federally defined sole community\nhospital or a rural referral center.\n  c. The commissioner may include in regulation a factor to enhance the\ndistribution to those hospitals that have taken actions in accordance\nwith the goals specified in paragraph b of this subdivision to be\napplied effective January first, two thousand one, except, however, in\nno event shall the distribution of the funds be delayed because of the\ndevelopment of the factor pursuant to this paragraph.\n  3. The commissioner shall cause reports to be prepared and submitted\nby rural hospitals at such times and in such manner as are consistent\nwith the purposes of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>