<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-03-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2994-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2994_A">
        <num>2994-A</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is formally a party in a domestic partnership or similar\nrelationship with the other person, entered into pursuant to the laws of\nthe United States or of any state, local or foreign jurisdiction, or\nregistered as the domestic partner of the other person with any registry\nmaintained by the employer of either party or any state, municipality,\nor foreign jurisdiction; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is formally recognized as a beneficiary or covered person under\nthe other person's employment benefits or health insurance; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is dependent or mutually interdependent on the other person for\nsupport, as evidenced by the totality of the circumstances indicating a\nmutual intent to be domestic partners including but not limited to:\ncommon ownership or joint leasing of real or personal property; common\nhouseholding, shared income or shared expenses; children in common;\nsigns of intent to marry or become domestic partners under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nor</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision; or the length of the personal relationship\nof the persons.\n  Each party to a domestic partnership shall be considered to be the\ndomestic partner of the other party. "Domestic partner" shall not\ninclude a person who is related to the other person by blood in a manner\nthat would bar marriage to the other person in New York state. "Domestic\npartner" also shall not include any person who is less than eighteen\nyears of age or who is the adopted child of the other person or who is\nrelated by blood in a manner that would bar marriage in New York state\nto a person who is the lawful spouse of the other person.\n  8. "Emancipated minor patient" means a minor patient who is the parent\nof a child, or who is sixteen years of age or older and living\nindependently from his or her parents or guardian.\n  9. "Ethics review committee" means the interdisciplinary committee\nestablished in accordance with the requirements of section twenty-nine\nhundred ninety-four-m of this article.\n  10. "General hospital" means a general hospital as defined in\nsubdivision ten of section twenty-eight hundred one of this chapter\nexcluding a ward, wing, unit or other part of a general hospital\noperated for the purpose of providing services for persons with mental\nillness pursuant to an operating certificate issued by the commissioner\nof mental health.\n  11. "Guardian of a minor" or "guardian" means a health care guardian\nor a legal guardian of the person of a minor.\n  12. "Health care" means any treatment, service, or procedure to\ndiagnose or treat an individual's physical or mental condition.\nProviding nutrition or hydration orally, without reliance on medical\ntreatment, is not health care under this article and is not subject to\nthis article.\n  13. "Health care agent" means a health care agent designated by an\nadult pursuant to article twenty-nine-C of this chapter.\n  14. "Health care decision" means any decision to consent or refuse to\nconsent to heal...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>