<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2995-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2995-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2995-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2995-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2995-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2995-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2995-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2995_B">
        <num>2995-B</num>
        <heading>Hospital report cards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Utilization and performance information to promote quality\nimprovement activities which was collected and evaluated for appropriate\ndissemination pursuant to subparagraph (ii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of the former section twenty-eight hundred seven-n of\nthis chapter, as added by section sixty of chapter six hundred\nthirty-nine of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-six;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Statewide performance data comparing utilization and selected\nperformance measures to accepted norms and/or benchmarks developed by\nrecognized experts, which were developed pursuant to subparagraph (iii)\nof paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of the former section twenty-eight\nhundred seven-n of this chapter, as added by section sixty of chapter\nsix hundred thirty-nine of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-six; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Other hospital data, if any, collected for public dissemination by\nthe state task force on health care quality improvement pursuant to the\nformer section twenty-eight hundred four-b of this chapter, as added by\nsection sixty-a of chapter six hundred thirty-nine of the laws of\nnineteen hundred ninety-six.\n  2. Preparation of data and public review. The department shall\nthereafter prepare and risk-adjust as appropriate the collected hospital\ndata for dissemination pursuant to the former subparagraph (iii) of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section twenty-eight hundred four-b\nof this chapter, as added by section sixty-a of chapter six hundred\nthirty-nine of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-six. The department\nshall coordinate its efforts with programs of the national forum for\nhealth care quality measurement and reporting (quality forum). The\ndepartment shall provide each hospital with a copy of the hospital data\nto be disseminated concerning it. In a manner and time required by the\ndepartment, the hospital shall be provided with an opportunity to\ncorrect factual inaccuracies, and to file a statement in a form\nprescribed by the department concerning the data, which statement shall\nbe disseminated with such data.\n  3. Dissemination. The department shall thereafter disseminate the\ncollected hospital data, with corrections and statements, if any.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Thereafter, the hospital data so disseminated shall be updated at\nregular intervals to be determined by the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All hospital data disseminated shall include the following\nstatement: "THE DATA COLLECTED BY THE DEPARTMENT IS ACCURATE TO THE BEST\nOF THE KNOWLEDGE OF THE DEPARTMENT, BASED ON THE INFORMATION SUPPLIED BY\nTHE HOSPITAL WHICH IS THE SUBJECT OF THE DATA."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2995_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the department determines that any data to be disseminated\npursuant to this section is not useful for making quality\ndeterminations, the department shall recommend to the legislature the\nnecessary statutory changes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>