<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-JJ"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-JJ"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2999-JJ"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-JJ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-JJ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-JJ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-JJ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2999_JJ">
        <num>2999-JJ</num>
        <heading>Registration of temporary health care services agencies; requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The names and addresses of the temporary health care services\nagency controlling person or persons.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The names and addresses of health care entities where the\ncontrolling person or persons or their family members:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have an ownership relationship; or\n  (ii) direct the management or policies of such health care entities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A demonstration that the applicant is of good moral character and\nable to comply with all applicable state laws and regulations relating\nto the activities in which it intends to engage under the registration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Registration and registration annual renewal fees of one thousand\ndollars and shall only be used for the purpose of operating this\nregistry.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state of incorporation of the agency.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any additional information that the commissioner determines is\nnecessary to properly evaluate an application for registration.\n  3. As a condition of registration, a temporary health care services\nagency:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall document that each individual engaged to provide health care\nservices to health care entities currently meets the minimum licensing,\ntraining, and continuing education standards for the position in which\nthe health care personnel will be working.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall comply with all pertinent requirements and qualifications\nfor personnel employed in health care entities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall not restrict in any manner the employment opportunities of\nits health care personnel.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall not require the payment of liquidated damages, employment\nfees, or other compensation should the health care personnel be hired as\na permanent employee of a health care entity in any contract with any\nhealth care personnel or health care entity or otherwise.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall retain all records related to health care personnel for six\ncalendar years and make them available to the department upon request.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall comply with any requests made by the department to examine\nthe books and records of the agency, subpoena witnesses and documents\nand make such other investigation as is necessary in the event that the\ndepartment has reason to believe that the books or records do not\naccurately reflect the financial condition or financial transactions of\nthe agency.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_JJ__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall comply with any additional requirements the department may\ndeem necessary.\n  4. A registration issued by the commissioner according to this section\nshall be effective for a period of one year, unless the registration is\nrevoked or suspended, or unless ownership interest of ten percent or\nmore, or management of the temporary health care services agency, is\nsold or transferred. When ownership interest of ten percent or more, or\nmanagement of a temporary health care services agency is sold or\ntransferred, the registration of the agency may be transferred to the\nnew owner or operator for thirty days, or until the new owner or\noperator applies and is granted or denied a new registration, whichever\nis sooner.\n  5. The commissioner may, after appropriate notice and hearing,\nsuspend, revoke, or refuse to issue or renew any registration or issue\nany fines established pursuant to section twenty-nine hundred\nninety-nine-ll of this article if the applicant fails to comply with\nthis article or any guidelines, rules and regulations promulgated\nthereunder.\n  6. The commissioner shall make available a list of temporary health\ncare services agencies registered with the department on the\ndepartment's public website.\n  7. The department shall publish a quarterly report containing\naggregated and de-identified data collected pursuant to this article on\nthe department's website.\n  8. The department, in consultation with the department of labor, shall\nprovide a report to the governor and legislature on or before January\nfirst, two thousand twenty-four, summarizing the key findings of the\ndata collected pursuant to this article. The department shall further\nhave authority to utilize any data collected pursuant to this article\nfor additional purposes consistent with this chapter, including but not\nlimited to determinations of whether an acute labor shortage exists, or\nany other purpose the department deems necessary for health care related\ndata purposes...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>