<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3004-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3004-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3004-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3004-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3004-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3004-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3004-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3004_A">
        <num>3004-A</num>
        <heading>Regional emergency medical advisory committees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3004-a. Regional emergency medical advisory committees. 1. Regional\nemergency medical advisory committees shall develop policies,\nprocedures, and triage, treatment, and transportation protocols which\nare consistent with the standards of the state emergency medical\nadvisory committee and which address specific local conditions.\nRegional emergency medical advisory committees may also approve\nphysicians to provide on line medical control, coordinate the\ndevelopment of regional medical control systems, and participate in\nquality improvement activities addressing system-wide concerns.\nHospitals and prehospital medical care services shall be authorized to\nrelease patient outcome information to regional emergency medical\nadvisory committees for purposes of assessing prehospital care concerns.\nRegional quality improvement programs shall be presumed to be an\nextension of the quality improvement program set forth in section three\nthousand six of this article, and the provisions of subdivisions two and\nthree of such section three thousand six shall apply to such programs.\n  2. The committee shall nominate to the commissioner a physician with\ndemonstrated knowledge and experience in emergency medical services to\nserve on the state emergency medical advisory committee.\n  3. No civil action shall be brought in any court against any member,\nofficer or employee of the committee for any act done, failure to act,\nor statement or opinion made, while discharging his or her duties as a\nmember, officer, or employee of the committee, without leave from a\njustice of the supreme court, first had and obtained.  In no event shall\nsuch member, officer, or employee be liable for damages in any such\naction if he or she shall have acted in good faith, with reasonable care\nand upon probable cause.\n  4. Any decision of a regional emergency medical advisory committee\nregarding provision of a level of care, including staffing requirements,\nmay be appealed to the state emergency medical advisory committee by any\nregional EMS council, ambulance service, advanced life support service,\ncertified first responder, emergency medical technician, or advanced\nemergency medical technician adversely affected.  No action shall be\ntaken to implement a decision regarding existing levels of care or\nstaffing while an appeal of such decision is pending. Any decision of\nthe state emergency medical advisory committee may be appealed pursuant\nto subdivision two-a of section three thousand two-a of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>