<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3005-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3005-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3005-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3005-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3005-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3005-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3005-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3005_B">
        <num>3005-B</num>
        <heading>Emergency medical technician five year re-certification demonstration program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3005-b. Emergency medical technician five year re-certification\ndemonstration program. 1. There is hereby created within the department\na demonstration program (referred to in this section as the "program")\nto allow emergency medical technicians and advanced emergency medical\ntechnicians who have been in continuous practice and who have\ndemonstrated competence in applicable behavioral and performance\nobjectives, to be re-certified for a five year period. No person shall\nbe re-certified under the program unless he or she has completed at\nleast one hundred thirty hours of instruction in emergency medical\nservices as approved by the commissioner including but not limited to\npediatrics, geriatrics, environmental emergencies, legal issues,\nemergency vehicle operations course and medical emergencies. Renewals of\ncertification under the program shall be deemed equivalent to renewals\nunder subdivision two of section three thousand two of this article.\n  2. The program shall be limited to persons who are employed by the New\nYork city fire department or who are in practice in the following\ncounties: Delaware, Fulton, Hamilton, Montgomery, Nassau, Otsego,\nSchoharie or Suffolk. The commissioner may limit the number of\nparticipants in the program, except that such limit shall be no less\nthan four thousand participants.\n  3. Within a year after implementing the program and annually\nthereafter, the commissioner shall report to the governor and the\nlegislature on the impact of the program on the quality of patient care\nand the effectiveness of the program in retaining and recruiting\ncertified emergency medical technicians and advanced emergency medical\ntechnicians.\n  4. The commissioner, in consultation with the state emergency medical\nservices council, shall make regulations necessary to implement this\nsection.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2028\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>