<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3061"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3061"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3061"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3061/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3061/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3061/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3061/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3061">
        <num>3061</num>
        <heading>Declaration of purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3061. Declaration of purpose. Trauma is the leading cause of death\nand disability during the first four decades of life. In the aftermath\nof the events of September eleventh, two thousand one, the medical\nresponse to natural and man-made disasters is also recognized as a\npublic concern of the highest order. The furnishing of emergency\nmedical, trauma, and disaster care is therefore a matter of vital\nconcern affecting the public health, safety and welfare. Emergency\nmedical, trauma, and disaster care, the planning and coordination of\nsuch care between prehospital and inhospital personnel and collaborating\npublic health, safety, and welfare officials, the quality management and\nreview of such care, and the development and maintenance of a statewide\nsystem for interfacility transfer, including but not limited to\naeromedical transport, of critically ill or injured patients between\ngeneral hospitals and other health care facilities, are essential public\nhealth services. It is the purpose of this article to promote the public\nhealth, safety and welfare by providing for development and maintenance\nof systems for emergency medical, trauma, and disaster care, and for\nexpeditious transfer of patients in need of such care to facilities\nappropriately staffed and equipped to provide this care in a timely and\neffective manner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>