<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3064"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3064"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3064"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3064/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3064/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3064/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3064/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3064">
        <num>3064</num>
        <heading>State trauma advisory committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3064. State trauma advisory committee. 1. There is hereby continued\nin the department the state trauma advisory committee. It shall consist\nof trauma surgeons, trauma nurses, emergency physicians, emergency\nnurses, and other emergency medical and trauma care professionals\nappointed by the commissioner. It shall be representative of each\ngeographic area of the state and those medical and nursing specialties\nand subspecialties regularly involved in trauma care. It shall advise\nthe department and the commissioner regarding trauma and disaster care\nwithin the state, and assist the department and the commissioner in the\ncoordination of trauma and disaster care, including but not limited to,\nthe development, periodic revision, and application of statewide\nappropriateness review standards, quality improvement guidelines for\ntrauma and disaster care, trauma systems, trauma centers and trauma\nstations, in a manner consistent with the intent and provisions of\nsections twenty-eight hundred five-j and three thousand two-a of this\nchapter, and similar advisory guidelines for trauma and disaster care\nwith the consent of the commissioner, which shall not have the force and\neffect of law unless adopted as rules and regulations by the state\nhospital review and planning council, subject to approval by the\ncommissioner. The commissioner shall appoint a physician to chair the\ncommittee.\n  2. The state trauma advisory committee shall continue to meet as\nfrequently as its business may require. The members of the state trauma\nadvisory committee shall receive no compensation for their services as\nmembers, but each shall be allowed the necessary and actual expenses\nincurred in the performance of his or her duties under this section.\n  3. The commissioner shall designate an officer or employee of the\ndepartment to assist the state trauma advisory committee in the\nperformance of its duties under this section.\n  4. In no event shall any member, officer, or employee of the state\ntrauma advisory committee be liable for damages in any civil action for\nany act done, failure to act, or statement or opinion made, while\ndischarging his or her duties as a member, officer, or employee of the\nstate trauma advisory committee if he or she shall have acted in good\nfaith, with reasonable care.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>