<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3074"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3074"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3074"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3074/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3074/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3074/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3074/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3074">
        <num>3074</num>
        <heading>State emergency medical services for children advisory committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3074. State emergency medical services for children advisory\ncommittee. 1. There is hereby continued in the department the state\nemergency medical services for children advisory committee. It shall\nconsist of child health professionals and child health advocates\nrepresentative of all geographic areas of the state and of those\noccupations regularly involved in the care of children with emergency\nhealth care needs. Its members shall include, but not necessarily be\nlimited to, a pediatric emergency medicine physician and nurse, a\npediatric critical care physician and nurse, a pediatric surgeon, a\npediatric physiatrist, a pediatric primary care physician, an emergency\nmedicine physician, a pediatric emergency medical services physician, a\npediatric toxicologist physician, a prehospital care provider, a school\nnurse, a hospital administrator, the parent of a previously ill or\ninjured child, and the parent of a child with special health care needs,\nappointed by the commissioner upon recommendation of the appropriate\nstatewide professional or parental organizations for terms of four\nyears, which may be renewed. It shall advise the department, the\ncommissioner, the state emergency medical services council, the state\nemergency medical advisory committee, and the state trauma advisory\ncommittee regarding all aspects of emergency medical services for\nchildren, including, but not necessarily limited to, pediatric emergency\nmedical, trauma, and disaster care, and the early care of maltreated\nchildren and children with special health care needs. The state\nemergency medical services director, the state emergency medical\nservices medical director, the state emergency medical services for\nchildren program director, the state emergency medical services for\nchildren program coordinator, the state trauma medical director, the\nstate trauma program manager, the governor's highway traffic safety\nadministrator, and the state emergency medical services for children\ndata manager, shall also serve as nonvoting members ex officio. The\ncommissioner shall appoint a physician to chair the committee.\n  2. The state emergency medical services for children advisory\ncommittee shall meet as frequently as its business may require, but\nordinarily no less than quarterly. The members of the state emergency\nmedical services for children advisory committee shall receive no\ncompensation for their services as members, but each shall be allowed\nthe necessary and actual expenses incurred in the performance of his or\nher duties under this section.\n  3. The commissioner shall designate an officer or employee of the\ndepartment to assist the state emergency medical services for children\nadvisory committee in the performance of its duties under this section,\nto coordinate the activities of the state emergency medical services for\nchildren program and to facilitate communication with the state\nemergency medical services council, the state emergency medical advisory\ncommittee, and the state trauma advisory committee.\n  4. In no event shall any member, officer, or employee of the state\nemergency medical services for children advisory committee be liable for\ndamages in any civil action for any act done, failure to act, or\nstatement or opinion made, while discharging his or her duties as a\nmember, officer, or employee of the state emergency medical services for\nchildren advisory committee if he or she shall have acted in good faith,\nwith reasonable care.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>