<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3302"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3302"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3302"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3302">
        <num>3302</num>
        <heading>Definitions of terms of general use in this article</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>substances recognized as drugs in the official United States\nPharmacopoeia, official Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States,\nor official National Formulary, or any supplement to any of them;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>substances intended for use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation,\ntreatment, or prevention of disease in man or animals; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>substances (other than food) intended to affect the structure or a\nfunction of the body of man or animal. It does not include devices or\ntheir components, parts, or accessories.\n  13. "Federal agency" means the Drug Enforcement Administration, United\nStates Department of Justice, or its successor agency.\n  14. "Federal controlled substances act" means the Comprehensive Drug\nAbuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970, Public Law 91-513, and any act\nor acts amendatory or supplemental thereto or regulations promulgated\nthereunder.\n  15. "Federal registration number" means such number assigned by the\nFederal agency to any person authorized to manufacture, distribute,\nsell, dispense or administer controlled substances.\n  16. "Habitual user" means any person who is, or by reason of repeated\nuse of any controlled substance for non-legitimate or unlawful use is in\ndanger of becoming, dependent upon such substance.\n  17. "Institutional dispenser" means a hospital, veterinary hospital,\nclinic, dispensary, maternity home, nursing home, mental hospital or\nsimilar facility approved and certified by the department as authorized\nto obtain controlled substances by distribution and to dispense and\nadminister such substances pursuant to the order of a practitioner.\n  18. "License" means a written authorization issued by the department\nor the New York state department of education permitting persons to\nengage in a specified activity with respect to controlled substances.\n  19. "Manufacture" means the production, preparation, propagation,\ncompounding, cultivation, conversion or processing of a controlled\nsubstance, either directly or indirectly or by extraction from\nsubstances of natural origin, or independently by means of chemical\nsynthesis, or by a combination of extraction and chemical synthesis, and\nincludes any packaging or repackaging of the substance or labeling or\nrelabeling of its container, except that this term does not include the\npreparation, c...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a practitioner as an incident to his administering or\ndispensing of a controlled substance in the course of his professional\npractice; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a practitioner, or by his authorized agent under his\nsupervision, for the purpose of, or as an incident to, research,\nteaching, or chemical analysis and not for sale; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a pharmacist as an incident to his dispensing of a controlled\nsubstance in the course of his professional practice.\n  20. "Narcotic drug" means any of the following, whether produced\ndirectly or indirectly by extraction from substances of vegetable\norigin, or independently by means of chemical synthesis, or by a\ncombination of extraction and chemical synthesis:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>opium and opiate, and any salt, compound, derivative, or\npreparation of opium or opiate;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any salt, compound, isomer, derivative, or preparation thereof\nwhich is chemically equivalent or identical with any of the substances\nreferred to in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, but not including the\nisoquinoline alkaloids of opium;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>opium poppy and poppy straw.\n  21. "Opiate" means any substance having an addiction-forming or\naddiction-sustaining liability similar to morphine or being capable of\nconversion into a drug having addiction-forming or addiction-sustaining\nliability. It does not include, unless specifically designated as\ncontrolled under section thirty-three hundred six of this title, the\ndextrorotatory isomer of 3-methoxy-n-methylmorphinan and its salts\n(dextromethorphan). It does include its racemic and levorotatory forms.\n  22. "Opium poppy" means the plant of the species Papaver somniferum\nL., except its seeds.\n  23. "Person" means individual, institution, corporation, government or\ngovernmental subdivision or agency, business trust, estate, trust,\npartnership or association, or any other legal entity.\n  24. "Pharmacist" means any person licensed by the state department of\neducation to practice pharmacy.\n  25. "Pharmacy" means any place registered as such by the New York\nstate board of pharmacy and registered with the Federal agency pursuant\nto the federal controlled substances act.\n  26. "Poppy straw" means all parts, except the seeds, of the opium\npoppy, after mowing.\n  27. "Practitioner" means:\n  A physician, dentist, podiatrist, veterinarian, scientific\ninvestigator, or other person licensed, or otherwise permitted to\ndispense, administer or conduct research with respect to a controlled\nsubstance in the course of a licensed professional practice or research\nlicensed pursuant to this article. Such person shall be deemed a\n"practitioner" only as to such substances, or conduct relating to such\nsubstances, as is permitted by his license, permit or otherwise\npermitted by law.\n  28. "Prescribe" means a direction or authorization, by prescription,\npermitting an ultimate user lawfully to obtain controlled substances\nfrom any person authorized by law to dispense such substances.\n  29. "Prescription" shall mean an official New York state prescription,\nan...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is engaged in the compounding of sterile drugs as defined in\nsection sixty-eight hundred two of the education law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is currently registered as an outsourcing facility pursuant to\narticle one hundred thirty-seven of the education law; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3302__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>complies with all applicable requirements of federal and state\nlaw, including the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act.\n  Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, when an\noutsourcing facility distributes or dispenses any drug to any person\npursuant to a prescription, such outsourcing facility shall be deemed to\nbe providing pharmacy services and shall be subject to all laws, rules\nand regulations governing pharmacies and pharmacy services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>