<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3315"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3315"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3315"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3315">
        <num>3315</num>
        <heading>Applications for renewal of licenses to manufacture or distribute controlled substances</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3315__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any material change in the circumstances or factors listed in\nsection thirty-three hundred twelve of this article;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3315__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>every known charge or investigation, pending or concluded during\nthe period of the license, by any governmental agency with respect to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3315__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>each incident or alleged incident involving the theft, loss, or\npossible diversion of controlled substances manufactured or distributed\nby the applicant; and\n  (ii) compliance by the applicant with the requirements of the federal\ncontrolled substances act, or the laws of any state with respect to any\nsubstance listed in section thirty-three hundred six of this article.\n  3. An applicant for renewal shall be under a continuing duty to report\nto the department any change in facts or circumstances reflected in the\napplication or any newly discovered or occurring fact or circumstance\nwhich is required to be included in the application.\n  4. If the commissioner is not satisfied that the applicant is entitled\nto a renewal of such license, he shall within forty-five days after the\nfiling of the application serve upon the applicant or his attorney of\nrecord in person or by registered or certified mail an order directing\nthe applicant to show cause why his application for renewal should not\nbe denied. Such order shall specify in detail the respects in which the\napplicant has not satisfied the commissioner that the license should be\nrenewed.\n  5. Within thirty days of service of such order, the applicant may\neither submit additional material to the commissioner or demand a\nhearing or both.  If a hearing is demanded the commissioner shall fix a\ndate for hearing not sooner than fifteen days nor later than thirty days\nafter receipt of the demand, unless such time limitation is waived by\nthe applicant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>