<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3338"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3338"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3338"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3338/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3338/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3338/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3338/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3338">
        <num>3338</num>
        <heading>Official New York state prescription forms</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3338. Official New York state prescription forms. 1. Official New\nYork state prescription forms shall be prepared and issued by the\ndepartment in the manner and detail as the commissioner in consultation\nwith the commissioner of education may, by regulation, require, and,\neach form shall be serialized. Such forms shall be furnished to\npractitioners authorized to write such prescriptions and to\ninstitutional dispensers. Such prescription blanks shall not be\ntransferable.\n  2. Except as expressly authorized by section thirty-three hundred\nthirty-four or thirty-three hundred thirty-seven of this article,\ncontrolled substances may be prescribed or dispensed only upon an\nofficial New York state prescription or, pursuant to regulations, an\nelectronic prescription or out-of-state prescription.\n  3. The commissioner in consultation with the commissioner of education\nis hereby authorized and empowered to make rules and regulations, not\ninconsistent with this article, with respect to the retention or filing\nof such official New York state prescription forms, electronic\nprescriptions and out-of-state prescriptions, including information\nrequired to be filed with the department, the maximum number of official\nprescription forms which may be issued at any one time, the manner in\nwhich such forms shall be issued, the period of time after issuance by\nthe department that such form shall remain valid for use, and the manner\nin which practitioners associated with institutional dispensers may use\nsuch forms, or any other matter of procedure or detail necessary to\neffectuate or clarify the provisions of this section and to secure\nproper and effective enforcement of the provisions of this article.\n  4. Upon a finding by the commissioner that a person has willfully\nfailed to comply with the provisions of this article, the commissioner\nmay revoke, cancel or withhold official New York state prescription\nforms which have been issued or for which application has been made.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>