<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3339"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3339"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3339"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3339/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3339/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3339/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3339/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3339">
        <num>3339</num>
        <heading>Refilling of prescriptions for controlled substances</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3339. Refilling of prescriptions for controlled substances. 1.\nPrescriptions for a schedule II controlled substance and those schedule\nIII or schedule IV controlled substances which the commissioner may\nrequire by regulation may not be refilled.\n  2. A prescription, except for a schedule II controlled substance or\nthose schedule III or schedule IV controlled substances which the\ncommissioner may require by regulation may be refilled not more than the\nnumber of times specifically authorized by the prescriber upon the\nprescription, provided however no such authorization shall be effective\nfor a period greater than six months from the date the prescription is\nsigned. In the event that the prescription authorizes the dispensing of\nmore than a thirty day supply of schedule III, schedule IV or schedule V\nsubstances pursuant to regulations of the commissioner enumerating\nconditions warranting specified greater supplies, the prescription may\nbe refilled only once.\n  3. Unless an earlier refilling is authorized by the prescriber, no\nprescription for a controlled substance may be refilled earlier than\nseven days prior to the date the previously dispensed supply would be\nexhausted if used in conformity with the directions for use.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>