<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3398-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3398_K">
        <num>3398-K</num>
        <heading>Granting, suspending or revoking licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3398-k. Granting, suspending or revoking licenses. After due\nnotice and an opportunity to be heard, established by rules and\nregulations, the commissioner may decline to grant a new license, impose\nconditions or limits with respect to the grant of a license, modify an\nexisting license or decline to renew a license, and may suspend or\nrevoke a license already granted after due notice and an opportunity to\nbe heard, as established by rules and regulations, whenever the\ncommissioner finds that:\n  1. A material statement contained in an application is or was false or\nmisleading;\n  2. The applicant or licensee, or a person in a position of management\nand control thereof or of the licensed activity, does not have good\nmoral character, necessary experience or competency, adequate\nfacilities, equipment, process controls, or security to process,\ndistribute, transport or sell cannabinoid hemp, hemp extract or products\nderived therefrom;\n  3. After appropriate notice and opportunity, the applicant or licensee\nhas failed or refused to produce any records or provide any information\nrequired by this article or the regulations promulgated pursuant\nthereto;\n  4. The licensee has conducted activities outside of those activities\npermitted on its license; or\n  5. The applicant or licensee, or any officer, director, partner, or\nany other person exercising any position of management or control\nthereof or of the licensed activity has willfully failed to comply with\nany of the provisions of this article or regulations under it and other\nlaws of this state applicable to the licensed activity.\n  * NB Repealed 6 months after the full cannabis control board created\nby Article 2 of the cannabis law has been appointed\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>