<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3398-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3398_E">
        <num>3398-E</num>
        <heading>Information to be requested in applications for licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3398-e. Information to be requested in applications for licenses.\n1.  The commissioner may specify the manner and form in which an\napplication shall be submitted to the department for licensure under\nthis article.\n  2. The commissioner may adopt regulations establishing what relevant\ninformation shall be included on an application for licensure under this\narticle. Such information may include, but is not limited to:\ninformation about the applicant's identity; ownership and investment\ninformation, including the corporate structure; evidence of good moral\ncharacter; financial statements; information about the premises to be\nlicensed; information about the activities to be licensed; and any other\nrelevant information specified in regulation.\n  3. All license applications shall be signed by the applicant if an\nindividual, by a managing partner if a limited liability company, by an\nofficer if a corporation, or by all partners if a partnership. Each\nperson signing such application shall verify it as true under the\npenalties of perjury.\n  4. All license applications shall be accompanied by a check, draft or\nother forms of payment as the department may require or authorize in the\nreasonable amount required by this article for such license.\n  5. If there be any change, after the filing of the application or the\ngranting, modification or renewal of a license, in any of the material\nfacts required to be set forth in such application, a supplemental\nstatement giving notice of such change, duly verified, shall be filed\nwith the department within ten days after such change. Failure to do so,\nif willful and deliberate, may be grounds for revocation of the license.\n  * NB Repealed 6 months after the full cannabis control board created\nby Article 2 of the cannabis law has been appointed\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>