<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-342"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-342"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="342"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-342/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-342/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-342/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-342/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_342">
        <num>342</num>
        <heading>County or part-county health districts; withdrawal of a city</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 342. County or part-county health districts; withdrawal of a city.\n1. The governing authorities of any city which has consented to be\nincluded in a county or part-county health district, may, at any time\nafter three years shall have elapsed since such city has been included\nin such health district, by resolution adopted by said authorities,\nprovide for the withdrawal of such city from the county or part-county\nhealth district.\n  2. Before such action for the withdrawal of a city from a county or\npart-county health district is taken an opportunity shall be given for a\npublic hearing before such governing authorities. Public notice shall be\ngiven and the board of health of the county or part-county health\ndistrict shall be notified in writing, at least thirty days in advance,\nof the time and place of such hearing.\n  3. The withdrawal of a city from a county or part-county health\ndistrict, shall become effective at a time to be stated in the\nresolution adopted by the governing authorities of the city pursuant to\nthe provisions of this section, which said time shall be not less than\nthirty days from the date of the adoption of said resolution. Upon the\ndate when such resolution shall become effective, the local health\ndistrict of such city shall be reinstated and it shall have all the\npowers of a local health district as though such city had not been\nincluded in the county or part-county health district pursuant to the\nprovisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>