<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3551"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3551"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3551"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3551/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3551/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3551/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3551/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3551">
        <num>3551</num>
        <heading>License required</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3551. License required. 1. On and after the effective date of this\narticle, no person shall operate a tanning facility unless such facility\nis licensed as provided in this article.\n  2. The department shall license each applicant who submits an\napplication on a form prescribed by the commissioner and meets the\nrequirements of this article and any rules or regulations promulgated\npursuant to this article, upon payment of a registration fee of one\nhundred twenty dollars.\n  3. The commissioner shall promulgate such rules and regulations as are\nnecessary to effectuate the provisions of this article, including, but\nnot limited to, establishing staggered biennial registration periods and\nthe beginning dates thereof; assigning licensees to specific biennial\nregistration periods through appropriate classification or grouping;\nsetting deadline dates for making application for registration;\nprescribing the form and content of the license; and establishing other\nreasonable requirements, including appropriate proration of registration\nfees in connection with the initiation of a staggered biennial\nregistration system.\n  4. No license issued hereunder shall be effective for more than two\nyears from the date of issuance.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>