<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3555"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3555"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-08-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3555"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3555/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3555/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3555/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3555/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3555">
        <num>3555</num>
        <heading>Restrictions on the use of ultraviolet radiation devices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3555. Restrictions on the use of ultraviolet radiation devices. 1.\nNo owner, operator, or employee of a tanning facility shall permit the\nuse of the tanning facility by a person eighteen years of age or older\nuntil such person provides a driver's license or other photographic\nidentification card issued by a government entity or educational\ninstitution indicating that the individual is at least eighteen years of\nage and the facility has on file a signed written statement, in a form\nprescribed by the commissioner, acknowledging that such person has read\nthe warnings required under subdivision two of section thirty-five\nhundred fifty-four of this article and agrees to wear safety goggles\nbefore using an ultraviolet radiation device. Such signed statement of\nacknowledgment may be retained by the tanning facility off premises\nprovided that an electronic image or facsimile of the original signed\nstatement of acknowledgment is readily available by the owner or\nemployee responsible for the operation of the ultraviolet radiation\ndevice of such facility.\n  2. No owner, operator, or employee of a tanning facility shall permit\nthe use of an ultraviolet radiation device by a person under eighteen\nyears of age.\n  3. This section shall be exclusive and shall preempt any contrary\nlocal law or ordinance, except that this section shall not preempt or\nsupersede local laws or ordinances imposing additional stricter\nrestrictions on the use and operation of ultraviolet radiation devices\nat tanning facilities which are in effect prior to the effective date of\nthis section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>