<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3556"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3556"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3556"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3556/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3556/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3556/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3556/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3556">
        <num>3556</num>
        <heading>Ultraviolet nail drying devices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3556. Ultraviolet nail drying devices. 1. The department shall\nreview the existing medical and scientific literature, published\nreports, and articles regarding the potential health hazards associated\nwith the use of ultraviolet nail drying devices and identify any health\nhazards. As part of such review, the department shall consult with\nexperts in the fields of skin cancer research and human exposure to\nartificial ultraviolet radiation. The department shall also review the\nfeasibility and effectiveness of requiring appearance enhancement\nbusinesses conducting the practice of nail specialty, as defined in\nsubdivision four of section four hundred of the general business law, to\nadvise users of ultraviolet nail drying devices to apply a sunscreen or\na similar substance designed to block ultraviolet radiation to the hands\nand wrists prior to using such device.\n  2. Upon completion of such review, based on the findings of the\ndepartment, the department of state may promulgate any regulations\ndeemed appropriate for governing the use of ultraviolet nail drying\ndevices by any appearance enhancement business, required to be licensed\nby the department of state pursuant to article twenty-seven of the\ngeneral business law. If promulgated, such regulations shall include a\nrequirement that any appearance enhancement business conducting the\npractice of nail specialty post a notice regarding any health hazards\nassociated with the use of ultraviolet nail dryers and any steps users\nmay take to mitigate such hazards in an area clearly visible to patrons\nin the licensed premises or in the place where the practice of an\noccupation licensed pursuant to article twenty-seven of the general\nbusiness law is conducted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>