<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3602"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3602"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3602"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3602">
        <num>3602</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>those services provided by a home care\nservices agency;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>home health aide services;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>personal care\nservices;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>homemaker services;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>housekeeper or chore services.\n  2. "Home care services agency" means an organization primarily engaged\nin arranging and/or providing directly or through contract arrangement\none or more of the following: Nursing services, home health aide\nservices, and other therapeutic and related services which may include,\nbut shall not be limited to, physical, speech and occupational therapy,\nnutritional services, medical social services, personal care services,\nhomemaker services, and housekeeper or chore services, which may be of a\npreventive, therapeutic, rehabilitative, health guidance, and/or\nsupportive nature to persons at home.\n  3. "Certified home health agency" means a home care services agency\nwhich possesses a valid certificate of approval issued pursuant to the\nprovisions of this article, or a residential health care facility or\nhospital possessing a valid operating certificate issued under article\ntwenty-eight of this chapter which is authorized under section\nthirty-six hundred ten of this article to provide a long term home\nhealth care program. Such an agency, facility, or hospital must be\nqualified to participate as a home health agency under the provisions of\ntitles XVIII and XIX of the federal Social Security Act and shall\nprovide, directly or through contract arrangement, a minimum of the\nfollowing services which are of a preventive, therapeutic,\nrehabilitative, health guidance and/or supportive nature to persons at\nhome: nursing services; home health aide services; medical supplies,\nequipment and appliances suitable for use in the home; and at least one\nadditional service which may include, but not limited to, the provisions\nof physical therapy, occupational therapy, speech pathology, nutritional\nservices and medical social services.\n  4. "Home health aide services" means simple health care tasks,\npersonal hygiene services, housekeeping tasks essential to the patient's\nhealth and other related supportive services. Such services sh...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nare diagnosed by a physician as having acquired immune deficiency\nsyndrome (AIDS), or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are deemed by a physician, within his judgment,\nto be infected with the etiologic agent of acquired immune deficiency\nsyndrome, and who has an illness, infirmity or disability which can be\nreasonably ascertained to be associated with such infection. Such\nprogram shall be provided only by a provider of a long term home health\ncare program specifically authorized pursuant to this article to provide\nan AIDS home care program or by an AIDS center, as defined in\nregulations promulgated by the commissioner, specifically authorized\npursuant to this article to provide an AIDS home care program. Such\nprogram shall be provided in the person's home or in the home of a\nresponsible relative, other responsible adult, adult care facilities\nspecifically approved to admit or retain residents for such program, or\nin other residential settings as approved by the commissioner in\nconjunction with the commissioner of social services. Such program shall\nprovide services including, but not be limited to, the full complement\nof health, social and environmental services provided by long term home\nhealth care programs in accordance with regulations promulgated by the\ncommissioner. Such programs shall also provide such other services as\nrequired by the commissioner to assure appropriate care at home for\npersons eligible under this section.\n  * 15. "Limited home care services agency" means a certified operator\nof an adult home or an enriched housing program which directly provides:\npersonal care services authorized and provided in accordance with rules\nand regulations of the department of social services; and the\nadministration of medications and application of sterile dressings by a\nregistered nurse, provided, however, that the services provided by such\nagency are not services that must be provided to residents of such\nfacilities pursuant to article seven of the social services law and\nrules and regulations of the department of social services. Such\noperator may pr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>