<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3609"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3609"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3609"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3609/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3609/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3609/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3609/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3609">
        <num>3609</num>
        <heading>Grants for planning an establishment of new certified home health agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3609. Grants for planning an establishment of new certified home\nhealth agencies. 1. The commissioner is hereby authorized, within the\namount allocated pursuant to subdivisions one, two and three of section\nthirty-six hundred fifteen of this article, to make grants to voluntary\nnot-for-profit organizations in areas of the state determined by the\ncommissioner to be in need of home care services.\n  2. Such grants shall be awarded for the purposes of planning for\nestablishment as a certified home health agency pursuant to section\nthirty-six hundred six of this chapter.\n  3. Such grants shall not exceed twenty thousand dollars per annum and\nare not renewable.\n  4. The grant applications shall include such information as required\nby the commissioner.\n  5. Funds for such grants shall be made available pursuant to the\nfunding formula and allocations as provided in subdivisions one, two and\nthree of section thirty-six hundred fifteen of this article.\n  6. The commissioner shall approve applications in accordance with the\nprovisions of subdivisions five, six and seven of section thirty-six\nhundred fifteen of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>