<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-401"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-401"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="401"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-401/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-401/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-401/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-401/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_401">
        <num>401</num>
        <heading>Land; purchase or acquisition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 401. Land; purchase or acquisition. 1. The commissioner, when an\nappropriation therefor has been made by the legislature, may acquire any\nreal property which he may deem necessary for any departmental purpose\nby purchase or acquisition pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law.\n  Title to any such real property shall be taken in the name of and be\nvested in the people of the state of New York; provided, however, that\nno real property shall be so acquired by purchase unless the title\nthereto shall be approved by the attorney general.\n  2. Whenever real property is to be acquired pursuant to the eminent\ndomain procedure law the commissioner shall cause to be made by the\nstate department of transportation an accurate acquisition map as\nprovided in such law.\n  3. On the approval of such map by the commissioner, the original\ntracing of such map shall be filed in the main office of the department.\n  4. If the commissioner shall determine, prior to the filing of such\nmap in the office of the clerk or register of the county, that changes,\nalterations or modifications of such map as filed in the main office of\nthe department should be made, he or she shall, subject to the\nprovisions of article two of the eminent domain procedure law, if\napplicable, direct the preparation by the department of transportation\nof an amended map. On the approval of such amended map by the\ncommissioner, it shall be filed in the main office of the department and\nthe amended map shall thereupon in all respects and for all purposes\nsupersede the map previously filed.\n  5. If the commissioner shall determine, prior to the filing of a copy\nof such acquisition map in the office of the county clerk or register as\nprovided in section four hundred two of the eminent domain procedure\nlaw, that such map should be withdrawn, he or she may file a certificate\nof withdrawal in the offices of the department and of the department of\nlaw. Upon the filing of such certificate of withdrawal, the map to which\nit refers shall be cancelled and all rights thereunder shall cease and\ndetermine.\n  6. The commissioner shall deliver to the attorney general a copy of\nsuch acquisition map, whereupon it shall be the duty of the attorney\ngeneral to advise and certify to the commissioner the names of the\nowners of the property, easements, interests or rights described in the\nsaid acquisition map, including the owners of any right, title or\ninterest therein, pursuant to the requirements of section four hundred\nthree of the eminent domain procedure law.\n  7. If, at or after the vesting of title to such property in the people\nof the state of New York as provided for in the eminent domain procedure\nlaw, the commissioner shall deem it necessary to cause the removal of an\nowner or occupant from any real property so acquired, he may cause such\nowner or occupant to be removed therefrom by proceeding in accordance\nwith section four hundred five of the eminent domain procedure law. The\nproceeding shall be brought in the name of the commissioner as agent of\nthe state and the attorney general shall represent the petitioner in the\nproceedings. No execution shall issue for costs, if any, awarded against\nthe state or the commissioner, but they shall be part of the costs of\nthe acquisition of the real property and be paid in like manner.\nProceedings may be brought separately against one or more of the owners\nor occupants of any such property, or one proceeding may be brought\nagainst all or several of the owners or occupants of any or all such\nproperty within the territorial jurisdiction of the same court, justice\nor judge; judgment shall be made for immediate removal of persons\ndefaulting in appearance or in answering, or withdrawing their answers,\nif any, without awaiting the trial or decision of issues raised by\ncontestants, if any.\n  8. Claims for the value of any property acquired and for legal damages\ncaused by any such acquisition may be adjusted by the commissioner, even\nthough a claim has been filed with the court of claims, if the amount\nthereof can be agreed upon with the owner or owners thereof. If the\namount of a claim cannot be agreed upon, the commissioner shall offer to\nthe owner or owners the amount determined by the commissioner to be the\nvalue of such claim. Upon the acceptance of such offer the commissioner\nshall enter into an agreement with such owner or owners providing for\nsuch payment with interest thereon, if any, as allowed by law and\nreserving to such owner or owners the right to file such claim with the\ncourt of claims or if a claim has been filed reserving the right to\nprosecute said claim. The reservation of the right to file said claim in\nthe court of claims shall not extend or affect in any way the time\nlimited for the filing of such claim as provided for in the court of\nclaims act. The failure of the owner or owners to file said claim within\nthe time of filing claims specified by the court of claims act shall be\ndeemed an acceptance of the amount paid as full settlement of such\nclaim. If such offer is refused by the owner or owners, or is not\naccepted within ninety days after notification by the commissioner of\nsuch offer by registered mail, interest on the amount of the claim so\noffered shall be suspended from the date of such refusal or the\nexpiration of such ninety days, whichever is earlier, to the date of the\nentry of judgment in the court of claims. If such offer is refused or is\nnot accepted within said ninety days the offer shall be deemed withdrawn\nand may be revived only at the discretion of the commissioner. Upon\nmaking any agreement provided for in section three hundred four of the\neminent domain procedure law, the commissioner shall deliver to the\ncomptroller such agreement and a certificate stating the amount due such\nowner or owners thereunder on account of such acquisition of his or\ntheir property and the amounts so fixed shall be paid out of the state\ntreasury after audit by the comptroller from moneys appropriated for the\nacquisition of such real property, but not until there shall have been\nfiled with the comptroller a certificate of the attorney general showing\nthe person or persons claiming the amounts so agreed upon to be legally\nentitled thereto.\n  9. Application for reimbursement of incidental expenses as provided in\nsection seven hundred two of the eminent domain procedure law shall be\nmade to the commissioner upon forms prescribed by him and shall be\naccompanied by such information and evidence as the commissioner may\nrequire. Upon approval of such application, the commissioner shall\ndeliver a copy thereof to the comptroller together with a certificate\nstating the amount due thereof, and the amount so fixed shall be paid\nout of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from monies\nappropriated for the acquisition of property under this section.\n  10. The commissioner, with the approval of the director of the budget,\nshall establish and may from time to time amend rules and regulations\nauthorizing the payment of actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses of occupants of property acquired pursuant to this section; of\nactual direct losses of tangible personal property as a result of moving\nor discontinuing a business or farm operation, but not exceeding an\namount equal to the reasonable expenses that would have been required to\nrelocate such property, as determined by the commissioner; and actual\nreasonable expenses in searching for a replacement business or farm; or\nin hardship cases for the advance payment of such expenses and losses.\nFor the purposes of making payment of such expenses and losses only the\nterm "business" means any lawful activity conducted primarily for\nassisting in the purchase, sale, resale, manufacture, processing or\nmarketing of products, commodities, personal property or services by the\nerection and maintenance of an outdoor advertising display or displays,\nwhether or not such display or displays are located on the premises on\nwhich any of the above activities are conducted.  Such rules and\nregulations may further define the terms used in this subdivision.  In\nlieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving expenses, any such\ndisplaced owner or tenant of residential property may elect to accept a\nmoving expense allowance, plus a dislocation allowance, determined in\naccordance with a schedule prepared by the commissioner and made a part\nof such rules and regulations.  In lieu of such actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses, any such displaced owner or tenant of\ncommercial property who relocates or discontinues his business or farm\noperation may elect to accept a fixed relocation payment in an amount\nequal to the average annual net earnings of the business or farm\noperation, except that such payment shall be not less than two thousand\nfive hundred dollars nor more than ten thousand dollars. In the case of\na business, no such fixed relocation payment shall be made unless the\ncommissioner finds and determines that the business cannot be relocated\nwithout a substantial loss of its existing patronage, and that the\nbusiness is not part of a commercial enterprise having at least one\nother establishment, which is not being acquired by the state or the\nUnited States, which is engaged in the same or similar business.  In the\ncase of a business which is to be discontinued but for which the\nfindings and determinations set forth above cannot be made, the\ncommissioner may prepare an estimate of what the actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses, exclusive of any storage charges, would be if\nthe business were to be relocated and enter into an agreed settlement\nwith the owner of such business for an amount not to exceed such\nestimate in lieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses. Application for payment under this subdivision shall b</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>