<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4014"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4014"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4014"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4014/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4014/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4014/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4014/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4014">
        <num>4014</num>
        <heading>Hospice residence pilot program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4014. Hospice residence pilot program. 1. The commissioner is hereby\nauthorized to establish a hospice residence pilot program. Such program,\nsubject to the rules and regulations of the commissioner, shall\nauthorize the operation of not more than ten hospice residences operated\nfor the purpose of providing more than two hospice patients but not more\nthan sixteen hospice patients with hospice care. The locations of the\nhospice residence pilot program shall be geographically disbursed\nthroughout the state and approved by the commissioner. To the extent\nthat patients may access hospital or skilled nursing home care, the care\nplan for such patients shall provide for such care.\n  2. The commissioner shall require each hospice residence participating\nin the pilot program established pursuant to this section to submit a\nreport, which shall include data analyzing the cost and efficiency of\nhospice care under such pilot program. On or before December\nthirty-first, two thousand seven, the commissioner shall submit a report\nto the governor, the temporary president of the senate and the speaker\nof the assembly analyzing the findings of the individual hospice\nresidences that participated in the pilot program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>