<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-403"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-403"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="403"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-403/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-403/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-403/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-403/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_403">
        <num>403</num>
        <heading>Hospitals; property; authority to acquire and to hold</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_403__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Helen Hayes hospital;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_403__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Roswell Park Cancer Institute;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_403__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The New York state home for veterans and their dependents at\nOxford;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_403__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The New York state home for veterans in the city of New York;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_403__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The New York state home for veterans in western New York;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_403__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The New York state home for veterans in the lower-Hudson Valley.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other inconsistent provisions of law,\nincluding, but not limited to, article four-C of the economic\ndevelopment law, and subject to the provisions of any lease, loan\nagreement or other agreement with the dormitory authority of the state\nof New York or any predecessor or successor agency or corporation, the\ncommissioner, with the approval of the director of the budget, may\ncontract with the Roswell Park Cancer Institute corporation, for the\ntransfer of the operations of the Roswell Park Cancer Institute or any\npart thereof, practice plan or of any other program operated by such\nhospital. Such contract shall include terms and conditions under which\nthe Roswell Park Cancer Institute corporation may issue bonds, notes or\nother evidences of indebtedness.  Payments made pursuant to such\ncontract or any other contracts between the department of health and the\nRoswell Park Cancer Institute corporation shall be limited to amounts\nmade available pursuant to appropriations.  Upon the transfer of the\noperations of Roswell Park Cancer Institute to the Roswell Park Cancer\nInstitute corporation, the Roswell Park Cancer Institute corporation\nshall operate the Roswell Park Cancer Institute for the department in\naccordance with the terms of any lease or other agreement between the\ndepartment and the dormitory authority pertaining to the use, operation,\nmaintenance and replacement of Roswell Park Cancer Institute.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>