<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409_A">
        <num>409-A</num>
        <heading>Department of health New York city veterans home income fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall, after the first day of July, nineteen\nhundred ninety-one, pay over moneys received by the department for the\ncare, maintenance and treatment of patients at the New York state home\nfor veterans in the city of New York, together with moneys received from\nfees, including parking fees, refunds, reimbursements, sales of property\nand miscellaneous receipts of such home other than gifts, grants,\nbequests and moneys received under research contracts to the comptroller\nto be deposited by the comptroller in the fund. Such moneys shall be\nkept separate and shall not be commingled with any other moneys in the\nhands of the comptroller. All deposits of such money shall, if required\nby the comptroller, be secured by obligations of the United States or of\nthe state of market value equal at all times to the amount of the\ndeposit and all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such\nsecurities for such deposits.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the terms of any agreement between the department and\nthe dormitory authority, any such moneys in the fund not required for\nimmediate use, may, in the discretion of the comptroller, be invested by\nthe comptroller in obligations of the United States or the state or\nobligations the principal and interest of which are guaranteed by the\nUnited States or the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The comptroller shall at all times maintain on deposit in the fund\nthe aggregate amount of money needed by the department during the next\nsucceeding six calendar months to comply in full with all obligations of\nthe department under the terms of any lease, sublease or agreement of\nthe department with the dormitory authority relating to the New York\nstate home for veterans in the city of New York which is then in effect,\nincluding without limitation by the specification thereof,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\namount needed to make rental or other payments thereunder during such\nsemiannual period and (ii) the amount needed to establish and maintain\nreserves thereunder during such period.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The comptroller shall from time to time but in no event later than\nthe last day of March, June, September and December of each year pay\nover and deposit in the special revenue funds - other, miscellaneous\nspecial revenue fund - 339, New York city veterans' home account, all\nmoneys in the fund in excess of the aggregate amount of money required\nto be maintained in the department of health New York City veterans home\nincome fund pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.  Prior to\nmaking any such transfer, the comptroller shall make and deliver to the\ndirector of the budget and to the dormitory authority a certificate\nstating the aggregate amount to be maintained on deposit in the fund to\ncomply in full with the provision of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\nWhen further directed by the commissioner, the comptroller shall\ntransfer revenues and/or appropriations between and among this account\nand the special revenue funds - other, miscellaneous special revenue\nfund - 339, Roswell Park cancer institute account, Helen Hayes hospital\naccount, New York state home for veterans and their dependents at Oxford\naccount, western New York veteran's home account and New York state home\nfor veterans in the lower-Hudson Valley account.  For purposes of\ntransferring appropriations it is intended that the following accounts\nbe understood to be part of the same program and same fund for purposes\nof section fifty-one of the state finance law, thereby authorizing\nunlimited interchangeability of appropriated amounts between the\nfollowing accounts in the special revenue funds - other, miscellaneous\nspecial revenue fund - 339: Roswell Park Cancer Institute Account, Helen\nHayes Hospital Account, New York State Home for Veterans and Their\nDependents at Oxford Account, Western New York Veterans' Home Account,\nNew York State Home for Veterans in the lower-Hudson Valley Account, and\nNew York City Veterans' Home Account.  The comptroller shall, as\ndetermined by the commissioner and consistent with any repayment\nagreement entered into between the director of the budget and the\ncommissioner, transfer funds from the New York city veteran's home\naccount to the department of health services account to repay all or\npart of any outstanding liabilities in the health services account\nattributed to the New York city veterans' home.\n  3. To secure the payment of any money due or to become due in any year\nunder any lease, sublease or agreement entered into between the\ndepartment and the dormitory authority relating to the New York state\nhome for veterans in the city of New York, the commissioner may pledge\nor assign to the dormitory authority all or any moneys in the fund\nestablished pursuant to this section, a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>