<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-409/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409">
        <num>409</num>
        <heading>Department of health income fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall, after the first day of July, nineteen\nhundred  seventy-one,  pay  over  moneys  received  by  the   department\nincluding,  subject  to subdivision six of this section, moneys received\nfrom the  Roswell  Park  Cancer  Institute  corporation  for  the  care,\nmaintenance  and  treatment  of  patients  at  state  hospitals  in  the\ndepartment as enumerated in section four hundred three of this  chapter,\ntogether with money received from fees, including parking fees, refunds,\nreimbursements,  payments received pursuant to leases, sales of property\nand miscellaneous receipts of such hospitals other than  gifts,  grants,\nbequests  and  moneys  received  under  research contracts, and clinical\npractice  income  received  pursuant  to  a   clinical   practice   plan\nestablished  pursuant to subdivision fourteen of section two hundred six\nof this  chapter  except  for  the  amount  of  money  required  by  the\ncomptroller  to  be  maintained  on  deposit in the department of health\nincome fund pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision less  payments\nrequired  to  be  made  into  pools  created  by  this  chapter  and for\nassessments established pursuant to this chapter and less  refunds  made\npursuant  to  law, to the comptroller to be deposited by the comptroller\nin the department of health income  fund.  Such  moneys  shall  be  kept\nseparate  and shall not be commingled with any other moneys in the hands\nof the comptroller. All deposits of such money shall, if required by the\ncomptroller, be secured by obligations of the United States  or  of  the\nstate  of  market  value equal at all times to the amount of the deposit\nand all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such securities\nfor such deposits. The commissioner shall identify  to  the  comptroller\nmoneys  received  from  Roswell Park Cancer Institute corporation or its\nsubsidiaries.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the terms of any agreement between the  department  and\nthe  dormitory  authority,  any  such moneys in the department of health\nincome fund not required for immediate use, may, in  the  discretion  of\nthe  comptroller,  be  invested by the comptroller in obligations of the\nUnited States or the state or obligations the principal and interest  of\nwhich are guaranteed by the United States or the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The  comptroller  shall  at  all times maintain on deposit in the\ndepartment of health income fund the aggregate amount of money needed by\nthe department during the next succeeding six calendar months to  comply\nin  full with all obligations of the department under the terms of every\nlease, sublease or  agreement  of  the  department  with  the  dormitory\nauthority  which  is then in effect, including without limitation by the\nspecification thereof,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount needed  to  make  rental  payments\nthereunder  during such semiannual period, and (ii) the amount needed to\nestablish and maintain reserves thereunder during such period.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The comptroller shall from time to time but in no event later than\nthe last day of March, June, September and December of each year pay\nover and deposit in the special revenue funds - other, miscellaneous\nspecial revenue fund - 339, Roswell Park cancer institute account, Helen\nHayes hospital account, New York state home for veterans and their\ndependents at Oxford account, western New York veterans' home account\nand New York state home for veterans in the lower-Hudson Valley account,\nin accordance with directions from the commissioner of health concerning\nthe distribution of revenues among the various accounts, all moneys in\nthe department of health income fund in excess of the aggregate amount\nof money required to be maintained in the department of health income\nfund pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.  Prior to making any\nsuch transfer, the comptroller shall make and deliver to the director of\nthe budget and to the dormitory authority his certificate stating the\naggregate amount to be maintained on deposit in the department of health\nincome fund to comply in full with the provision of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision.  When further directed by the commissioner, the\ncomptroller shall transfer revenues and/or appropriations between and\namong these accounts and the special revenue funds - other,\nmiscellaneous special revenue fund - 339, New York city veteran's home\naccount.  For purposes of transferring appropriations it is intended\nthat the following accounts be understood to be part of the same program\nand same fund for purposes of section fifty-one of the state finance\nlaw, thereby authorizing unlimited interchangeability of appropriated\namounts between the following accounts in the special revenue funds -\nother, miscellaneous special revenue fund - 339: Roswell Park Cancer\nInstitute Account, Helen Hayes Hospital Account, New York State Home for\nVeterans and Their Dependents at Oxford Account, Western New York\nVeterans' Home Account, New York State Home for Veterans in the\nlower-Hudson Valley Account, and New York City Veterans' Home Account.\nThe comptroller shall, as determined by the commissioner and consistent\nwith any repayment agreement entered into between the director of the\nbudget and the commissioner, transfer funds from the Roswell Park cancer\ninstitute account, Helen Hayes hospital account, New York state home for\nveterans and their dependents at Oxford account, western New York\nveterans' home account or New York state home for veterans in the\nlower-Hudson Valley account to the department of health services account\nto repay all or part of any outstanding liabilities in the health\nservices account attributed to the respective hospitals for which such\naccounts were established.\n  3. To secure the payment of any money due or to become due in any year\nunder any lease, sublease or agreement entered into between the\ndepartment and the dormitory authority, the commissioner may pledge or\nassign to the dormitory authority all or any moneys in the department of\nhealth income fund established pursuant to this section, and any and ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section, into\na depositary account owned and controlled by the Roswell Park Cancer\nInstitute corporation.\n  6. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section, upon the\npayment or provision for payment of all outstanding bonds issued on or\nbefore March thirty-first, two thousand twenty-five by the dormitory\nauthority to make loans to the department to finance or refinance state\nhospital facilities in accordance with the terms of the bond resolution\nunder which such bonds were issued, the provisions of subdivisions two\nand five of this section requiring</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_409__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the payment and identification by\nthe department to the comptroller of moneys received from the Roswell\nPark Cancer Institute corporation, (ii) the deposit and maintenance of\nsuch moneys from the Roswell Park Cancer Institute corporation by the\ncomptroller in the department of health income fund, and (iii) the\nrelease of excess moneys in the department of health income fund\nattributed to the operation of the Roswell Park Cancer Institute\ncorporation or its subsidiaries, shall no longer be applicable and,\nthereafter, all such moneys from the operation of the Roswell Park\nCancer Institute corporation shall remain in the custody and/or control\nof the corporation and/or its subsidiaries.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>