<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4122"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4122"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4122"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4122">
        <num>4122</num>
        <heading>Vital statistics; deputy registrars and subregistrars; appointment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4122. Vital statistics; deputy registrars and subregistrars;\nappointment. 1. Immediately upon his acceptance of appointment, each\nregistrar of vital statistics shall appoint a deputy whose duty it shall\nbe to act in his stead in case of his absence or inability, and such\ndeputy shall accept such appointment, in writing, and be subject to the\nprovisions of this article and all rules and regulations governing\nregistrars.\n  2. When it appears necessary for the convenience of the people in any\ndistrict, the registrar is authorized, with the approval of the\ncommissioner, to appoint one or more suitable persons to act as\nsubregistrars, who shall be authorized to receive birth and death\ncertificates and to issue burial or removal permits in and for such\nportions of the district as may be designated, and each such\nsubregistrar shall note on each certificate over his signature the date\nof filing and shall forward all certificates to the local registrar of\nthe district within three days, and in all cases before the third day of\nthe following month.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>