<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4123"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4123"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4123"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4123/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4123/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4123/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4123/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4123">
        <num>4123</num>
        <heading>Vital statistics; registrars; term of office; oath; removal</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4123. Vital statistics; registrars; term of office; oath; removal.\n1. Unless the charter of the city or village shall provide otherwise,\nthe term of office of a registrar of vital statistics shall be four\nyears, except that in a town or village of the first class operating\nunder the general town or village law, the term of office of registrar\nof vital statistics shall be coterminous with the term of office of the\ntown or village clerk, as the case may be. The term of office of a\ncounty or part-county registrar shall be coterminous with that of the\ncounty commissioner of health or public health director. If there be no\ncounty commissioner of health or public health director, then the term\nof office of such county or part-county registrar shall be as determined\nby the board of supervisors of such county.\n  2. Each registrar of vital statistics shall hold office until his\nsuccessor is appointed and shall have qualified.\n  3. Any registrar, deputy registrar or subregistrar of vital\nstatistics, who fails or neglects to discharge efficiently the duties of\nhis office in accordance with the provisions of this article or the\nregulations of the public health council, or to make prompt and complete\nreturns of births and deaths as required thereby, shall be removed\nforthwith by the commissioner or by the person or board authorized by\nlaw to appoint such registrar, deputy registrar or subregistrar.  Such\nother penalties may be imposed upon him as are provided by this article.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provisions of the laws of this state,\neach registrar, deputy registrar and subregistrar of vital statistics\nshall file his oath of office with the clerk or clerks of the county or\ncounties in which his registration district is located.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>