<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4140"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4140"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4140"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4140/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4140/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4140/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4140/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4140">
        <num>4140</num>
        <heading>Deaths; registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4140. Deaths; registration. 1. The death of each person who has died\nin this state shall be registered immediately and not later than\nseventy-two hours after death or the finding of a dead human body, by\nfiling with the registrar of the district in which the death occurred or\nthe body was found a certificate of such death, in a manner and format\nas prescribed by the commissioner, which shall include through\nelectronic means in accordance with section forty-one hundred\nforty-eight of this title.\n  2. If the certificate of death is properly executed and complete, the\nregistrar of the district in which the death occurred shall then issue a\nburial or removal permit to the funeral director or undertaker. In case\nthe death occurred from a disease which is designated in the sanitary\ncode as a communicable disease, no permit for the removal or other\ndisposition of the body shall be issued by the registrar, except to a\nfuneral director or undertaker licensed in accordance with the\nprovisions of this chapter, under such conditions as may be prescribed\nin the sanitary code.\n  3. The commissioner and the department of health of the city of New\nYork shall deliver to the state board of elections, at least monthly,\nrecords in a format as mutually determined by both agencies, of the\nnames of all persons of voting age for whom death certificates were\nissued. Such records shall be arranged by county of residence and shall\ninclude the name, residence address and birth date of each such person.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>