<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4173"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4173"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-12-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4173"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4173/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4173/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4173/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4173/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4173">
        <num>4173</num>
        <heading>Records; transcripts and certifications by registrars; fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4173__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4173__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, the registrar shall be entitled to a fee of ten dollars for\neach certification of birth or death or for each certified copy or\ncertified transcript of any record of a birth or of a death or for a\ncertification that a search discloses no record of a birth or of a\ndeath, furnished by him to an applicant, except that no fee shall be\ncharged for a search, certification of birth or death or certified copy\nor certified transcript of a birth or a death record to be used for\nschool entrance, employment certificate or for purposes of public relief\nor government compensation or when required by the veterans\nadministration to be used in determining the eligibility of any person\nto participate in the benefits made available by the veterans\nadministration, provided, however, that if such registrar is a city\nclerk, town clerk or village clerk, he shall collect such fees for and\non behalf of the city, town or village in which he serves, provided,\nhowever, that an amount equivalent to the sum of such fees shall be paid\nat least monthly by such city, town or village to such city clerk, town\nclerk or village clerk entitled to receive fees as a registrar of vital\nstatistics.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4173__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4173__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, in the\nfollowing county jurisdictions the fee shall be set by the county health\ncommissioner: Chemung, Monroe, Onondaga, Tompkins; and in the following\nlocal jurisdictions the fee shall be set by the local legislative body:\ncity of Oswego, city of Albany, city of Jamestown. In such\njurisdictions, the fee may be set up to the amount charged by the\ncommissioner as prescribed in subdivision two of section forty-one\nhundred seventy-four of this title.\n  4. All fees for searches, certification, certified copies and\ncertified transcripts collected by a registrar of vital statistics in a\nstate hospital, charitable or penal institution shall be transmitted by\nhim to the executive department, having jurisdiction, management and\ncontrol of such hospital or institution, to be paid into the state\ntreasury as provided by section one hundred twenty-one of the state\nfinance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>