<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4176"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4176"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4176"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4176">
        <num>4176</num>
        <heading>Records; correction of defective registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4176. Records; correction of defective registration. 1. If defects\nbe found in the registration under the supervision of a registrar of\nvital statistics, the commissioner shall notify such registrar that such\ndefects must be corrected within ten days of the date of the notice.\n  2. If such defects are not so corrected the commissioner shall take\ncontrol of such registration and of the records thereof, and enforce the\nrules and regulations in regard thereto and secure a complete\nregistration in such district, and such control shall continue until the\nregistrar of vital statistics shall satisfy the commissioner that he\nwill make such record and registry complete as required by law and in\nthe sanitary code.\n  3. The expenses incurred by the commissioner or his authorized\nrepresentative while in control of such registration shall be a charge\nupon the city, town or village comprising the registration district.\n  4. No certificate of birth or death, after its acceptance for\nregistration by the registrar, and no new certificate or other record\nmade in pursuance of this article, shall be altered or changed in any\nrespect except to correct errors made in completing the certificate by\nthe person responsible for preparing the certificate or as otherwise\nprovided in this article. The commissioner shall provide the application\nform for a correction of a record which must be properly dated, signed\nand witnessed, or subscribed and affirmed by the persons making them as\ntrue under the penalties of perjury, together with such supporting\nproofs as may be prescribed by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>