<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4179"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4179"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-09-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4179"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4179">
        <num>4179</num>
        <heading>Vital records; fees; city of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4179. Vital records; fees; city of New York. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of paragraph one of subdivision a of section 207.13 of the\nhealth code of the city of New York, the department of health shall\ncharge, and the applicant shall pay, for a search of two consecutive\ncalendar years under one name and the issuance of a certificate of\nbirth, death or termination of pregnancy, or a certification of birth or\ndeath, or a certification that the record cannot be found, a fee of\nfifteen dollars for each copy. Provided, however, that no such fee shall\nbe charged when the department of corrections and community supervision\nor a local correctional facility as defined in subdivision sixteen of\nsection two of the correction law requests a certificate of birth or\ncertification of birth for the purpose of providing such certificate of\nbirth or certification of birth to an incarcerated individual in\nanticipation of such incarcerated individual's release from custody or\nto obtain a death certificate to be used for administrative purposes for\nan incarcerated individual who has died under custody or when the office\nof children and family services or an authorized agency requests a\ncertified copy or certified transcript of birth for a youth placed in\nthe custody of the local commissioner of social services or the custody\nof the office of children and family services pursuant to article three\nof the family court act for the purpose of providing such certified copy\nor certified transcript of birth to such youth in anticipation of\ndischarge from placement. Whenever a request is made by the department\nof corrections and community supervision for a certified copy or\ncertified transcript of birth on behalf of an incarcerated individual\npursuant to this section, a certified copy of the sentence and\ncommitment or certificate of conviction shall be deemed to grant\nauthorization by the incarcerated individual to the department to submit\nsuch request on their behalf, and no other authorization shall be\nrequired.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>