<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4400"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4400"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4400"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4400/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4400/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4400/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4400/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4400">
        <num>4400</num>
        <heading>Statement of policy and purposes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4400. Statement of policy and purposes. Encouraging the expansion of\nhealth care services options available to the citizens of the state is a\nmatter of vital state concern. Without such an expansion, increased\nhealth insurance and other benefits will continue to escalate the costs\nof medical care and overload the health care delivery system. The health\nmaintenance organization concept, through which members of an enrolled\npopulation are each entitled to receive comprehensive health services\nfor an advance or periodic charge, represents a promising new\nalternative for the delivery of a full range of health care services at\na reasonable cost.\n  Accordingly, it shall be the policy of this state to expand the health\ncare services options available, and to assure greater choice in the\nselection of a health care plan, by removal of legal and other\nimpediments to the development of competitive health maintenance\norganizations acceptable to the public.\n  It is the intent of the legislature that the commissioner therefore\nestablish a comprehensive system of authorization and regulation of\nhealth maintenance organizations in the state, as provided in this\narticle, in order to assure that health services of good quality be\nprovided to all citizens who choose to take advantage of that\nalternative to meet their health care needs. The commissioner shall\ncooperate with the superintendent of financial services and with other\nstate officials and agencies which establish standards and requirements\npertaining to the provision and financing of health care services in\norder to assure necessary, equitable and consistent state supervision of\nall health care systems without duplication of inspection or services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>