<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-09-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4406-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4406_I">
        <num>4406-I</num>
        <heading>Utilization review determinations for medically fragile children</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4406_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Consider as medically necessary all covered services that assist\nmedically fragile children in reaching their maximum functional\ncapacity, taking into account the appropriate functional capacities of\nchildren of the same age. In the case of Medicaid managed care, health\nmaintenance organizations shall continue to cover services until that\nchild achieves age-appropriate functional capacity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4406_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall not base determinations solely upon review standards\napplicable to (or designed for) adults to medically fragile children.\nDeterminations shall take into consideration the specific needs of the\nchild and the circumstances pertaining to their growth and development.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4406_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Accommodate unusual stabilization and prolonged discharge plans\nfor medically fragile children, as appropriate. Health maintenance\norganizations, and as applicable their contracted utilization review\nagents, shall consider when developing and approving discharge plans\nissues including sudden reversals of condition or progress which may\nmake discharge decisions uncertain or more prolonged than for other\nchildren or adults.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4406_I__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It is the health maintenance organization's network management\nresponsibility to identify an available provider of needed covered\nservices, as determined through a person centered care plan, to effect\nsafe discharge from a hospital or other facility. In the case of\nMedicaid managed care, payments shall not be denied to a discharging\nhospital or other facility due to lack of an available post-discharge\nprovider as long as they have worked with the utilization review agent\nto identify an appropriate provider.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4406_I__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This section does not limit any other rights the medically fragile\nchild may have, including the right to appeal the denial of out of\nnetwork coverage at in-network cost sharing levels where an appropriate\nin-network provider is not available pursuant to subdivision one-b of\nsection forty-nine hundred four of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4406_I__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Health maintenance organizations shall contract with providers\nwith demonstrated expertise in caring for the medically fragile\nchildren.  Network providers shall refer to appropriate network\ncommunity and facility providers for covered services to meet the needs\nof the child or seek authorization from the health maintenance\norganization for out-of-network providers when participating providers\ncannot meet the child's needs.\n  3. In the case of Medicaid managed care, when rendering or arranging\nfor care or payment, both the provider and the health maintenance\norganization shall inquire of, and shall consider the desires of the\nfamily of a medically fragile child including, but not limited to, the\navailability and capacity of the family, the need for the family to\nsimultaneously care for the family's other children, and the need for\nparents to continue employment.\n  4. In the case of Medicaid managed care, the health maintenance\norganization shall pay for all days of inpatient hospital care at a\nparticipating specialty care center for medically fragile children when\nthe health maintenance organization and the specialty care facility\nmutually agree the patient is ready for discharge from the specialty\ncare center to the patient's home but requires specialized home services\nthat are not available or in place, or the patient is awaiting discharge\nto a residential health care facility when no residential health care\nfacility bed is available given the specialized needs of the medically\nfragile child. In the case of Medicaid managed care, the health\nmaintenance organization shall pay, for all days of residential health\ncare facility care at a participating specialty care center for\nmedically fragile children when the health maintenance organization and\nthe specialty care facility mutually agree the patient is ready for\ndischarge from the specialty care center to the patient's home but\nrequires specialized home services that are not available or...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>