<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-451"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-451"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="451"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-451/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-451/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-451/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-451/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_451">
        <num>451</num>
        <heading>Directors of hospitals; removal and suspension</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 451. Directors of hospitals; removal and suspension. 1. The director\nof a hospital in the department may be removed by the commissioner for\ncause stated in writing, after an opportunity has been given the\ndirector to be heard thereon. Such action by the commissioner shall be\nfinal. The board of visitors of the hospital, however, shall be notified\nof any such hearing and its members be given an opportunity to be heard\nthereat. Pending the investigation by the commissioner or board of\nvisitors of any charges against a director, the commissioner may suspend\nsuch director.\n  2. The commissioner may prefer charges of misconduct or incompetency\nagainst the director of a hospital in the department, to the board of\nvisitors, and the board of visitors shall thereupon investigate the\ntruth of such charges and make its recommendations thereon to the\ncommissioner, or the commissioner or his duly authorized representative\nmay investigate any charges of like nature made to the commissioner.\nThe investigating authority may subpoena witnesses, and take and hear\ntestimony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>