<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-460-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-460-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="460-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-460-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-460-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-460-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-460-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_460_A">
        <num>460-A</num>
        <heading>Restrictions on body piercing studios</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 460-a. Restrictions on body piercing studios. 1. No owner, operator\nor employee of a body piercing studio shall permit body piercing on a\nperson under eighteen years of age unless such person provides the body\npiercing studio with the written consent, in a form prescribed by the\ncommissioner, of a parent or legal guardian to use such body piercing\nstudio. The parent or legal guardian shall sign such consent form in the\npresence of the owner of the body piercing studio or a body piercing\nspecialist of such studio. Such original written consent shall be\nretained by the body piercing studio for a period of twelve months and\nmay be retained off premises provided that an electronic image or\nfacsimile of the original signed consent form is readily available by\nthe owner or employee responsible for the operation of the body piercing\nstudio.\n  2. A written consent form signed by a parent or legal guardian\npursuant to subdivision one of this section shall expire twelve months\nfrom the date it is signed by the parent or legal guardian. Upon the\nexpiration of a written consent form, a new written consent shall be\nprovided in the manner prescribed in subdivision one of this section\nprior to the use of a body piercing studio by any person under eighteen\nyears of age.\n  3. This section shall be exclusive and shall preempt any contrary\nlocal law or ordinance, except that this section shall not preempt or\nsupersede local laws or ordinances imposing additional stricter\nrestrictions on the operation of body piercing studios which are in\neffect prior to the effective date of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>