<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-463"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-463"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="463"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-463/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-463/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-463/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-463/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_463">
        <num>463</num>
        <heading>Denial of permit; notice of hearing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 463. Denial of permit; notice of hearing. The department shall,\nbefore making a final determination to deny an application for a permit,\nnotify the applicant in writing of the reasons for such proposed denial\nand shall afford the applicant an opportunity to be heard in person or\nby counsel prior to denial of the application. Such notification shall\nbe served personally or by certified mail or in any manner authorized by\nthe civil practice law and rules for service of a summons. If a hearing\nis requested, such hearing shall be held at such time and place as the\ndepartment shall prescribe. If the applicant fails to make a written\nrequest for a hearing within thirty days after receipt of such\nnotification, then the notification of denial shall become the final\ndetermination of the department. The department, acting by such officer\nas the commissioner may designate, shall have the power to subpoena and\nbring before the officer any person in this state, and administer an\noath to and take testimony of any person or cause his deposition to be\ntaken. A subpoena issued under this section shall be regulated by the\ncivil practice law and rules. If, after such hearing, the application is\ndenied, written notice of such denial shall be served upon the applicant\npersonally or by certified mail or in any manner authorized by the civil\npractice law and rules for the service of a summons.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>