<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4670"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4670"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4670"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4670/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4670/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4670/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4670/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4670">
        <num>4670</num>
        <heading>Receiverships</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4670__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>when the community is issued a new certificate of authority; or\n  (ii) at such time as all of the residents in the community have been\nprovided alternate residential and health care services.\n  b. At the time of termination, the receiver shall render a full and\ncomplete accounting to the court and shall make disposition of surplus\nmoney at the discretion of the court.\n  7. a. Any person who is served a copy of an order of the court\nappointing the receiver shall, upon being notified of the name and\naddress of the receiver, make all payments for goods supplied by the\ncommunity, or services rendered by the community, to the receiver. A\nreceipt shall be given for each such payment, and copies of all such\nreceipts shall be kept on file by the receiver. The amount so received\nshall be deposited by the receiver in a special account which shall also\nbe used for all disbursements made by the receiver.\n  b. Any person refusing or omitting to make such a payment after such\nservice and notice may be sued therefor by the receiver. Such person\nshall not in such suit dispute the authority of the receiver to incur or\norder such expenses, or the right of the receiver to such payments made\nto him or her. The receipt provided by the receiver for any sum paid to\nhim or her shall, in all suits and proceedings and for every other\npurpose, be as effectual in favor of any person holding the receipt as\nactual payment of the amount thereof to the operator or other person or\npersons who would, but for the provisions of this section, have been\nentitled to receive the sum to be paid. No resident shall be discharged,\nnor shall any contract or rights be forfeited or impaired, nor any\nforfeiture or liability be incurred, by reason of any omission to pay\nany operator, owner, contractor or other person any sum so paid to the\nreceiver.\n  8. Any other provision of this article notwithstanding, the\ncommissioner may, if such commissioner deems appropriate, grant to any\ncomm...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>