<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4802"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4802"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4802"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4802">
        <num>4802</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the commissioner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4802. Powers and duties of the commissioner. 1. The commissioner or\nhis designated representative from the department shall have the right\nof entry at reasonable hours into any workplace when the commissioner\nhas reason to believe that employees are being exposed to toxic\nsubstances at hazardous levels to conduct such investigations as the\ncommissioner authorizes. The commissioner shall make available to\nappropriate authorities the results of any such investigation in which\nhazardous levels of toxic substances are found.\n  2. The commissioner may make public, available information containing\ndescriptions of the toxic effects and the circumstances under which\nthese effects are produced for toxic substances found in the course and\nscope of employment. He shall prepare this information in a clear and\ncoherent manner using words with common and everyday meanings to be\nforwarded to the industrial commissioner of the department of labor for\nuse in compliance with the provisions of article twenty-eight of the\nlabor law. The information provided may be based on the Threshold Limit\nValues For Chemical Substances And Physical Agents In The Workroom\nEnvironment With Intended Changes For 1979, as amended from time to\ntime, and the current Registry Of Toxic Effects Of Chemical Substances\nOf The National Institute Of Occupational Safety And Health.\n  3. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations and take\nall other actions necessary for the effective implementation of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>