<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4804"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4804"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4804"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4804">
        <num>4804</num>
        <heading>Outreach programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4804. Outreach programs. 1. The department may develop and implement\noutreach programs to inform employees of their right to information\nregarding the toxic effects and circumstances under which these effects\nare produced by toxic substances found in the course of employment.\n  2. The department is authorized and empowered to enter into\ncontractual agreements with public and private organizations to develop\nand implement such an outreach program.\n  3. As part of the outreach program, health officials may maintain a\nsupply of informational leaflets in public buildings, including but not\nlimited to local employment services offices of the department of labor,\ninstitutions and facilities under the supervision or control of the\ndepartment of health, hospitals, union halls, community centers, schools\nand local agencies providing services to employers and employees to help\ninsure that such persons are informed of the toxic substance information\nprogram. The department shall periodically distribute to newspapers,\ntelevision and radio stations throughout the state public service\nannouncements describing the toxic substance information outreach\nprogram.\n  4. The department of health shall develop informational leaflets\nconcerning the toxic substance information program in cooperation with\nthe industrial commissioner. The industrial commissioner may mail such\nleaflets to employers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>