<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-520"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-520"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="520"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_520">
        <num>520</num>
        <heading>County laboratories; establishment; charges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 520. County laboratories; establishment; charges. 1. The board of\nsupervisors of any county may establish therein a laboratory or\nlaboratories which shall serve the whole or part of the county.\n  2. In the resolution of the board of supervisors establishing such\nlaboratory it shall define the area which it is intended to serve, which\narea from time to time may by resolution be altered; provided, however,\nthat in defining such area the territory included in a town shall not be\ndivided and provided further, that no city or any part thereof shall be\nincluded in the area so defined unless the mayor and the common council,\nor the officials exercising similar powers, shall have consented\nthereto.\n  3. The services of such laboratories shall be rendered at an adequate\nand reasonable charge, except that, with the approval of the\ncommissioner, one or more services may be rendered without any charge.\n  4. The board of supervisors may, in lieu of the establishment of a\nlaboratory and with the approval of the commissioner, provide for\nlaboratory service by contracting with an established laboratory which\nis conveniently located.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>