<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-524"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-524"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="524"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-524/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-524/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-524/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-524/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_524">
        <num>524</num>
        <heading>County laboratories; boards of managers; officers; meetings; compensation and expenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 524. County laboratories; boards of managers; officers; meetings;\ncompensation and expenses. 1. Except in counties wherein the laboratory\nfunctions as a division of the county health department or wherein the\nboard of managers has been abolished, the board of managers of each\nlaboratory shall elect a chairman, vice chairman and a secretary.\n  2. The board of managers of each laboratory shall hold a meeting at\nleast four times in each year, and at such other times as it may deem\nnecessary.\n  3. Each member of the board of managers attending meetings of such\nboard shall receive his actual and necessary expenses incident thereto,\nto be audited and paid in the same manner as other expenses of the\nlaboratory.\n  4. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to effect any\nchange in the administration and organization of a county board of\nhealth which shall be vested with the powers and duties of a board of\nmanagers pursuant to subdivision five of section five hundred\ntwenty-three of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>