<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-570"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-570"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="570"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-570/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-570/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-570/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-570/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_570">
        <num>570</num>
        <heading>Declaration of policy and statement of purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 570. Declaration of policy and statement of purpose. The proper\nperformance of clinical laboratory and blood banking services is a\nmatter of vital concern, affecting the public health, safety and\nwelfare. Clinical laboratories and blood banks provide essential public\nhealth services in aiding the health care provider by furnishing\ninformation invaluable to the diagnosis and treatment of disease. The\nimproper performance of a laboratory procedure may induce an erroneous\ndiagnosis or contribute to the selection of an inappropriate method of\ntreatment, resulting in prolonged or unnecessary hospitalization, injury\nor even death. The protection of the people of this state requires\naffirmative action to insure that the performance of clinical laboratory\nand blood banking services meet high standards of public health care.\n  It is the purpose of this title to promote the public health, safety\nand welfare by requiring the licensure of clinical laboratories and\nblood banks, by establishing minimum qualifications for directors, and\nby requiring that the performance of all procedures employed by clinical\nlaboratories and blood banks meet minimum standards accepted and\napproved by the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>