<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-576-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-576-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="576-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-576-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-576-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-576-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-576-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_576_A">
        <num>576-A</num>
        <heading>Clinical laboratories and cytotechnologists examining Pap smears</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Cytotechnologist". A clinical laboratory professional\nspecializing in the analysis of cytopathology samples, including Pap\nsmears, for cervical cancer and related diseases who meets the\nqualifications specified by the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Cytotechnologist work standard".</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A limitation on the number\nof Pap smears (also known as gynecologic slides) and non-gynecologic\nslides a cytotechnologist may examine during a particular time period,\nor other limitation on the quantity, speed or manner of examination of\nslides by a cytotechnologist, under regulations of the department.\n  (ii) The department may establish regulations for cytotechnologist\nworkload standards that shall be at least as stringent as federal\nregulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Employ". To employ or contract with a cytotechnologist to examine\ngynecologic slides.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Clinical laboratory". A clinical laboratory issued a permit\npursuant to this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Work day". A twenty-four hour period during which a\ncytotechnologist examines gynecologic slides for a clinical laboratory.\n  2. Compliance with cytotechnologist work standard. No cytotechnologist\nshall exceed the applicable cytotechnologist work standard. No clinical\nlaboratory shall require, authorize, encourage or permit any\ncytotechnologist to exceed the applicable cytotechnologist work\nstandard. In determining whether a cytotechnologist exceeds the\napplicable cytotechnologist work standard, all work done by the\ncytotechnologist during a given work day shall be considered, without\nregard to which clinical laboratory or other person for which or whom it\nwas performed.\n  3. Record-keeping.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each clinical laboratory shall maintain\nrecords, in a form prescribed by the department, which set forth, for\neach cytotechnologist employed by the clinical laboratory:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name of the cytotechnologist;\n  (ii) the number of hours worked by the cytotechnologist in each work\nday;\n  (iii) the number of gynecologic slides and non-gynecologic slides\nexamined by the cytotechnologist during each work day; and\n  (iv) such other information as the department may require by\nregulation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such records of clinical laboratories and cytotechnologists shall\nbe made available for inspection and copying by the department upon\nrequest.\n  4. Multiple employers. Whenever a cytotechnologist is employed by more\nthan one clinical laboratory or other person during a work day, the\ncytotechnologist shall advise each clinical laboratory of any previous\nemployment during the work day and the amount of work performed, to\ninsure that the applicable cytotechnologist work standard is not\nexceeded.\n  5. Standards for gynecologic slides.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A gynecologic slide of a Pap\nsmear shall not be tested or reported on if:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the apparent condition of the specimen indicates that it is\nunsatisfactory for testing or that it is inappropriate for the test\nrequested;\n  (ii) it has been collected, labeled, preserved or otherwise handled in\nsuch a manner that it has become unsatisfactory or unreliable as a test\nspecimen;\n  (iii) the slide is broken;\n  (iv) it contains insufficient cells or the cells are obscured by\ninflammation, blood or lubricating ointment, so that an adequate\ndiagnosis cannot be made; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the slide is otherwise unsatisfactory, as defined by department\nregulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the slide is unsatisfactory as set forth in this subdivision,\nthe clinical laboratory shall have an affirmative duty to advise the\ncollecting physician or other practitioner that the slide is\nunsatisfactory and request the submission of a new slide.\n  6. Re-examination of slides. The department shall prescribe, by\nregulation, a system of targeted re-examination of gynecologic slides\nexamined and found to be not abnormal or questionable. The factors to be\nconsidered in the targeted re-examination may include, but are not\nlimited to, the prior cancer and other history of the patient, the\nresults of previous slide examinations, and the experience and ability\nof the cytotechnologist. Each clinical laboratory shall follow the\nprescribed re-examination system.\n  7. Notwithstanding any provisions of subdivision one of this section\nto the contrary, the department may, pursuant to regulation, increase\nthe maximum number of slides which may be examined in a work day for\nclinical laboratories using slide examination or preparation technology\napproved by the federal food and drug administration, provided that such\nstandards shall be at least as stringent as federal standards\npromulgated under the federal clinical laboratory improvement amendments\nof nineteen hundred eighty-eight or other applicable federal law.\n  8. Violations.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sections twelve, twelve-a, and twelve-b of this\nchapter shall apply to violations of this section, except that the civil\npenalty for a violation of this section by a cytotechnologist shall not\nexceed five hundred dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_576_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any clinical laboratory or other person violating this section\nis licensed, certified or registered by the department under other\nprovisions of law, the violation of this section may be grounds for\ndisciplining the person under such law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>