<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-605"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-605"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="605"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-605/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-605/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-605/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-605/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_605">
        <num>605</num>
        <heading>State aid; amount of reimbursement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 605. State aid; amount of reimbursement. 1. A state aid base grant\nshall be reimbursed to municipalities for the core public health\nservices identified in section six hundred two of this title, in an\namount of the greater of one dollar and thirty cents per capita, for\neach person in the municipality, or seven hundred fifty thousand\ndollars, provided that the municipality expends at least seven hundred\nfifty thousand dollars, for such core public health services. A\nmunicipality must provide all the core public health services identified\nin section six hundred two of this title to qualify for such base grant\nunless the municipality has the approval of the commissioner to expend\nthe base grant on a portion of such core public health services. If any\nservices in such section are not provided, the commissioner shall limit\nthe municipality's per capita or base grant to reflect the scope of the\nreduced services, in an amount not to exceed five hundred seventy-seven\nthousand five hundred dollars. The commissioner may use the amount that\nis not granted to contract with agencies, associations, or organizations\nto provide such services; or the health department may use such\nproportionate share to provide the services upon approval of the\ndirector of the division of the budget.\n  2. State aid reimbursement for public health services provided by a\nmunicipality under this title, shall be made if the municipality is\nproviding some or all of the core public health services identified in\nsection six hundred two of this title, pursuant to an approved\napplication for state aid, at a rate of no less than thirty-six per\ncentum, except for the city of New York which shall receive no less than\ntwenty per centum, of the difference between the amount of moneys\nexpended by the municipality for public health services required by\nsection six hundred two of this title during the fiscal year and the\nbase grant provided pursuant to subdivision one of this section.\nProvided, however, that a municipality's documented fringe benefit costs\nsubmitted under an application for state aid and otherwise eligible for\nreimbursement under this article shall not exceed fifty per centum of\nthe municipality's eligible personnel services. No such reimbursement\nshall be provided for services that are not eligible for state aid\npursuant to this article.\n  3. Municipalities shall make every reasonable effort to collect\npayments for public health services provided. All such revenues shall be\nreported to the commissioner pursuant to section six hundred six of this\ntitle and will be deducted from expenditures identified under\nsubdivision two of this section to produce a net cost eligible for state\naid.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>