<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-606"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-606"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="606"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_606">
        <num>606</num>
        <heading>Assessment of fees; third-party coverage or indemnification</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 606. Assessment of fees; third-party coverage or indemnification. 1.\nAssessment of fees by municipalities. Each municipality shall establish\na schedule of fees for public health services provided by the\nmunicipality and shall make every reasonable effort to collect such\nfees. Fees for personal health services shall be reflective of an\nindividual's ability to pay and shall not be inconsistent with the\nreimbursement guidelines of articles twenty-eight and thirty-six of this\nchapter and applicable federal laws and regulations. To the extent\npossible revenues generated shall be used to enhance or expand public\nhealth services. In its state aid application, each municipality shall\nprovide the department with a projection of fees and revenue to be\ncollected for that year. Each municipality shall periodically report to\nthe department fees and revenue actually collected.\n  2. Assessment of fees by the commissioner. In each municipality, the\ncommissioner shall establish a fee and revenue plan for services\nprovided by the department in a manner consistent with the standards and\nregulations established pursuant to subdivision one of this section.\n  3. Third party coverage or indemnification. For any public health\nservice for which coverage or indemnification from a third party is\navailable, the municipality must seek such coverage or indemnification\nand report any associated revenue to the department in its state aid\napplication.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>