<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-607"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-607"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="607"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_607">
        <num>607</num>
        <heading>Supplemental health services grants</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 607. Supplemental health services grants. 1. There shall be\nestablished within the special revenue fund-other a local public health\nservices program account. All revenues derived from fees collected by\nthe department pursuant to subdivision two of section six hundred six of\nthis article and all fines levied and collected by the department from\nenforcement actions pursuant to the services provided under titles one\nand two of this article, and monies received or recovered as a result of\nany audit exception assessed against the state aid reimbursement to a\nmunicipality under this article, shall be deposited in the local public\nhealth services program account.\n  2. Notwithstanding the limitations of available state aid defined in\nsection six hundred sixteen of this article, monies available for\nsupplemental health services grants in the local health services program\naccount shall be used by the commissioner for the purpose of providing\nsupplemental health services grants to municipalities for the\nenhancement of public health services, as an incentive for a\nmunicipality not organized as a county health district or a part-county\nhealth district to become organized or in recognition of municipalities\nwhich have consistently maximized revenue collections. Criteria for\neligibility for grants under this section shall be established by the\ncommissioner. Monies received from such supplemental grants shall be\nused to enhance or expand public health services and may not supplant\nthe amount that otherwise would be provided by the municipality or\nappropriated to the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>