<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-609"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-609"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="609"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-609/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-609/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-609/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-609/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_609">
        <num>609</num>
        <heading>State aid; laboratories</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 609. State aid; laboratories. 1. Where a laboratory shall have been\nor is hereafter established pursuant to article five of this chapter,\nthe state, through the legislature and within the limits to be\nprescribed by the commissioner, shall provide aid at a per centum,\ndetermined in accordance with the provisions of subdivision two of\nsection six hundred five of this article, of the actual cost of repair,\nrelocation, equipment and maintenance of the laboratory or laboratories\nfor services associated with a core public health service, as described\nin section six hundred two of this title. Such cost shall be the excess,\nif any, of such expenditures over available revenues of all types,\nincluding adequate and reasonable fees, derived from or attributable to\nthe performance of laboratory services.\n  2. Where a county or city provides or shall have provided for\nlaboratory service by contracting with an established laboratory for\nservices associated with a core public health service, as described in\nsubdivision three of section six hundred two of this title, with the\napproval of the commissioner, it shall be entitled to state aid at a per\ncentum, determined in accordance with the provisions of subdivision two\nof section six hundred five of this article, of the cost of the\ncontracts.\n  3. The work of all laboratories except the laboratories in the\ndepartment of health in the city of New York established or for which\naid is received in accordance with the provisions of this chapter shall\nbe inspected and standardized by the commissioner and no state aid shall\nbe given to any county or city unless the area of the district, site,\ndesign and construction of the buildings, equipment, work and conduct of\nthe laboratory shall be first approved in writing, after inspection, by\nthe commissioner or his representative.\n  4. The governing body of any county or city which has established and\nis maintaining a laboratory or which is providing laboratory services by\ncontract with another laboratory and which desires to make applications\nfor state aid under this title shall annually on such dates as may be\nfixed by the commissioner submit the request of such county or city for\nsuch state aid and shall support such request with such information as\nthe commissioner may require. The commissioner shall prescribe the form\nin which such information shall be submitted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>