<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-616"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-616"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="616"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-616/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-616/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-616/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-616/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_616">
        <num>616</num>
        <heading>Limitations on state aid</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 616. Limitations on state aid.  1. The total amount of state aid\nprovided pursuant to this article shall be limited to the amount of the\nannual appropriation made by the legislature. In no event, however,\nshall such state aid be less than an amount to provide the full base\ngrant and, as otherwise provided by subdivision two of section six\nhundred five of this article, no less than thirty-six per centum, except\nfor the city of New York which shall receive no less than twenty per\ncentum, of the difference between the amount of moneys expended by the\nmunicipality for eligible public health services pursuant to an approved\napplication for state aid during the fiscal year and the base grant\nprovided pursuant to subdivision one of section six hundred five of this\narticle.\n  2. No payments shall be made from moneys appropriated for the purpose\nof this article to a municipality for contributions by the municipality\nfor indirect costs.\n  3. Administrative policy changes relating to state aid shall not be\nimplemented without reasonable and statewide advance written notice to\nmunicipalities.\n  4. Moneys appropriated for the purposes of this article to a\nmunicipality may include reimbursement of a municipality's fringe\nbenefits, including but not limited to employee retirement funds, health\ninsurance and federal old age and survivor's insurance. However, costs\nsubmitted under an application for state aid must be consistent with a\nmunicipality's documented fringe benefit costs and shall not exceed\nfifty per centum of the municipality's eligible personnel services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>