<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-617"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-617"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="617"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-617/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-617/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-617/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-617/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_617">
        <num>617</num>
        <heading>Maintenance of effort</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 617. Maintenance of effort. Such amount of state aid provided will\nbe used to support and to the extent practicable, to increase the level\nof funds that would otherwise be made available for such purposes and\nnot to supplant the amount to be provided by the municipalities. If a\nmunicipality that is provided state aid pursuant to title one of this\narticle reduces its expenditures beneath the amount expended in its base\nyear, which is the most recent fiscal year for which the municipality\nhas filed all expenditure reports to the department, state aid\nreimbursement provided pursuant to subdivision one of section six\nhundred five of this article will be reduced by the percentage reduction\nin expenditures between its base year and its current fiscal year. For\npurposes of this section, reductions in expenditures shall be adjusted\nfor: an absence of extraordinary expenditures of a temporary nature,\nsuch as disaster relief; unavoidable or justifiable program reductions,\nsuch as a program being subsumed by another agency; or in circumstances\nwhere the municipality can demonstrate, to the department's\nsatisfaction, that the need for the expenditure no longer exists.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>