<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-618"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-618"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="618"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-618/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-618/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-618/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-618/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_618">
        <num>618</num>
        <heading>Performance and accountability</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 618. Performance and accountability. The commissioner shall\nestablish, in consultation with the municipalities, uniform statewide\nperformance standards for the services funded pursuant to this article;\nprovided, however, the commissioner may modify a specific standard for a\nmunicipality if such municipality demonstrates adequate justification.\nThe commissioner shall recognize the particular needs and capabilities\nof the various municipalities. The commissioner shall monitor the\nperformance and expenditures of each municipality to ensure that each\none satisfies the performance standards. Any municipality failing to\nsatisfy its standards may be subject to a reduction or loss of aid until\nsuch municipality can demonstrate that it has the capacity to satisfy\nsuch standards. The commissioner shall establish a uniform accounting\nsystem for monitoring the expenditures for services of each municipality\nto which aid is granted and the amount of state aid received including\nany performance payments pursuant to section six hundred nineteen-a of\nthis article. Such reporting system shall require information on the\namount of public health moneys received from the federal government, the\nprivate sector, grants, and fees. Each such municipality shall comply\nwith the regulations of such accounting and reporting systems.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>