<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="903"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_903">
        <num>903</num>
        <heading>Primary care physician loan repayment program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_903__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>beginning January first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, to any\nresident who first entered a primary care medical training program on or\nafter January first, nineteen hundred ninety-four in the second or third\nyear of such program; provided such resident agrees to practice primary\ncare in an underserved area in New York state for one year for each such\nannual award received, with such practice beginning immediately after\ncompletion of such residency training. Such resident shall be eligible\nfor an award of up to ten thousand dollars per year and beginning\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred ninety-seven of up to fifteen thousand\ndollars per year; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_903__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>beginning January first, nineteen hundred ninety-five, to a\nprimary care physician, emergency medicine physician or other physician\nspecialty determined by the commissioner to be in short supply, licensed\nto practice medicine in New York state, who agrees to practice for at\nleast two years in an underserved area. Such physician shall be eligible\nfor a loan repayment award of up to ten thousand dollars per year and\nbeginning January first, nineteen hundred ninety-seven of up to fifteen\nthousand dollars per year for each of the first two years of practice in\nsuch area; provided, however, if such physician agrees to practice for\nan additional two years in such area, then such physician shall be\neligible for an award of up to fifteen thousand dollars per year and\nbeginning January first, nineteen hundred ninety-seven of up to twenty\nthousand dollars per year for each of the second two years of such\npractice.\n  3. Loan repayment awards made to a physician pursuant to subdivision\ntwo of this section shall not exceed the total qualifying outstanding\ndebt of the physician from student loans to cover tuition and other\nrelated educational expenses, made by or guaranteed by the federal or\nstate government, or made by a lending or educational institution\napproved under title IV of the federal higher education act. Loan\nrepayment awards shall be used solely to repay such outstanding debt.\n  4. Within such time as the commissioner shall by regulation provide, a\nrecipient of an award shall have practiced as a primary care physician\nin an underserved area in the state of New York or, in the case of a\nrecipient of an award after completion of residency training, the\nrecipient shall have practiced in an underserved area for that number of\nmonths calculated by multiplying by twelve the number of annual awards\nreceived by the recipient. If a recipient fails to comply fully with\nsuch conditions, the president shall be entitled to receive from such\nrecipient ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>