<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="102"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_102">
        <num>102</num>
        <heading>Filing and publication of codes, rules and regulations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_102__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a United States statute or a code, rule or regulation published\nin the Code of Federal Regulations or in the Federal Register; or (ii)\nreadily available without charge on the internet to the legislative\nlibrary and, within each judicial department of the state, one court law\nlibrary designated by the chief administrator of the courts; provided\nthat for materials readily available on the internet, the agency shall\nidentify the address at which such materials can be accessed;\n  d. notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary, photocopies\nof any codes, rules and regulations shall be available to the public\nupon payment of a fee not to exceed twenty-five cents per page; and\n  e. the secretary of state shall cause such compilation to be printed;\nhowever, he may exclude from such printed compilation any previously\npublished portion of a rule which is precisely identified in the text\nthereof pursuant to paragraph c of subdivision one of this section.\n  5. The compilation printed pursuant to paragraph e of subdivision four\nof this section shall be known as the "official compilation of codes,\nrules and regulations of the state of New York" and shall presumptively\nestablish the codes, rules and regulations of the state of New York,\nexcept such as relate solely to the organization or internal management\nof a department, board, bureau, authority, commission or other agency of\nthe state, in force and effect on the first day of January, nineteen\nhundred forty-five. The official supplements to such compilation\npublished as hereinafter provided shall presumptively establish any\nchanges in such codes, rules and regulations and any new codes, rules or\nregulations except such as relate solely to the organization or internal\nmanagement of a department, board, bureau, authority, commission or\nother agency of the state, affected by addition, amendment or repeal, or\nadopted during the period ending on the thirty-first day of December in\nany year immedi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>