<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="103"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_103">
        <num>103</num>
        <heading>Future editions and supplements of official compilations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 103. Future editions and supplements of official compilations. 1.\nIn any year the secretary of state may, whenever he shall believe that\nthe public interest will be served thereby, cause a new edition of such\nofficial compilation or any volume thereof to be published, which\ncompilation shall be published as soon as practicable, and shall set\nforth the codes, rules and regulations except such as relate solely to\nthe organization or internal management of a department, board, bureau,\nauthority, commission or other agency of the state on file in the office\nof the department of state on the date as of which such new edition is\npublished.\n  2. The secretary of state may, whenever he deems it to be necessary,\ncause to be published an official supplement to the official\ncompilation, showing all new and all changes in existing codes, rules\nand regulations adopted since the effective date of the codes, rules and\nregulations embraced in the latest edition of the official compilation\nor since the end of the period covered by the preceding supplement.\n  3. Any new edition of such compilation published as heretofore\nprovided, and any supplementation thereof or thereto, shall\npresumptively establish that the codes, rules and regulations contained\ntherein are on file in the department of state, and are effective,\nunless otherwise stated, on the date as of which such new edition, or\nany volume thereof, or a supplementation thereto, is published.\n  4. Any code, rule or regulation contained in any new edition of the\nofficial compilation, or any volume thereof, or any supplementation\nthereto, shall not be printed in any official supplement published for\nany period prior to the date as of which such new edition, volume, or\nsupplementation is published.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>