<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="107"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_107">
        <num>107</num>
        <heading>Intergovernmental agreements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 107. Intergovernmental agreements. 1. The secretary of state shall\ncompile and keep current a list of all interstate compacts and other\nintergovernmental agreements between or among states, subdivisions of\nthis state and other states, or between this state or any subdivision\nthereof and the federal government having the force of law to which this\nstate or any subdivision thereof is party.  Such list shall contain the\ncitations to the statutes or other official documents of this state\ncontaining the text of any such compact or agreement together with a\nlisting of all other jurisdictions party to the compact or agreement,\nthe date on which each such jurisdiction entered into participation in\nsuch compact or agreement with this state or subdivision thereof; the\nstatus of each such compact or agreement in respect of withdrawals\ntherefrom and the citations to any act or resolution of the congress of\nthe United States, if any, consenting to such compact or agreement. The\nlist required to be kept pursuant to this subdivision also shall include\ncompacts and agreements adopted by this state or any subdivision thereof\nbut not in effect by reason of the absence of such other parties thereto\nas may be necessary to make the compact or agreement effective and\nbinding.\n  2. In any case where the statutes of this state do not contain the\nfull text of a compact or agreement to which subdivision one of this\nsection applies, the secretary of state shall receive a true copy of the\ncompact or agreement and keep the same on file.\n  3. Any amendment, supplementary agreement or administrative rule or\nregulation having the force of law implementing, adding to or modifying\nany such compact or agreement to which this state or a subdivision\nthereof is party shall be listed or filed in the same manner as the\ncompact or agreement itself.\n  4. The secretary of state shall make the list maintained by him\npursuant to this act and any information contained therein available to\nany person upon request, but shall not be required to furnish copies of\nany compact or agreement, unless so required by a provision of law or\nadministrative rule other than this section.\n  5. The listing and filing requirements of this section shall be in\naddition to and not in substitution for any requirements for listing or\nfiling, publication or distribution contained in particular compacts or\nagreements to which this state is or may be a party.\n  6. Upon receipt by the governor of a formal notice from another state\nof such state's withdrawal from an interstate compact to which New York\nis party, the governor shall transmit such notice or a copy thereof to\nthe secretary of state. Any agency or subdivision of this state\nadministering, participating in or entering into any compact or\nagreement shall furnish the secretary of state with all information\nnecessary to permit such secretary to perform his duties and\nresponsibilities pursuant to this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>