<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-133"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-133"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="133"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_133">
        <num>133</num>
        <heading>Certification of notarial signatures</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 133. Certification of notarial signatures. The county clerk of a\ncounty in whose office any notary public has qualified or has filed\ntheir autograph signature and a certificate of official character,\nshall, when so requested and upon payment of a fee of three dollars,\naffix to any certificate of proof or acknowledgment or oath signed by\nsuch notary anywhere in the state of New York, a certificate under their\nhand and seal, stating that a commission or a certificate of official\ncharacter of such notary with their autograph signature has been filed\nin the county clerk's office, and that the county clerk was at the time\nof taking such proof or acknowledgment or oath duly authorized to take\nthe same; that the county clerk is well acquainted with the handwriting\nof such notary public or has compared the signature on the certificate\nof proof or acknowledgment or oath with the autograph signature\ndeposited in their office by such notary public and believes that the\nsignature is genuine. An instrument with such certificate of\nauthentication of the county clerk affixed thereto shall be entitled to\nbe read in evidence or to be recorded in any of the counties of this\nstate in respect to which a certificate of a county clerk may be\nnecessary for either purpose. In addition to the foregoing powers, a\ncounty clerk of a county in whose office a notary public has qualified\nmay certify the signature of an electronic notary public, registered\nwith the secretary of state pursuant to section one hundred\nthirty-five-c of this article, provided such county clerk has received\nfrom the secretary of state, an exemplar of the notary public's\nregistered electronic signature.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>