<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-135-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-135-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="135-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-135-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-135-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-135-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-135-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_135_B">
        <num>135-B</num>
        <heading>Advertising by notaries public</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 135-b. Advertising by notaries public. 1. The provisions of this\nsection shall not apply to attorneys-at-law, admitted to practice in the\nstate of New York.\n  2. A notary public who advertises his or her services as a notary\npublic in a language other than English shall post with such\nadvertisement a notice in such other language the following statement:\n"I am not an attorney licensed to practice law and may not give legal\nadvice about immigration or any other legal matter or accept fees for\nlegal advice."\n  3. A notary public shall not use terms in a foreign language in any\nadvertisement for his or her services as a notary public that mean or\nimply that the notary public is an attorney licensed to practice in the\nstate of New York or in any jurisdiction of the United States. The\nsecretary shall designate by rule or regulation the terms in a foreign\nlanguage that shall be deemed to mean or imply that a notary public is\nlicensed to practice law in the state of New York and the use of which\nshall be prohibited by notary publics who are subject to this section.\n  4. For purposes of this section, "advertisement" shall mean and\ninclude material designed to give notice of or to promote or describe\nthe services offered by a notary public for profit and shall include\nbusiness cards, brochures, and notices, whether in print or electronic\nform.\n  5. Any person who violates any provision of this section or any rule\nor regulation promulgated by the secretary may be liable for civil\npenalty of up to one thousand dollars. The secretary of state may\nsuspend a notary public upon a second violation of any of the provisions\nof this section and may remove from office a notary public upon a third\nviolation of any of the provisions of this section, provided that the\nnotary public shall have been served with a copy of the charges against\nhim or her and been given an opportunity to be heard. The civil penalty\nprovided for by this subdivision shall be recoverable in an action\ninstituted by the attorney general on his or her own initiative or at\nthe request of the secretary.\n  6. The secretary may promulgate rules and regulations governing the\nprovisions of this section, including the size and type of statements\nthat a notary public is required by this section to post.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>