<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-137"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-137"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-03-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="137"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-137/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-137/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-137/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-137/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_137">
        <num>137</num>
        <heading>Statement as to authority of notaries public</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 137. Statement as to authority of notaries public. In exercising\npowers pursuant to this article, a notary public, in addition to the\nvenue of the act and signature of such notary public, shall print,\ntypewrite, stamp, or affix by electronic means where performing an\nelectronic notarial act in conformity with section one hundred\nthirty-five-c of the executive law, beneath their signature in black\nink, the notary public's name, the words "Notary Public State of New\nYork," the name of the county in which such notary public originally\nqualified, and the expiration date of such notary public's commission\nand, in addition, wherever required, a notary public shall also include\nthe name of any county in which such notary public's certificate of\nofficial character is filed, using the words "Certificate filed\n........... County." A notary public who is duly licensed as an attorney\nand counsellor at law in this state may substitute the words "Attorney\nand Counsellor at Law" for the words "Notary Public." A notary public\nwho has qualified or who has filed a certificate of official character\nin the office of the clerk in a county or counties within the city of\nNew York must also affix to each instrument such notary public's\nofficial number or numbers in black ink, as assigned by the clerk or\nclerks of such county or counties at the time such notary qualified in\nsuch county or counties and, if the instrument is to be recorded in an\noffice of the register of the city of New York in any county within such\ncity and the notary has been given a number or numbers by such register\nor his predecessors in any county or counties, when the notary public's\nautographed signature and certificate are filed in such office or\noffices pursuant to this chapter, the notary public shall also affix\nsuch number or numbers. No official act of such notary public shall be\nheld invalid on account of the failure to comply with these provisions.\nIf any notary public shall willfully fail to comply with any of the\nprovisions of this section, the notary public shall be subject to\ndisciplinary action by the secretary of state. In all the courts within\nthis state the certificate of a notary public, over the signature of the\nnotary public, shall be received as presumptive evidence of the facts\ncontained in such certificate; provided, that any person interested as a\nparty to a suit may contradict, by other evidence, the certificate of a\nnotary public.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>