<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-144-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-144-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="144-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-144-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-144-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-144-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-144-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_144_A">
        <num>144-A</num>
        <heading>Eligible professions for the purchase, sale, and use of body armor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 144-a. Eligible professions for the purchase, sale, and use of body\narmor. The secretary of state in consultation with the division of\ncriminal justice services, the division of homeland security and\nemergency services, the department of corrections and community\nsupervision, the division of the state police, and the office of general\nservices shall promulgate rules and regulations to establish criteria\nfor eligible professions requiring the use of body armor, as such term\nis defined in subdivision two of section 270.20 of the penal law. Such\nprofessions shall include those in which the duties may expose the\nindividual to serious physical injury that may be prevented or mitigated\nby the wearing of body armor. Such rules and regulations shall also\ninclude a process by which an individual or entity may request that the\nprofession in which they engage be added to the list of eligible\nprofessions, a process by which the department shall approve such\nprofessions, and a process by which individuals and entities may present\nproof of engagement in eligible professions when purchasing body armor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>