<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-148"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-148"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="148"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-148/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-148/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-148/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-148/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_148">
        <num>148</num>
        <heading>Distribution and fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 148. Distribution and fees. 1. a. The department of state shall mail\nor otherwise deliver a copy of each issue of the state register to the\noffice of the clerk of every county, to every library designated by the\ncommissioner of education, and upon written request, to the office of\nthe clerk of any city, town or village. Such copies shall be made\navailable for public inspection by such offices and libraries for not\nless than one year.\n  b. On or before September first, nineteen hundred eighty-three, and\nannually thereafter, the commissioner of education shall designate a\nsufficient number of libraries, not to exceed three hundred, to provide\na uniform, statewide distribution of copies of each issue of the state\nregister, and shall provide the department of state with a list of such\ndesignated libraries.\n  2. The department of state shall mail or otherwise deliver a copy of\neach regular issue and the quarterly index required by subdivision three\nof section one hundred forty-seven of this article to each agency and\nevery state legislator, unless the agency or state legislator has\nrequested that the department discontinue such delivery, and shall\nprovide notice and indicate the availability upon request of any special\nissue published pursuant to subdivision two of section one hundred\nforty-seven of this article by placing said notice in the regular issue\nappearing two weeks prior to the publication date of any such special\nissue. Such special issues shall be available to each agency and state\nlegislator at no charge.\n  3. Subscriptions to the state register shall be made available to the\npublic by either first or second class mail, or in electronic form at\nthe election of the subscriber. A reasonable rate for a subscription to\nprinted copies of the regular issue and quarterly index required by\nsubdivision three of section one hundred forty-seven of this article, to\nbe not more than eighty dollars per year for first class mail delivery\nand not more than forty dollars per year for second class mail delivery,\nshall be set by the secretary of state. The secretary of state may\ncharge no more than one dollar and fifty cents per single copy of a\nprinted regular issue or quarterly index of the state register. Rates\nshall not be set at such a level that the anticipated total subscription\nrevenues exceed the total cost of producing, printing and distributing\nthe state register.\n  4. Special issues published pursuant to subdivision two of section one\nhundred forty-seven of this article shall be made available to the\npublic at prices set by the secretary of state to reflect the cost of\nproducing, printing and distributing the special issues. The notice\nprovided in subdivision two of this section shall indicate the prices of\nthe special issues.\n  4-a. In addition to the state register, the department of state shall\nmake available at no cost an online version of the weekly state\nregister, quarterly index and any special issues as directed by statute\nor deemed appropriate by the secretary of state.\n  5. The secretary of state shall be entitled to charge and receive a\nreasonable sum from any person required by state statute to cause a\nnotice to be published in the state register.\n  6. All fees set by the secretary of state pursuant to this section are\nsubject to the approval of the director of the budget.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>