<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-152"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-152"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="152"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-152/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-152/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-152/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-152/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_152">
        <num>152</num>
        <heading>General functions, powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 152. General functions, powers and duties. The department of state,\nby and through the secretary of state or duly authorized officers or\nemployees, shall have the following functions, powers and duties:\n  1. To assist the governor in coordinating the activities and services\nof those departments and agencies of the state having relationships with\nmunicipalities to the end of providing more effective services to such\nmunicipalities.\n  2. To keep the governor informed as to the problems of municipalities\nand to advise and assist in formulating policies with respect thereto\nand utilizing the resources of the state government for the benefit of\nmunicipalities.\n  3. To serve as a clearinghouse, for the benefit of municipalities,\nregarding information relating to their common problems and to the state\nand federal services available to assist in the solution of those\nproblems.\n  4. To refer municipalities to the appropriate departments and agencies\nof the state and federal governments for advice, assistance and\navailable services in connection with particular problems\n  5. To advise and assist municipalities in the solution of particular\nproblems.\n  6. To conduct studies and analyses of the problems of municipalities\nand to make the results thereof available as the secretary may deem\nappropriate.\n  7. To encourage and assist cooperative efforts among municipalities in\ndeveloping among themselves solutions of their common problems.\n  8. To encourage expansion and improvement of training made available\nto municipal officials, in cooperation with municipalities and the\norganizations representing them.\n  9. To consult with and cooperate with municipalities and officers,\norganizations, groups and individuals representing them, to the end of\nmore effectively carrying out the functions, powers and duties of the\ndepartment.\n  10. To encourage and facilitate cooperation and collaboration among\nagencies and levels of government, and between government and the\nprivate sector, for the protection and development of human, natural and\nman-made resources.\n  11. To advise and assist municipalities in the performance of their\nplanning and development activities.\n  12. To aid and assist, in the provision and coordination of state\ntechnical assistance and services in connection with the planning and\ndevelopment activities of municipalities.\n  13. To provide assistance and guidance to municipalities and, as\nappropriate, to the private sector, through the compilation, formulation\nand dissemination of necessary information, projections and techniques\nrelating to development of resources.\n  14. To undertake any studies, inquiries, surveys or analyses necessary\nfor performance of the functions, powers and duties of the department\nthrough the personnel of the department or consultants, or in\ncooperation with any public or private agencies.\n  15. To adopt, amend or rescind such rules, regulations and orders as\nmay be necessary or convenient for the performance of its functions,\npowers and duties under this article.\n  16. To enter into contracts with any persons, firm, corporation or\ngovernmental agency, and to do all other things necessary or convenient\nto carry out the functions, powers and duties expressly set forth in\nthis article.\n  17. To effectuate the purposes of this article, and to enable the\ndepartment properly to carry out its functions, powers and duties, the\nsecretary of state may request from any state department or agency or\nfrom any municipality, and the same are hereby authorized to provide,\nappropriate assistance, services and data.\n  22. To prepare and recommend to the legislature and the governor\nlegislative proposals relating to municipalities.\n  23. With the approval of the governor, to accept and administer as\nagent of the state any gift, grant, devise or bequest, whether\nconditional or unconditional, including federal grants, for any of the\npurposes of this article. Any moneys so received may be expended subject\nto the same limitations as to approval of expenditures and audits as are\nprescribed for state moneys.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>