<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_C">
        <num>156-C</num>
        <heading>Fire safety standards for cigarettes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such certifications must be based upon testing conducted by a\nlaboratory that has been accredited pursuant to Standard ISO/IEC 17025\nof the international organization for standardization, or such other\ncomparable accreditation standard as the office of fire prevention and\ncontrol shall require by regulation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such certification shall be signed by an officer of the\nmanufacturer and shall contain for each cigarette brand style such\ninformation as shall be deemed necessary by the office of fire\nprevention and control, including but not limited to:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the brand and\nstyle; (ii) length in millimeters; (iii) circumference in millimeters;\n(iv) flavor, if applicable;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>filter or non-filter; (vi) package\ndescription; (vii) the name, address and telephone number of the\nlaboratory, if different than the manufacturer that conducted the test;\n(viii) the date that the testing occurred; and (ix) a notarized\nstatement from an officer or director of the laboratory certifying that\nthe cigarette meets the performance standards prescribed by the office\nof fire prevention and control.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a manufacturer has certified a cigarette pursuant to this\nsubdivision, and thereafter makes any change to such cigarette that is\nlikely to alter its compliance with the fire safety standards mandated\nby this section, then before such cigarette may be sold or offered for\nsale in this state such manufacturer shall retest such cigarette in\naccordance with the testing standards prescribed by the office of fire\nprevention and control and maintain records of such retesting as\nrequired by subdivision seven of this section. Any such altered\ncigarette which does not meet the performance standard prescribed by the\noffice of fire prevention and control may not be sold in the state.\nCopies of such written certifications shall be provided by the\ncertifying manufacturer to all wholesale dealers, as defined in\nsubdivision eight of section four hundred seventy of the tax law, and\nall agents, as defined in subdivision eleven of section four hundred\nseventy of the tax law. The office of fire prevention and control shall\nprescribe procedures by which stamping agents, wholesale dealers or\nretail dealers are notified of which cigarettes have been certified by\nmanufacturers as meeting the performance standards prescribed by the\noffice of fire prevention and control, which may include the maintenance\nof a website listing certified cigarette brands and styles.\n  4. The fire safety standards required pursuant to subdivision two of\nthis section shall take effect on such date as the office of fire\nprevention and control shall specify in promulgating such standards and\nsuch date shall be the earliest practicable date by which manufacturers\nof cigarettes can comply with such standards; provided, however, that\nsuch date shall not be later than one hundred eighty days after such\nstandards are promulgated. On and after such date, no person or entity\nshall sell in this state cigarettes that have not been certified by the\nmanufacturer in accordance with subdivision thr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that such cigarettes have been physically segregated\nfrom cigarettes offered for sale in New York; and (ii) no New York tax\nstamps have been placed on any cigarettes that have not been certified\nor marked in accordance with this section. In addition to any penalties\nimposed by this section the commissioner of taxation and finance, after\nan opportunity for a hearing has been afforded pursuant to subdivision\nfive of section four hundred eighty of the tax law, shall suspend for\nsix months the license of any agent issued pursuant to section four\nhundred seventy-two of the tax law, the license of any wholesale dealer\nissued pursuant to section four hundred eighty of the tax law, or the\nregistration of any retail dealer issued pursuant to section four\nhundred eighty-a of the tax law, when such agent, wholesale dealer or\nretail dealer violates this section three or more times within a three\nyear period, provided such violations occurred on at least three\nseparate calendar days.\n  b. In addition to any penalty prescribed by law, any corporation,\npartnership, sole proprietor, limited partnership, association or any\nother business entity engaged in the manufacture of cigarettes that\nknowingly makes a false certification pursuant to subdivision three of\nthis section shall be subject to a civil penalty of at least\nseventy-five thousand dollars and not to exceed two hundred fifty\nthousand dollars for each such false certification, and any entity that\nfails to pay a civil penalty imposed pursuant to this paragraph within\nthirty days after such penalty is imposed, shall be subject to a bar\nfrom selling cigarettes covered by that false certification in this\nstate until the state receives full payment of such penalty.\n  c. There is hereby established in the custody of the state comptroller\na special fund to be known as the "Cigarette Fire Safety Act Fund". Such\nfund shall consist of all moneys recovered from the assessment of civil\npenalties authorized b...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in\naccordance with the requirements applicable to manufacturers pursuant to\nthe regulations of the office of fire prevention and control, and (ii)\nby a laboratory that has been accredited pursuant to Standard ISO/IEC\n17025 of the international organization for standardization or such\nother comparable accreditation standard as the office of fire prevention\nand control shall require by regulation.\n  8. a. To enforce the provisions of this section, the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance and the state fire administrator may take\nadministrative action imposing the civil penalties and suspensions\nauthorized by subdivision five of this section. In addition, the\nattorney general may bring an action on behalf of the people of the\nstate of New York to enjoin acts in violation of this section and to\nrecover any civil penalties unless civil penalties have been previously\nrecovered in such administrative proceedings.\n  b. Any enforcement officer as defined in section thirteen hundred\nninety-nine-t of the public health law shall have the power to impose\nupon any retail dealer the civil penalties authorized by subdivision\nfive of this section, following a hearing conducted in the same manner\nas hearings conducted under article thirteen-E of the public health law.\n  c. To enforce the provisions of this section, the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance and the state fire administrator, or their duly\nauthorized representatives, are hereby authorized to examine the books,\npapers, invoices and other records of any person in possession, control\nor occupancy of any premises where cigarettes are placed, stored, sold\nor offered for sale, as well as the stock of cigarettes in any such\npremises. Every person in the possession, control or occupancy of any\npremises where cigarettes are placed, sold or offered for sale, is\nhereby directed and required to give the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance and the state fire administrator, and their duly authorized\nrepr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>