<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_A">
        <num>156-A</num>
        <heading>Establishment of a specialized hazardous materials emergency response training program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hands-on training, including information in regard to leak and\nspill control, product neutralization, pickup and disposal, fire\ncontrol, decontamination procedures and use and application of foam\nagents;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hazard assessment with emphasis on incident scene decision-making,\nincluding: potential threat to public safety and need for evacuation,\ncalculation of the effect of weather on certain chemicals and evaluation\nof the result of chemical exposures to air, water, soil, vegetation,\nlives and property and impact on the personal safety of those working in\nthe accident area;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>calibration and use of emergency equipment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>chemical and biological properties of various classes of\nchemicals, for example, flammables, oxidizers, corrosives, poisons; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>weapons of mass destruction and response to terrorism.\n  3. Such specialized hazardous materials emergency response training\nprogram curriculum shall also include guidance regarding emergency\nresponse to incidents involving lithium-ion batteries. For the purposes\nof this section, "lithium-ion battery" shall have the same meaning as in\nsection four hundred ninety-five of the general business law.\n  4. The state fire administrator is hereby directed to issue a report\nto the governor, speaker of the assembly, temporary president of the\nsenate, chairman of the assembly transportation committee and the\nchairman of the senate transportation committee by February fifteenth of\neach year on the operations of the program set forth in this section.\n  5. The state fire administrator shall promulgate such rules and\nregulations as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>