<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_D">
        <num>156-D</num>
        <heading>Thermal imaging camera grant program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 156-d. Thermal imaging camera grant program. 1. Subject to available\nappropriation, there is hereby established in the office of fire\nprevention and control a thermal imaging camera grant program, under\nwhich grants shall be made available to fire organizations for the\npurchase of one thermal imaging camera each or for reimbursement to such\nfire organizations for public funds, other than state or federal funds,\nthat have been expended by such fire organizations on or after April\nfirst, two thousand for the purchase of a thermal imaging camera,\nprovided, however, no reimbursement, when combined with any required\nmatch, shall exceed the office of general services contract price per\ncamera. Such grants shall be made available upon application by such\nfire organizations. Fire organizations that are without a thermal\nimaging camera shall receive priority from the office of fire prevention\nand control for grants made pursuant to this section. The office of fire\nprevention and control may require, pursuant to such uniform standards\nas such office may prescribe, that applicants for such grants or\nreimbursement provide matching funds of up to, but not more than, the\namount awarded; provided, however, that a fire organization having an\nannual operating budget of one hundred fifty thousand dollars or less\nshall not be required to provide matching funds. The office of fire\nprevention and control shall promulgate such rules and regulations as\nare necessary to advance the purposes of this section. Such regulations\nshall establish, among other things, training requirements for the use\nof thermal imaging cameras by fire organizations.\n  2. As used in this section, "fire organizations" means a board of fire\ncommissioners, which operates a fire department pursuant to the town\nlaw, a fire department established pursuant to the village law or\ngeneral city law or a fire company located within a fire protection\ndistrict pursuant to the town law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>