<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-10-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="156"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-156/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156">
        <num>156</num>
        <heading>Functions, powers and duties of the office</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_156__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>arson suppression, detection, investigation and\nprosecution,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fire prevention and control, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_156__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fire\nservice-related problems, to the end of providing more effective\nservices to the public and strengthening governmental programs relating\nto such matters.\n  1-a. Advise and assist the state education department in the\ndevelopment of a specialized course of study for teachers of fire and\narson prevention.\n  2. Advise and assist fire companies, municipal corporations and\ndistricts, including agencies and departments thereof in developing\nmeasures for more effective fire and arson prevention and control; to\nassist and encourage cooperative efforts to solve common problems\nrelating to fire and arson prevention and control and to serve as a\nclearinghouse of information about fire and arson prevention and\ncontrol, about reported cases of burn injuries or wounds sustained, and\nabout state and federal services available to assist in solving such\nproblems.\n  3. Employ or contract with individuals, agencies or corporations to\nassist fire companies, municipal corporations and districts in the\ndevelopment of an arson investigation program or in the investigation of\ncases of suspected arson or cases of burn injuries or wounds sustained\nupon the request of such an entity. However, nothing in this provision\nshall be construed to remove the primary responsibility for arson\ninvestigations from appropriate local jurisdictions or agencies.\n  4. Improve arson evidence analysis and testing at existing facilities\nand periodically recommend to the governor and the legislature methods\nto improve such services.\n  5. Collect, compile and disseminate information relating to fire and\narson prevention and control, reported cases of burn injuries or wounds\nsustained, the use of sprinkler systems, and to operate a state fire\nreporting system. The state fire reporting system shall include a\nprocedure for the identification of patterns of suspicious or criminal\nfires and for alerting appropriate state and local authorities. The fire\nreporting system shall also in...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>