<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="159-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_159_M">
        <num>159-M</num>
        <heading>Designation and redesignation of eligible entities in unserved areas</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_159_M__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In\ngeneral. If any geographic area of the state is not, or ceases to be,\nserved by an eligible entity under this article, and if the governor\ndecides to serve such area, the governor may solicit applications from,\nand designate as an eligible entity\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_159_M__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a private nonprofit organization (which may include an eligible\nentity) that is geographically located in the unserved area, that is\ncapable of providing a broad range of services designed to eliminate\npoverty and foster self-sufficiency, and that meets the requirements of\nthis article; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_159_M__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a private nonprofit eligible entity that is geographically located\nin an area contiguous to or within reasonable proximity of the unserved\narea and that is already providing related services in the unserved\narea.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_159_M__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Requirement. In order to serve as the eligible entity for the\narea, an entity described in subparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_159_M__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision shall agree to add additional members to the board of the\nentity to ensure adequate representation\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_159_M__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in each of the three required categories described in paragraph\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_159_M__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section one hundred fifty-nine-e of this\narticle, by members that reside in the community comprised by the\nunserved area; and\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_159_M__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in the category described in subparagraph two of paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_159_M__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision two of section one hundred fifty-nine-e of this article, by\nmembers that reside in the neighborhood to be served.\n  2. Special consideration. In designating an eligible entity under\nsubdivision one of this section, the governor shall grant the\ndesignation to an organization of demonstrated effectiveness in meeting\nthe goals and purposes of this article and may give priority, in\ngranting the designation, to eligible entities that are providing\nrelated services in the unserved area, consistent with the needs\nidentified by a community-needs assessment.\n  3. No qualified organization in or near area. If no private, nonprofit\norganization is identified or determined to be qualified under\nsubdivision one of this section to serve the unserved area as an\neligible entity the governor may designate an appropriate political\nsubdivision of the state to serve as an eligible entity for the area. In\norder to serve as the eligible entity for that area, the political\nsubdivision shall have a tripartite board or other mechanism as required\nin section one hundred fifty-nine-e of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>