<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="159-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_159_I">
        <num>159-I</num>
        <heading>Distribution of funds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 159-i. Distribution of funds. At least ninety percent of the\ncommunity services block grant funds received by the state shall be\ndistributed pursuant to a contract by the secretary to eligible entities\nas defined in subdivision one of section one hundred fifty-nine-e of\nthis article.  Each such eligible entity shall receive the same\nproportion of community services block grant funds as was the proportion\nof funds received in the immediately preceding federal fiscal year under\nthe federal community services block grant program as compared to the\ntotal amount received by all eligible entities in the state, under the\nfederal community services block grant program.\n  The secretary shall, pursuant to section one hundred fifty-nine-h of\nthis article, retain not more than five percent of the community\nservices block grant funds for administration at the state level.\n  The remainder of the community services block grant funds received by\nthe state shall be distributed pursuant to a contract by the secretary\nin the following order of preference: a sum of up to one-half of one\npercent of the community services block grant funds received by the\nstate to Indian tribes and tribal organizations as defined in this\narticle, on the basis of need; and to community based organizations.\nSuch remainder funds received by eligible entities will not be included\nin determining the proportion of funds received by any such entity in\nthe immediately preceding federal fiscal year under the federal\ncommunity services block grant program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>