<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="159"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-159/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_159">
        <num>159</num>
        <heading>Advisory council for fire prevention and control</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_159__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>execution of the functions, powers and duties of the\noffice with respect to fire and arson prevention and control services,\npolicies and programs;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_159__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>recommendations on courses of instruction and\nstandards for training of firefighters of fire departments, fire\ncompanies, municipal corporations, districts, and private industry of\nthe state;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_159__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>recommendations on federal and state legislation and\nprograms relating to fire and arson prevention services, policies and\nprograms; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_159__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>recommendations upon such other matters as the\ncommissioner and the state fire administrator may request.\n  2. The council shall be composed of the state fire administrator, as\nchair, or his or her designee, and twelve other members appointed as\nfollows: six members appointed by the governor; two members appointed by\nthe temporary president of the senate; one member appointed by the\nminority leader of the senate; two members appointed by the speaker of\nthe assembly; one member appointed by the minority leader of the\nassembly.\n  3. Membership of such council shall consist of representatives from\nthe volunteer and career fire service, at least half of which shall\nserve at the municipal level.\n  4. Members of the council, other than the state fire administrator,\nshall serve for terms of three years, with such terms to commence on\nApril first and expire on March thirty-first.\n  5. No member of the council shall be disqualified from holding any\nother public office or employment, nor shall he or she forfeit any such\noffice or employment by reason of the appointment hereunder,\nnotwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local law,\nordinance or city charter.\n  6. The council shall meet at least twice a year. Special meetings may\nbe called by the chairperson. The agenda and meeting place of all\nregular or special meetings shall be made available to the public in\nadvance of such meeting.\n  7. Members of the council shall serve without salary or per diem\nallowance, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of official duties under\nthis section, provided, however, that such members are not, at the time\nsuch expenses are incurred, public employees otherwise entitled to such\nreimbursement.\n  8. The chairperson may create subcommittees as he or she may from time\nto time deem appropriate to provide the council with advice and\nrecommendations. Members of such subcommittees shall ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>