<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_O">
        <num>160-O</num>
        <heading>Renewal certificate or license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-o. Renewal certificate or license. 1. a. To obtain a\nrecertification as a state certified real estate appraiser, or a renewal\nof license as a state licensed real estate appraiser, the holder of a\ncurrent, valid certificate or license shall make application and pay the\nprescribed fee to the department not earlier than one hundred twenty\ndays nor later than thirty days prior to the expiration date of the\ncertificate or license then held. With the application for\nrecertification or renewal of license, the state certified real estate\nappraiser or state licensed real estate appraiser shall present evidence\nin the form prescribed by the department of having completed the\ncontinuing education requirements, if any, for renewal specified in this\narticle.\n  b. If the department determines that an applicant has failed to meet\nthe requirements for renewal of certification or licensing through\nmistake, misunderstanding or circumstances beyond the control of the\napplicant, the department may extend the term of the certificate or\nlicense for a period not to exceed six months, upon payment by the\napplicant of the prescribed fee for the extension.\n  c. If the applicant satisfies the requirements for renewal during the\nextended term of certification or license, the beginning date of the new\nrenewal certificate or license shall be the day following the expiration\nof the certificate or license previously held by the applicant.\n  2. If a person fails to renew a certificate as a state certified real\nestate appraiser, or license as a state licensed real estate appraiser,\nprior to its expiration or within a period of extension granted by the\ndepartment pursuant to this article, the person may obtain a\nrecertification or renewal of license by satisfying all of the\nrequirements for renewal and by the payment of a late renewal fee.\n  3. The license of a state licensed real estate appraiser assistant may\nbe renewed in accordance with the provisions of subdivisions one and two\nof this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>