<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-T"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-T"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-T"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-T/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-T/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-T/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-T/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_T">
        <num>160-T</num>
        <heading>Continuing education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-t. Continuing education. 1. As a prerequisite to recertification\nor renewal of license, a certified or licensed real estate appraiser\nshall present evidence satisfactory to the department of having met the\ncontinuing education requirements, if any, pursuant to this article.\n  2. The basic continuing education requirement for recertification or\nrenewal of license shall be the completion by the applicant, during the\nimmediately preceding term of certification or license, of not less than\ntwenty-eight classroom hours of instruction in courses or seminars which\nhave received the approval of the department. Computer based and\ndistance learning courses may be approved by the department so long as\nproviders demonstrate the ability to monitor and verify participation by\nthe real estate appraiser for the specified time periods.\n  3. In lieu of meeting the requirements of subdivision two of this\nsection an applicant for recertification or renewal of license may\nsatisfy all or part of the requirements by presenting evidence of the\nfollowing:\n  a. Completion of an educational program of study determined by the\ndepartment to be equivalent, for continuing education purposes, to\ncourses approved by the department pursuant to subdivision two of this\nsection; or\n  b. Participation other than as a student in educational processes and\nprograms approved by the department which relate to real property\nappraisal theory, practices or techniques, including, but not\nnecessarily limited to, teaching, program development and preparation of\ntextbooks, monographs, articles and other instructional materials.\n  4. The secretary of state or her duly appointed designee shall adopt\nregulations upon recommendation by the board for implementations of the\nprovisions of this article to assure that persons renewing their\ncertifications as state certified real estate appraisers or licenses as\nstate licensed real estate appraisers have current knowledge of real\nproperty appraisal theories, practices and techniques which will provide\na high degree of service and protection to those members of the public\nwith whom they deal in a professional relationship under authority of\nthe certification or license. The regulations shall prescribe the\nfollowing:\n  a. Policies and procedures for obtaining departmental approval of\ncourses of instruction pursuant to subdivision two of this section;\n  b. Standards, policies and procedures to be applied by the department\nin evaluating applicant's claims of equivalency in accordance with\nsubdivision three of this section;\n  c. Standards, monitoring methods and systems for recording attendance\nto be employed by course sponsors as a prerequisite to department\napproval of courses for credit.\n  5. In adopting regulations pursuant to paragraph a of subdivision four\nof this section, the board shall give favorable consideration to courses\nof instruction, seminars and other real property appraisal educational\ncourses or programs previously or hereafter developed by or under the\nauspices of professional appraisal organizations and utilized by those\nassociations for purposes of designation or indicating compliance with\nthe continuing education requirements of such organizations.\n  6. No amendment or repeal of a regulation adopted by the secretary of\nstate or her duly appointed designee pursuant to this section shall\noperate to deprive a state certified real estate appraiser of credit\ntoward recertification, or a state licensed real estate appraiser of\ncredit toward renewal of license, for any course of instruction\ncompleted by the applicant prior to the amendment or repeal of the\nregulation which would have qualified for continuing education credit\nunder the regulation as it existed prior to the repeal or amendment.\n  7. A certification as a state certified real estate appraiser, or a\nlicense as a state licensed real estate appraiser, that has been revoked\nas a result of disciplinary action by the department shall not be\nreinstated unless the applicant presents evidence of completion of the\ncontinuing education required by this article. This requirement of\nevidence of continuing education shall not be imposed upon any applicant\nfor reinstatement who has been required to successfully complete the\nexamination for state certified or licensed real estate appraiser as a\ncondition to reinstatement of certification or license.\n  8. The board shall prescribe the continuing education requirements for\nlicensed real estate appraiser assistants; provided, however, that in no\nevent shall such requirements be less than the minimum criteria\nestablished by the Appraisal Subcommittee of the Federal Financial\nInstitutions Examination Council or by the Appraiser Qualification Board\nof the Appraisal Foundation as referred to in title XI of the Financial\nInstitutions Reform, Recovery and Enforcement Act of 1989.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>