<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Y"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Y"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-Y"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_Y">
        <num>160-Y</num>
        <heading>Contingent fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-y. Contingent fees. 1. A state certified or licensed real estate\nappraiser may not accept a fee for an appraisal assignment as defined in\nsection one hundred sixty-x of this article, that is contingent upon the\nappraiser reporting a predetermined estimate, analysis, or opinion or is\ncontingent upon the opinion, conclusion or valuation reached, or upon\nthe consequences resulting from the appraisal assignment.\n  2. A state certified or licensed real estate appraiser who enters into\nan agreement to perform specialized services, as defined in section one\nhundred sixty-x of this article, may be paid a fixed fee or a fee that\nis contingent on the results achieved by the specialized services.\n  3. If a state certified or licensed real estate appraiser enters into\nan agreement to perform specialized services for a contingent fee, this\nfact shall be clearly stated in each written report. In each written\nreport, this fact shall be clearly stated in a prominent location in\nsuch report and also in each letter of transmittal and in the\ncertification or authentication of the statements made by the appraiser\nin such a report.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>