<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-DD"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-DD"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-DD"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_DD">
        <num>160-DD</num>
        <heading>New York black car operators' injury compensation fund, inc</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-dd. New York black car operators' injury compensation fund, inc.\nThere is hereby created a not-for-profit corporation to be known as the\nNew York black car operators' injury compensation fund, inc. To the\nextent that the provisions of the not-for-profit corporation law do not\nconflict with the  provisions of this article, or with the plan of\noperation established pursuant to this article, the not-for-profit\ncorporation law shall apply to the fund, which shall be a type C\ncorporation pursuant to such law. If an applicable provision of this\narticle or of the fund's plan of operation relates to a matter embraced\nin a provision of the not-for-profit corporation law but is not in\nconflict therewith, both provisions shall apply. The fund shall perform\nits functions in accordance with its plan of operation established and\napproved pursuant to section one hundred sixty-gg of this article and\nshall exercise its powers through a board of directors established\npursuant to this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>