<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-AAA"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-AAA"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-AAA"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-AAA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-AAA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-AAA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-AAA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_AAA">
        <num>160-AAA</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-aaa. Definitions. For the purposes of this article:\n  1. "Independent livery driver" means a livery driver that is\ndispatched by an independent livery base.\n  2. "Annualized basis" means the product of the number of livery\ndrivers affiliated with a dispatching livery base and the number of\nmonths each such driver is affiliated with the livery base, divided by\ntwelve.\n  3. "Covered services" means all dispatches from a livery base\nregardless of where the pick-up or discharge occurs.\n  4. "Fund" means the independent livery driver benefit fund as\nestablished in this article.\n  5. "Independent livery base" has the same meaning as set forth in\nsection eighteen-c of the workers' compensation law.\n  6. "Livery" means a for-hire vehicle licensed by a local taxi and\nlimousine commission, carrying no more than five passengers or such\nother limited number as set by a local taxi and limousine commission,\nwhich charges for service on the basis of flat rate, time, mileage or\nzones, and which is dispatched by a livery dispatch facility, but shall\nnot include a vehicle owned or driven by a black car operator, as\ndefined in article six-F of this chapter.\n  7. "Livery driver" means an individual that drives a livery, is\ndispatched by a livery base, receives compensation for such driving, and\nis licensed to do so by a local taxi and limousine commission.\n  8. "Livery base" means a central facility that manages, organizes or\ndispatches liveries, and is licensed to do so by a local taxi and\nlimousine commission.\n  9. "Livery registrant" means a person in whose name a livery is\nlicensed by a local taxi and limousine commission.\n  10. "Local taxi and limousine commission" means a unit of local\ngovernment in New York city, Nassau county or Westchester county\nauthorized to license and regulate liveries.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>