<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-KKKK"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-KKKK"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-KKKK"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-KKKK/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-KKKK/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-KKKK/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-KKKK/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_KKKK">
        <num>160-KKKK</num>
        <heading>Restrictions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-kkkk. Restrictions. An appraisal management company that applies\nfor a certificate of registration shall not knowingly:\n  1. Employ any person in a position in which the person has the\nresponsibility to order appraisals or valuation services or to review\ncompleted appraisals who has had a license, registration or certificate\nto act as an appraiser in this state or in any other state, denied,\nrevoked, or surrendered in lieu of a pending revocation, unless such\nlicense has been reinstated;\n  2. Enter into any independent contractor arrangement, whether in\nverbal, written, or by other form, with any person who has had a\nlicense, registration or certificate to act as an appraiser in this\nstate or in any other state, denied, revoked, or surrendered in lieu of\na pending revocation, unless such license has been reinstated; and\n  3. Enter into any contract, agreement, or other business relationship,\nwhether in verbal, written, or other form, with any entity that employs,\nhas entered into an independent contract arrangement, or has entered\ninto any contract, agreement, or other business relationship, whether in\nverbal, written, or any other form, with any person who has ever had a\nlicense, registration or certificate to act as an appraiser in this\nstate or in any other state, denied, revoked, or surrendered in lieu of\na pending revocation, unless such license has been reinstated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>