<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_I">
        <num>160-I</num>
        <heading>Examination requirement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-i. Examination requirement. An original certification as a state\ncertified real estate appraiser or an original license as a state\nlicensed real estate appraiser shall not be issued to any person who has\nnot demonstrated through a written examination process that he or she\npossesses the following:\n  1. Appropriate knowledge of technical terms commonly used in or\nrelated to real estate appraising, appraisals, report writing and\neconomic concepts applicable to real estate;\n  2. Understanding of the principles of land economics, real estate\nappraisal processes, and of problems likely to be encountered in\ngathering, interpreting and processing of data in carrying out appraisal\ndisciplines;\n  3. Understanding of the standards for the development and\ncommunication of real estate appraisals as provided in this article;\n  4. Knowledge of theories of depreciation, cost estimating, methods of\ncapitalization, and the mathematics of real estate appraisal that are\nappropriate for the classification of certificate applied for;\n  5. Knowledge of other principles and procedures as may be appropriate\nfor the respective classifications;\n  6. Basic understanding of real estate law; and\n  7. Understanding of the types of misconduct for which disciplinary\nproceedings may be initiated against a state certified real estate\nappraiser or a state licensed real estate appraiser, as set forth in\nthis article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>