<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_H">
        <num>160-H</num>
        <heading>Licenses and certifications</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-h. Licenses and certifications. 1. There shall be one class of\nlicense for state licensed real estate appraiser assistants, one class\nof license for state licensed real estate appraisers and two classes of\ncertification for state certified real estate appraisers. The classes of\ncertification shall be state certified residential real estate appraiser\nand state certified general real estate appraiser. The board shall\nprescribe the scope of practice for each license and both classes of\ncertification, provided, however, that in no event shall the scope of\npractice prescribed by the board be less than the minimum criteria\nestablished by the Appraisal Subcommittee of the Federal Financial\nInstitutions Examination Council or by the Appraiser Qualification Board\nof the Appraisal Foundation as referred to in title XI of the Financial\nInstitutions Reform, Recovery and Enforcement Act of 1989.\n  2. The application for original certification and recertification or\noriginal license and renewal of license, and examination shall specify\nwhether it is for a license or certification being applied for and\npreviously granted. If the application is for a license or renewal, it\nshall specify for what class of license the application is being made.\nIf the application is for a certification or recertification, it shall\nspecify for what class of certification the application is being made.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>