<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-W"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-W"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-10-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-W"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_W">
        <num>160-W</num>
        <heading>Hearing and judicial review</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-w. Hearing and judicial review. 1. The hearing on the charges\nshall be at a time and place prescribed by the department.\n  2. If the department determined that a state certified or licensed\nreal estate appraiser or licensed real estate appraiser assistant is\nguilty of a violation of any of the provisions of this article, it shall\nprepare a finding of fact and recommend that such appraiser be\nreprimanded, that their certification or license be suspended or\nrevoked, and/or indicate whether a fine shall be imposed. The decision\nand order of the department shall be final.\n  3. Any final decision or order of the department in certifying or\ndenying certification or in recertification, or in licensing, denying\nlicense, or in renewal of a license, under this article or in revoking\nor suspending such certification or license or imposing any fine or\nreprimand on the holder of such certification or license shall be\nsubject to review by a proceeding brought under and pursuant to article\nseventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules at the insistence of\nthe applicant for such certification, the holder of the certificate or\nlicense so revoked or suspended or the person fined, reprimanded or\notherwise aggrieved.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>