<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJJJ"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJJJ"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-JJJJ"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJJJ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJJJ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJJJ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJJJ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_JJJJ">
        <num>160-JJJJ</num>
        <heading>Employee requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJJJ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe appraisal management company accepts the appraiser for consideration\nfor future appraisal assignments in covered transactions or for\nsecondary mortgage market participants in connection with covered\ntransactions; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJJJ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>engages the appraiser to perform one or more\nappraisals on behalf of a creditor for a covered transaction or\nsecondary mortgage market participant in connection with covered\ntransactions.\n  3. An appraisal management company may not hire, employ or engage, or\nin any way contract with or pay a person who is not licensed or\ncertified as a real estate appraiser by the department pursuant to\narticle six-E of this chapter for the purposes of performing an\nappraisal as defined in this article. Nothing in this section shall\nprohibit an appraisal management company from hiring, employing,\nengaging or contracting with or paying a person to perform a property\ninspection, or property evaluation if they are licensed as an appraiser,\na real estate broker including associate real estate brokers and real\nestate salespersons pursuant to article twelve-A of the real property\nlaw or a home inspector pursuant to article twelve-B of the real\nproperty law, or a person to perform a broker price opinion if they are\nlicensed as a real estate broker including associate real estate brokers\nand real estate salespersons pursuant to article twelve-A of the real\nproperty law.\n  4. An appraiser shall be considered part of an appraisal management\ncompany's appraiser panel until:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJJJ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the appraisal management company\nsends a written notice to such appraiser removing such appraiser with an\nexplanation; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJJJ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>receives a written notice from such appraiser asking\nto be removed or of the death or incapacity of such appraiser.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>