<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_K">
        <num>160-K</num>
        <heading>Experience requirement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-k. Experience requirement. 1. An original certification of a\nstate certified real estate appraiser, or an original license of a state\nlicensed real estate appraiser, shall not be issued to any person who\ndoes not possess the equivalent of two years of appraisal experience in\nreal property appraisal as defined by the board supported by adequate\nwritten reports. Such experience may include fee and staff appraisal, ad\nvalorem tax appraisal, review appraisal, appraisal analysis, highest and\nbest use analysis, feasibility analysis or study, and teaching of\nappraisal courses at a university, college, or junior college when such\ncourses have a duration of not less than ten weeks.\n  2. A person who is not a state certified real estate appraiser under\nthis article may assist a state certified real estate appraiser in the\npreparation of an appraisal, provided that he or she is actively and\npersonally supervised by the state certified real estate appraiser and\nprovided that any appraisal report is reviewed and signed by the\nsupervising state certified appraiser.\n  3. Each applicant for certification or license shall furnish under\noath a detailed listing of the real estate appraisal reports for each\nyear for which experience is claimed by the applicant. Upon request, the\napplicant shall make available to the department for examination, a\nsample of appraisal reports which the applicant has prepared in the\ncourse of his or her appraisal practice.\n  4. No state certified real estate appraiser shall supervise more than\nthree licensed real estate appraiser assistants.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>