<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJ"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJ"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-06-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-JJ"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-JJ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_JJ">
        <num>160-JJ</num>
        <heading>Assessment of fund members; customer surcharges; audit powers of the fund, the board and the fund's insurer</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\ncosts of the insurance purchased pursuant to subdivision three of\nsection one hundred sixty-ii of this article or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the benefits due\nunder the workers' compensation law in the event the fund self-insures\npursuant to subdivision two of section one hundred sixty-ii of this\narticle, and to pay</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJ__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>its expenses in carrying out its powers and\nduties under this article and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJ__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>its liabilities, if any, pursuant to\nsection fourteen-a of the workers' compensation law, the fund shall\nascertain by reasonable estimate the total funding necessary to carry on\nits operations.\n  2. Based upon its estimation of operating costs, the fund shall\nestablish a proposed uniform percentage surcharge to be added to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJ__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\ninvoices or billings for covered services sent to the customers of the\nfund's members by a member or its agent and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJ__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the credit payments for\ncovered services received by a member or its agent. The proposed\nsurcharge shall become effective thirty days after being filed with the\ndepartment. Notwithstanding the foregoing, beginning on the first day of\nthe first calendar month that shall commence at least seventy-five days\nafter the effective date of this article, and until the fund shall have\nfiled with the department a different surcharge amount, a three percent\nsurcharge shall be added to every invoice or billing for covered\nservices sent by a member or its agent to, and every credit payment for\ncovered services received by a member or its agent from, the customers\nof the fund's members. Each member of the fund shall be liable for\npayment to the fund of an amount equal to the product of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_160_JJ__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\npercentages surcharge due pursuant to this article, divided by one\nhundred and (ii) all payments received by the member or its agent for\ncovered services from the member's customers, as provided in this\nsubdivision, regardless of whether the surcharge was billed or charged.\n  3. No local licensing authority or the department or the New York\nstate department of motor vehicles shall issue, continue or renew any\nlicense or registration certificate, or permit for the operation of any\ncentral dispatch facility unless such central dispatch facility, as a\ncondition of maintaining its license and/or registration certificate,\nadds the surcharge required by this section to every invoice and billing\nfor covered services sent to, and every credit payment for covered\nservices received from, its customers and pays to the fund no later than\nthe fifteenth day of each month the total surcharges due pursuant to\nthis article.\n  4. Each central dispatch facility shall submit to the fund with its\nmonthly payment a detailed accounting of the charge and surcharge\namounts charged to and received from customers for covered services\nduring the previous month. The first such payment and accounting shall\nbe due on the fifteenth day of the month following the imposition of the\nsurcharge pursuant to subdivision two of this section.\n  5. Should the fund determine that the surcharge amounts that have been\npaid to it are inadequate to meet its obligations under this article, it\nshall determine the surcharge rate required to eliminate such deficiency\nand shall file such revised surcharge rate with the department in\naccordance with subdivision two of this section. Commencing thirty days\nafter such filing, the members of the fund shall charge the revised\nsurcharge rate and shall pay to the fund the total amount of surcharges\nin accordance with this article.\n  6. The fund shall have the power directly or through its agent to\nconduct financial audits of its members to v...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>