<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_C">
        <num>160-C</num>
        <heading>State board of real estate appraisal</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-c. State board of real estate appraisal. 1. There is hereby\nestablished within the department of state a state board of real estate\nappraisal which shall consist of nine members, three of whom shall be\npublic members and six of whom shall be real estate appraisers, who\nshall have and exercise the powers of the board as set forth in section\none hundred sixty-d of this article.\n  2. Three members shall be appointed by the governor, one of whom shall\nbe a public member; two members shall be appointed by the temporary\npresident of the senate, one of whom shall be a real estate appraiser\nand one of whom shall be a public member; two members shall be appointed\nby the speaker of the assembly, one of whom shall be a real estate\nappraiser and one of whom shall be a public member; one member shall be\nappointed by the minority leader of the senate; one member shall be\nappointed by the minority leader of the assembly. The term of each\nmember shall be five years.\n  3. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the members of the first board who\nare real estate appraisers, need not be certified or licensed under this\narticle prior to their appointment to the board. The board shall appoint\nan executive secretary who shall be a real estate appraiser.\n  4. The executive secretary and real estate appraiser members first\nappointed to the board shall be certified designated members in good\nstanding of a nationally recognized real estate appraisal organization\nthat as of June first, nineteen hundred eighty-nine, required appraisal\nexperience, education and testing in order to become a designated\nmember, in addition to adherence to standards of professional practice\nin order to retain such designation. Each real estate appraiser member\nof the board appointed after January first, nineteen hundred ninety-six,\nmust be a state certified real estate appraiser. At least one-half of\nthe appraiser members appointed after January first, nineteen hundred\nninety-six, shall hold the general appraisal certificate. Any vacancy\noccurring on the board shall be filled within sixty days of its\noccurrence, in the same manner as the member whose vacancy is being\nfilled was appointed. A person appointed to fill a vacancy occurring\nother than by expiration of a term shall be appointed for the unexpired\nterm of the member he succeeds.  No person shall serve as a member of\nthe board for more than two consecutive terms. The public members of the\nboard shall not be engaged in the practice of real estate appraising.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>