<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Z"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Z"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-Z"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_Z">
        <num>160-Z</num>
        <heading>Retention of records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-z. Retention of records. 1. A state certified or licensed real\nestate appraiser shall retain for three years, originals or true copies\nof all written contracts engaging his or her services for real property\nappraisal work, and all reports and supporting data assembled and\nformulated by the appraiser in preparing the reports.\n  2. Such period for retention of records is applicable to each\nengagement of the services of the appraiser and shall commence upon the\ndate of the submittal of the appraisal to the client unless, within such\nthree year period, such appraiser is notified that the appraisal or\nreport is involved in litigation, in which event the three year period\nfor the retention of records shall commence upon the date of the final\ndisposition of such litigation.\n  3. All records required to be maintained under the provisions of this\narticle shall be made available by the state certified or licensed real\nestate appraiser for inspection and copying by the board on reasonable\nnotice to such appraiser. All such records copied by the board shall be\nkept confidential, except where disclosure of same is required by law or\nmandate of a court.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>