<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-IIII"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-IIII"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-IIII"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-IIII/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-IIII/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-IIII/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-IIII/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_IIII">
        <num>160-IIII</num>
        <heading>Controlling persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-iiii. Controlling persons. 1. Each appraisal management company\napplying for a certificate of registration shall designate one\ncontrolling person who shall be the main contact for all communication\nbetween the department and the appraisal management company. Such\ndesignated controlling person shall never have had a license or\ncertificate to act as an appraiser denied, revoked, or surrendered in\nlieu of possible discipline in any state and shall be of good moral\ncharacter, as determined by the department. Applicants shall cooperate\nwith any such background investigation conducted by the department.\n  2. Each person that owns more than ten percent of an appraisal\nmanagement company shall be of good moral character, as determined by\nthe department. Applicants shall cooperate with any such background\ninvestigation conducted by the department.\n  3. Each appraisal management company applying for a certificate of\nregistration shall certify to the department that it has reviewed each\nentity that owns more than ten percent of the appraisal management\ncompany and that no entity that owns more than ten percent of the\nappraisal management company is more than ten percent owned by any\nperson that has had a license or certificate to act as an appraiser\ndenied, revoked, or surrendered in lieu of a pending revocation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>