<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-160-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160_M">
        <num>160-M</num>
        <heading>Nonresident certification and licensing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 160-m. Nonresident certification and licensing. 1. Every applicant\nfor certification or licensing under this article who is not a resident\nof this state shall submit, with the application for certification or\nlicense, an irrevocable consent that service of process upon him or her\nmay be made by delivery of the process to the secretary of state if, in\nan action against the applicant in a court of this state arising out of\nthe applicant's activities as a state certified real estate appraiser,\nor a state licensed real estate appraiser, the plaintiff cannot, in the\nexercise of due diligence, effect personal service upon the applicant.\n  2. When a nonresident of this state, certified or licensed under the\nlaws of his resident state, the certification and licensing process of\nwhich has not been disapproved by the appraisal subcommittee of the\nfederal financial institutions examination council, does not maintain an\noffice for providing appraisal services to clients in this state, and\nhas complied with subdivision one of this section, such nonresident may,\nupon recommendation of the board, pursuant to such temporary licensing\nrules or regulations as the board may promulgate, provide certified or\nlicensed appraisals. No temporary certificate or license shall be valid\nfor a duration greater than one year after the date of issue. Any person\nperforming, or seeking to perform, federally related appraisals shall be\nliable for, and pay, all fees, rated proportionately, which would apply\nto such person were he or she a resident of this state.\n  3. A nonresident of this state who has complied with subdivision one\nof this section, but who does not qualify for treatment under\nsubdivision two of this section, may obtain a certificate as a state\ncertified real estate appraiser or a license as a state licensed real\nestate appraiser by conformity to all the provisions of this article\nrelating to state certified or licensed real estate appraisers.\n  4. The board shall recognize on a temporary basis the certification or\nlicense of an appraiser issued by another state pursuant to section 1122\nof Title XI of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and\nEnforcement Act of 1989, Pub. Law. No. 101-73, 103 Stat. 183 (1989)\n(codified at 12 U.S.C. 331 et seq.).\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>