<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-162"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-162"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="162"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-162/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-162/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-162/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-162/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_162">
        <num>162</num>
        <heading>Contracts for professional services of state and municipal employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 162. Contracts for professional services of state and municipal\nemployees.  Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, general,\nspecial or local, the state and any municipal subdivision thereof and\nany department, bureau, board, commission, authority or any other agency\nor instrumentality of the state or any municipal subdivision thereof,\nare hereby severally authorized and empowered to enter into any contract\nor arrangement with the United States of America or any office,\ndepartment, agency or instrumentality thereof for the performance at\ncost by engineers, architects, draftsmen and chemists employed by the\nstate or such municipal subdivision, upon such terms and conditions as\nmay be mutually agreed upon, of any project or work authorized by or\npursuant to any act of congress or the cost of which has been provided\nfor by an appropriation or contract authorization made by any act of\ncongress which involves or requires the professional services of such\nemployees. The making or performance of any such contract or arrangement\nshall in no wise be deemed to affect or result in the impairment,\ndiminution or abridgment of the compensation, or any of the civil\nservice, retirement and other rights, privileges and immunities of any\nemployee engaged in the performance of any service thereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>