<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-164"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-164"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="164"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-164/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-164/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-164/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-164/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_164">
        <num>164</num>
        <heading>Reports by and to the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 164. Reports by and to the department.  Each department, other than\nthe executive department, shall make an annual report to the governor\nand legislature on or before the fifteenth day of May, for the preceding\ncalendar year. It shall contain such information concerning the\ndepartment and its several divisions, bureaus, offices, agencies and\ninstitutions, and their activities and affairs, and such\nrecommendations, as the head of the department shall deem necessary or\nproper, and any matters required by express provision of law to be\nincluded in such report. A department also shall make such other and\nspecial reports as the governor or either house of the legislature may\nrequire. From time to time, the head of a department may require from\nany board, commission or other body in the department or from any\nsubordinate officer or employee, division or bureau of the department,\nor from any institution subject to the supervision of the department, or\nfrom any agency of the department, such reports or information as such\nhead may deem necessary. Unless expressly authorized by the head of the\ndepartment, there shall be hereafter no separate report, annual or\notherwise, directly to the legislature or governor by any such board,\ncommission, body, officer, division, bureau, institution or agency\nnotwithstanding any existing provision of law authorizing or requiring\nsuch report.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>