<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-E*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-E*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-06-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="170-E*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-E*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-E*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-E*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-E*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_170_E*2">
        <num>170-E*2</num>
        <heading>Collection of demographic information</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_E*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>each major Asian group shall include Chinese, Japanese, Filipino,\nKorean, Vietnamese, Asian Indian, Bangladeshi, Pakistani, and all of the\nten most populous Asian groups in the most recent five-year American\ncommunity survey published by the United States Census Bureau; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_E*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>each major Pacific Islander group shall include Native Hawaiian,\nGuamanian and Chamorro, and Samoan; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_E*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>collection categories shall include a category for other Asian or\nPacific Island group.\n  2. Every state agency, board, department, or commission that directly\ncollects demographic data as to the ancestry or ethnic origin of\nresidents of the state of New York shall use separate collection\ncategories and tabulations for the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_E*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the primary language spoken at home; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_E*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the ethnic group or ancestry.\n  3. Upon the release of a new five-year American community survey\npublished by the United States Census Bureau, every state agency, board,\ndepartment or commission shall update their data collection and\nreporting practices as required by this section and shall continue to\ncollect and report on any demographic group no longer included in the\nten most populous groups until the release of the following five-year\nAmerican community survey, at which time state agencies, boards,\ndepartments or commissions may cease to collect and report on such\ndemographic groups provided they remain outside the ten most populous\ngroups.\n  4. The data collected pursuant to the different collection categories\nand tabulations described in subdivision one of this section, to the\ndegree that the data quality is sufficient, shall be included in every\ndemographic report on ancestry or ethnic origins of residents of the\nstate of New York by the state agency, board, department, or commission\npublished or released on or after December first, two thousand\ntwenty-three; provided, however, that for the department of labor,\ndivision of criminal justice services, office of mental health and\noffice of temporary and disability assistance such requirements shall be\neffective July first, two thousand twenty-four. The data shall be made\navailable to the public in accordance with state and federal law, except\nfor personal identifying information, which shall be deemed\nconfidential, by posting the data on the internet web site of the\nagency, board, department, or commission on or before December first,\ntwo thousand twenty-three, and annually thereafter; provided, however,\nthat for the department of labor, division of criminal justice services,\noffice of mental health and office of temporary and disability\nassistance such requirements shall be effective July first, two thousand\ntwenty-four. If the data quality is determined to be insufficient for\npub...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>