<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="170-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_170_H">
        <num>170-H</num>
        <heading>Additional collection of demographic information</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each major North African (NA) group shall include Egyptian,\nMoroccan, Algerian, Sudanese, Tunisian, and Libyan; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each major Middle Eastern (ME) group shall include Yemeni,\nIranian, Palestinian, Iraqi, Lebanese, Israeli, Jordanian, Syrian,\nArmenian, and Saudi; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Collection categories shall include a category for other Middle\nEastern or North African groups.\n  2. The data collected pursuant to the different collection categories\nand tabulations described in subdivision one of this section, to the\ndegree that the data quality is sufficient, shall be included in every\ndemographic report on ancestry or ethnic origins of residents of the\nstate of New York by the state agency, board, department, or commission\npublished or released on or after January first, two thousand\ntwenty-seven. The data shall be made available to the public in\naccordance with state and federal law, except for personal identifying\ninformation, which shall be deemed confidential, by posting the data on\nthe internet web site of the agency, board, department, or commission on\nor before January first, two thousand twenty-seven, and annually\nthereafter. If the data quality is determined to be insufficient for\npublication, an explanation of the problem with the data quality shall\nbe included in any report or publication made available to the public.\nThis subdivision shall not be construed to prevent any other state\nagency from posting data collected pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection on the agency's internet web site, in the manner prescribed by\nthis section.\n  3. A state agency, board, or commission that cannot comply with the\nrequirements of this section shall, at least sixty days before the\napplicable deadline, post publicly on its web site a written progress\nreport that describes with specificity the steps the agency, board, or\ncommission has taken to comply with this section, the impediments that\nprevented compliance, the efforts undertaken by the agency, board, or\ncommission to come into compliance, and an estimated timeframe for\ncompliance. The written report shall be updated every six months from\nthe date of the original posting.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>