<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-08-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="170-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-170-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_170_C">
        <num>170-C</num>
        <heading>Regulatory penalties for small businesses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide the small business with a copy of the\napplicable small business regulation guides pursuant to section one\nhundred two-a of the state administrative procedure act and any other\nhelpful guidance or information detailing the agency's rules and\nregulations, to the extent such materials exist, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the extent\npracticable, provide such small business assistance with compliance with\nthe agency's rules and regulations. The agency shall have the discretion\nto determine the appropriate period of time to allow such small business\nto cure or take such other ameliorative action to address such\nviolation, which shall be reasonable but shall not be less than fifteen\nbusiness days unless a longer period is allowed pursuant to law or\nregulation.\n  2. As used in this section "state agency" shall mean an agency as\ndefined in subdivision one of section one hundred two of the state\nadministrative procedure act; provided that "state agency" shall not\ninclude the department of taxation and finance, the workers'\ncompensation board nor the department of financial services.\n  3. Nothing herein shall prevent or preclude any other waivers of\npenalties that may be applicable by this or any other agency.\n  4. Every state agency shall provide to the division for small\nbusiness, created pursuant to section one hundred thirty-two of the\neconomic development law, the following information covering the\nprevious calendar year, annually by July first following the effective\ndate of this subdivision, and every July first thereafter:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>how many\ncure periods or other opportunities for ameliorative action were\nafforded pursuant to subdivision one of this section and how many small\nbusinesses made use of such options,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>how many cure periods and other\nopportunities for ameliorative action were successfully completed and\nresulted in the avoidance of a penalty,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>what, if any, guidance,\ninformation, and assistance with compliance was provided to small\nbusinesses issued pursuant to subdivision one of this section, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe range of time granted by the state agency to correct first time\nviolations and the type of violations that were ameliorated. The\ndivision for small business shall by October first following the\neffective date of this subdivision, and every October first thereafter,\nprepare a report compiling this information, by agency, and shall post\nthis report on its website and shall provide a copy of such report to\nthe governor, the speaker of the assembly and the temporary president of\nthe senate.\n  * NB Repealed December 20, 2027\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>