<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="172-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_172_B">
        <num>172-B</num>
        <heading>Reports by registered charitable organizations; registration to be cancelled for failure to file</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_172_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon prior written authorization by the attorney general any\ncharitable organization registered pursuant to section one hundred\nseventy-two of this article, which is the parent organization of one or\nmore affiliates thereof, and such affiliates, may comply with the\nreporting requirements of subdivision one, two, two-a or three of this\nsection, by filing a combined written annual financial report upon forms\nprescribed by the attorney general.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this subdivision the term "affiliate" shall include any\nchapter, branch, auxiliary, or other subordinate unit of any registered\ncharitable organization, howsoever designated, whose policies, fund\nraising activities, and expenditures are supervised or controlled by\nsuch parent organization.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be appended to each combined annual financial report a\nschedule, containing such information as may be prescribed by the\nattorney general, reflecting the activities of each affiliate, which\nshall contain a statement signed under penalties for perjury, by the\npresident or other authorized officer certifying that the information\ncontained therein is true.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The failure of a parent organization to file a combined annual\nfinancial written report shall not excuse either the parent organization\nor its affiliates from complying with the provisions of subdivision one,\ntwo, two-a or three of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A combined annual financial report filed pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be accompanied by a fee, paid to the attorney general,\nof twenty-five dollars plus ten dollars for each organization included\nin such annual financial report, but the aggregate fee shall not exceed\nfive hundred dollars.\n  5. The attorney general shall cancel the registration of any\norganization which fails to comply with subdivision one, two, two-a or\nthree of this section within the time therein prescribed, or fails to\nfurnish such additional information as is requested by the attorney\ngeneral within the required time; except that the time may be extended\nby the attorney general for a period not to exceed one hundred eighty\ndays. Notice of such cancellation shall be mailed to the registrant at\nleast twenty days before the effective date thereof.\n  6. Every charitable organization registered or required to register\npursuant to section one hundred seventy-two of this article shall keep\nand maintain records, books and reports for at least three years after\nthe end of the period of registration to which they relate which shall\nat all times be available for inspection, by the attorney general, or\nany duly authorized representatives at the principal office of such\norganization.\n  7. The attorney general may accept a copy of a current financial\nreport previously filed by a charitable organization with any other\ngovernmental agency in compliance with the provisions of this article\nprovided that the report filed with such other governmental agency shall\nbe substantially similar in content to the financial report required by\nthis section.\n  8. Any financial report filed by any charitable organization required\nto be registered but which has not previously registered pursuant to\nthis article or article eight of the estates, powers and trusts law must\nbe accompanied by all registration material required to be filed by this\narticle.\n  9. Any registered charitable organizati...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>