<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-11-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="172"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-172/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_172">
        <num>172</num>
        <heading>Registration of charitable organizations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The name of the organization and the name or names under which it\nintends to solicit contributions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The names and business, residence, or other addresses where each\ncan regularly be found of the officers, directors, trustees, and\nexecutive personnel of the organization.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The addresses of the organization and the addresses of any offices\nin this state. If the organization does not maintain an office, the name\nand address of the person having custody of its financial records.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where and when the organization was established, the form of its\norganization, its tax exempt status together with a copy of the most\nrecent letter of exemption, if any, issued by the internal revenue\nservice, the most recent communication from the internal revenue service\nregarding any audit thereby, if any, and a copy of any certificate of\nincorporation, by-laws, amendments and other operative organizational\ndocuments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A clear description of the specific programs stating whether in\nexistence or planned for which the contributions to be solicited will be\nused.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The date on which the fiscal year of the organization ends.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether the organization is authorized by any other governmental\nauthority to solicit contributions and whether it or any of its present\nofficers, directors, executive personnel or trustees are or have ever\nbeen fined or otherwise penalized or enjoined from soliciting\ncontributions or have been found to have engaged in unlawful practices\nregarding solicitation of contributions or administration of charitable\nassets and whether its registration or license has been suspended or\ncancelled by any court or other governmental agency together with the\nidentity of such courts or governmental agencies and the reasons for\nsuch fine, penalty, injunction, suspension or cancellation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The names and addresses of any professional fund raisers, fund\nraising counsels and commercial co-venturers who are acting or have\nagreed to act on behalf of the organization.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A copy of its annual report, if any, for the immediately preceding\nfiscal year in accordance with the requirements of section one hundred\nseventy-two-b of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The names and addresses of any chapters, branches, affiliates or\norganizations that share in the contributions or other revenue raised in\nthis state.\n  2. The registration form shall be signed under penalties for perjury\nby the president or other authorized officer and the chief fiscal\nofficer of the organization.\n  3. At the time of filing such registration, each charitable\norganization shall pay to the attorney general a fee of twenty-five\ndollars.\n  4. Any charitable organization required to register with the attorney\ngeneral pursuant to this article and properly registered pursuant to\narticle eight of the estates, powers and trusts law that has not\npreviously registered pursuant to this article shall not be required to\nregister separately, but shall file with the attorney general a\nstatement that it is registered pursuant to article eight of the\nestates, powers and trusts law. Such statement shall be accompanied by\nall additional documents required to complete registration pursuant to\nthis article, including any additional financial filings required by\nthis article.\n  5. Registration pursuant to this article shall remain in effect unless\nit is either cancelled as provided in this article, withdrawn by the\norganization or the organization has failed to file the required\nfinancial report and such failure has not been remedied pursuant to\nsubdivision seven of this section.\n  6. Every registered organization shall file with the attorney general\nwithin thirty days of any material change in the information required to\nbe furnished by such organization under subdivision one of this section\na prescribed form stating any such changes and signed under penalties\nfor perjury by the president or other authorized officer of the\norganization.\n  7. In no event shall a registration of a charitable organization to\nsolicit contributions in New York pursuant to this article continue, or\nbe continued, in effect after the date such organization should ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>