<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="174-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_174_A">
        <num>174-A</num>
        <heading>Contracts with charitable organizations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a concise, accurate statement of the charitable organization's\nright to cancel;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a concise, accurate statement of the period during which the\ncontract may be cancelled;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the address to which the notice of cancellation is to be sent;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the address of the attorney general to which a duplicate of the\nnotice of cancellation is to be sent; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a clear statement of the financial arrangement including, if\napplicable, a statement of the percentage of the total funds collected\non behalf of the charitable organization which shall be paid to the\nprofessional fund raiser or any other person for purposes other than the\nexclusive benefit of the charitable organization.\n  5. Any funds collected by any professional fund raiser, fund raising\ncounsel, professional solicitor, commercial co-venturer, charitable\norganization or any other person in violation of this section shall be\ndeemed to be held in trust for the benefit of the charitable\norganization without deduction for costs or expenses of any nature. A\ncharitable organization shall be entitled to recover all funds collected\nin violation of this section together with costs, disbursements and\nallowances.\n  6. The failure of a professional fund raiser, fund raising counsel or\ncommercial co-venturer to immediately discontinue solicitation or any\nother fund raising activity upon receipt of a notice of cancellation in\naccordance with the provisions of this article within fifteen days of\nthe cancellation of the contract shall be deemed to be a continuing\nfraud upon the people of the state of New York.\n  7. In addition to all other remedies provided by law the attorney\ngeneral may bring an action to enjoin the violation of the provisions of\nthis section and to recover restitution, damages, costs and attorneys\nfees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>