<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="174-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_174_D">
        <num>174-D</num>
        <heading>Unauthorized use of names when soliciting or collecting contributions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 174-d. Unauthorized use of names when soliciting or collecting\ncontributions.\n  1. No person shall, for the purpose of soliciting contributions from\npersons in this state, use the name of any other person, except that of\nan officer, director or trustee of the charitable organization by or for\nwhich contributions are solicited, without the written consent of such\nother person.\n  2. A person shall be deemed to have used the name of another person\nfor the purpose of soliciting contributions if such latter person's name\nis listed on any stationery, advertisement, brochure or correspondence\nin or by which a contribution is solicited by or on behalf of a\ncharitable organization or his name is listed or referred to in\nconnection with a request for a contribution as one who has contributed\nto, sponsored or endorsed the charitable organization or its activities.\n  3. Nothing contained in this section shall prevent the publication of\nnames of contributors without their written consents, in an annual or\nother periodic report issued by a charitable organization for the\npurpose of reporting on its operations and affairs to its membership or\nfor the purpose of reporting contributions to contributors.\n  4. A violation of this section shall be a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>