<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="174"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-174/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_174">
        <num>174</num>
        <heading>Solicitation by unregistered charitable organizations, professional fund-raisers or commercial co-venturers a fraud upon the people of th...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 174. Solicitation by unregistered charitable organizations,\nprofessional fund-raisers or commercial co-venturers a fraud upon the\npeople of the state. 1. No charitable organization shall employ any\nprofessional fund raiser or commercial co-venturer unless and until such\nfund raiser or commercial co-venturer is registered pursuant to this\narticle. Any such contract of employment shall be voidable at the option\nof the charitable organization.\n  2. No professional fund raiser or commercial co-venturer shall enter\ninto any contract or raise any funds for any organization required to be\nregistered pursuant to this article unless such charitable organization\nactually so registered.\n  3. No professional fund raiser required to be registered under this\narticle shall employ any professional solicitor who is not registered in\naccordance with this article.\n  4. In addition to all other remedies provided by law the attorney\ngeneral may bring an action to enjoin the violation of the provisions of\nthis section. The attorney general may give notice of at least fifteen\ndays in writing by registered or certified mail to the organization,\nperson or persons violating the provisions hereof, requiring that\nregistration be accomplished or that the solicitation funds be\nimmediately terminated. The failure to immediately discontinue\nsolicitation or to register in accordance with the provisions of this\narticle within fifteen days of service of such notice shall be deemed to\nbe a continuing fraud upon the people of the state of New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>