<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-190"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-190"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-190/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-190/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-190/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-190/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190">
        <num>190</num>
        <heading>Division of military and naval affairs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 190. Division of military and naval affairs. 1. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of any other law, the head of the division of military and\nnaval affairs shall be the adjutant general who shall be appointed by\nthe governor and who, except when any one of such officers shall be in\nthe active service of the United States, shall be the commanding general\nof the New York army national guard, the commander of the New York air\nnational guard or the commanding officer of the New York naval militia.\nThe governor may exercise and perform his functions, powers and duties\nas commander-in-chief of the militia of the state in whole or in part\nthrough such division.\n  2. The division of military and naval affairs shall include the\norganized militia; the state reserve list; the state retired list; all\noffices, headquarters, units, forces, commands, arsenals, depots,\narmories, bureaus, agencies, bases, camps, ranges, and other military\n(including air) and naval activities, property, installations,\nstructures, facilities and functions of the state and all military\n(including air), naval and civilian personnel who may be serving or\nemployed therein.\n  3. The organization of the present office of the chief of staff is\ncontinued as part of the division of military and naval affairs. The\npowers and duties of such office and the bureaus thereof shall be\nexercised and performed under the supervision, direction and control of\nthe chief of staff, subject to the approval of the adjutant general.\n  4. The adjutant general is hereby authorized to create, organize,\nreorganize, convert, inactivate or disband such other offices,\nheadquarters, commands, bureaus and agencies for the performance of the\nfunctions of the division as he may deem necessary, within the amount\nappropriated therefor.\n  5. The adjutant general, in conjunction with the department of state,\nshall establish and maintain on the division's website a public listing\nof all approved not-for-profit corporations soliciting funds for or\notherwise benefiting the armed forces of the United States or of any\nforeign country, or their auxiliaries, or of this or any other state or\nterritory.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>