<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-191"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-191"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="191"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-191/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-191/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-191/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-191/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_191">
        <num>191</num>
        <heading>Restoration and display of New York state's military battle flags</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish project schedules and timetables; project expenses\nincluding an estimate of total conservation, display interpretation, and\ncontinuing management costs; and propose a budget for the recommended\nexpenses;\n  (ii) recommend specific conservation measures;\n  (iii) obtain a professional condition report and photograph of each\nitem in the collection; and\n  (iv) establish a plan for continuing management and conservation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Recommend hiring consultants as required, subject to budgetary\nlimitations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Recommend hiring a professional textile conservator or other\nsuitable professional to commence the conservation work within budgetary\nlimitations under the supervision of New York State's Military Heritage\nmuseum curator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Coordinate and conduct fund raising activities for the\nconservation, preservation, interpretation, display and continuing\nmanagement of the state's military battle flag collection, including:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>soliciting gifts, grants or donations of any kind; and\n  (ii) soliciting donations from businesses, individuals of all ages and\norganizations.\n  All monetary grants, gifts, or donations, shall be deposited in the\ntrust fund.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Advise the division of military and naval affairs on matters\nrelated to the restoration and display of the state's military battle\nflags.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is hereby established the New York state military battle\nflags partnership trust fund (hereinafter referred to as "trust fund" or\n"fund"). The fund shall be in the joint custody of the state comptroller\nand commissioner of taxation and finance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Moneys in the fund shall consist of donations and any\nappropriations by the legislature to match any such donations. Any\ninterest received by the comptroller on moneys on deposit in the trust\nfund shall be retained in and become part of the trust fund.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Money in the fund may be used for restoration and display of the\nstate's military battle flags. When all of the state's military battle\nflags have been restored and provision has been made for their public\ndisplay subject to the approval of the advisory committee, any remaining\nfunds are to be used as needed for the maintenance and display of the\nflags.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_191__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The moneys of the fund shall be paid out on the audit and warrant\nof the comptroller on vouchers certified or approved by the adjutant\ngeneral of the division of military and naval affairs.\n  4. The committee shall file an annual report of its activities and\nprovide a full accounting of the New York state military battle flags\npartnership trust fund. This report shall be filed with the governor,\nthe speaker of the assembly and the majority leader of the senate no\nlater than the end of each state fiscal year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>