<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="200"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_200">
        <num>200</num>
        <heading>Office of general services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 200. Office of general services.  There is hereby created an office\nof general services in the executive department. The head of the office\nof general services shall be the commissioner of general services. He\nshall be appointed by the governor by and with the advice and consent of\nthe senate and hold office during the pleasure of the governor. He shall\nreceive a salary to be fixed by the governor within the amount\nappropriated therefor.  Such commissioner, subject to rules prescribed\nby the governor, may establish such bureaus or divisions in the office\nof general services as he may deem necessary and may appoint such\ndeputies, directors, assistants and other employees as may be needed for\nthe performance of his duties and may prescribe their powers and duties\nand fix their compensation within the amount appropriated therefor. Such\noffice may have an office seal. The principal office of the office of\ngeneral services shall be in the city of Albany, and branch offices may\nbe established by direction of the governor, subject to appropriations\nfor their maintenance.\n  Such commissioner may adopt, amend or rescind rules and regulations\nrelating to the discharge of his functions, powers and duties and those\nof the office of general services as prescribed by law. Nothing\ncontained herein shall limit or impair compliance with the requirements\nof section one hundred sixty-three of the state finance law, with\nrespect to rules promulgated by the commissioner pursuant to such\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>