<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_P">
        <num>209-P</num>
        <heading>Research development program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish criteria for the awarding of funds made available\nthrough the research development program; all awards shall be made on a\ncompetitive basis;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide a schedule for issuance of requests for proposals for the\nresearch development program awards;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide a schedule for completion of review of proposals submitted\nby institutions of higher education and research institutions to the\noffice;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide procedures for the issuance of awards from the research\ndevelopment program.\n  3. The faculty development program is hereby created to assist\ninstitutions of higher education and research institutions with the\nretention and recruitment of research faculty. Funds appropriated for\nthis program shall be administered by the office pursuant to request for\nproposals. Consideration for the allocation of awards shall be given to\nall institutions of higher education and research institutions within\nthe state provided such institutions demonstrate to the satisfaction of\nthe advisory council a specific need for such funds and the manner in\nwhich such award for the recruitment and retention of research faculty\nwould enhance the research capabilities and reputation of the\ninstitution. Criteria for such awards shall include, but not be limited\nto, the ability of the faculty member to leverage and attract federal\nfunds, venture capital and private industry funds, and the willingness\nof the faculty member to pursue entrepreneurial enterprises resulting in\nnew business or the expansion of existing business in New York state.\nThe office shall promulgate rules and regulations to establish:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the duration of grants for faculty awards;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>matching funds required from the academic and research\ninstitutions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a schedule for an annual reduction of the faculty development\naward, and a corresponding increase in the matching funds from the\nacademic or research institution; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>other rules and regulations deemed necessary by the office for the\nadministration of this program.\n  3-a. The faculty development and technology transfer advisory council\nshall be established by the commissioner of economic development to\nreview and recommend proposals submitted for consideration under\nsubdivisions three and five of this section. The council shall consist\nof eleven members that shall include representatives from four different\nuniversities, one national lab, two New York state incubators or New\nYork state innovation hot spots, two companies and two non-profits with\na statewide economic development mission. Each representative shall have\ntechnology transfer experience. In addition, at least six members of the\ncouncil shall have a demonstrated background in bio-medicine,\nbiotechnology or other life sciences.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The capital facility program shall provide financing for the\ndesign, acquisition, construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation or\nimprovement of research and development facilities, including equipment.\nFunds appropriated or reappropriated for the capital facility program by\nchapter six hundred twenty-four of the laws of nineteen hundred\nninety-nine shall be awarded to no more than six primary host\ninstitutions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Criteria for the issuance of awards by the advisory council shall\ninclude but need not be limited to the following: potential future\ngrowth and economic impact within New York state of the proposed\nresearch to be undertaken at such facilities, available expertise at\nsuch campus in the scientific discipline designated for the center for\nadvanced technology and/or the center's host campus, an evaluation of\nthe ability of the proposed research to be undertaken at such facilities\nto aid existing business and to create new business in New York state,\nand the ability of the proposal to leverage and attract federal funds,\nventure capital and private industry funds.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The capital facility program shall also provide financing for the\nreconstruction, rehabilitation or improvement of existing laboratory\nfacilities. Funds available pursuant to this subdivision shall be\navailable for research facilities at all institutions of higher\neducation and research institutions in New York state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_P__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office and the city university construction fund may contract\nfor the construction fund to design, construct, acquire, reconstruct,\nrehabilitate and improve research and development facilities for those\nprimary host institutions which are senior colleges of the city\nuniversity of New York.\n  5. An incentive program is hereby created to provide additional\nassistance to technology transfer or commercialization activities at\ninstitutions of higher education and research institutions in the state\nof New York for the purpose of encouraging technology transfer from\ninstitutions of higher education and research institutions to businesses\nand for commercialization within New York state. Funds appropriated for\nthis program shall be available for personal service expenses to enhance\nthe technology transfer abilities or commercialization of research of\nhigher education and research institutions to businesses within New York\nstate including but not limited to patent applications, the creation of\nbusiness and marketing plans, venture capital conferences and\nnon-capital costs associated with the development of real property owned\nby such institution of higher education or research institution for\nresearch and development purposes. Funds awarded under the incentive\nprogram shall not exceed fifty percent of the cost of the purpose for\nwhich such funds shall be applied. The faculty development and\ntechnology transfer advisory council, as established by subdivision\nthree-a of this section, shall review and recommend proposals submitted\nfor consideration pursuant to this subdivision. Preference shall be\ngiven to proposals developed in coordination with a private or public\nmedical school located in the state.\n  6. A center for advanced technology development program is created\nwhereby funds shall be awarded to centers for advanced technology for\nthe purpose of enhancing and expanding the existing role of the center\nin the area for which it is designated...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>