<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_D">
        <num>209-D</num>
        <heading>Transfer of powers of science and technology foundations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-d. Transfer of powers of science and technology foundations.\nExcept as otherwise provided in section two hundred nine-f of this\narticle, the functions and powers possessed by and all of the\nobligations and duties of the science and technology foundation as\nestablished pursuant to article ten-A of the public authorities law\nshall be transferred and assigned to, assumed by and devolved upon the\noffice. Such transfer shall occur no later than January thirty-first,\ntwo thousand, provided, however, that such transfer may occur prior to\nJanuary thirty-first, two thousand pursuant to a memorandum of\nunderstanding executed by the chairman of the science and technology\nfoundation and the executive director of the office, and provided that,\nin the event that it is impractical to effectuate such transfer on or\nbefore January thirty-first, two thousand, the chairperson of the\nscience and technology foundation and the executive director of the\noffice may upon notification to the governor, temporary president of the\nsenate, and speaker of the assembly on or before January fifteenth, two\nthousand, execute a memorandum of understanding to govern the\nexpeditious transfer required pursuant to this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>