<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209">
        <num>209</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209. Definitions. As used in this article, the following terms shall\nhave the following meaning unless otherwise specified:\n  1. "Office" shall mean the New York state office of science,\ntechnology and academic research.\n  2. "Advisory council" shall mean the advisory council of the New York\nstate office of science, technology, and academic research.\n  3. "Executive director" shall mean the executive director of the New\nYork state office of science, technology, and academic research.\n  4. "Research development program" shall mean the program established\nby section two hundred nine-p of this article to encourage and enhance\nthe economic development role of academic institutions in New York\nstate.  Such program shall include, but not be limited to, the faculty\ndevelopment program, the capital facilities program, the incentive\nprogram, and the centers for advanced technology development program.\n  5. "Primary host institution" shall mean, in a case where two or more\ninstitutions form a partnership or consortium of research entities, one\ninstitution must be designated the institution through which awards\nshall be administered.\n  6. "Life sciences" shall mean those science disciplines relating to\nthe study of living organisms and vital processes.\n  7. "Enabling sciences" shall mean those science disciplines which may\nbe directly applied to life science research, including but not limited\nto, engineering, material science, chemistry, computer science,\nelectronics, physics, bioinfomatics, nanotechnologies and applications\nof microelectronics and micro-electromechanical devices.\n  8. "Project sponsor" shall mean any public, not-for-profit private or\nacademic research institution or any subsidiary thereof located in the\nstate of New York. A project sponsor may include a not-for-profit\ncorporation created on behalf of a public, not-for-profit private or\nacademic research institution.\n  9. "Construction" shall mean the erection, acquisition, alteration,\nreconstruction, rehabilitation, improvement, equipping, enlargement or\nextension of a life sciences and/or enabling sciences facility,\nincluding land acquisition and the engineering, architectural, legal,\nfiscal and economic investigations, studies, surveys, designs, plans,\ndrawings, specifications, procedures and other actions relating to a\nlife science or enabling science facility.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>