<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-213"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-213"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="213"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_213">
        <num>213</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of real property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 213. Acquisition of real property. 1. The superintendent shall from\ntime to time establish headquarters or substations in such localities as\nhe shall deem most suitable for the efficient performance of police duty\nin the rural sections of the state, and for that purpose and for other\npurposes of the division he may, when an appropriation therefor has been\nmade by the legislature, acquire, in the name of the people of the state\nof New York, by lease, purchase, lease-purchase subject to the approval\nof such lease-purchase agreement by the director of the budget or,\npursuant to the provisions of the eminant domain procedure law, any real\nproperty which he may deem necessary therefor; provided, however, that\nno such real property shall be so acquired by purchase or lease-purchase\nunless the title thereto shall be approved by the attorney general.\n  2. Whenever real property is to be acquired pursuant to the eminent\ndomain procedure law, the superintendent shall cause to be made by the\nstate department of transportation an accurate acquisition map.\n  3. On the approval of such map by the superintendent of the division\nof state police, the original tracing of such map shall be filed in the\nmain office of the division of state police pursuant to the provisions\nof the eminent domain procedure law.\n  4. If the superintendent shall determine, prior to the filing of such\nmap in the office of the clerk or register of the county, that changes,\nalterations or modifications of such map as filed in the main office of\nthe division of state police should be made, he or she shall, subject to\nthe provisions of article two of the eminent domain procedure law, if\napplicable, direct the preparation by the department of transportation\nof an amended map. On the approval of such amended map by the\nsuperintendent, it shall be filed in the main office of the division of\nstate police and the amended map shall thereupon in all respects and for\nall purposes supersede the map previously filed.\n  5. If the superintendent shall determine, prior to the filing of a\ncopy of such acquisition map in the office of the county clerk or\nregister as provided in section four hundred two of the eminent domain\nprocedure law, that such map should be withdrawn, he or she may file a\ncertificate of withdrawal in the offices of the division of state police\nand of the department of law. Upon the filing of such certificate of\nwithdrawal, the map to which it refers shall be cancelled and all rights\nthereunder shall cease and determine.\n  6. The superintendent shall deliver to the attorney general a copy of\nsuch acquisition map, whereupon it shall be the duty of the attorney\ngeneral to advise and certify to the superintendent the names of the\nowners of the property, easements, interests or rights described in the\nsaid acquisition map, including the owners of any right, title or\ninterest therein pursuant to the requirements of section four hundred\nthree of the eminent domain procedure law.\n  7. If, at or after the vesting of title to such property in the people\nof the state of New York as provided for in the eminent domain procedure\nlaw, the superintendent shall deem it necessary to cause the removal of\nan owner or occupant from any real property so acquired, he may cause\nsuch owner or occupant to be removed therefrom by proceeding in\naccordance with section four hundred five of the eminent domain\nprocedure law. The proceeding shall be brought in the name of the\nsuperintendent as agent of the state and the attorney general shall\nrepresent the petitioner in the proceedings. No execution shall issue\nfor costs, if any, awarded against the state or the superintendent, but\nthey shall be part of the costs of the acquisition of the real property\nand be paid in like manner.  Proceedings may be brought separately\nagainst one or more of the owners or occupants of any such property, or\none proceeding may be brought against all or several of the owners or\noccupants of any or all such property within the territorial\njurisdiction of the same court, justice or judge; precepts or final\norders shall be made for immediate removal of persons defaulting in\nappearance or in answering, or withdrawing their answers, if any,\nwithout awaiting the trial or decision of issues raised by contestants,\nif any.\n  8. Upon making any agreement provided for in section three hundred\nfour of the eminent domain procedure law, the superintendent shall\ndeliver to the comptroller such agreement and a certificate stating the\namount due such owner or owners thereunder on account of such\nappropriation of his or their property and the amounts so fixed shall be\npaid out of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from\nmoneys appropriated for the acquisition of such real property, but not\nuntil there shall have been filed with the comptroller a certificate of\nthe attorney general showing the person or persons claiming the amount\nso agreed upon to be legally entitled thereto.\n  9. Application for reimbursement of incidental expenses as provided in\nsection seven hundred two of the eminent domain procedure law shall be\nmade to the superintendent upon forms prescribed by him and shall be\naccompanied by such information and evidence as the superintendent may\nrequire. Upon approval of such application, the superintendent shall\ndeliver a copy thereof to the comptroller together with a certificate\nstating the amount due thereof, and the amount so fixed shall be paid\nout of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from moneys\nappropriated for the acquisition of property under this section.\n  10. The commissioner, with the approval of the director of the budget,\nshall establish and may from time to time amend rules and regulations\nauthorizing the payment of actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses of occupants of property acquired pursuant to this section; of\nactual direct losses of tangible personal property as a result of moving\nor discontinuing a business or farm operation, but not exceeding an\namount equal to the reasonable expenses that would have been required to\nrelocate such property, as determined by the commissioner; and actual\nreasonable expenses in searching for a replacement business or farm; or\nin hardship cases for the advance payment of such expenses and losses.\nFor the purposes of making payment of such expenses and losses only the\nterm "business" means any lawful activity conducted primarily for\nassisting in the purchase, sale, resale, manufacture, processing or\nmarketing of products, commodities, personal property or services by the\nerection and maintenance of an outdoor advertising display or displays,\nwhether or not such display or displays are located on the premises on\nwhich any of the above activities are conducted.  Such rules and\nregulations may further define the terms used in this subdivision. In\nlieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving expenses, any such\ndisplaced owner or tenant of residential property may elect to accept a\nmoving expense allowance, plus a dislocation allowance, determined in\naccordance with a schedule prepared by the commissioner and made a part\nof such rules and regulations. In lieu of such actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses, any such displaced owner or tenant of\ncommercial property who relocates or discontinues his business or farm\noperation may elect to accept a fixed relocation payment in an amount\nequal to the average annual net earnings of the business or farm\noperation, except that such payment shall be not less than two thousand\nfive hundred dollars nor more than ten thousand dollars.  In the case of\na business, no such fixed relocation payment shall be made unless the\ncommissioner finds and determines that the business cannot be relocated\nwithout a substantial loss of its existing patronage, and that the\nbusiness is not part of a commercial enterprise having at least one\nother establishment, which is not being acquired by the state or the\nUnited States, which is engaged in the same or similar business. In the\ncase of a business which is to be discontinued but for which the\nfindings and determinations set forth above cannot be made, the\ncommissioner may prepare an estimate of what the actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses, exclusive of any storage charges, would be if\nthe business were to be relocated and enter into an agreed settlement\nwith the owner of such business for an amount not to exceed such\nestimate in lieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses. Application for payment under this subdivision shall be made\nto the commissioner upon forms prescribed by him and shall be\naccompanied by such information and evidence as the commissioner may\nrequire. Upon approval of such application, the commissioner shall\ndeliver a copy thereof to the comptroller together with a certificate\nstating the amount due thereunder, and the amount so fixed shall be paid\nout of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from moneys\nappropriated for the acquisition of property under this section. As used\nin this subdivision the term "commercial property" shall include\nproperty owned by an individual, family, partnership, corporation,\nassociation or a nonprofit organization and includes a farm operation.\nAs used in this subdivision the term "business" means any lawful\nactivity, except a farm operation, conducted primarily for the purchase,\nsale, lease and rental of personal and real property, and for the\nmanufacture, processing, or marketing of products, commodities, or any\nother personal property; for the sale of services to the public; or by a\nnonprofit organization.\n  11. Authorization is hereby given to the commissioner to make\nsupplemental relocation payments, separately computed and stated, to\ndisplaced owners and tenants of residential property acquired p</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>