<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="216-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_216_D">
        <num>216-D</num>
        <heading>Consumer product protection</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 216-d. Consumer product protection. 1. The superintendent, in\nconsultation with the commissioner of the division of criminal justice\nservices, shall establish a program to investigate actual and/or\nsuspected cases of consumer product tampering, as defined in sections\n145.35, 145.40 and 145.45 of the penal law, within this state and may\nassign such employees, as deemed necessary for the proper operation of\nsuch program.\n  2. Such program shall provide that the state police may, upon request,\nact as the coordinating agency responding to cases of suspected product\ntampering. The superintendent in conjunction with the commissioner of\nthe division of criminal justice services, shall, by regulation,\nestablish uniform procedures that may be used by other agencies involved\nin such cases.\n  3. The superintendent, in conjunction with the commissioner of the\ndivision of criminal justice services, and with the cooperation of the\ndepartment of health, the department of agriculture and markets, and\nother pertinent agencies, shall promulgate such additional rules and\nregulations which in his/her discretion are necessary for the efficient\noperation of this section. These regulations should include but not be\nlimited to the following:\n  a. the establishment of uniform procedures to be used whenever a law\nenforcement or regulatory agency or other agency becomes involved in a\nconsumer product tampering incident. Such regulations shall require that\nthe state police provide direct investigative assistance or support\nservices to any law enforcement or regulatory agency upon request;\n  b. the establishment of a computerized central data base, located at\ndivision headquarters, which will function as an information management\nand retrieval system for matters involving consumer product tampering.\nNotification of all consumer product tampering cases made to law\nenforcement, regulatory agencies or other agencies shall be reported to\nthe central data base within five hours of such notification;\n  c. authorization, upon request, to use the scientific crime detection\nlaboratory to analyze evidence in connection with state police cases or\ncases that originate with other law enforcement, regulatory agencies or\nother agencies; and\n  d. establishment of a twenty-four hour consumer product tampering\nphone line, to be set up at Headquarters' communication section in\nAlbany.\n  4. The superintendent, in cooperation with the division of criminal\njustice services, shall make recommendations to the municipal police\ntraining council for the establishment of a formalized consumer product\ntampering training program for all law enforcement personnel.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>