<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="216-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-216-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_216_C">
        <num>216-C</num>
        <heading>Holiday compensation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 216-c. Holiday compensation. 1. Notwithstanding the provisions of\nsection one hundred thirty-five of the civil service law, members of the\ndivision of state police, other than troopers attending the state police\nacademy for basic training, the division physician, assistant division\nphysicians, inspectors, deputy chief inspectors, confidential assistant\nto the superintendent, the assistant deputy superintendents, the chief\ninspector, the counsel, first assistant counsel, assistant counsels,\ndeputy superintendents, first deputy superintendent, state police\ndirector of personnel, assistant director of personnel-state police and\nthe state police director of scientific laboratory shall effective April\nfirst, nineteen hundred eighty-five for members in the collective\nnegotiating unit consisting of commissioned and non-commissioned\nofficers in the division of state police and effective June thirteenth,\nnineteen hundred eighty-five for such other members receive annual\nholiday compensation in an amount to be computed for each member by\ndividing his annual basic salary by one thousand nine hundred ninety-two\nhours to obtain an hourly rate of pay and multiplying such hourly rate\nby fifty-two and four-tenths hours, adjusted to the next higher whole\ndollar amount. Such compensation shall be in lieu of any other premium\nwhich may be paid for work on a legal holiday and shall be included in\nand be a part of the member's annual basic salary and on and after April\nfirst nineteen hundred eighty-five for members in the collective\nnegotiating unit consisting of commissioned and non-commissioned\nofficers in the division of state police established pursuant to article\nfourteen of the civil service law and on and after June thirteenth,\nnineteen hundred eighty-five for such other members is included in the\nannual basic salary schedules applicable to such members pursuant to\nthis article.\n  * 2. In addition to the compensation provided in subdivision one of\nthis section, members of the collective negotiating unit consisting of\ninvestigators, senior investigators and investigative specialists in the\ndivision of state police, on the payroll on November first of each year,\nshall continue to receive holiday compensation, effective April first,\ntwo thousand ten, in the amount of fifteen hundred thirty-six dollars.\nEffective April first, two thousand fourteen, such amount shall be\nincreased to fifteen hundred sixty-seven dollars. Effective April first,\ntwo thousand fifteen, such amount shall be increased to fifteen hundred\nninety-eight dollars. Effective April first, two thousand sixteen, such\namount shall be increased to sixteen hundred twenty-two dollars.\nEffective April first, two thousand seventeen, such amount shall be\nincreased to sixteen hundred forty-six dollars. Such payments shall be\nin addition to, and shall not be part of, the member's annual basic\nsalary, except for the purpose of retirement, and shall be made in a\nseparate check during the payroll period which includes December first\neach year.\n  * NB Effective until certain conditions are met as set forth in\nchapter 182 of 2025 ยง 26\n  * 2. In addition to the compensation provided in subdivision one of\nthis section, members of the collective negotiating unit consisting of\ninvestigators, senior investigators and investigative specialists in the\ndivision of state police, on the payroll on November first of each year,\nshall receive holiday compensation as follows:\n          April 1, 2023       $1,835\n          April 1, 2024       $1,890\n          April 1, 2025       $1,947\n  Such payments shall be in addition to, and shall not be part of, the\nmember's annual basic salary, except for the purpose of retirement and,\neffective May eighth, two thousand twenty-five, overtime, and shall be\nmade in a separate check during the payroll period which includes\nDecember first each year.\n  * NB Effective upon certain conditions being met as set forth in\nchapter 182 of 2025 ยง 26\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>