<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="221-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_221_B">
        <num>221-B</num>
        <heading>Reporting to New York state violent crimes analysis program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 221-b Reporting to New York state violent crimes analysis program.\n1.  Every law enforcement agency which receives a report of an actual or\nattempted abduction or molestation shall notify the New York state\nviolent crimes analysis program, via the requirements of the New York\nstatewide police information network, of such report. Such program shall\nmake comparisons of data in its files, and report to the law enforcement\nagency making an initial report, any similarities to other reports\nreceived by such program. The violent crimes analysis program shall also\nnotify the unit of a law enforcement agency which investigates homicides\nwhen a report reveals similarities, patterns or modus operandi which\nappear in reports of homicides.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, every\nlaw enforcement agency that accepts responsibility for investigating a\nhomicide or attempted homicide, the discovery of unidentified human\nremains, a reported missing person case where circumstances indicate a\nstrong possibility of foul play, or a sexual assault or attempted sexual\nassault, shall make a written report of such investigation to the New\nYork state violent crimes analysis program. Such program shall conduct a\ncomputerized commonality analysis and provide the submitting law\nenforcement agency the results of such analysis. Every written report\nmade to the violent crimes analysis program shall be in form and content\nas determined and prescribed by such program, upon the approval of the\nsuperintendent of state police. An initial written report shall be made\nto the violent crimes analysis program within thirty days of\ncommencement of an investigation. The results of a computerized\ncommonality analysis shall be provided by such program to the submitting\nlaw enforcement agency upon completion of such analysis in a timely\nmanner, as prescribed by the superintendent of state police.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>