<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="221"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_221">
        <num>221</num>
        <heading>System of criminal justice information</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 221. System of criminal justice information. 1. When any peace\nofficer or police agency within this state shall receive a complaint\nthat a felony involving the use of deadly physical force or a deadly\nweapon has been committed, and if the perpetrator thereof be not\napprehended within thirty minutes after such complaint has been\nreceived, or, in the case of any other felony, if the perpetrator\nthereof be not apprehended within five hours, such police agency shall\ncause information of such felony to be electronically entered into the\nNew York statewide police information network in accordance with the\nrules for such entry promulgated by the superintendent of state police.\nPolice agencies not directly connected with the New York statewide\npolice information network shall transmit such information to the\nnearest or most convenient electronic entry point, from which point it\nwill be immediately dispatched, in conformity with the orders, rules or\nregulations governing the network.\n  2. Any warrant of arrest, bench warrant or superior court warrant of\narrest, as such terms are defined in section 1.20 of the criminal\nprocedure law, relating to any offense defined as a felony in\nsubdivision five of section 10.00 of the penal law, or a probation\nwarrant issued pursuant to section 410.40 of the criminal procedure law,\nmust be entered into the system no later than forty-eight hours from the\ntime it is received by the police officer or peace officer to whom it is\naddressed if the subject of the warrant has not been apprehended prior\nto that time.\n  3. When any police officer, peace officer or police agency in the\nstate shall receive a complaint of a missing child, as defined in\nsubdivision one of section eight hundred thirty-seven-e of this chapter,\nsuch police officer, peace officer or police agency may, in his or her\ndiscretion, as appropriate, cause information concerning such missing\nchild to be promptly dispatched over the police communication system.\nPolice agencies not connected with the basic system may transmit such\ninformation to the nearest or most convenient electronic entry point,\nfrom which point it may be promptly dispatched, in conformity with the\norders, rules or regulations governing the system. No dispatch or\ntransmission of a report concerning a missing child shall be required by\nthis subdivision if the investigating police department advises, in its\ndiscretion, that the release of such information may jeopardize the\ninvestigation or the safety of the child, or requests forbearance for\nany reason.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>