<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-227"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-227"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="227"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_227">
        <num>227</num>
        <heading>Disability benefits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 227. Disability benefits. The following benefits shall be paid by\nthe state on account of disability of a member of the division of state\npolice:\n  1. To every person now a member or who shall hereafter become a member\nof the division of state police, who is now or who shall hereafter\nbecome physically or mentally unable to perform his regular duties in a\nmanner satisfactory to the superintendent of the division of state\npolice there shall be paid during the period of such disability an\namount of not less than one-third nor more than one-half of his salary\nincluding maintenance allowance, which amount within such limits shall\nbe determined by a board consisting of the superintendent of state\npolice, the attorney-general and the state comptroller. A member of the\nNew York state employees' retirement system who has heretofore served as\na member of the division of state police for a period of fifteen years\nor more and who, following such a period of service, has heretofore been\nretired for ordinary disability under the provisions of section\nseventy-eight of the civil service law shall, notwithstanding the\nprovisions of section ninety-three of the civil service law, receive\nfrom the state from appropriations made for the purpose of this section\nsuch sum as will bring his retirement allowance under section\nseventy-eight of the civil service law up to the amount which he would\nhave received under this subdivision if he were not a member of the New\nYork state employees' retirement system and were entitled to the\nbenefits provided for by this subdivision, to be determined in the\nmanner prescribed thereby.\n  2. The provisions of this section shall not apply in the case of any\nmember of the division of state police who is a member of the New York\nstate employees' retirement system unless he was retired by such system\nfor ordinary disability prior to May twenty-second, nineteen hundred\nforty-two.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>