<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-240"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-240"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="240"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-240/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-240/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-240/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-240/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_240">
        <num>240</num>
        <heading>Office of probation and correctional alternatives</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 240. Office of probation and correctional alternatives. 1. There\nshall be in the division of criminal justice services an office of\nprobation and correctional alternatives, hereinafter referred to in this\narticle as "the office". The head of the office shall be the director of\nprobation and correctional alternatives, who shall be appointed by the\ncommissioner, subject to the approval of the governor.\n  2. The director shall serve as special advisor to the governor\nregarding matters pertaining to probation and alternatives to\nincarceration. The director shall, in consultation with the\ncommissioner, coordinate and make recommendations relating to the type\nand nature of alternative to incarceration programs needed to reduce\nincarceration where the purpose of such incarceration can be adequately\nserved by alternative programs and shall work with local probation\ndepartments and the commissioner to enhance and develop probation\nservices and alternative to incarceration programs throughout the state.\n  3. The commissioner, in consultation with the director, shall appoint\nstaff and perform such other functions to ensure the efficient operation\nof the office within the amounts made available therefor by\nappropriation.\n  4. As used in this article, the term "director" shall mean the\ndirector of the office of probation and correctional alternatives,\n"office" shall mean the office of probation and correctional\nalternatives, "commissioner" shall mean the commissioner of the division\nof criminal justice services and "division" shall mean the division of\ncriminal justice services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>