<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-243"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-243"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="243"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-243/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-243/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-243/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-243/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_243">
        <num>243</num>
        <heading>Supervision of administration of local probation and correctional alternatives</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_243__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office shall have the authority to certify to the\ncommissioner those correctional alternative programs subject to\nsupervision of the office and determined to perform a criminal justice\nfunction, as defined in subdivision ten of section eight hundred\nthirty-five of this chapter, for the purpose of permitting access to\ncriminal history records for criminal justice purposes, subject to the\napproval of the commissioner. Any such correctional alternative program\nmay apply for certification to the office in writing, on forms\nprescribed by the office. Such application shall specify, at a minimum,\nthe following: the nature and scope of the program; the necessity for\naccess to such records related to their criminal justice function; the\nnames of employees, and their job titles or positions, for whom access\nis being sought; and any other information the office deems necessary.\nCertification shall include the designation of those employees of such\nprograms for whom access to such records is authorized. No designated\nemployee shall have access to such records until such person has\nsatisfactorily completed appropriate training, required by the division.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_243__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, probation departments\nconducting investigations ordered by a court, for purposes of\ndetermining custody, adoption, visitation, or guardianship shall have\naccess to criminal history records maintained by state law enforcement\nagencies for criminal justice purposes.\n  4. The office shall recommend to the commissioner rules and\nregulations which shall include guidelines and procedures on the\nplacement of sex offenders designated as level two or level three\noffenders pursuant to article six-C of the correction law. Such\nregulations shall instruct local probation departments to consider\ncertain factors when investigating and approving the residence of level\ntwo or level three sex offenders sentenced to a period of probation.\nSuch factors shall include the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_243__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the location of other sex offenders required to register under the\nsex offender registration act, specifically whether there is a\nconcentration of registered sex offenders in a certain residential area\nor municipality;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_243__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of registered sex offenders residing at a particular\nproperty;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_243__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the proximity of entities with vulnerable populations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_243__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>accessibility to family members, friends or other supportive\nservices, including but not limited to locally available sex offender\ntreatment programs with preference for placement of such individuals\ninto programs that have demonstrated effectiveness in reducing sex\noffender recidivism and increasing public safety; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_243__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the availability of permanent, stable housing in order to reduce\nthe likelihood that such offenders will be transient.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>