<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-248"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-248"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="248"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-248/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-248/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-248/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-248/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_248">
        <num>248</num>
        <heading>Establishment of probation scholarships</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 248. Establishment of probation scholarships. The office, out of\nmoneys appropriated to it for that purpose, is authorized to grant\nscholarships for graduate training in any course of study that would be\nof substantial value in the field of probation at graduate schools\nlocated within the state whose programs are registered by the regents.\n  Each such scholarship shall entitle the holder thereof to a sum not to\nexceed four thousand dollars annually while in attendance at any of the\nsaid schools for a period not to exceed two years of graduate\nprofessional study.\n  Scholarships under this section shall be awarded only to residents of\nthe state of New York who hold a degree of bachelor of arts or bachelor\nof science from a college or university, or the equivalent thereof.\n  The office, after consultation with the state probation commission,\nshall recommend to the commissioner rules governing the award of such\nscholarships, the publication of notices offering scholarships, the\nissuance and cancellation of certificates entitling persons to the\nbenefits thereof, the use of such scholarships by the persons entitled\nthereto, the courses that may be included under such scholarships, the\nschools which may be attended under such scholarships, the rights and\nduties of scholarship holders and of the schools which they attend, and\nproviding generally for the carrying into effect of the provisions of\nthis section; and may, by appropriate rule, require that holders of such\nscholarships be available for employment in probation work in the state\nof New York upon the completion of the training for which the\nscholarship is provided. The office shall, after consultation with the\nstate probation commission, award such scholarships within such\nestablished rules, and any scholarship may be revoked for cause.\n  Payments of money under this section may be made to the holder of the\nscholarship or to the school or college attended under the scholarship,\non behalf of, and for the benefit of, the holder of the scholarship.\n  Payments of money shall be ordered by the comptroller upon vouchers of\nthe office certifying that the person named therein is entitled to\nreceive the sum either directly, or for his or her benefit.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>