<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-255"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-255"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="255"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-255/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-255/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-255/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-255/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_255">
        <num>255</num>
        <heading>Probation in the city of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 255. Probation in the city of New York. 1. There is hereby created a\ndepartment of probation in and for the city of New York to have charge\nof all probation work in the supreme, family and criminal courts in the\ncounties of Bronx, Kings, New York, Queens and Richmond.\n  2. The head of such department shall be a director of probation\nappointed by the mayor of the city of New York to serve during the\npleasure of the mayor. The director shall have charge of the\nadministration of the department and shall be responsible for carrying\nout the functions of the department including intake, investigation,\nsupervision, conciliation and pre-disposition social treatment in cases\ncoming to the courts referred to in this section.  The director may,\nfrom time to time, create, abolish, transfer and consolidate bureaus and\nother units within the department as he may determine necessary for\nefficient operation thereof. He also shall have the power to appoint and\nremove such deputy directors, assistants, probation officers and other\nemployees as may be needed for the performance of the duties of the\ndepartment and may prescribe their duties and fix their compensation,\nwithin appropriations made available therefor by the city of New York\nand subject to all applicable civil service laws and rules and\nregulations. The director may, in his discretion, appoint volunteer\nprobation officers, when necessary, provided they have the\nqualifications required of salaried officers, but no such volunteer\nprobation officer shall receive pay from the public funds for his\nservices. The city of New York shall make the necessary appropriation\nfor the salaries of the director and of all officers and employees of\nthe department as referred to herein, as well for the expenses actually\nand necessarily incurred by such director, officers and employees in the\nperformance of their duties.\n  3. The director shall discharge his powers and responsibilities in\naccordance with all laws and rules applicable to probation and with the\ngeneral rules regulating methods and procedure in the administration of\nprobation as adopted from time to time pursuant to section two hundred\nforty-three of this chapter. He may adopt departmental rules, not\ninconsistent with law or the aforesaid general rules, to regulate the\npolicies, programs, standards, and methods of procedure in relation to\nprobation and the powers and duties of officers and employees as in his\njudgment he deems proper.\n  4. The head of such probation department, out of moneys appropriated\nto such department for that purpose, is authorized to grant scholarships\nto employees in the probation service in such department, for graduate\ntraining in the field of probation at graduate schools or departments of\nsocial work located within the state whose programs are registered by\nthe regents and accredited by the council on social work education. Each\nsuch scholarship shall entitle the holder thereof to a sum sufficient to\npay the cost of tuition, not to exceed two thousand dollars annually,\nwhile in attendance at any of the said schools or departments for a\nperiod not to exceed two years of graduate professional study.\nScholarships under this section shall be awarded to employees in the\nprobation service in such department who apply therefor in the order of\ntheir seniority in their civil service titles.\n  5. Notwithstanding any other provision of law or of the New York city\ncharter or administrative code, any duly appointed officer or employee\nof such probation department may reside in any county within the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>