<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-257-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-257-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="257-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-257-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-257-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-257-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-257-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_257_C">
        <num>257-C</num>
        <heading>Probation administrative fee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 257-c. Probation administrative fee. 1. Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of law, every county and the city of New York, may adopt a\nlocal law requiring individuals currently serving or who shall be\nsentenced to a period of probation upon conviction of any crime under\narticle thirty-one of the vehicle and traffic law to pay to the local\nprobation department with the responsibility of supervising the\nprobationer an administrative fee of thirty dollars per month. The\ndepartment shall waive all or part of such fee where, because of the\nindigence of the offender, the payment of said surcharge would work an\nunreasonable hardship on the person convicted, his or her immediate\nfamily, or any other person who is dependent on such person for\nfinancial support.\n  2. The provisions of subdivision six of section 420.10 of the criminal\nprocedure law shall govern for purposes of collection of the\nadministrative fee.\n  3. The probation administrative fee authorized by this section shall\nnot constitute nor be imposed as a condition of probation.\n  4. In the event of non-payment of any fees which have not been waived\nby the local probation department, the county or the city of New York\nmay seek to enforce payment in any manner permitted by law for\nenforcement of a debt.\n  5. Monies collected pursuant to this section shall be utilized for\nprobation services by the local probation department. Such moneys shall\nnot be considered by the division when determining state aid pursuant to\nsection two hundred forty-six of the executive law. Monies collected\nshall not be used to replace federal funds otherwise utilized for\nprobation services.\n  * NB Expires September 1, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>