<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="259-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_259_O">
        <num>259-O</num>
        <heading>Interstate hearings for parole violations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 259-o. Interstate hearings for parole violations. 1. For the\npurposes of this section, "preliminary violation hearing" means a\nhearing to determine whether there are reasonable grounds to believe\nthat a person released on parole has violated the conditions of his\nparole.\n  2. Whenever there is reasonable cause to believe that a person\nreleased on parole in another state but under the parole supervision of\nthis state pursuant to section two hundred fifty-nine-m of this article\nhas violated the conditions thereof, a member or designee of the board\nof parole, upon request of the sending state, may conduct a preliminary\nviolation hearing unless such hearing is waived by the parolee.\n  3. Whenever there is reasonable cause to believe that a person\nreleased on parole in this state but under the parole supervision of\nanother state pursuant to section two hundred fifty-nine-m of this\narticle has violated the conditions thereof, any person duly authorized\nin such other state to conduct preliminary violation hearings, upon\nrequest of the chairman of the board of parole, may conduct such\nhearing, unless such hearing is waived by the parolee.  The preliminary\nviolation hearing and the determinations made thereat shall have the\nsame force and effect as preliminary violation hearing conducted in this\nstate by the board of parole or a member, hearing officer or panel\nthereof.\n  4. Whenever a preliminary violation hearing is conducted in another\nstate pursuant to this section, the alleged violator must be afforded a\nfinal hearing within ninety days from the date of his return to this\nstate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>