<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="259-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_259_E">
        <num>259-E</num>
        <heading>Institutional parole services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 259-e. Institutional parole services. The department shall provide\ninstitutional parole services. Such services shall include preparation\nof reports and other data required by the state board of parole in the\nexercise of its functions with respect to release on presumptive\nrelease, parole, conditional release or post-release supervision of\nincarcerated individuals. Additionally, the department shall determine\nwhich incarcerated individuals are in need of a deaf language\ninterpreter or an English language interpreter, and shall inform the\nboard of such need within a reasonable period of time prior to an\nincarcerated individual's scheduled appearance before the board.\nEmployees of the department who collect data, interview incarcerated\nindividuals and prepare reports for the state board of parole in\ninstitutions under the jurisdiction of the department shall work under\nthe direct supervision of the deputy commissioner of the department in\ncharge of program services. Data and reports submitted to the board\nshall address the statutory factors to be considered by the board\npursuant to the relevant provisions of section two hundred fifty-nine-i\nof this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>