<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="259-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_259_Q">
        <num>259-Q</num>
        <heading>Civil actions against board personnel</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_259_Q__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>within the scope of the employment and in the discharge of the\nduties of such officer or employee, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_259_Q__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not done or omitted with the\nintent to violate any rule or regulation of the department, board or\nformer division or of any statute or governing case law of the state or\nof the United States at the time the damages were sustained; provided\nthat the officer or employee shall comply with the provisions of\nsubdivision four of section seventeen of the public officers law.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_259_Q__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this section shall supplement, and be\navailable in addition to, the provisions of section seventeen of the\npublic officers law and, insofar as this section is inconsistent with\nsection seventeen of the public officers law, the provisions of this\nsection shall be controlling.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_259_Q__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this section shall not be construed in any way\nto impair, modify or abrogate any immunity available to any officer or\nemployee of the board of parole or former division of parole under the\nstatutory or decisional law of the state or the United States.\n  5. This section shall not in any way impair, limit or modify the\nrights and obligations of any insurer under any policy of insurance.\n  6. The benefits of subdivision three hereof shall inure only to\nofficers and employees of the board of parole or former division of\nparole and shall not enlarge or diminish the rights of any other party.\n  7. This section shall apply with respect to claims arising on or after\nthe effective date of this section. Claims arising prior thereto shall\nbe governed by section seventeen of the public officers law or section\ntwenty-four of the correction law as the case may be.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>