<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="259-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-259-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_259_B">
        <num>259-B</num>
        <heading>State board of parole; organization</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_259_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have been awarded a\ndegree from an accredited four-year college or university or a graduate\ndegree from such college or university or accredited graduate school and\nshall have had at least five years of experience in one or more of the\nfields of criminology, administration of criminal justice, law\nenforcement, sociology, law, social work, corrections, psychology,\npsychiatry or medicine; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_259_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have at least ten years of experience in\none or more of the fields of criminology, administration of criminal\njustice, law enforcement, sociology, law, social work, corrections,\npsychology, psychiatry or medicine.\n  3. The governor shall designate one of the members of the board as\nchairman to serve in such capacity at the pleasure of the governor or\nuntil the member's term of office expires and a successor is designated\nin accordance with law, whichever first occurs. The chairman shall be\nresponsible for the administrative functions and daily operations of the\nparole board and its staff, except as otherwise provided by law.\n  4. The members of the board shall not hold any other public office;\nnor shall they, at any time of their appointment nor during their\nincumbency, serve as a representative of any political party on an\nexecutive committee or other governing body thereof, nor as an executive\nofficer or employee of any political committee, organization or\nassociation.\n  5. Each member of the board shall receive for his services an annual\nsalary to be fixed by the governor within the amount appropriated\ntherefor. Each member of such board shall also receive his necessary\nexpenses actually incurred in the discharge of his duties.\n  6. Any member of the board may be removed by the governor for cause\nafter an opportunity to be heard.\n  7. Except as otherwise provided by law, a majority of the board shall\nconstitute a quorum for the transaction of all business of the board.\n  8. Members of the board shall devote their full time to their duties\nand shall hold no other salaried public position.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>