<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-262"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-262"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="262"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-262/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-262/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-262/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-262/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_262">
        <num>262</num>
        <heading>Office assistance; plan; approval</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 262. Office assistance; plan; approval. 1. Upon request of either\nthe county executive or the advisory board, through the chairperson, the\noffice shall assist the county in the development of its plan by\nproviding technical assistance either directly or through contract with\npersons or organizations which have expertise in the area of pre-trial\nservices or alternatives to incarceration programs.\n  2. Upon development of a proposed plan but at least thirty days prior\nto approval by the board, public comment shall be solicited for\nconsideration by the board prior to final action.\n  3. Upon approval by the board, by a majority of its members, any\ncounty outside the city of New York acting through its county executive,\nand upon approval of the local legislative body, may submit a proposed\nservice plan to the office for approval. The city of New York acting\nthrough the mayor and upon approval by the board of estimate may submit\na proposed service plan to the office for approval.\n  4. a. Each such plan shall be submitted to the office no later than\none hundred eighty days after the effective date of the chapter of the\nlaws of nineteen hundred eighty-eight which amended this paragraph and\nadded these words or by the first day of April of each subsequent year\nand shall provide that upon approval it shall become effective. Annual\nrenewals of service plans are required and shall be submitted to the\noffice no later than the first day of April of each year following\nsubmission of the original plan. A plan may be amended from time to time\nby the advisory board, subject to the approval of the local legislative\nbody and the office. The office may recommend amendments to a plan,\nsubject to the approval of the advisory board and the local legislative\nbody. Reasons for such amendments may include but shall not be limited\nto the addition or deletion of eligible programs with due consideration\nto their utilization by the court, their effect on diverting the jail\nbound population, reducing the overcrowding problem and their\ncost-effectiveness.\n  b. The office shall either approve or deny the plan no later than\nsixty days following its submission. If the plan is denied, the office\nshall notify the county executive in writing of such denial and the\nreasons therefor and shall specify any measures which should be\nundertaken to secure the approval of the office. Nothing herein shall\nprohibit the amendment of a plan to overcome the office's stated reasons\nfor denial or the resubmission of such proposed plan for approval.\n  * NB Repealed September 1, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>