<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-266"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-266"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="266"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-266/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-266/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-266/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-266/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_266">
        <num>266</num>
        <heading>Additional authority of the office; state assistance; approved amendments for eligible alcohol and substance abuse programs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_266__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the first year of implementation and operation of the eligible\nalcohol and substance abuse program, the office shall reimburse to the\nmunicipality one hundred percent of the costs incurred, provided that,\nupon approval of the contract and consistent with implementation plans\napproved by the office, up to one-half of the state's share of the cost\nof such program may be immediately allocated to the municipality for\npurposes of implementation of the program. The balance of the state's\nshare of the costs shall be allocated to the municipality in a manner\ndetermined by the office.\n  (ii) In the second year of operation of such eligible alcohol and\nsubstance abuse program, such program shall be included in the approved\nservice plan submitted by the municipality and the office shall\nreimburse to the municipality seventy-five percent of the costs of\napproved expenditures. Municipalities shall provide at least twenty-five\npercent of costs of approved expenditures of the contract.\n  (iii) In the third and any subsequent year of operation of such\nalcohol and substance abuse program, such program shall be included in\nthe approved service plan submitted by the municipality and the office\nshall reimburse to the municipality fifty percent of the costs of\napproved expenditures. Municipalities shall provide at least fifty\npercent of costs of approved expenditures of the contract.\n  In no event shall the state's share be used to replace expenditures\npreviously incurred by the municipality for such alcohol and substance\nabuse programs;\n  c. An agreement by the municipality to provide for the payment of the\nmunicipality's share of the costs of the alcohol and substance abuse\nprogram or programs, and to proceed expeditiously with, and implement,\nsuch program or programs, as approved by the office; and\n  d. Any costs in excess of the amount provided for in this subdivision\nshall be the responsibility of the municipality, except as otherwise\nprovided in th...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>