<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-27"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-27"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-27/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-27/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-27/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-27/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27">
        <num>27</num>
        <heading>Continuity of local governments</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 27. Continuity of local governments. 1. Every county, except those\nwholly contained within a city, every city, every town and every village\nshall have power to provide by local law, and every other public\ncorporation, district corporation or public benefit corporation shall\nhave power to provide by resolution, for its continuity and that of its\nelective and appointive officers, including members of its legislative\nor governing body when, in the event of a disaster and the emergency\nconditions caused thereby, any of such officers is unable to discharge\nthe powers and duties of his office or is absent from the political\nsubdivision. In any such local law or resolution, provision may be made\nthat the removal of a disability or the termination of an absence from\nthe political subdivision of an officer higher on a list or order of\nsuccession provided therein to an office shall not terminate the service\nin such office of an individual lower on such list or order of\nsuccession who is temporarily filling such office. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of any general or special law or city or village charter, a\nlocal law or resolution adopted pursuant to this section may be made\neffective without approval at a mandatory or permissive referendum but\nin no case shall such local law or resolution become effective until one\ncertified copy thereof has been filed with the clerk of the political\nsubdivision or other appropriate official designated for such purpose by\nthe respective legislative or governing body, one certified copy thereof\nhas been filed in the office of the state comptroller and three\ncertified copies thereof have been filed in the office of the secretary\nof state.\n  No provision of this subdivision shall be construed or interpreted as\naffecting the validity of any ordinance, local law or resolution enacted\nprior to April first, nineteen hundred seventy-nine or actions taken\nthereunder by the government of any county, city, town or village.\n  2. The provisions of this section shall not be applicable in any case\nwhere the continuity of the government of a political subdivision or\nthat of any of its elective or appointive officers is otherwise provided\nfor by or pursuant to law.\n  3. This section shall be construed liberally. The powers herein\ngranted shall be in addition to and not in substitution of any power\ngranted, procedure provided or provision made in any other law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>