<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-273"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-273"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-11-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="273"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-273/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-273/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-273/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-273/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_273">
        <num>273</num>
        <heading>Vacancies; quorum</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event of a vacancy caused by\ndeath, resignation, removal or disability of a commissioner, the vacancy\nshall be filled by the governor by and with the advice and consent of\nthe senate for the unexpired term.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event of a vacancy caused by the death, resignation,\nremoval or disability of the chairman, the vacancy shall be filled by\nthe governor by and with the advice and consent of the senate for the\nunexpired term. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the\ncontrary, the governor shall designate one of the commissioners to serve\nas acting chairman for a period not to exceed six months or until a\nsuccessor chairman has been confirmed by the senate, whichever comes\nfirst. Upon the expiration of the six month term, if the governor has\nnominated a successor chairman, but the senate has not acted upon the\nnomination, the acting chairman can continue to serve as acting chairman\nfor an additional ninety days or until the governor's successor chairman\nnomination is confirmed by the senate, whichever comes first.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The governor shall provide immediate written notice to the\ntemporary president of the senate of the designation of a commissioner\nas acting chairman.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the governor has not nominated a successor chairman upon\nthe expiration of the six month term or (ii) the senate does not confirm\nthe governor's successor nomination within the additional ninety days,\nthe commissioner designated as acting chairman shall no longer be able\nto serve as acting chairman and the governor is prohibited from\nextending the powers of that acting chairman or from designating another\ncommissioner to serve as acting chairman.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A commissioner serving as the acting chairman of the authority\nshall be deemed a state officer for purposes of section seventy-three of\nthe public officers law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_273__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A majority of the members of the authority shall constitute a\nquorum for the purpose of conducting the business thereof and a majority\nvote of all the members in office shall be necessary for action.\nProvided, however, that a commissioner designated as an acting chairman\npursuant to subdivision two of section fourteen of this chapter shall\nhave only one vote for purposes of conducting the business of the\nauthority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>