<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_C">
        <num>29-C</num>
        <heading>Radiological preparedness</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>may monitor directly and record the off-site presence of\nradioactive material in the vicinity of nuclear electric generating\nfacilities located in the state of New York;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall obtain from the licensees, United States nuclear regulatory\ncommission-required high range radiation, temperature and pressure\nlevels in the containment buildings and in the containment building\nvents of nuclear electric generating facilities located in the state of\nNew York; and,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall obtain, subject to the approval of the United States nuclear\nregulatory commission, any reactor data provided by the licensee to the\nUnited States nuclear regulatory commission, which the disaster\npreparedness commission determines, as a result of the report issued\npursuant to section twenty-nine-d of this article, to be a reliable\nindicator of a possible radiological accident.\n  Upon the occurrence of a radiological accident, the commission shall\npromptly provide appropriate and available radioactivity monitoring data\nto any chief executive who requests it. For the purposes of this\nsection, the term "radiological accident" shall be limited to a\nradiological accident occurring at a nuclear electric generating\nfacility.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any licensee of the United States nuclear regulatory commission\nfor a nuclear electric generating facility shall be liable for an annual\nfee to support state and local governmental responsibilities under\naccepted radiological emergency preparedness plans related to the\nfacility operated by such licensee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amount of such fee shall be one million dollars. Such fee,\nwhich shall be payable to the commission on or before December first,\nshall be expended or distributed only by appropriation.\n  3. Such fees shall be expended by the commission for purposes of\nsupporting state and local government responsibilities under accepted\nradiological emergency preparedness plans, including:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>purchase, installation, maintenance and operation of equipment\nused by the commission and local governments to monitor and record the\npotential and actual presence of radioactive materials within the\nappropriate planning radius from a nuclear electric generating facility;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>purchase, storage and distribution by the commission of equipment,\ndrugs or other material for the purpose of protecting public health and\nsafety;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>personal service, administrative costs and contractual services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>emergency services personnel training and the plans, development,\nimplementation, testing and revisions; and,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state or local share when applying for matching funds.\n  3-a.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision three of this\nsection, the New York state emergency management office (SEMO) and the\ncoalition of nuclear counties, which constitutes the counties of Monroe,\nWayne, Oswego, Orange, Putnam, Rockland and Westchester, shall each\nreceive an equal one-half portion of the total amount of proceeds\nresulting from the total assessments and contributions made pursuant to\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The one-half portion of the proceeds resulting from the total\nassessments and contributions made pursuant to this section received by\nthe coalition of nuclear counties shall be distributed pursuant to the\nfollowing formula:\n  Monroe county 12.3%\n  Orange county 10%\n  Oswego county 12.5%\n  Putnam county 9.8%\n  Rockland county 18%\n  Wayne county 12.4%\n  Westchester county 25%\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>