<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_G">
        <num>29-G</num>
        <heading>Emergency management assistance compact</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the responsibility of each party state to formulate\nprocedural plans and programs for interstate cooperation in the\nperformance of the responsibilities listed in this section. In\nformulating such plans, and in carrying them out, the party states,\ninsofar as practical, shall:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Review individual state hazard analysis and, to the extent\nreasonably possible, determine all those potential emergencies the party\nstates might jointly suffer, whether due to natural disaster,\ntechnological hazard, man-made disaster, emergency aspects or resource\nshortages, civil disorders, insurgency or enemy attack.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Review party states' individual emergency plans and develop a plan\nwhich will determine the mechanism for the interstate management and\nprovision of assistance concerning any potential emergency.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Develop interstate procedures to fill any identified gaps and to\nresolve any identified inconsistencies or overlaps in existing or\ndeveloped plans.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Assist in warning communities adjacent to or crossing the state\nboundaries.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Protect and assure uninterrupted delivery of services, medicines,\nwater, food, energy and fuel, search and rescue and critical lifeline\nequipment, services and resources, both human and material.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Inventory and set procedures for the interstate loan and delivery\nof human material resources, together with procedures for reimbursement\nor forgiveness.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide, to the extent authorized by law, for temporary suspension\nof any statutes or ordinances that restrict the implementation of the\nabove responsibilities.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authorized representative of a party state may request\nassistance of another party state by contacting the authorized\nrepresentative of that state. The provisions of this agreement shall\nonly apply to requests for assistance made by and to authorized\nrepresentatives. Requests may be verbal or in writing. If verbal, the\nrequest shall be confirmed in writing within thirty days of the verbal\nrequest. Requests shall provide the following information:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A description of the emergency service function for which\nassistance is needed, such as, but not limited to, fire services, law\nenforcement, emergency medical, transportation, communications, public\nworks and engineering, building inspection, planning and information\nassistance, mass care, resource support, health and medical services,\nand search and rescue.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount and type of personnel, equipment, materials and\nsupplies needed, and a reasonable estimate of the length of time that\nthey will be needed.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_29_G__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The specific place and time for staging of the assisting party's\nresponse and a point of contact at that location.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_G__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be frequent consultation between state officials who\nhave assigned emergency management responsibilities and other\nappropriate representatives of the party states with affected\njurisdictions and the United States government, with free exchange of\ninformation, plans and resource records relating to emergency\ncapabilities.\n  4. Any party state requested to render mutual aid or conduct exercises\nand training for mutual aid shall take such action as is necessary to\nprovide and make available the resources covered by this compact in\naccordance with the terms hereof provided, that it is understood that\nthe state rendering aid may withhold resources to the extent necessary\nto provide reasonable protection for such state.\n  Each party state shall afford to the emergency forces of any party\nstate, while operating within its state limits under the terms and\nconditions of this compact, the same powers (except that of arrest\nunless specifically authorized by the receiving state), duties, rights\nand privileges as are afforded forces of the state in which they are\nperforming emergency services. Emergency forces will continue under the\ncommand and control of their regular leaders, but the organizational\nunits will come under the operational control of the emergency services\nauthorities of the state receiving assistance. These conditions may be\nactivated, as needed, only subsequent to a declaration of a state of\nemergency or disaster by the governor of the party state that is to\nreceive assistance or commencement of exercises or training for mutual\naid and shall continue so long as the exercises or training for mutual\naid are in progress, the state, or states, of emergency or disaster\nremains in effect or loaned resources remain in the receiving states,\nwhichever is longer.\n  5. Whenever any person holds a license, certificate or other permit\nissued by any state party to the compact evidencing the meeting of\nqualifications for professional,...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This compact shall become operative immediately upon its\nenactment into law by any two states; thereafter, this compact shall\nbecome effective as to any other state upon its enactment by such state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any party state may withdraw from this compact by enacting a\nstatute repealing the same, but no such withdrawal shall take effect\nuntil thirty days after the governor of the withdrawing state has given\nnotice in writing of such withdrawal to the governors of all other party\nstates. Such action shall not relieve the withdrawing state from\nobligations assumed hereunder prior to the effective date of withdrawal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_G__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Duly authenticated copies of this compact and of such\nsupplementary agreements as may be entered into shall, at the time of\ntheir approval be deposited with each of the party states and with the\nfederal emergency management agency and other appropriate agencies of\nthe United States government.\n  12. This compact shall be construed to effectuate the purposes stated\nin subdivision one of this section. If any provision of this compact is\ndeclared unconstitutional, or the applicability thereof to any person or\ncircumstances is held invalid, the constitutionality of the remainder of\nthis compact and the applicability thereof to other persons and\ncircumstances shall not be affected thereby.\n  13. Nothing in this compact shall authorize or permit the use of\nmilitary forces by the National Guard of a state at any place outside\nthe state in any emergency for which the president is authorized by law\nto call into federal service the militia, or for any purposes for which\nthe use of the army or the air force would in the absence of express\nstatutory authorization be prohibited under section 1385 of title 18,\nUnited States code.\n  14. The legally designated state official who is assigned\nresponsibility for emergency management shall not offer resources to, or\nrequest resources from, another compact member state, without prior\ndiscussion with and concurrence from the state agency, department,\noffice, division, board, bureau, commission or authority that may be\nasked to provide resources or that may utilize resources from another\ncompact member state.\n  15. The director of the state emergency management office shall, on or\nbefore the first day of January, two thousand two, provide to the\nlegislature and the governor copies of all mutual aid plans and\nprocedures promulgated, developed or entered into after the effective\ndate of this section. The director of the state emergency management\noffice shall annually hereafter provide the legislature and gover...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>