<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-29-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_J">
        <num>29-J</num>
        <heading>Acceptance of gifts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 29-j. Acceptance of gifts. 1. The state office of emergency\nmanagement within the division of homeland security and emergency\nservices may accept any assistance, including but not limited to gifts\nor grants of real or personal property, but not including money, from\nany public or private source for the purpose of preparing for,\nresponding to, or recovering from a state disaster emergency. Such\nassistance may be used to support state and local disaster operations or\ndistributed to disaster response organizations supporting local disaster\nresponse operations. To the extent practicable, the office of emergency\nmanagement shall distribute such assistance in consultation with local\ngovernments, not-for-profit organizations, and other disaster response\norganizations that have experience responding to state disaster\nemergencies.\n  2. The state office of emergency management shall maintain a database\nof all assistance accepted during the state disaster emergency and shall\nmake such information available to the public on its website. The\ndatabase shall include, but is not limited to, the name of the donor,\ntype of assistance provided, value of the assistance, recipient of the\nassistance (if available), date of the donation and date of\ndistribution.\n  3. The director of the office of emergency management, in consultation\nwith the commissioner of the division of homeland security and emergency\nservices, may promulgate rules and regulations necessary to implement\nthis section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>