<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-292"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-292"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-10-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="292"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-292/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-292/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-292/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-292/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_292">
        <num>292</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state of New York shall be\nconsidered an employer of any employee or official, including any\nelected official, of the New York state executive, legislature, or\njudiciary, including persons serving in any judicial capacity, and\npersons serving on the staff of any elected official in New York state,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a city, county, town, village or other political subdivision of\nthe state of New York shall be considered an employer of any employee or\nofficial, including any elected official, of such locality's executive,\nlegislature or judiciary, including persons serving in any local\njudicial capacity, and persons serving on the staff of any local elected\nofficial.\n  6. The term "employee" in this article does not include any individual\nemployed by his or her parents, spouse, or child.\n  7. The term "commissioner", unless a different meaning clearly appears\nfrom the context, means the state commissioner of human rights; and the\nterm "division" means the state division of human rights created by this\narticle.\n  8. The term "national origin" shall, for the purposes of this article,\ninclude "ancestry."\n  9. The term "place of public accommodation, resort or amusement" shall\ninclude, regardless of whether the owner or operator of such place is a\nstate or local government entity or a private individual or entity,\nexcept as hereinafter specified, all places included in the meaning of\nsuch terms as: inns, taverns, road houses, hotels, motels, whether\nconducted for the entertainment of transient guests or for the\naccommodation of those seeking health, recreation or rest, or\nrestaurants, or eating houses, or any place where food is sold for\nconsumption on the premises; buffets, saloons, barrooms, or any store,\npark or enclosure where spirituous or malt liquors are sold; ice cream\nparlors, confectionaries, soda fountains, and all stores where ice\ncream, ice and fruit preparations or their derivatives, or where\nbeverages of any kind are retailed for consumption on the premises;\nwholesale and retail stores and establishments dealing with goods or\nservices of any kind, dispensaries, clinics, hospitals, bath-houses,\nswimming pools, laundries and all other cleaning establishments, barber\nshops, beauty parlors, theatres, motion picture houses, airdromes, roof\nga...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>public housing,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>housing operated by housing companies under the supervision of the\ncommissioner of housing,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>housing constructed after July first, nineteen hundred fifty,\nwithin the state of New York\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_292__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>which is exempt in whole or in part from taxes levied by the state\nor any of its political subdivisions,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_292__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>which is constructed on land sold below cost by the state or any\nof its political subdivisions or any agency thereof, pursuant to the\nfederal housing act of nineteen hundred forty-nine,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_292__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>which is constructed in whole or in part on property acquired or\nassembled by the state or any of its political subdivisions or any\nagency thereof through the power of condemnation or otherwise for the\npurpose of such construction, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_292__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for the acquisition, construction, repair or maintenance of which\nthe state or any of its political subdivisions or any agency thereof\nsupplies funds or other financial assistance,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>housing which is located in a multiple dwelling, the acquisition,\nconstruction, rehabilitation, repair or maintenance of which is, after\nJuly first, nineteen hundred fifty-five, financed in whole or in part by\na loan, whether or not secured by a mortgage, the repayment of which is\nguaranteed or insured by the federal government or any agency thereof,\nor the state or any of its political subdivisions or any agency thereof,\nprovided that such a housing accommodation shall be deemed to be\npublicly assisted only during the life of such loan and such guaranty or\ninsurance; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>housing which is offered for sale by a person who owns or\notherwise controls the sale of ten or more housing accommodations\nlocated on land that is contiguous (exclusive of public streets), if</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_292__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nthe acquisition, construction, rehabilitation, repair or maintenance of\nsuch housing accommodations is, after July first, nineteen hundred\nfifty-five, financed in whole or in part by a loan, whether or not\nsecured by a mortgage, the repayment of which is guaranteed or insured\nby the federal government or any agency thereof, or the state or any of\nits political subdivisions or any agency thereof, provided that such a\nhousing accommodation shall be deemed to be publicly assisted only\nduring the life of such loan and guaranty or insurance, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_292__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a\ncommitment, issued by a government agency after July first, nineteen\nhundred fifty-five, is outstanding that acquisition of such housing\naccommodations may be financed in whole or in part by a loan, whether or\nnot secured by a mortgage, the repayment of which is guaranteed or\ninsured by the federal government or any agency thereof, or the state or\nany of its political subdivisions or any agency thereof.\n  12. The term "multiple dwelling", as herein used, means a dwelling\nwhich is occupied, as a rule, for permanent residence purposes and which\nis either sold, rented, leased, let or hired out, to be occupied as the\nresidence or home of three or more families living independently of each\nother. A "multiple dwelling" shall not be deemed to include a hospital,\nconvent, monastery, asylum or public institution, or a fireproof\nbuilding used wholly for commercial purposes except for not more than\none janitor's apartment and not more than one penthouse occupied by not\nmore than ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a physical, mental or medical\nimpairment resulting from anatomical, physiological, genetic or\nneurological conditions which prevents the exercise of a normal bodily\nfunction or is demonstrable by medically accepted clinical or laboratory\ndiagnostic techniques or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a record of such an impairment or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a\ncondition regarded by others as such an impairment, provided, however,\nthat in all provisions of this article dealing with employment, the term\nshall be limited to disabilities which, upon the provision of reasonable\naccommodations, do not prevent the complainant from performing in a\nreasonable manner the activities involved in the job or occupation\nsought or held.\n  21-a. "Predisposing genetic characteristic" shall mean any inherited\ngene or chromosome, or alteration thereof, and determined by a genetic\ntest or inferred from information derived from an individual or family\nmember that is scientifically or medically believed to predispose an\nindividual or the offspring of that individual to a disease or\ndisability, or to be associated with a statistically significant\nincreased risk of development of a physical or mental disease or\ndisability.\n  21-b. "Genetic test" shall mean a test for determining the presence or\nabsence of an inherited genetic characteristic in an individual,\nincluding tests of nucleic acids such as DNA, RNA and mitochondrial DNA,\nchromosomes or proteins in order to identify a predisposing genetic\ncharacteristic.\n  21-e. The term "reasonable accommodation" means actions taken which\npermit an employee, prospective employee or member with a disability, or\na pregnancy-related condition, to perform in a reasonable manner the\nactivities involved in the job or occupation sought or held and include,\nbut are not limited to, provision of an accessible worksite, acquisition\nor modification of equipment, support services for persons with impaired\nhearing or vision, job restructuring and modified work schedules;\nprovided, however, that such actions do not impose an undue hardship on\nthe business, program or enterprise of the entity from which action is\nrequested.\n  21-f. The term "pregnancy-related condition" means a medical condition\nrelated to pregnancy or childbirth that inhibits the exercise of a\nnormal bodily function or...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any person who is pregnant or has a child or is in the process of\nsecuring legal custody of any individual who has not attained the age of\neighteen years, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one or more individuals (who have not attained the age of eighteen\nyears) being domiciled with:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_292__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a parent or another person having legal custody of such individual\nor individuals, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_292__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the designee of such parent.\n  27. The term "sexual orientation" means heterosexuality,\nhomosexuality, bisexuality or asexuality, whether actual or perceived.\n  28. The term "military status" when used in this article means a\nperson's participation in the military service of the United States or\nthe military service of the state, including but not limited to, the\narmed forces of the United States, the army national guard, the air\nnational guard, the New York naval militia, the New York guard, and such\nadditional forces as may be created by the federal or state government\nas authorized by law.\n  29. The term "reserve armed forces", when used in this article, means\nservice other than permanent, full-time service in the military forces\nof the United States including but not limited to service in the United\nStates Army Reserve, the United States Naval Reserve, the United States\nMarine Corps Reserve, the United States Air Force Reserve, or the United\nStates Coast Guard Reserv...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any education corporation or association which holds itself out to\nthe public to be non-sectarian and exempt from taxation pursuant to the\nprovisions of article four of the real property tax law; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any for-profit entity that operates a college, university,\nlicensed private career school or certified English as a second language\nschool which holds itself out to the public to be non-sectarian and\nwhich is not exempt from taxation pursuant to the provisions of article\nfour of the real property tax law; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any public school, including any school district, board of\ncooperative educational services, public college or public university.\n  41. The term "citizenship or immigration status" means the citizenship\nof any person or the immigration status of any person who is not a\ncitizen of the United States. Nothing in this article shall preclude\nverification of citizenship or immigration status where required by law,\nnor shall an adverse action based on verification of citizenship or\nimmigration status be prohibited where such adverse action is required\nby law.\n  42. The term "real estate appraisal" shall have the same meaning as in\nsubdivision two of section one hundred sixty-a of this chapter.\nProvided, however, that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>real estate appraisals subject to this\narticle include those performed by any person or entity whose business\nholds itself out as engaging in residential real estate appraisals,\nregardless of whether or not such person or entity is certified or\nlicensed to provide real estate appraisals pursuant to the provisions of\narticle six-E of this chapter, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_292__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the purposes of this article,\nthe real estate appraisal includes all oral communications and all\nwritten comments and other documents submitted as support for the\nestimate, opinion of value, or analysis.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>