<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-295"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-295"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="295"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-295/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-295/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-295/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-295/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_295">
        <num>295</num>
        <heading>General powers and duties of division</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_295__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To receive, investigate and pass upon complaints alleging\nviolations of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_295__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon its own motion, to test and investigate and to make, sign and\nfile complaints alleging violations of this article and to initiate\ninvestigations and studies to carry out the purposes of this article.\n  7. To hold hearings, to provide where appropriate for\ncross-interrogatories, subpoena witnesses, compel their attendance,\nadminister oaths, take the testimony of any person under oath, and in\nconnection therewith, to require the production for examination of any\nbooks or papers relating to any matter under investigation or in\nquestion before the division. The division may make rules as to the\nissuance of subpoenas which may be issued by the division at any stage\nof any investigation or proceeding before it.\n  In any such investigation or hearing, the commissioner, or an officer\nduly designated by the commissioner to conduct such investigation or\nhearing, may confer immunity in accordance with the provisions of\nsection 50.20 of the criminal procedure law.\n  8. To create such advisory councils, local, regional or state-wide, as\nin its judgment will aid in effectuating the purposes of this article\nand of section eleven of article one of the constitution of this state,\nand the division may empower them to study the problems of\ndiscrimination in all or specific fields of human relationships or in\nspecific instances of discrimination because of age, race, creed, color,\nnational origin, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression,\nmilitary status, sex, disability or marital status and make\nrecommendations to the division for the development of policies and\nprocedures in general and in specific instances. The advisory councils\nalso shall disseminate information about the division's activities to\norganizations and individuals in their localities. Such advisory\ncouncils shall be composed of representative citizens, serving without\npay, but with reimbursement for actual and necessary traveling expenses;\nand the division may make provision ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>