<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="296-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_296_D">
        <num>296-D</num>
        <heading>Unlawful discriminatory practices relating to non-employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 296-d. Unlawful discriminatory practices relating to non-employees.\nIt shall be an unlawful discriminatory practice for an employer to\npermit unlawful discrimination against non-employees in its workplace.\nAn employer may be held liable to a non-employee who is a contractor,\nsubcontractor, vendor, consultant or other person providing services\npursuant to a contract in the workplace or who is an employee of such\ncontractor, subcontractor, vendor, consultant or other person providing\nservices pursuant to a contract in the workplace, with respect to an\nunlawful discriminatory practice, when the employer, its agents or\nsupervisors knew or should have known that such non-employee was\nsubjected to an unlawful discriminatory practice in the employer's\nworkplace, and the employer failed to take immediate and appropriate\ncorrective action. In reviewing such cases involving non-employees, the\nextent of the employer's control and any other legal responsibility\nwhich the employer may have with respect to the conduct of the person\nwho engaged in the unlawful discriminatory practice shall be considered.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>