<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="296-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-296-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_296_A">
        <num>296-A</num>
        <heading>Unlawful discriminatory practices in relation to credit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_296_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an applicant or\nclass of applicants is denied credit in circumstances where other\napplicants of like overall credit worthiness are granted credit, or (ii)\nspecial requirements or conditions, such as requiring co-obligors or\nreapplication upon marriage, are imposed upon an applicant or class of\napplicants in circumstances where similar requirements or conditions are\nnot imposed upon other applicants of like overall credit worthiness.\n  3. It shall not be considered discriminatory if credit\ndifferentiations or decisions are based upon factually supportable,\nobjective differences in applicants' overall credit worthiness, which\nmay include reference to such factors as current income, assets and\nprior credit history of such applicants, as well as reference to any\nother relevant factually supportable data; provided, however, that no\ncreditor shall consider, in evaluating the credit worthiness of an\napplicant, aggregate statistics or assumptions relating to race, creed,\ncolor, national origin, citizenship or immigration status, sexual\norientation, gender identity or expression, military status, sex,\nmarital status, status as a victim of domestic violence or disability,\nor to the likelihood of any group of persons bearing or rearing\nchildren, or for that reason receiving diminished or interrupted income\nin the future.\n  3-a. It shall not be an unlawful discriminatory practice to consider\nage in determining credit worthiness when age has a demonstrable and\nstatistically sound relationship to a determination of credit\nworthiness.\n  4. a. If so requested by an applicant for credit, a creditor shall\nfurnish such applicant with a statement of the specific reasons for\nrejection of the applicant's application for credit.\n  b. If so requested in writing by an individual who is or was married,\na creditor or credit reporting bureau shall maintain in its records a\nseparate credit history for any such individual. Such separate history\nshall include all ob...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_296_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>impose a fine in an amount not to exceed ten thousand dollars for\neach violation, to be paid to the people of the state of New York;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_296_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>award compensatory damages to the person aggrieved by such\nviolation;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_296_A__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for a claim of sex discrimination only, award reasonable\nattorney's fees attributable to such claim to any prevailing party;\nprovided, however, that a prevailing respondent or defendant in order to\nrecover such reasonable attorney's fees must make a motion requesting\nsuch fees and show that the action or proceeding brought was frivolous.\nIn no case shall attorney's fees be awarded to the department, nor shall\nthe department be liable to a prevailing party for attorney's fees. In\norder to find the action or proceeding to be frivolous, the\nsuperintendent must find in writing one or more of the following:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_296_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the action or proceeding was commenced, used or continued in bad\nfaith, solely to delay or prolong the resolution of the litigation or to\nharass or maliciously injure another; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_296_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the action or proceeding was commenced or continued in bad faith\nwithout any reasonable basis and could not be supported by a good faith\nargument for an extension, modification or reversal of existing law. If\nthe action or proceeding was promptly discontinued when the party or\nattorney learned or should have learned that the action or proceeding\nlacked such a reasonable basis, the court may find that the party or the\nattorney did not act in bad faith.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_296_A__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>require the regulated creditor to cease and desist from such\nunlawful discriminatory practices;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_296_A__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>require the regulated creditor to take such further affirmative\naction as will effectuate the purposes of this section, including, but\nnot limited to, granting the credit which was the subject of the\ncomplaint.\n  d. Any complainant, respondent or other person aggrieved by any order\nor final determination of the superintendent may obtain judicial review\nthereof.\n  8. Where the superintendent makes a determination that a regulated\ncreditor has engaged in or is engaging in discriminatory practices, the\nsuperintendent is empowered to issue appropriate orders to such creditor\npursuant to the banking law. Such orders may be issued without the\nnecessity of a complaint being filed by an aggrieved person.\n  9. Whenever any creditor makes application to the superintendent of\nfinancial services to take any action requiring consideration by the\nsuperintendent of the public interest and the needs and convenience\nthereof, or requiring a finding that the financial responsibility,\nexpe...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>