<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-298-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-298-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="298-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-298-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-298-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-298-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-298-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_298_A">
        <num>298-A</num>
        <heading>Application of article to certain acts committed outside the state of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 298-a. Application of article to certain acts committed outside the\nstate of New York. 1. The provisions of this article shall apply as\nhereinafter provided to an act committed outside this state against a\nresident of this state or against a corporation organized under the laws\nof this state or authorized to do business in this state, if such act\nwould constitute an unlawful discriminatory practice if committed within\nthis state.\n  2. If a resident person or domestic corporation violates any provision\nof this article by virtue of the provisions of this section, this\narticle shall apply to such person or corporation in the same manner and\nto the same extent as such provisions would have applied had such act\nbeen committed within this state except that the penal provisions of\nsuch article shall not be applicable.\n  3. If a non-resident person or foreign corporation violates any\nprovision of this article by virtue of the provisions of this section,\nsuch person or corporation shall be prohibited from transacting any\nbusiness within this state. Except as otherwise provided in this\nsubdivision, the provisions of section two hundred ninety-seven of this\narticle governing the procedure for determining and processing unlawful\ndiscriminatory practices shall apply to violations defined by this\nsubdivision insofar as such provisions are or can be made applicable. If\nthe division of human rights has reason to believe that a non-resident\nperson or foreign corporation has committed or is about to commit\noutside of this state an act which if committed within this state would\nconstitute an unlawful discriminatory practice and that such act is in\nviolation of any provision of this article by virtue of the provisions\nof this section, it shall serve a copy of the complaint upon such person\nor corporation by personal service either within or without the state or\nby registered mail, return receipt requested, directed to such person or\ncorporation at his or her or its last known place of residence or\nbusiness, together with a notice requiring such person or corporation to\nappear at a hearing, specifying the time and place thereof, and to show\ncause why a cease and desist order should not be issued against such\nperson or corporation. If such person or corporation shall fail to\nappear at such hearing or does not show sufficient cause why such order\nshould not be issued, the division shall cause to be issued and served\nupon such person or corporation an order to cease or desist from the act\nor acts complained of. Failure to comply with any such order shall be\nfollowed by the issuance by the division of an order prohibiting such\nperson or corporation from transacting any business within this state. A\nperson or corporation who or which transacts business in this state in\nviolation of any such order is guilty of a class A misdemeanor. Any\norder issued pursuant to this subdivision may be vacated by the division\nupon satisfactory proof of compliance with such order. All orders issued\npursuant to this subdivision shall be subject to judicial review in the\nmanner prescribed by article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and\nrules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>