<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-320"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-320"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="320"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-320/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-320/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-320/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-320/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_320">
        <num>320</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and declaration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 320. Legislative findings and declaration. The legislature finds and\ndeclares that an institution embodying the heritage, ideals and concerns\nof the people of the state of New York for peace and social justice as\nexemplified by the philosophy and nonviolent leadership of Dr. Martin\nLuther King, Jr. is an appropriate response to the significant public\nneed for the state to develop methods in addition to current law\nenforcement responses to curb the use of violence and encourage the\nnonviolent management of social conflict.\n  It is further found and declared that people throughout the state fear\nviolence and deplore the social injustice that can give rise to\nviolence. New York state citizens are experiencing increasing racial and\ncultural hostilities stemming from rapid social change and real and\nperceived conflicts over group and individual interests and they may be\ndisadvantaged by a lack of problem-solving skills for redressing these\nsocial conflicts.\n  It is further found and declared that many potentially destructive\nconflicts between different societal groups and interests have been\nresolved constructively and effectively at the national, state and local\nlevel through the use of nonviolent methods as were advocated and\nexemplified by the life of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.\n  It is further found and declared there is a need to examine the\nhistory, nature, elements and future of nonviolent processes for\nconflict resolution, and to develop new techniques to promote\nnonviolence solutions to economic, political, social and cultural\nconflicts in the state. Such activities conducted through government,\nprivate enterprise, and voluntary associations can be strengthened by a\nstate institution devoted to research, education and training and the\nprovision of information services with respect to nonviolent conflict\nresolution techniques.\n  To accomplish these public purposes, it therefore is necessary that\nthe state of New York establish the New York state Martin Luther King,\nJr. institute for nonviolence to serve the citizens of the state and\ntheir government through education and training opportunities, basic and\napplied research opportunities, and information services, with respect\nto the promotion of nonviolent methods and techniques to resolve\nconflicts among individuals and groups of New York state citizens.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>