<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-322"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-322"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="322"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_322">
        <num>322</num>
        <heading>The New York state Martin Luther King, Jr</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_322__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A member of the state legislature appointed to the board shall\nserve for a single term not to exceed five years and shall serve as a\nmember only while he or she is a member of the legislature.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_322__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Of the six directors appointed by the governor who are not members\nof the legislature, three directors shall serve for terms of four years,\ntwo directors shall serve for terms of three years, and one director\nshall serve for a one year term. Thereafter, each director, except for a\ndirector appointed to fill an unexpired term, shall serve for a five\nyear term. No director may serve on the board for more than ten years.\n  2. In the event of a vacancy occurring in the office of a director by\ndeath, resignation or otherwise, the governor shall appoint a successor,\nwith the advice and consent of the New York state senate, to serve for\nthe balance of the unexpired term.\n  3. The board of directors shall provide for the holding of regular and\nspecial meetings. A majority of the directors shall constitute a quorum\nfor the transaction of any business and, unless a greater number is\nrequired by the by-laws of the corporation, the acts of a majority of\nthe directors present at a meeting at which a quorum is present shall be\ndeemed to be the acts of the board.\n  4. The board of directors shall adopt by-laws for the corporation and\nmay appoint such officers and employees as it deems advisable and may\nfix their compensation and prescribe their duties.\n  5. The directors appointed by the governor shall serve without salary,\nbut each director, including the chairperson shall be entitled to\nreimbursement for such director's reasonable actual and necessary\nexpenses incurred in the performance of his or her official duties, and\nexcept in the case of any director who serves as a member of the\nlegislature or serves in an ex officio capacity, a per diem allowance\nwhen rendering services as such director.\n  6. No member of the board of directors shall participate in a decision\non the awarding of any grant or contract to an individual or\norganization with whom such member is affiliated.\n  7. Directors other than the chancellor of the state university of New\nYo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>