<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-373"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-373"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="373"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-373/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-373/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-373/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-373/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_373">
        <num>373</num>
        <heading>Required immediate applicability of existing state codes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 373. Required immediate applicability of existing state codes.  1.\nThe state building construction code provided for in article eighteen of\nthis chapter, as added by chapter eight hundred of the laws of nineteen\nhundred fifty-one and the state building conservation and fire\nprevention code provided for in article eighteen-A of this chapter shall\nbe applicable from and after the first day of March, nineteen hundred\neighty-two in every local government that does not on such date have in\neffect a building or fire protection code. Said state building\nconstruction code and state building conservation and fire prevention\ncode shall also be applicable in every local government that on the\nfirst day of March, nineteen hundred eighty-two has a building or fire\nprevention code in effect but which prior to the first day of January,\nnineteen hundred eighty-four, repeals such code, provided, however, that\nin the case of any such repeal, the state building construction code and\nthe state building conservation and fire prevention code shall apply\nwithin such local government from and after the date of such repeal.\n  2. The secretary shall, within thirty days after the effective date of\nthis article, notify the elective or appointive chief executive officer\nor, if there be none, the chairman of the legislative body of each local\ngovernment and county of the provisions of this section.\n  3. The secretary shall, within ninety days after the effective date of\nthis article, promulgate regulations establishing minimum standards for\nadministration and enforcement of the state building construction code\nand the state building conservation and fire prevention code by local\ngovernments to which this section applies.\n  4. Within sixty days after the effective date of the regulations\nrequired by subdivision three of this section the elective or appointive\nchief executive officer of each local government to which this section\napplies shall report in writing to the executive or appointive chief\nexecutive officer or, if there be none, the chairman of the county\nlegislative body of the county in which the local government is\nsituated, the measures it has taken or contemplates taking for\nadministration and enforcement of the state building construction code\nand the state building conservation and fire prevention code.\n  5. Within one hundred twenty days after the effective date of the\nregulations required by subdivision three of this section the elective\nor appointive chief executive officer or, if there be none, the chairman\nof the county legislative body shall forward to the secretary the\nreports of the local governments required by subdivision four of this\nsection together with a report of the measures such county or local\ngovernment has taken or contemplates taking for administration and\nenforcement of the state building construction code and the state\nbuilding conservation and fire prevention code.\n  6. On and after the first day of March, nineteen hundred eighty-two,\nthe provisions of subdivisions three, four and five of section three\nhundred eighty-one of this article shall immediately apply to the\nadministration and enforcement of the state building construction code\nand the state building conservation and fire prevention code by every\nlocal government in which such codes have been made applicable pursuant\nto this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>