<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-375"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-375"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="375"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-375/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-375/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-375/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-375/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_375">
        <num>375</num>
        <heading>Powers of the council</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_375__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred\ntwenty-two-c of the general business law.\n  8. To examine, evaluate, and make recommendations concerning the\nstandardization of the uniform code and local building codes and permit\nprocesses for the purpose of facilitating and encouraging the\ninstallation and operation of solar and wind energy generating systems\nthroughout the state. For this purpose, the council is authorized to\nhold public hearings and consult with the solar and wind energy\ngenerating industry throughout the state. Any recommendations formulated\npursuant to this subdivision shall be submitted to the governor, the\nsecretary of state, the temporary president of the senate and the\nspeaker of the assembly along with such legislative proposals as the\ncouncil deems necessary to implement its recommendations.\n  9. To examine, evaluate, and make recommendations concerning the\nstandardization of the uniform code and local building codes and permit\nprocesses for the purpose of protection against the effects of sea level\nrise, flooding, saltwater corrosion, coastal or riparian erosion,\nstorms, and other degradation that may arise out of characteristics of\nthe coastal environment or structures located wholly or partially in a\nFederal Emergency Management Agency ("FEMA") designated</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_375__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Special\nFlood Hazard Area according to FEMA's current flood insurance rate maps,\nor (ii) a Moderate Risk Flood Hazard Area according to FEMA's current\nflood insurance rate maps. For this purpose, the council is authorized\nto hold public hearings and consult with relevant stakeholders\nthroughout the state. Any recommendations formulated pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be submitted to the governor, the secretary of state,\nthe temporary president of the senate and the speaker of the assembly\nalong with such legislative proposals as the council deems necessary to\nimplement its recommendations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>