<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-376"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-376"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="376"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-376/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-376/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-376/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-376/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_376">
        <num>376</num>
        <heading>Powers of the secretary</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 376. Powers of the secretary. The secretary is authorized and\nempowered: 1. To assign to the council such officers and employees of\nthe department as he may deem necessary from time to time to assist the\ncouncil in carrying out its functions and duties under this article.\n  2. To appoint experts, consultants, technical advisers and advisory\ncommittees for assistance and recommendations relative to the\nformulation and adoption of the uniform fire prevention and building\ncode and to assist the council and the secretary in carrying out the\npurposes of this article.\n  3. To authorize or provide for the testing and approval of materials,\ndevices and methods of construction.\n  4. To issue and to publish or cause to be published, including but not\nlimited to publication on the department's website, written\ninterpretations of the uniform code upon written request of a permit\napplicant or an official responsible for the administration and\nenforcement of the provisions of such code. Subsequent enforcement of\nsuch code shall be consistent with such written interpretations.\n  5. To do all things necessary or desirable to further and effectuate\nthe general purposes and specific objectives of this article.\n  6. To issue and to post or cause to be posted a document summarizing\nthe current requirements for swimming pools contained in the uniform\ncode, as such code may from time to time be amended, on the department's\nwebsite. Such document shall include reference to the fact that local\nlaws regarding fencing and other safety requirements for swimming pools\nmay be more restrictive than requirements for swimming pools contained\nin the uniform code.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>