<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-377"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-377"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="377"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-377/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-377/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-377/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-377/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_377">
        <num>377</num>
        <heading>New York state uniform fire prevention and building code</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 377. New York state uniform fire prevention and building code. 1.\nThe council shall formulate a uniform fire prevention and building code\nwhich shall take effect on the first day of January, nineteen hundred\neighty-four. The council may from time to time amend particular\nprovisions of the uniform code and shall periodically review the entire\ncode to assure that it effectuates the purposes of this article and the\nspecific objectives and standards hereinafter set forth. The secretary\nshall conduct public hearings on said uniform code and any amendment\nthereto. The secretary shall review such code or amendment, together\nwith any changes incorporated by the council as a result of such\nhearings, to insure that it effectuates the purposes of this article.\nUpon being so satisfied, the secretary shall approve said code or\namendment prior to its becoming effective.\n  2. The uniform fire prevention and building code shall:\n  a. provide reasonably uniform standards and requirements for\nconstruction and construction materials for public and private\nbuildings, including factory manufactured homes, consonant with accepted\nstandards of engineering and fire prevention practices;\n  b. formulate such standards and requirements, so far as may be\npracticable, in terms of performance objectives, so as to make adequate\nperformance for the use intended the test of acceptability;\n  c. permit to the fullest extent feasible, use of modern technical\nmethods, devices and improvements which tend to reduce the cost of\nconstruction without substantially affecting reasonable requirements for\nthe health, safety and security of the occupants or users of buildings;\n  d. encourage, so far as may be practicable, the standardization of\nconstruction practices, methods, equipment, material and techniques; and\n  e. eliminate restrictive, obsolete, conflicting and unnecessary\nbuilding regulations and requirements which tend to increase\nunnecessarily construction costs or retard unnecessarily the use of new\nmaterials, or provide unwarranted preferential treatment to types or\nclasses of material or products or methods of construction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>