<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-378"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-378"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-04-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="378"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-378/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-378/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-378/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-378/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_378">
        <num>378</num>
        <heading>Standards for New York state uniform fire prevention and building code</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be\ndeveloped to address future physical climate risk due to sea level rise,\nand/or storm surges and/or flooding, based on available data from\nnationally recognized sources or data produced by state agencies based\non nationally recognized procedures, analysis, and studies predicting\nthe likelihood of extreme weather events, including hazard risk analysis\ndata if applicable, and after consultation with the department of\nenvironmental conservation, and (ii) if appropriate, provide for regular\ninspection, and repair, as necessary, of the interior structural\nelements of buildings.\n  2. Standards for the condition, occupancy, maintenance, conservation,\nrehabilitation and renewal of certain existing buildings, structures and\npremises and for the safeguarding of life and property therein and\nthereabout from the hazards of fire, explosion or release of toxic gases\narising from the storage, handling or use of combustible or hazardous\nsubstances, materials or devices.\n  3. Standards for passenger elevators to promote uniformity and ease of\nuse for individuals with disabilities including, but not limited to:\n  a. placement and identification of operating controls,\n  b. door jamb markings,\n  c. operation and leveling features,\n  d. operation, width, and safety features for doors,\n  e. hall buttons, and\n  f. hall lanterns.\n  3-a. a. Standards for emergency planning and preparedness for\nhigh-rise buildings that address the needs of individuals with\ndisabilities which shall be developed in consultation with organizations\nthat advocate on behalf of individuals with disabilities to be\nidentified by the department of state in consultation with the office of\nthe chief disability officer.\n  b. The standards to be developed shall consider but not be limited to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>procedures for evacuating individuals with disabilities;\n  (ii) if it is necessary for the fire safety and emergency evacuation\nplan that the owner or the owner's agent shall establish and maintain to\ninclude a list of names and room numbers for individuals with\ndisabilities who have affirmatively notified the owner or the owner's\nagent that they are disabled, would require assistance in the event of\nan emergency and have requested that their names and room numbers be\nincluded in such list;\n  (iii) if it is necessary for the fire safety and emergency evacuation\nplan that the owner or the owner's agent shall establish and maintain to\ninclude a notification mechanism to the occupants that a list of\nindividuals with disabilities who would need assistance in case of an\nemergency may exist and is maintained by the owner or the owner's agent,\nthat such list would include only those individuals who have requested\ninclusion, that such list would be made available to building staff and\nmanagement as well as local law enforcement and fire safety personnel,\nand the method by which occupants can affirmatively place their name on\nsuch list;\n  (iv) if it is necessary for the fire safety and emergency evacuation\nplan that the owner or the owner's agent shall establish and maintain to\ninclude information on the location and type of evacuation assistance\ndevices or assistive technologies that are available within the\nbuilding; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if it is necessary for the fire safety and emergency evacuation\nplan that the owner or the owner's agent shall establish and maintain to\ncontain floor plans identifying the locations of accessible egress\nroutes, including areas of refuge and exterior areas for assisted care.\n  c. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, standards\ndeveloped pursuant to this subdivision shall specify that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it shall be the duty of every owner of a high-rise building, or of\nthe owner's agent, to establish and maintain a fire safety and emergency\nevacuation plan as provided for in this subdivision;\n  (ii) the owner or owner's agent shall make the fire safety and\nemergency evacuation plan available in the building for reference and\nreview by building management and staff, subject to paragraph h of this\nsubdivision, and by building occupants, provided that if any such plan\nis required to include a list of individuals with disabilities who have\naffirmatively notified the owner or the owner's agent that they are\ndisabled, would need assistance in the case of an emergency, and have\nrequested that their names and room numbers be included in such list,\nbuilding occupants shall not be given access to any such list of\nindividuals with disabilities and their room numbers;\n  (iii) copies of the fire safety and emergency evacuation plan shall be\nprovided to local law enforcement and fire safety personnel upon\nrequest; and\n  (iv) the fire safety and emergency evacuation plan shall be made\navailable in a large-print document (18-point font size or larger);\nBraille (Grade II); and/or any other alternative formats upon request,\nsubject to the limitations on dissemination to building occupants of any\nlist of individuals with disabilities and their room numbers contained\nin subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph.\n  d. A copy of the fire safety and emergency evacuation plan shall be\nmaintained at all times in a place easily accessible by law enforcement\nand/or fire safety personnel. Such a place may include but is not\nlimited to the management office, the security desk, in the vicinity of\nthe firefighter's elevator recall key, the life safety panel, or the\nfire pump room.\n  e. On an annual basis, every high-rise building owner or the agent of\nsuch owner shall update the fire safety and emergency evacuation plan\nand provide occupants with a notice detailing the pr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>this\nsubdivision shall not apply to hospitals as defined in subdivision one\nof section twenty-eight hundred one of the public health law, assisted\nliving residences licensed under article forty-six-B of the public\nhealth law, and adult care facilities licensed under article seven of\nthe social services law; and (ii) residential high-rise buildings whose\nunits are limited to households containing residents fifty years of age\nand older and that have implemented specialized evacuation plans in\nconsultation with local first responders may use those plans to satisfy\nthe requirements of this subdivision.\n  h. Any building management, building staff, local law enforcement and\nfire safety personnel who receive, as part of or in connection with a\nfire safety and emergency evacuation plan developed pursuant to this\nsubdivision, a list of individuals with disabilities who require\nassistance in the event of an emergency shall maintain the\nconfidentiality of the information in such list and shall use and\ndisclose it only for purposes permitted pursuant to this subdivision or\nany standards developed pursuant to this subdivision.\n  4. Standards for areas of public assembly requiring:\n  a. approved fire protection equipment and systems shall be installed;\n  b. interior finishes shall be of appropriate grade to materially\nretard the spread of smoke and flame, taking into consideration the fire\nprotection equipment and systems in place, and shall be maintained in\nthat condition;\n  c. no combustible material shall be placed in such amounts and\nlocations as would cause existing fire protection equipment and systems\nto be substantially overburdened, nor shall any material be placed in\nsuch manner as would cause safe exit to be significantly impeded; and\n  d. incorporation of the retroactivity provisions of article\neighteen-AA of this chapter.\n  e. for buildings included in group C5 of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\n900.2 of title nine of the official compilation of codes, rules and\nregulations of the state of New York, that water closets and urinals\nprovided for occupants, based upon capacity, shall be deemed sanitary\nfixtures and shall be distributed on a basis such that the number of\nsuch sanitary fixtures provided in rest facilities for men shall be\nequal to the number of water closets provided in rest facilities\nprovided for women in buildings with an occupancy of four hundred or\nless. For buildings consisting of more than four hundred occupants, an\nadditional water closet shall be added to a rest facility provided for\nwomen for each sanitary fixture added to a similarly situated rest\nfacility provided for men.\n  The standards shall include provisions for the type, number, spacing\nand location of fire protection equipment and systems, the\nclassification and maintenance of interior finishes, and the\naccumulation of materials.\n  5. Standards for hotels, motels and lodging houses, requiring that a\nnotice be posted in a prominent place in each guest room, including but\nnot limited to the following information:\n  a. location of nearest exits and fire alarms;\n  b. procedures to be followed when the fire or smoke detector gives\nwarning; and\n  c. procedures to be followed in the event of fire or smoke\ndevelopment.\n  5-a. Standards for installation of carbon monoxide detectors requiring\nthat every one or two-family dwelling, or any dwelling accommodation\nlocated in a building owned as a condominium or cooperative in the state\nor any multiple dwellings shall have installed an operable carbon\nmonoxide detector of such manufacture, design and installation standards\nas are established by the council. Carbon monoxide detectors required by\nthis section are required only where the dwelling unit has appliances,\ndevices or systems that may emit carbon monoxide or has an attached\ngarage. For purposes of this subdivision, multiple dwelling means a\nd...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"assistive listening\nsystem" shall mean situational-personal acoustic communication equipment\ndesigned to improve the transmission and auditory reception of sound;\nand\n  (ii) "place of public assembly" shall mean a facility which is open to\nthe public as a theater, meeting hall, hearing room, amphitheater,\nauditorium, or in any other similar capacity.\n  b. Standards for such systems shall be developed by the state fire\nprevention and building code council upon receiving recommendations from\nthe advisory board on assistive listening systems in places of public\nassembly.\n  c. The appropriate building code or ordinance shall designate such\nplaces of public assembly which shall be required to install such\nassistive listening systems.\n  11. Standards for buildings shall authorize the installation of\npotable water heaters for all domestic uses, including space heating.\n  * 12. a. Standards for bed and breakfast dwellings shall be\npromulgated for fire safety. Notwithstanding any other provision of this\narticle, for the purposes of this subdivision a "bed and breakfast\ndwelling" shall include an owner-occupied residence providing at least\nthree but not more than five rooms for temporary transient lodgers with\nsleeping accommodations and a meal in the forenoon of the day. Such\nstandards shall distinguish bed and breakfast dwellings from one and two\nfamily dwellings, provide specific options for hard-wired single-station\nsmoke detectors and provide a notice to each guest that contains:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the location of nearest exits and fire alarms;\n  (ii) procedures to be followed when fire or smoke detectors give\nwarning; and\n  (iii) procedures to be followed in the event of fire or smoke\ndevelopment.\n  b. Such standards shall also include egress design options to preserve\nthe aesthetic charm and historical significance of such dwellings that\nshall be limited to one of the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an automatic sprinkler head in the stairwell area of any means of\negress;\n  (ii) an external second floor egress; or\n  (iii) a portable escape device for each guest room.\n  c. The standards required by this subdivision shall be promulgated and\nimplemented not later than one hundred twenty days after the effective\ndate of this paragraph.\n  * NB There are 2 sub 12's\n  * 12. Standards for hospice residences, as defined in section four\nthousand two of the public health law, which shall be deemed to be\neither a single family dwelling or a two family dwelling for the\npurposes of local laws and ordinances relating to fire safety and\nbuilding construction standards.\n  * NB There are 2 sub 12's\n  13. Standards for the abandonment or removal of heating oil storage\ntanks and related piping in connection with the conversion of liquid\nfuel burning appliance to alternative fuel requiring:\n  a. The entire contents of the heating oil storage tank and related\npiping shall be emptied, cleaned and purged of all vapor. The contents\nof the storage tank and related piping shall be removed from the\npremises or property and disposed of in accordance with applicable\nlocal, state or federal rules and regulations;\n  b. If the heating oil storage tank is to be abandoned in place, the\nvent line shall remain open and intact, unless the tank is filled with\nan inert material. The oil fill pipe and other related piping shall\neither be removed, or the oil fill pipe shall be filled with concrete;\n  c. If the heating oil storage tank is to be removed, the vent line,\noil fill pipe and related piping shall also be removed, or the oil fill\npipe shall be filled with concrete;\n  d. An appropriate and qualified inspector, as determined by the local\ngovernment, shall cause an inspection to be made of the abandonment or\nremoval in connection with the conversion to determine conformity with\nthe uniform code; provide, however, that the local government official\nmay waive such in...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_378__subsec_i__subsec_2003">
            <num>(2003)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or\nany similar standard which may be approved by the council shall be\nexempt from the provisions of this subdivision and any swimming pool,\nother than a hot tub or spa, with an automatic power safety cover which\ncomplies with American Society of Testing and Materials International\nstandard F1346</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_378__subsec_i__subsec_2003">
            <num>(2003)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or any similar standard which may be approved by\nthe council shall be exempt from the provisions of paragraph b of this\nsubdivision.\n  d. temporary swimming pool enclosure shall be required to be replaced\nby a permanent enclosure which is in compliance with New York state\ncodes, regulations or local laws within ninety days from the issuance of\na local building permit or the commencement of the installation of an\nin-ground swimming pool, whichever is later. A local building department\nmay issue a waiver to allow an extension of such ninety day time period\nfor good cause including but not limited to adverse weather conditions\ndelaying construction.\n  15. Standards for temporary swimming pool enclosures used during the\ninstallation or construction of swimming pools requiring that any such\nenclosure shall sufficiently prevent any access to such swimming pool by\nany person not engaged in the installation or construction of such\nswimming pool and shall sufficiently provide for...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the repair, alteration, addition, relocation, or change of\noccupancy or use of such buildings; and\n  (ii) the installation or continued use and maintenance of fossil-fuel\nequipment and building systems, including as related to cooking\nequipment, in any such buildings.\n  c. In addition, in effectuating the provisions set forth in paragraph\na of this subdivision the code shall include exemptions for the purposes\nof allowing the installation and use of fossil-fuel equipment and\nbuilding systems where such systems are installed and used:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for generation of emergency back-up power and standby power\nsystems;\n  (ii) in a manufactured home as defined in subdivision seven of section\nsix hundred one of the executive law; or\n  (iii) in a building or part of a building that is used as a\nmanufacturing facility, commercial food establishment, laboratory, car\nwash, laundromat, hospital, other medical facility, critical\ninfrastructure, including but not limited to emergency management\nfacilities, wastewater treatment facilities, and water treatment and\npumping facilities, agricultural building, fuel cell system, or\ncrematorium, as such terms are defined by the code council.\n  d. Where the uniform code includes an allowed exemption pursuant to\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or (iii) of paragraph c of this subdivision, other than\nagricultural buildings as defined by the council, such exemption shall\ninclude provisions that, to the fullest extent feasible, limit the use\nof fossil-fuel equipment and building systems to the system and area of\nthe building for which a prohibition on fossil-fuel equipment and\nbuilding systems is infeasible; except with respect to servicing\nmanufacturing or industrial processes, require the area or service\nwithin a new building where fossil-fuel equipment and building systems\nare installed be electrification ready; and minimize emissions from the\nfossil-fuel equipment and building systems that are allowed to be used,\nprovided that such provisions do not adversely affect health, safety,\nsecurity, or fire protection. Financial considerations shall not be\nsufficient basis to determine physical or technical infeasibility.\n  e. Exemptions included in the uniform code pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be periodically reviewed by the code council to assure\nthat they continue to effectuate the purposes of paragraph a of this\nsubdivision and subparagraph three of paragraph b of subdivision two of\nsection three hundred seventy-one of this article to the fullest extent\nfeasible.\n  f. The code shall allow for exemption of a new building construction\nproject that requires an application for new or expanded electric\nservice, pursuant to subdivision one of section thirty-one of the public\nservice law and/or section twelve of the transportation corporations\nlaw, when electric service cannot be reasonably provided by the grid as\noperated by the local electric corporation or municipality pursuant to\nsubdivision one of section sixty-five of the public service law;\nprovided, however, that the public service commission shall determine\nreasonableness for purposes of this exemption. For the purposes of this\nparagraph, "grid" shall have the same meaning as electric plant, as\ndefined in subdivision twelv...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Fossil-fuel equipment and building systems" shall mean (A)\nequipment, as such term is defined in section 11-102 of the energy law,\nthat uses fossil-fuel for combustion; or (B) systems, other than items\nsupporting an industrial or commercial process as referred to in the\ndefinition of equipment in section 11-102 of the energy law, associated\nwith a building that will be used for or to support the supply,\ndistribution, or delivery of fossil-fuel for any purpose, other than for\nuse by motor vehicles.\n  (ii) "Electrification ready" means the new building or portion thereof\nwhere fossil-fuel equipment and building systems are allowed to be used\nwhich contains electrical systems and designs that provide sufficient\ncapacity for a future replacement of such fossil-fuel equipment and\nbuilding systems with electric-powered equipment, including but not\nlimited to sufficient space, drainage, electrical conductors or\nraceways, bus bar capacity, and overcurrent protective devices for such\nelectric-powered equipment.\n  20. a. Except as otherwise provided by statute, no change to the\nbuilding code shall become effective until at least ninety days after\nthe date on which notice of such change has been published in the state\nregister, unless the council finds that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an earlier effective date is necessary to protect health, safety\nand security; or\n  (ii) the change to the code will not impose any additional compliance\nrequirements on any person.\n  b. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph a of this subdivision,\nthe council may provide that, in the period during which changes to the\ncode have been adopted but are not yet effective pursuant to paragraph a\nof this subdivision, a person shall have the option of complying with\neither the provisions of the code as changed or with the code provisions\nas they were set forth immediately prior to the change.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>