<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="382-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_382_A">
        <num>382-A</num>
        <heading>Buildings with truss type construction; notice requirements and enforcement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 382-a. Buildings with truss type construction; notice requirements\nand enforcement. 1. All commercial and industrial structures that\nutilize truss type construction shall be marked by a sign or symbol in a\nmanner sufficient to warn persons conducting fire control and other\nemergency operations of the existence of truss construction in the\nstructure.\n  2. The council shall promulgate rules and regulations it deems\nnecessary to carry into effect the provisions of this section,\nincluding, but not limited to:\n  a. The dimensions and color of such sign or symbol;\n  b. The time within which commercial and industrial structures that\nutilize truss type construction shall be so marked; and\n  c. The location on each commercial and industrial structure that\nutilizes truss type construction where such sign or symbol should be\nposted.\n  3. The fee for producing the signs or symbols used to mark buildings\nwith truss type construction shall be fifty dollars, which cost shall be\nborne by the owner of such building.\n  4. Local governments shall provide by local law for the enforcement of\nthe provisions of this section. Local governments may provide for joint\nenforcement of the provisions of this section by agreement pursuant to\narticle five-G of the general municipal law.\n  5. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any city with a\npopulation of one million or more persons.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>