<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-01-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="382-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-382-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_382_B">
        <num>382-B</num>
        <heading>Residential buildings with truss type, pre-engineered wood or timber construction; notice requirements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 382-b. Residential buildings with truss type, pre-engineered wood or\ntimber construction; notice requirements. 1. a. Any person utilizing\ntruss type, pre-engineered wood or timber construction for the erection\nof any new residential structure, for any addition to an existing\nresidential structure, or for any rehabilitation of an existing\nresidential structure, shall, upon application for a building permit\nwith the local government having jurisdiction, include on the permit\napplication that truss type, pre-engineered wood or timber construction\nis being utilized.\n  b. The property owner or the property owner's representative shall\ncomplete a form prescribed by the council designating the structure as\ntruss type, pre-engineered wood or timber construction and file such\nform with the application for a building permit.\n  c. Upon receiving the application for a building permit and a form\ndesignating the structure as truss type, pre-engineered wood or timber\nconstruction, the local government having jurisdiction shall notify by\ncertified mail, facsimile, e-mail or other electronic means, the chief\nof the fire district, fire department or fire company having\njurisdiction over the structure to be erected, added to, or modified, or\nhis or her designee, that truss type, pre-engineered wood or timber\nconstruction is being utilized.\n  d. As a condition of the final receipt of a certificate of occupancy\nor certificate of completion, a sign or symbol designed and approved by\nthe council shall be affixed to any electric box attached to the\nexterior of the structure, if one exists.\n  e. The property owner or his or her representative shall be\nresponsible for maintaining the sign or symbol on the electric box of\nthe residence, as required by paragraph d of this subdivision, and shall\nreplace the sign or symbol when any changes or modifications are made to\nthe electric box or the sign or symbol is damaged.\n  2. a. The local building department or local code enforcement official\nhaving jurisdiction over the residential structure to be erected, added\nto, or modified, or his or her designee shall consult with the county\nfire coordinator, local 911 and emergency dispatchers, and the local\nfire protection provider or entity deemed pertinent to determine the\nmanner sufficient to warn persons conducting fire control and other\nemergency operations of the existence of truss type, pre-engineered wood\nor timber construction in the structure.\n  b. The chief of the fire district, fire department, or fire company\nhaving jurisdiction over the residential structure to be erected, added\nto, or modified, or his or her designee shall use the information\nprovided under subdivision one of this section to warn persons\nconducting fire control and other emergency operations of the existence\nof truss type, pre-engineered wood or timber construction in the\nstructure.\n  c. Nothing contained in this section shall in any way affect or\ndiminish section two hundred five-b of the general municipal law.\n  3. The council shall promulgate rules and regulations it deems\nnecessary to carry into effect the provisions of this section including,\nbut not limited to, the dimensions and color of such sign or symbol.\n  4. Local governments shall provide by local law or resolution for the\nenforcement of the provisions of this section, if necessary. Local\ngovernments may provide for joint enforcement of the provisions of this\nsection by agreement pursuant to article five-G of the general municipal\nlaw.\n  5. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any city with a\npopulation of one million or more persons.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>