<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-4-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-4-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-4-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-4-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-4-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-4-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_B">
        <num>4-B</num>
        <heading>Chief disability officer</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Persons with disabilities" shall mean any person who has a\ndisability as defined in subdivision twenty-one of section two hundred\nninety-two of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"State agency" or "state agencies" shall mean any state\ndepartment, board, bureau, division, commission, committee, public\nauthority, public corporation, council, office or other governmental\nentity performing a governmental or proprietary function for the state,\nexcept the judiciary or the state legislature.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The governor shall appoint a chief disability officer. The\nchief disability officer shall advise and assist state agencies in\ndeveloping policies designed to help meet the needs of persons with\ndisabilities.  The chief disability officer shall be appointed by the\ngovernor and receive a salary to be fixed by the governor within the\namounts appropriated therefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The chief disability officer shall:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be the state's coordinator\nfor the implementation of the Americans with Disabilities Act; (ii)\ncoordinate state activities to ensure that state programs do not\ndiscriminate against and are accessible to persons with disabilities;\n(iii) ensure that such programs provide services to individuals with\ndisabilities in the most integrated setting appropriate to their needs;\nand (iv) work with state agencies to develop legislation and potential\nregulatory changes to help effectuate the duties and responsibilities\nrequired in this article, and any other changes that may significantly\naffect the lives of persons with disabilities in the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The chief disability officer shall, to the extent practicable,\nreview and report to the governor upon proposed legislation and\nregulations. The chief disability officer shall submit comments, where\nappropriate, to the state agency which referred such proposed\nlegislation and regulations evaluating:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the impact of the proposed\nlegislation or regulation upon persons with disabilities; (ii) the\nrelationship and impact of such proposed legislation or regulation on\nexisting programs affecting persons with disabilities; and (iii) any\nmodifications that would help persons with disabilities or aid in the\nimplementation of the new proposal. All state agencies shall cooperate\nwith the chief disability officer to ensure that the chief disability\nofficer is able to fulfill the requirements under this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>