<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-400"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-400"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="400"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-400/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-400/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-400/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-400/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_400">
        <num>400</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and objectives</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 400. Legislative findings and objectives. The American flag is the\nsymbol of our country, of the ideals embodied in our constitution, and\nis the symbol of the spirit which should animate our institutions. It is\nthe emblem of freedom in its truest and best sense, signifying\ngovernment resting on the consent of governed; liberty regulated by law;\nthe protection of the weak against the strong; and security against the\nexercise of arbitrary power and as such it is recognized that the flag\nand all it symbolizes occasions deep emotional feeling in many people.\nBecause of the flag's significance as a symbol of our country, and the\nfeeling our citizens have toward it, the flag should not be a vehicle\nfor the expression of political, social or economic philosophy as some\ngroups and individuals have tried to use it.\n  Therefore, the legislature hereby finds and declares that the best\ninterests of the people of the state of New York will be served by\nenacting a comprehensive article setting forth rules for the display and\nuse of the American flag on and in public buildings within the state in\norder to give the flag the respect it is due and to lessen the\npossibility that the flag could be used to express political, social or\neconomic causes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>