<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-403-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-403-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-08-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="403-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-403-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-403-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-403-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-403-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_403_A">
        <num>403-A</num>
        <heading>Display of prisoner of war and missing in action flag</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 403-a. Display of prisoner of war and missing in action flag. 1.\nEvery county outside the city of New York, city, town, and village is\nencouraged to display the prisoner of war and missing in action flag at\nthe building housing its local legislative body on all days on which the\nflag of the United States of America is displayed. Every county outside\nthe city of New York, and every city, town, and village shall fly an\nofficial National League of Families POW/MIA flag, as designated by 36\nU.S.C. 902 at the building housing its local legislative body if a\ncongressionally chartered veterans organization including any post,\nchapter, detachment unit, auxiliary unit or society of such veterans\norganization has provided the county, city, town, or village with such\nflag and, upon such municipality's request, any necessary attachments or\nfasteners required to enable the flag to be visible to the public, on\nthe following days: Armed Forces Day, the third Saturday in May;\nMemorial Day, the last Monday in May; Flag Day, the second Sunday in\nJune; Independence Day, July 4; National POW/MIA Recognition Day, the\nthird Friday in September except if such date of commemoration cannot be\nobserved due to a religious holiday, such observances shall then be\nconducted on the second Friday in September and Veterans Day, November\n11.\n  2. Every state police facility, including but not limited to the\nheadquarters, substations, and training academy, is encouraged to\ndisplay the prisoner of war and missing in action flag on all days on\nwhich the flag of the United States of America is displayed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>