<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-412"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-412"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="412"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_412">
        <num>412</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 412. Definitions. As used in this article,\n  1. "Office" shall mean the office of children and family services\nestablished in the department of family assistance by chapter four\nhundred thirty-six of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-seven.\n  2. "Commissioner" shall mean the commissioner of children and family\nservices, designated as the head of the office of children and family\nservices by chapter four hundred thirty-six of the laws of nineteen\nhundred ninety-seven.\n  3. "Youth" shall mean any person under twenty-one years of age.\n  4. "Municipality" shall mean a county, or a city having a population\nof one million or more.\n  5. "Youth development program" shall mean a local program designed to\naccomplish the broad purposes of this article subject to the rules and\nregulations of the office; provided however, the term "youth development\nprogram" shall not include approved runaway programs or transitional\nindependent living support programs as such terms are defined in section\nfive hundred thirty-two-a of this chapter.\n  6. "State aid" shall mean payments by the state to a municipality for\nor toward the cost of establishment, operation and/or maintenance of\napproved youth programs in accordance with the provisions of this\narticle.\n  7. "Youth board" shall mean the citizen board of a youth bureau.\n  8. "Municipal youth bureau" shall mean either:\n  a. In a city having a population of one million or more, the New York\nCity department of youth and community development, or a successor\nentity;\n  b. A youth bureau that engages in activities, including, but not\nlimited to, the operation, administration or monitoring of youth\ndevelopment programs, throughout a particular county; or\n  c. A youth bureau that engages in activities, including, but not\nlimited to, the operation, administration or monitoring of youth\ndevelopment programs, throughout two or more particular counties, in\naccordance with subdivision five of section four hundred twenty-two of\nthis article.\n  9. "Local youth bureau" shall mean a youth bureau, not included within\nthe definition of municipal youth bureau pursuant to subdivision eight\nof this section, that engages in activities, including, but not limited\nto, the operation, administration or monitoring of youth development\nprograms, throughout a particular village, town or city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>