<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-420"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-420"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="420"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-420/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-420/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-420/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-420/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_420">
        <num>420</num>
        <heading>State aid</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>describe the need in the municipality for youth development\nprograms, and specify, at minimum, how the municipality will address the\nneed for youth development in villages, towns and cities which have a\nyouth population of twenty thousand or more persons;\n  (ii) detail how the municipality will allocate the funding it receives\npursuant to this subdivision, including an accounting of all of the\neligible entities within such municipality that will receive funding\nunder this subdivision, the youth development services that such\nentities will provide, and the amount of funding that each entity will\nreceive;\n  (iii) specify how the municipality will measure performance outcomes\nfor such services and programs covered under the plan;\n  (iv) specify the projected performance outcomes for services and\nprograms covered under the plan, including projected positive outcomes\nfor youth who participate in the services and programs; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide information on the performance outcomes of services\nprovided under the municipality's most recent plan approved pursuant to\nthis subdivision, including outcome based measures that demonstrate the\nquality of services provided and program effectiveness of programs\nfunded under such plan.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The office of children and family services may approve all or part\nof a municipality's comprehensive plan. If the office does not approve a\nmunicipality's comprehensive plan, such municipality shall have sixty\ndays from receipt of the notification of disapproval to submit a revised\nplan.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the municipality is seeking state aid to provide services for\nrunaway and homeless youth, as defined in article nineteen-H of this\nchapter, the runaway and homeless youth plan, as required by subdivision\ntwo of this section, shall be submitted as part of the comprehensive\nplan that is required pursuant to this paragraph; provided however, that\nstate aid to provide services for runaway and homeless youth services\nshall be from, and limited to, funds appropriated separately for such\nrunaway and homeless youth program purposes by the state, and shall not\nbe included under the limits set forth in this subdivision.\n  2. Runaway and homeless youth plan; state aid.\n  a.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A municipality may submit to the office of children and family\nservices a plan for the providing of services for runaway and homeless\nyouth, as defined in article nineteen-H of this chapter. Where such\nmunicipality is receiving state aid pursuant to paragraph a of\nsubdivision one of this section, such runaway and homeless youth plan\nshall be submitted as part of the comprehensive plan and shall be\nconsistent with the goals and objectives therein.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A runaway and homeless youth plan shall be developed in\nconsultation with the municipal youth bureau and the county or city\ndepartment of social services, shall be in accordance with the\nregulations of the office of children and family services, shall provide\nfor a coordinated range of services for runaway and homeless youth and\ntheir families including preventive, temporary shelter, transportation,\ncounseling, and other necessary assistance, and shall provide for the\ncoordination of all available county resources for runaway and homeless\nyouth and their families including services available through the\nmunicipal youth bureau, the county or city department of social\nservices, local boards of education, local drug and alcohol programs and\norganizations or programs which have past experience dealing with\nrunaway and homeless youth.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In its plan a municipality may:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>include provisions for transitional independent living support\nprograms and runaway and homeless youth crisis services programs as\nprovided in article nineteen-H of this chapter;\n  (ii) authorize services under article nineteen-H of this chapter to be\nprovided to homeless young adults, as such term is defined in section\nfive hundred thirty-two-a of this chapter;\n  (iii) authorize runaway and homeless youth to be served in accordance\nwith any of the following provisions of this chapter:\n  (A) paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section five hundred\nthirty-two-b;\n  (B) paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section five hundred\nthirty-two-d;\n  (C) paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section five hundred\nthirty-two-b;\n  (D) paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section five hundred\nthirty-two-d;\n  (E) to allow a youth under the age of sixteen to be served in a\ntransitional independent living support program pursuant to subparagraph\n(ii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section five hundred\nthirty-two-d; and\n  (iv) if a municipality provides shelter in accordance with items (C),\n(D) and (E) of clause (iii) of this subparagraph, then such municipality\nshall, within sixty days, notify the office of children and family\nservices in writing of the circumstances that made the provision of\nshelter necessary, efforts made by the program to find suitable\nalternative living arrangements for such youth, and the outcome of such\nefforts. If the office determines that such shelter was inappropriate,\nthe office may instruct the program on how to seek a more suitable\nalternative living arrangement.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such plan shall also provide for the designation and duties of the\nrunaway and homeless youth service coordinator defined in section five\nhundred thirty-two-a of this chapter who is available on a twenty-four\nhour basis and maintains information concerning available shelter space,\ntransportation and services.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such plan may include provision for the per diem reimbursement for\nresidential care of runaway and homeless youth in certified residential\nrunaway and homeless youth programs which are authorized agencies.\n  a-1. Each municipality that does not submit a runaway and homeless\nyouth plan in accordance with paragraph a of this subdivision, shall\ninclude within their comprehensive plan submitted pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section, an assessment of the need within the\nmunicipality for services to assist runaway and homeless youth and youth\nin need of crisis intervention or respite services. Provided however,\nthat state aid to provide for runaway and homeless youth services shall\nbe from and limited to funds appropriated separately for such runaway\nand homeless youth program purposes by the state, and shall not be\nincluded under the limits set forth in subdivision one of this section.\n  b. Each municipality shall submit to the office of children and family\nservices such...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A description of the current runaway and homeless population\nincluding their age, place of origin, family status, service needs and\neventual disposition;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A description of the public and private resources available to\nserve runaway and homeless youth within the municipality;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A description of new services to be provided and current services\nto be expanded.\n  c. The office of children and family services shall review such plan\nin accordance with subparagraph two of paragraph c of subdivision one of\nthis section and may approve or disapprove such plan or any part,\nprogram, or project within such plan, and may propose such modifications\nand conditions as deemed appropriate and necessary.\n  d.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Municipalities having an approved runaway and homeless youth\nplan pursuant to this subdivision shall be entitled to reimbursement by\nthe state for sixty percent of the entire amount of the expenditures for\nprograms contained in such plan as approved by the office of children\nand family services, after first deducting therefrom any federal or\nother state funds received or to be received on account thereof. All\nreimbursement pursuant to this subdivision shall be from and limited to\nfunds appropriated separately for such runaway and homeless youth\nprogram purposes by the state, and shall not be included under the\nlimits set in subdivision one of this section. A municipality's share of\nthe cost of such programs may be met in part by donated private funds or\nin-kind services, as defined by the office, provided that such private\nfunding or receipt of services shall not in the aggregate be more than\nfifty percent of such municipality's share.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_420__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law and subject to\nfunds appropriated separately therefor, a municipality having an\napproved runaway and homeless youth plan which includes provisions for\ntransitional independent living support programs shall be entitled to\nreimbursement by the state for sixty percent of the entire amount of the\napproved expenditures for transitional independent living support\nprograms contained in the plan as approved by the office of children and\nfamily services. The municipality's share of the cost of such programs\nmay be met by donated private funds or in-kind services, as defined by\nthe office, provided that such receipt of in-kind services shall not in\nthe aggregate be more than fifty percent of such municipality's share.\n  3. For the purpose of reimbursement by the state, administrative\nexpenses shall include compensation for personal services paid by a\nmunicipality, to any employee for the purpose of administering the\nbenefits provide...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>