<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-422"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-422"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="422"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-422/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-422/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-422/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-422/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_422">
        <num>422</num>
        <heading>Youth bureaus</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 422. Youth bureaus. 1. a. Any city, town or village desiring to\nestablish a local youth bureau may apply to the municipality which such\ncity, town or village is located within, for approval of its plans. The\napplication shall be in writing, specifying the nature of the program,\nand shall contain such information as the municipality shall require.\n  b. All local youth bureaus approved by the office of children and\nfamily services on or before April first, two thousand thirteen shall be\ndeemed approved local youth bureaus for the purpose of this article.\n  2. No application for the approval of a local youth bureau shall be\nconsidered by the municipality that has not been first approved by the\ngoverning body of the city, town or village making the application.\n  3. The municipality may approve or disapprove the proposed local youth\nbureau.\n  4. The approval of a local youth bureau shall authorize the city, town\nor village to establish, operate and maintain the program and will allow\nthe municipality to distribute to such local youth bureau, state aid\nreceived in accordance with subdivision one of section four hundred\ntwenty of this article.\n  5. Two or more municipalities may join together to establish, operate\nand maintain a municipal youth bureau and may make and perform\nagreements in connection therewith. Such agreements shall include\nprovisions for the proportionate cost to be borne by each municipality\nand for the manner of employment of personnel and may provide that a\nfiscal officer of one such municipality shall be the custodian of the\nmoneys made available for expenditure for such purposes by all such\nmunicipalities and that such fiscal officer may make payments therefrom\nupon audit of the appropriate auditing body or officer of his or her\nmunicipality. In making claims for state aid pursuant to subdivision one\nof section four hundred twenty of this article, each such municipality\nshall claim for its proportionate share of the total joint expenditures\nso made. However, where it is provided that there shall be a disbursing\nmunicipality, such disbursing municipality shall claim for the total\njoint program expenditures so made and shall disburse such state aid to\neach participating municipality based upon the proportionate share of\nexpenditures so made.\n  6. Notwithstanding any provision of law, rule or regulation to the\ncontrary, no municipal youth bureau serving one or more municipalities\nwith a total youth population of twenty-five thousand or less shall be\nrequired under this article, or for purposes of receiving state aid\nhereunder, to employ a full time executive director for their respective\nproposed or approved youth programs, as the case may be.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>