<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-423"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-423"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="423"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-423/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-423/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-423/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-423/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_423">
        <num>423</num>
        <heading>Grants; raising and paying over of local funds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 423. Grants; raising and paying over of local funds. 1. The office,\nwith the approval of the governor, may accept as agent of the state any\ngift or grant for any of the purposes of this article. Any moneys so\nreceived may be expended by the office to effectuate any of the purposes\nof this article, subject to the same limitations as to approval of\nproject, approval of expenditures and audit as are prescribed for state\nmoneys appropriated for the purposes of this article.\n  2. A board of education, board of trustees or trustee of a school\ndistrict may raise, appropriate and pay over to a municipality in which\nit is in whole or in part located moneys to be expended by such\nmunicipality for any purpose authorized by this article. Such a\nmunicipality may accept and expend moneys so received only for such\npurpose. Moneys so appropriated and paid over by a school district shall\nnot be included in computing the amount that should be apportioned to\nsuch school district pursuant to article seventy-three of the education\nlaw.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>