<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-436"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-436"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="436"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-436/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-436/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-436/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-436/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_436">
        <num>436</num>
        <heading>Hearings; immunity</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 436. Hearings; immunity.  1. A hearing upon any investigation or\nreview authorized by this article or by article fourteen-h of the\ngeneral municipal law may be conducted by two or more members of the\ncommission or by a hearing officer duly designated by the commission, as\nthe commission shall determine.\n  2. A person who has violated any provision of this article or article\nfourteen-h of the general municipal law, or of the rules and regulations\nof the commission, or any term of any license issued under said articles\nor said rules and regulations, is a competent witness against another\nperson so charged. In any hearing upon any investigation or review\nauthorized by this article or article fourteen-h of the general\nmunicipal law, for or relating to a violation of any provision of said\narticles or of the rules and regulations of the commission or of the\nterm of any such license, the commission, may confer immunity upon such\nwitness in accordance with the provisions of section 50.20 of the\ncriminal procedure law. Such immunity shall be conferred only upon the\nvote of at least three members of the commission, and only after\naffording the attorney general and the appropriate district attorney a\nreasonable opportunity to be heard with respect to any objections which\nthey or either of them may have to the granting of such immunity.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>