<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-48"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-48"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="48"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-48/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-48/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-48/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-48/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48">
        <num>48</num>
        <heading>General functions, powers and duties of office of welfare inspector general</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 48. General functions, powers and duties of office of welfare\ninspector general. The office of welfare inspector general, by and\nthrough the welfare inspector general, or his duly authorized deputy,\ndirector, assistant, officer or employee, shall have the following\nfunctions, powers and duties notwithstanding section one hundred\nthirty-six of the social services law:\n  1. To receive and investigate complaints from the public or any other\nsource concerning alleged abuses, suspected frauds, and other violations\nof the welfare system which shall be deemed to include medical\nassistance. As used in this article, the term "medical assistance" shall\nhave the same meaning contained in section three hundred sixty-five-a of\nthe social services law.\n  2. To receive complaints of alleged failures to prosecute frauds\nagainst the welfare system which shall be deemed to include medical\nassistance and to investigate the same.\n  3. To receive complaints of alleged failures to enforce the state's\nlaws regarding the employment of welfare recipients in available\nemployment, and to investigate the same.\n  4. To receive complaints of alleged failures of local officials and\nemployees to comply with state laws and regulations regarding welfare\nadministration which shall be deemed to include medical assistance, and\nto investigate the same.\n  5. On the initiative of the office and at the direction of the welfare\ninspector general, to conduct any investigation: of the operations of\nthe state social services department and local social services\ndistricts, the state health department and local health departments, and\nthe state department of mental hygiene and community mental health\nboards in order to insure proper expenditure of welfare funds; of\nviolations of the welfare system; of failure to prosecute welfare\nfrauds; of failure to enforce the state's laws regarding the employment\nof welfare recipients in available employment; of failure of local\nofficials and employees to comply with state law, rules, and regulations\nregarding welfare administration which shall be deemed to include\nmedical assistance, and other matters relating thereto.\n  6. To exercise and perform such other functions, powers and duties as\nmay from time to time be conferred or imposed by law.\n  7. To make an annual report to the governor, the comptroller and the\nlegislature concerning its work during the preceding year, and to make\nsuch further interim reports to them as they or any of them shall deem\nadvisable or require.\n  8. To conduct any inquiry pertinent or material to the discharge of\nthe functions, powers and duties imposed by law; and through designated\nmembers of the staff, to subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, take\ntestimony and compel the production of such books, papers, records and\ndocuments as may be relevant to any such inquiry and investigation.\n  9. To do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the\nfunctions, powers and duties set forth in this article, to the extent\nthey conform with applicable federal requirements, if any.\n  10. To make, amend or repeal such rules and regulations as may be\nnecessary with the approval of the state comptroller, for the\nperformance of the duties imposed hereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>