<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-483"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-483"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="483"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-483/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-483/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-483/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-483/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_483">
        <num>483</num>
        <heading>General functions, powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 483. General functions, powers and duties. The state office of rural\naffairs by and through the director or his duly authorized officers and\nemployees, shall have the following functions, powers and duties:\n  1. To serve as a clearinghouse and provide comprehensive information\nrelating to rural development and revitalization upon request to any\nagency, individual or corporation.\n  2. To advise and assist agencies, individuals and corporations in\nanswering particular rural revitalization and development needs;\nincluding cooperative efforts among such agencies, individuals, and\ncorporations to solve common problems or provide services in rural\nareas.\n  3. To receive notification from all state and federal agencies,\nindividuals or corporations engaged in rural development and\nrevitalization of program descriptions, appropriation data, and\napplication procedures. The office shall maintain a listing of existing\nprograms and advise local agencies, individuals or corporations of their\nexistence.\n  4. To assist, upon request, applicant local agencies, individuals or\ncorporations located in rural areas in obtaining timely and efficient\nresponses from state and federal agencies; to assist such applicants in\nconsideration of alternative program grant strategies; to assist state\nand federal agencies in cooperative approaches to address the needs of\nsuch applicants; and to provide technical assistance to agencies in\nformulating and implementing rural development and revitalization\nprograms.\n  5. To review application procedures formulated by state agencies and\nto recommend improvements designed to increase the cost-effectiveness of\nsuch procedures for rural revitalization and development efforts; and to\nenhance the probability such procedures will benefit rural areas.\n  6. To encourage the assistance of the private sector in effectuating\nrural development and revitalization.\n  7. To provide legal consultation concerning local government matters\nto officials of municipalities located in rural areas on a wide range of\nproblems and programs, including the exercise of home rule powers,\nreapportionment of local legislative bodies, drafting and revising of\nlocal laws including charters, and drafting and implementing of\nmunicipal cooperation agreements. All such assistance shall be advisory\nin nature, and shall not include the actual drafting of final legal\ndocuments or the provision of actual legal representation.\n  8. To assist the governor and the legislature in the integration and\nformulation of state rural development and revitalization policy and\nlong-range plans for rural areas and in answering needs related thereto.\n  9. To facilitate efforts of local agencies, individuals and\ncorporations in developing cooperative responses to rural needs.\nPersonnel of the office shall be available to participate in an advisory\ncapacity at local meetings exploring such cooperative agreements; and\nshall assist in the identification of appropriate state agencies and\npersonnel who may be instrumental in facilitating such efforts.\n  10. To provide legal advice and assistance concerning rural\ndevelopment and revitalization matters to officials of the executive\ndepartment and the legislature; and to analyze and make recommendations\nconcerning proposed new state legislation or programs that may affect\nrural areas.\n  11. To apply for and receive, consistent with appropriation,\nnotification, and approval requirements of the state finance law, grants\nor financial assistance from the federal government or other approved\nagencies, individuals or corporations.\n  12. To adopt such rules and regulations, procedures, instructions, and\nforms as are required to carry out the functions, powers and duties\nimposed upon the office by this article.\n  13. To assist the governor in coordinating the activities and services\nof those departments and agencies of the state having relationships with\nlocal rural agencies, individuals and corporations in order to provide\nmore effective service to them and to simplify state procedures relating\nthereto.\n  14. To keep the governor informed about the problems and needs of\nagencies, individuals and corporations that are involved with rural\ndevelopment and revitalization; and to assist in formulating policies\nwith respect thereto and utilizing the resources of the executive branch\nof the state government for the benefit of rural areas.\n  15. To refer local agencies, individuals and corporations to the\nappropriate departments and agencies of the state and federal\ngovernments for advice, assistance, and available services in connection\nwith particular rural development and revitalization problems or needs.\n  16. To develop pilot programs or projects and make studies and\nanalyses of the problems or needs of rural areas and to make the results\nthereof available for the benefit of such agencies as the director may\ndeem appropriate.\n  17. To encourage the expansion and improvement of in-service training\nopportunities and to make information available to officials of local\nagencies in rural areas on matters pertaining to rural development and\nrevitalization.\n  18. To consult with and cooperate with agencies and officers,\norganizations, groups, and individuals representing rural areas or doing\nrural development and revitalization in such manner as the director may\ndetermine will effectively carry out the functions, powers, and duties\nof the office.\n  19. To do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the\nfunctions, powers, and duties expressly set forth in this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>