<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-49"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-49"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="49"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-49/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-49/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-49/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-49/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49">
        <num>49</num>
        <heading>Cooperation and assistance of other agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 49. Cooperation and assistance of other agencies. The office of\nwelfare inspector general may request from any department, board,\nbureau, commission or other agency of the state and its political\nsubdivisions, and the same are authorized and directed to provide, such\ncooperation and assistance, services and data as will enable the office\nproperly to carry out its functions, powers and duties.  As an incident\nto rendering such cooperation and assistance, all governmental agencies\nshall be required to submit a written response to the office of welfare\ninspector general respecting its reports and findings when so requested\nby said office. Section one hundred thirty-six of the social services\nlaw shall in no way be construed to restrict any person or governmental\nbody from cooperating and assisting the welfare inspector general\nhereunder. Section six hundred ninety-seven or any other provision of\nthe tax law shall in no way be construed to restrict the office of\nwelfare inspector general from obtaining the name, address, social\nsecurity number, employment history and number of dependents claimed for\nany individual certified by the welfare inspector general, or his\ndesignee, to be a welfare recipient and suspected of abusing, defrauding\nor otherwise violating the welfare system.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>