<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-500"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-500"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="500"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-500/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-500/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-500/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-500/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_500">
        <num>500</num>
        <heading>Office of children and family services; commissioner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 500.  Office of children and family services; commissioner. 1. There\nis hereby continued in the department of family assistance an autonomous\noffice of children and family services. The head of such office shall be\nthe commissioner of children and family services, who shall be appointed\nby the governor, by and with the advice and consent of the senate, and\nshall serve at the pleasure of the governor. The commissioner may\nappoint such officers, employees, agents and consultants as he or she\nmay deem necessary, prescribe their duties, fix their compensation and\nprovide for reimbursement of their expenses within the amounts available\ntherefor by appropriation.\n  2. The commissioner may promulgate, adopt, amend or rescind rules and\nregulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this article,\nprovided, however, that such rules and regulations shall be strictly\nlimited in their application to the means and methods of compliance with\nthe provisions of this article.\n  3. Whenever the division for youth or its director is referred to in\nany provision of this chapter or in any other law, such reference shall\nbe deemed to refer to the office of children and family services or the\ncommissioner of children and family services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>