<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="501-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_501_H">
        <num>501-H</num>
        <heading>Detention and appointment of an attorney for the child in proceedings involving youth governed by the interstate compact for juveniles</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 501-h. Detention and appointment of an attorney for the child in\nproceedings involving youth governed by the interstate compact for\njuveniles. 1. If a youth is detained under the interstate compact for\njuveniles established pursuant to section five hundred one-e of this\narticle, he or she shall be brought before the appropriate court within\nseventy-two hours or the next day the court is in session, whichever is\nsooner, and shall be advised by the judge of his or her right to remain\nsilent, his or her right to be represented by counsel of his or her own\nchoosing, and of the right to have an attorney assigned in accord with,\nas applicable, section two hundred forty-nine of the family court act or\narticle eighteen-B of the county law. The youth shall be allowed a\nreasonable time to retain counsel, contact his or her parents or other\nperson or persons legally responsible for his or her care or an adult\nwith whom the youth has a significant connection, and the judge may\nadjourn the proceedings for such purposes. Provided, however, that\nnothing in this section shall be deemed to require a youth to contact\nhis or her parents or other person or persons legally responsible for\nhis or her care. Provided further, however, that counsel shall be\nassigned immediately, and continue to represent the youth until any\nretained counsel appears. The court shall schedule a court appearance\nfor the youth no later than ten days after the initial court appearance,\nand every ten days thereafter, while the youth is detained pursuant to\nthe interstate compact for juveniles unless any such appearance is\nwaived by the attorney for the child.\n  2. All youth subject to proceedings governed by the interstate compact\nfor juveniles established pursuant to section five hundred one-e of this\narticle shall be appointed an attorney pursuant to, as applicable,\nsection two hundred forty-nine of the family court act or article\neighteen-B of the county law if independent legal representation is not\navailable to such youth.\n  * NB Repealed September 1, 2030\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>