<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="501-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-501-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_501_E">
        <num>501-E</num>
        <heading>Interstate compact for juveniles</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 501-e. Interstate compact for juveniles. The interstate compact\nfor juveniles is hereby enacted into law and entered into with all other\njurisdictions legally joining therein in a form substantially as\nfollows:\n                  THE INTERSTATE COMPACT FOR JUVENILES\n                                ARTICLE I\n                                 PURPOSE\n  The compacting states to this interstate compact recognize that each\nstate is responsible for the proper supervision or return of juveniles,\ndelinquents and status offenders who are on probation or parole and who\nhave absconded, escaped or run away from supervision and control and in\nso doing have endangered their own safety and the safety of others. The\ncompacting states also recognize that each state is responsible for the\nsafe return of juveniles who have run away from home and in doing so\nhave left their state of residence. The compacting states also recognize\nthat congress, by enacting the Crime Control Act, 4 U.S.C. Section 112\n(1965), has authorized and encouraged compacts for cooperative efforts\nand mutual assistance in the prevention of crime. It is the purpose of\nthis compact, through means of joint and cooperative action among the\ncompacting states to:\n  A. ensure that the adjudicated juveniles and status offenders subject\nto this compact are provided adequate supervision and services in the\nreceiving state as ordered by the adjudicating judge or parole authority\nin the sending state;\n  B. ensure that the public safety interests of the citizens, including\nthe victims of juvenile offenders, in both the sending and receiving\nstates are adequately protected;\n  C. return juveniles who have run away, absconded or escaped from\nsupervision or control or have been accused of an offense to the state\nrequesting their return;\n  D. make contracts for the cooperative institutionalization in public\nfacilities in member states for delinquent youth needing special\nservices;\n  E. provide for the effective tracking and supervision of juveniles;\n  F. equitably allocate the costs, benefits and obligations of the\ncompacting states;\n  G. establish procedures to manage the movement between states of\njuvenile offenders released to the community under the jurisdiction of\ncourts, juvenile departments, or any other criminal or juvenile justice\nagency which has jurisdiction over juvenile offenders;\n  H. insure immediate notice to jurisdictions where defined offenders\nare authorized to travel or to relocate across state lines;\n  I. establish procedures to resolve pending charges (detainers) against\njuvenile offenders prior to transfer or release to the community under\nthe terms of this compact;\n  J. establish a system of uniform data collection on information\npertaining to juveniles subject to this compact that allows access by\nauthorized juvenile justice and criminal justice officials, and regular\nreporting of compact activities to heads of state executive, judicial,\nand legislative branches and juvenile and criminal justice\nadministrators;\n  K. monitor compliance with rules governing interstate movement of\njuveniles and initiate interventions to address and correct\nnoncompliance;\n  L. coordinate training and education regarding the regulation of\ninterstate movement of juveniles for officials involved in such\nactivity; and\n  M. coordinate the implementation and operation of the compact with the\ninterstate compact for the placement of children, the interstate compact\nfor adult offender supervision and other compacts affecting juveniles\nparticularly in those cases where concurrent or overlapping supervision\nissues arise.\n  It is the policy of the compacting states that the activities\nconducted by the interstate commission created herein are the formation\nof public policies and therefore are public business. Furthermore, the\ncompacting states shall cooperate and observe their individual and\ncollective duties and responsibilities for the prompt return and\nacceptance of juveniles subject to the provisions of this compact. The\nprovisions of this compact shall be reasonably and liberally construed\nto accomplish the purposes and policies of the compact.\n                               ARTICLE II\n                               DEFINITIONS\n  As used in this compact, unless the context clearly requires a\ndifferent construction:\n  A. "Bylaws" means those bylaws established by the interstate\ncommission for its governance, or for directing or controlling its\nactions or conduct;\n  B. "Compact administrator" means the individual in each compacting\nstate appointed pursuant to the terms of this compact, responsible for\nthe administration and management of the state's supervision and\ntransfer of juveniles subject to the terms of this compact, the rules\nadopted by the interstate commission and policies adopted by the state\ncouncil under this compact;\n  C. "Compacting state" means any state which has enacted the enabling\nlegislation for this compact;\n  D. "Commissioner" means the voting representative of each compacting\nstate appointed pursuant to article III of this compact;\n  E. "Court" means any court having jurisdiction over delinquent,\nneglected, or dependent children;\n  F. "Deputy compact administrator" means the individual, if any, in\neach compacting state appointed to act on behalf of a compact\nadministrator pursuant to the terms of this compact responsible for the\nadministration and management of the state's supervision and transfer of\njuveniles subject to the terms of this compact, the rules adopted by the\ninterstate commission and policies adopted by the state council under\nthis compact;\n  G. "Interstate commission" means the interstate commission for\njuveniles created by article III of this compact;\n  H. "Juvenile" means any person defined as a juvenile in any member\nstate or by the rules of the interstate commission, including any:\n  1. "accused delinquent" which means a person charged with an offense\nthat, if committed by an adult, would be a criminal offense;\n  2. "adjudicated delinquent" which means a person found to have\ncommitted an offense that, if committed by an adult, would be a criminal\noffense;\n  3. "accused status offender" which means a person charged with an\noffense that would not be a criminal offense if committed by an adult;\n  4. "adjudicated status offender" which means a person found to have\ncommitted an offense that would not be a criminal offense if committed\nby an adult; and\n  5. "non-offender" which means a person in need of supervision who has\nnot been accused or adjudicated a status offender or delinquent;\n  I. "Non-compacting state" means any state which has not enacted the\nenabling legislation for this compact;\n  J. "Probation" or "parole" means any kind of supervision or\nconditional release of juveniles authorized under the laws of the\ncompacting states;\n  K. "Rule" means a written statement by the interstate commission\npromulgated pursuant to article VI of this compact that is of general\napplicability, implements, interprets or prescribes a policy or\nprovision of the compact, or an organizational, procedural, or practical\nrequirement of the commission, and has the force and effect of statutory\nlaw in a compacting state, and includes the amendment, repeal, or\nsuspension of an existing rule; and\n  L. "State" means a state of the United States, the District of\nColumbia (or its designee), the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the U.S.\nVirgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Marianas Islands.\n                               ARTICLE III\n                   INTERSTATE COMMISSION FOR JUVENILES\n  A. The compacting states hereby create the "interstate commission for\njuveniles." The commission shall be a body corporate and joint agency of\nthe compacting states. The commission shall have all the\nresponsibilities, powers and duties set forth herein, and such\nadditional powers as may be conferred upon it by subsequent action of\nthe respective legislatures of the compacting states in accordance with\nthe terms of this compact.\n  B. The interstate commission shall consist of commissioners appointed\nby the appropriate appointing authority in each state pursuant to the\nrules and requirements of each compacting state and in consultation with\nthe state council for interstate juvenile supervision created hereunder.\nThe commissioner shall be the compact administrator, deputy compact\nadministrator or designee from that state who shall serve on the\ninterstate commission in such capacity under or pursuant to the\napplicable law of the compacting state.\n  C. In addition to the commissioners who are the voting representatives\nof each state, the interstate commission shall include individuals who\nare not commissioners, but who are members of interested organizations.\nSuch non-commissioner members must include a member of the national\norganizations of governors, legislators, state chief justices, attorneys\ngeneral, interstate compact for adult offender supervision, interstate\ncompact for the placement of children, juvenile justice and juvenile\ncorrections officials, and crime victims. All non-commissioner members\nof the interstate commission shall be ex-officio (non-voting) members.\nThe interstate commission may provide in its bylaws for such additional\nex-officio (non-voting) members, including members of other national\norganizations, in such numbers as shall be determined by the commission.\n  D. Each compacting state represented at any meeting of the commission\nis entitled to one vote. A majority of the compacting states shall\nconstitute a quorum for the transaction of business, unless a larger\nquorum is required by the bylaws of the interstate commission.\n  E. The commission shall meet at least once each calendar year. The\nchairperson may call additional meetings and, upon the request of a\nsimple majority of the comp</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>