<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="503-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_503_A">
        <num>503-A</num>
        <heading>Temporary hold over units</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 503-a. Temporary hold over units. 1. The division may establish\nsecure temporary hold over units at its facilities for the accommodation\nof youth placed with the division pursuant to article three of the\nfamily court act, who are being transported to a division facility or\nprogram, a court appearance or a home visit, where travel arrangements\nor the distance to be travelled requires such a holdover. No youth shall\nbe held in these units in excess of twenty-four hours unless emergency\nconditions, including illness of the youth or severe weather, prevent\ntravel.\n  2. Temporary hold over units may be established on a regional basis.\nContact between youth who are housed in a hold over unit and residents\nof the facility shall be minimal.  Youth staying in a temporary hold\nover unit shall be under supervision at all times. At least one staff on\nduty shall be of the same gender as the youth.\n  3. The temporary hold over units shall contain individual sleeping\nrooms, dining facilities and an area for recreation.\n  4. Juvenile offenders committed to the custody of the division shall\nnot be housed in temporary hold over units at any time. Notwithstanding\nany other law, the division shall have the authority to house any\nadjudicated youth placed with the division pursuant to article three of\nthe family court act, in a secure temporary hold over unit, subject to\nthe provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>