<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-04-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="503"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_503">
        <num>503</num>
        <heading>Detention</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_503__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The division shall promulgate regulations governing procedures for\ncertification of detention facilities and for renewal, suspension and\nrevocation of such certifications. Such regulations shall provide for a\nhearing prior to the suspension or revocation of a certification.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_503__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office of children and family services may suspend a\ncertification for good cause shown. Suspension shall mean that no\npersons coming within the provisions of article three or seven of the\nfamily court act and no alleged or convicted juvenile offender may be\nreceived for care in a detention facility, but persons already in care\nmay remain in care. The office may impose such conditions in the event\nof a suspension as it shall deem necessary and proper.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_503__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such office may revoke a certification for good cause shown.\nRevocation shall mean that no persons coming within the provisions of\narticle three or seven of the family court act and no alleged or\nconvicted juvenile offender may be received for care nor remain at the\ndetention facility.\n  6. The division shall be responsible for bringing violations of law\npertaining to detention of juveniles to the attention of each\nappropriate attorney for the child or counsel for the defendant who may\npetition for habeas corpus for persons aggrieved thereby.\n  7. The person in charge of each detention facility shall keep a record\nof all time spent in such facility for each youth in care. The detention\nfacility shall deliver a certified transcript of such record to the\noffice, social services district, or other agency taking custody of the\nyouth pursuant to article three or seven of the family court act,\nbefore, or at the same time as the youth is delivered to the office,\ndistrict or other agency, as is appropriate.\n  8. The division shall list all facilities certified for the detention\nof children and shall file a copy of that list periodically with the\nclerk of the family court in each county, the clerk of the criminal\ncourt of the city of New York, the clerk of the supreme court in each\ncounty within the city of New York and the clerk of the county court in\neach county outside the city of New York.\n  9. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the office of children\nand family services in consultation with the state commission of\ncorrection shall jointly regulate, certify, inspect and supervise\nspecialized secure detention facilities for adolescent offenders.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>