<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-519"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-519"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="519"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-519/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-519/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-519/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-519/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_519">
        <num>519</num>
        <heading>Persons authorized to visit division facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 519. Persons authorized to visit division facilities. 1.  The\nfollowing persons shall be authorized to visit at pleasure all\nfacilities operated by the division: the governor, lieutenant governor,\ncommissioner of general services, secretary of state, comptroller,\nattorney general, members of the legislature, judges of the court of\nappeals, supreme court, family court, and county courts, district\nattorneys, county attorneys, and any person or agency otherwise\nauthorized by statute.\n  2. The director of the division shall promulgate rules and regulations\nsetting forth the policy of the division regarding visitation of\ndivision facilities and residents therein by persons other than those\nlisted in subdivision one of this section. The overall security and\nuninterrupted operation of such facilities and the safety and well being\nof the staff and residents therein shall be given due consideration in\nthe formulation of these rules and regulations for visitation as\nnecessary to ensure such security, safety and facility operation.  Such\nregulations shall include provisions regarding reasonable and\nappropriate visitation by family members and consultation by the youth's\nlegal representative.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>