<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="523-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_523_I">
        <num>523-I</num>
        <heading>Conduct and scope of investigations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 523-i. Conduct and scope of investigations. The office of the\nombudsman may investigate grievances and complaints pertaining to youth\nresiding in facilities operated by the office brought to the attention\nof the office of the ombudsman from any source, and may in pursuing its\ninvestigation visit any facility operated by the office at any time,\nwithout prior notice. Facility directors and facility staff shall\ncooperate with the investigation. At an ombudsman's request, the staff\nof a facility shall inform the residents of the ombudsman's availability\non site or on premises. An ombudsman shall have access to any resident\non request, and the facility shall provide a suitable room, if so\nrequested, for private counseling. An ombudsman shall have the right to\ninspect the facility, visit all areas and observe all parts and aspects\nof the facility program. An ombudsman shall interview facility staff\nduring regular hours of employment whenever feasible. An ombudsman shall\nhave access to all books, records, logs, reports, memoranda and any and\nall other materials or written documents pertaining to office facilities\nin the possession of the office, or its facilities. An ombudsman may\ncopy or make reference to any such report, document, memorandum, log\nentry or other material or written document and, unless such item is\nconfidential pursuant to statute, may include a copy in his or her\nreport. Consistent with applicable laws and regulations, the\nconfidentiality of records and documents obtained must be maintained by\nthe office of the ombudsman.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>