<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="523-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_523_K">
        <num>523-K</num>
        <heading>Notification to the office of the ombudsman of youth's need for legal counsel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 523-k. Notification to the office of the ombudsman of youth's need\nfor legal counsel. 1. If informed that a youth residing in a facility\noperated by the office has been or is about to be arrested by a law\nenforcement official, the office of the ombudsman shall take steps to\nsee that the youth is provided with adequate legal representation.\n  2. When a youth residing in a facility operated by the office is to be\ninterrogated or interviewed by a law enforcement official concerning a\ncriminal act, or by any person concerning a civil or criminal matter, an\nombudsman may request to be present during such interrogation or\ninterview. Under no circumstances shall an ombudsman serve as the\nyouth's attorney or legal representative, and an ombudsman shall so\ninform the youth and the representatives of the youth, but if requested\nto do so, shall take steps to see that the youth is provided with legal\nrepresentation.\n  3. Whenever it appears to the office of the ombudsman that a youth\nresiding in a facility operated by the office is in need of legal\nservices, the office of the ombudsman may contact the youth's attorney\nor legal representative or assist the youth in making such contact.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>