<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="523-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-523-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_523_L">
        <num>523-L</num>
        <heading>Independent review board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 523-l. Independent review board. The independent review board shall\nconsist of fifteen members who are not employed by the office and who\nare knowledgeable in the areas of juvenile justice and youth rights. The\nmembers of such board shall be appointed by the commissioner. Each board\nmember shall be appointed for a term of three years, which term may be\nrenewed once. At least one member shall be a former resident or parent\nof a resident; at least one member shall be a psychologist or other\nclinician; at least one member shall be an individual knowledgeable of\njuvenile legal rights matters; at least one member shall be a judge of\nthe family court; and at least one member shall be knowledgeable of the\ncriminal justice system. Members shall be reimbursed for travel expenses\nincurred in the conduct of their duties. The board shall review the\noffice of the ombudsman reports and meet at least bimonthly with the\nombudsmen, the director, the commissioner and other appropriate\npersonnel to discuss the reports. The board is an advisory body and has\nno administrative duties. It shall advise the commissioner on matters\npertaining to the office of the ombudsman and on matters related to\ncomplaint and grievance resolution. The board shall have the authority\nto:\n  1. request the office of the ombudsman and/or the commissioner to\nconduct investigations;\n  2. make inquiries at the request of the director or the commissioner,\nor, on its own motion, into matters affecting the legal rights of youth\nresiding in facilities operated by the office;\n  3. convene meetings and communicate freely with the ombudsmen and the\noffice of the ombudsman;\n  4. evaluate the effectiveness of the office of the ombudsman and make\nnecessary inquiries to that end; and\n  5. visit office facilities and grounds and inspect records of the\noffice pertaining to such facilities. Laws and regulations governing the\nconfidentiality of records must be adhered to, and the general counsel\nfor the office should be notified concerning the records to be\ninspected. During any such visit to facilities or inspection of records,\nthe board members may speak with youth and facility staff.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>