<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-527-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-527-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="527-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-527-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-527-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-527-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-527-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_527_E">
        <num>527-E</num>
        <heading>New facility operation agreements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 527-e. New facility operation agreements. 1. The division is hereby\nauthorized to enter into new facility operation agreements with\nnot-for-profit corporations. Such agreements shall provide for the\noperation of a program by a not-for-profit corporation at a youth center\nconstructed by or on behalf of the division and to which the state holds\ntitle. Any not-for-profit corporation which seeks to operate such a\nprogram shall submit an application to the division in the manner\nprovided for in this title. In addition to any other requirements\nimposed pursuant to section five hundred twenty-seven-g of this title,\nany such agreement shall provide that the lease from the state to the\nnot-for-profit corporation shall provide that, in lieu of any periodic\nrental or lease payment for use of the facility, the not-for-profit\ncorporation shall continue to operate the program as approved for a\nperiod of time as approved by the division (not exceeding thirty years)\nand that the responsibility for the general maintenance and operation of\nthe facility shall be the responsibility of the not-for-profit\ncorporation.\n  2. At the request of a municipality, the division may enter into a new\nfacility operation agreement wherein the municipality operates a program\nat a youth center constructed by or on behalf of the division and to\nwhich the state holds title, or such program is operated by a\nnot-for-profit corporation, pursuant to a contract with the division or\na municipality.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>