<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-529-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-529-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="529-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-529-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-529-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-529-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-529-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_529_A">
        <num>529-A</num>
        <heading>Payment of costs for medical and dental services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 529-a. Payment of costs for medical and dental services. 1.\nDiagnoses, tests, studies or analyses for the diagnosis of a disease or\ndisability, and care and treatment by a hospital, as defined in article\ntwenty-eight of the public health law, or by a physician, or by a\ndentist to youths in division facilities shall be without cost or charge\nto the persons receiving such examinations, care or treatment.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nthe division may require reimbursement for costs paid pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section from any third party coverage or\nindemnification covering a youth placed with the division. Such third\nparty coverage or indemnification shall first be applied against the\ntotal cost to the hospital or other provider as established in\naccordance with the provisions of section twenty-eight hundred seven of\nthe public health law relating to rates of payment of an individual's\ncare and treatment, as provided therein.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to affect the\nresponsibility for support of children in the division as prescribed\npursuant to section five hundred twenty-eight of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>