<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-532-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-532-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="532-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-532-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-532-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-532-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-532-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_532_C">
        <num>532-C</num>
        <heading>Notice to parent; return of runaway youth to parent; alternative living arrangements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 532-c. Notice to parent; return of runaway youth to parent;\nalternative living arrangements. 1. The staff of a residential runaway\nand homeless youth crisis services program shall, to the maximum extent\npossible, preferably within twenty-four hours but within no more than\nseventy-two hours following the youth's admission into the program,\nnotify such runaway youth's parent, guardian or custodian of his or her\nphysical and emotional condition, and the circumstances surrounding the\nrunaway youth's presence at the program, unless there are compelling\ncircumstances why the parent, guardian or custodian should not be so\nnotified. Where such circumstances exist, the program director or his or\nher designee shall either file an appropriate petition in the family\ncourt, refer the youth to the local social services district, or in\ninstances where abuse or neglect is suspected, report such case pursuant\nto title six of article six of the social services law.\n  2. Where custody of the youth upon leaving the program is assumed by a\nrelative or other person, other than the parent or guardian, the staff\nof the program shall so notify the parent or guardian as soon as\npracticable after the release of the youth. The officers, directors or\nemployees of the program shall be immune from any civil or criminal\nliability for or arising out of the release of a runaway or homeless\nyouth to a relative or other responsible person other than a parent or\nguardian.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>