<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="534-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_534_K">
        <num>534-K</num>
        <heading>Regularization of longshore workers' employment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_534_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To encourage as far as practicable the regularization of the\nemployment of longshore workers;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_534_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To bring the number of eligible longshore workers more closely\ninto balance with the demand for longshore workers' services within the\nport of New York district in this state without reducing the number of\neligible longshore workers below that necessary to meet the requirements\nof longshore workers in the port of New York district in this state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_534_K__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To eliminate oppressive, unlawful, discriminatory, and corrupt\nhiring practices affecting longshore workers and waterborne commerce in\nthe port of New York district in this state; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_534_K__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To eliminate unlawful practices injurious to waterfront labor.\n  4. A longshore worker who has been removed from the longshore workers'\nregister pursuant to this section may seek reinstatement upon fulfilling\nthe same requirements as for initial inclusion in the longshore workers'\nregister, but not before the expiration of one year from the date of\nremoval, except that immediate reinstatement shall be made upon proper\nshowing that the registrant's failure to work or apply for work the\nminimum number of days above described was caused by the fact that the\nregistrant was engaged in the military service of the United States or\nwas incapacitated by ill health, physical injury, or other good cause.\n  5. Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, the commission\nshall at any time have the power to register longshore workers on a\ntemporary basis to meet special or emergency needs.\n  6. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, the\ncommission shall have the power to remove from the longshore workers'\nregister any person (including those persons registered as longshore\nworkers for less than nine months) who shall have failed to have worked\nas a longshore worker in the port of New York district for such minimum\nnumber of days during a period of time as shall have been established by\nthe commission. In administering this section, the commission, in its\ndiscretion, may count applications for employment as a longshore worker\nat an employment information center established under section five\nhundred thirty-four-o of this article as constituting actual work as a\nlongshore worker, provided, however, that the commission shall count as\nactual work the compensation received by any longshore worker pursuant\nto the guaranteed wage provisions of any collective bargaining agreement\nrelating to longshore workers. Prior to the commencement of any period\nof time established by the commission pursuant to this section, the\ncommission shall estab...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>