<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="534-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_534_P">
        <num>534-P</num>
        <heading>Implementation of telecommunications hiring system for longshore workers and checkers; registration of telecommunications system controller</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 534-p. Implementation of telecommunications hiring system for\nlongshore workers and checkers; registration of telecommunications\nsystem controller. 1. The commission may designate one of the employment\ninformation centers it is authorized to establish and maintain under\nsection five hundred thirty-four-o of this article for the\nimplementation of a telecommunications hiring system through which\nlongshore workers and checkers may be hired and accept employment\nwithout any personal appearance at said center. Any such\ntelecommunications hiring system shall incorporate hiring and seniority\nagreements between the employers of longshore workers and checkers and\nthe labor organization representing longshore workers and checkers in\nthe port of New York district in this state, provided said agreements\nare not in conflict with the provisions of the article.\n  2. The commission shall permit employees of the association\nrepresenting employers of longshore workers and checkers and of the\nlabor organization representing longshore workers and checkers in the\nport of New York district in this state, or of a joint board of such\nassociation and labor organization, to participate in the operation of\nsaid telecommunications hiring system, provided that any such employee\nis registered by the commission as a "telecommunications system\ncontroller" in accordance with the provisions, standards and grounds set\nforth in the act with respect to the registration of checkers. No person\nshall act as a "telecommunications system controller" unless that person\nis so registered. Any application for such registration and any\nregistration made or issued may be denied, revoked, or suspended, as the\ncase may be, only in the manner prescribed in section five hundred\nthirty-four-n of this article. Any and all such participation in the\noperation of said telecommunications hiring system shall be monitored by\nthe commission.\n  3. Any and all records, documents, tapes, discs and other data\ncompiled, collected or maintained by said association of employers,\nlabor organization and joint board of such association and labor\norganization pertaining to the telecommunications hiring system shall be\navailable for inspection, investigation and duplication by the\ncommission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>