<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="534-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_534_E">
        <num>534-E</num>
        <heading>Designation as agent of the state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 534-e. Designation as agent of the state. 1. The commission is\nhereby designated on its own behalf or as agent of the state of New\nYork, as provided by the act of Congress of the United States, effective\nJune sixth, one thousand nine hundred and thirty-three, entitled "An act\nto provide for the establishment of a national employment system and for\nco-operation with the States in the promotion of such system and for\nother purposes," as amended, for the purpose of obtaining such benefits\nof such act of Congress as are necessary or appropriate to the\nestablishment and operation of employment information centers authorized\nby this act.\n  2. The commission shall have all powers necessary to cooperate with\nappropriate officers or agencies of this state or the United States, to\ntake such steps, to formulate such plans, and to execute such projects\n(including but not limited to the establishment and operation of\nemployment information centers) as may be necessary to obtain such\nbenefits for the operations of the commission in accomplishing the\npurposes of this act.\n  3. Any officer or agency designated by this state pursuant to said act\nof June sixth, nineteen hundred thirty-three, as amended, is authorized\nand empowered, upon the request of the commission and subject to its\ndirection, to exercise the powers and duties conferred upon the\ncommission by the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>