<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-W"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-W"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="534-W"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_534_W">
        <num>534-W</num>
        <heading>Annual preparation of a budget request and assessments</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 534-w. Annual preparation of a budget request and assessments. 1.\nThe commission shall annually submit a budget request, which shall be\nsubmitted to the director of the budget in such form as the director may\nrequire.\n  2. After taking into account such funds as may be available, the\nbalance of the commission's budgeted expenses shall be assessed upon\nemployers of persons registered or licensed under this act. Each such\nemployer shall pay an assessment computed upon the gross payroll\npayments made by such employer to longshore workers, pier\nsuperintendents, hiring agents and security officers for work or labor\nperformed within the port of New York district in this state, at a rate,\nnot in excess of two per cent, computed by the commission in the\nfollowing manner: the commission shall annually estimate the gross\npayroll payments to be made by employers subject to assessment and shall\ncompute a rate thereon which will yield revenues sufficient to finance\nthe commission's budget for each year.  Such budget to be assessed upon\nemployers may include a reasonable amount not to exceed ten percent of\nthe total of all other items of expenditure contained therein, which\nshall be allocated to an applicable fund balance to be held in the\ncommission's employers assessment account.\n  3. The commission may provide by regulation for the collection and\nauditing of assessments. Such assessments shall be payable pursuant to\nsuch provisions for administration, collection and enforcement as the\nstate may provide by legislation. In addition to any other sanction\nprovided by law, the commission may revoke or suspend any license held\nby any person under this article, or the person's privilege of employing\npersons registered or licensed hereunder, for non-payment of any\nassessment when due.\n  4. The assessment pursuant to this section shall be in lieu of any\nother charge for the issuance of licenses to stevedores, pier\nsuperintendents, hiring agents and security officers or for the\nregistration of longshore workers or the use of an employment\ninformation center. The commission shall establish reasonable procedures\nfor the consideration of protests by affected employers concerning the\nestimates and computation of the rate of assessment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>