<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-Y"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-Y"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="534-Y"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_534_Y">
        <num>534-Y</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers, employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 534-y. Transfer of officers, employees. 1. Any officer or employee\nin the state, county or municipal civil service in either state who\nshall transfer to service with the commission may be given one or more\nleaves of absence without pay and may, before the expiration of such\nleave or leaves of absence, and without further examination or\nqualification, return to the person's former position or be certified by\nthe appropriate civil service agency for retransfer to a comparable\nposition in such state, county, or municipal civil service if such a\nposition is then available.\n  2. The commission may, by agreement with any federal agency from which\nany officer or employee may transfer to service with the commission,\nmake similar provision for the retransfer of such officer or employee to\nsuch federal agency.\n  3. Any officer or employee in the state, county or municipal service\nin New York state who shall transfer to service with the commission and\nwho is a member of the New York state and local retirement system, shall\ncontinue to have all rights, privileges, obligations and status with\nrespect to such system as provided under the retirement and social\nsecurity law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>