<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="534-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_534_O">
        <num>534-O</num>
        <heading>Employment information centers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 534-o. Employment information centers. 1. The commission shall\nestablish and maintain one or more employment information centers within\nthe port of New York district in this state at such locations as it may\ndetermine. No person shall, directly or indirectly, hire any person for\nwork as a longshore worker or security officer within the port of New\nYork district in this state, except through such particular employment\ninformation center or centers as may be prescribed by the commission. No\nperson shall accept any employment as a longshore worker or security\nofficer within the port of New York district in this state, except\nthrough such an employment information center. At each such employment\ninformation center the commission shall keep and exhibit the longshore\nworkers' register and any other records it shall determine to the end\nthat longshore workers and security officers shall have the maximum\ninformation as to available employment as such at any time within the\nport of New York district in this state and to the end that employers\nshall have an adequate opportunity to fill their requirements of\nregistered longshore workers and security officers at all times.\n  2. Every employer of longshore workers or security officers within the\nport of New York district in this state shall furnish such information\nas may be required by the rules and regulations prescribed by the\ncommission with regard to the name of each person hired as a longshore\nworker or security officer, the time and place of hiring, the time,\nplace and hours of work, and the compensation therefor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>