<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="534-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_534_C">
        <num>534-C</num>
        <heading>New York waterfront commission established</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 534-c. New York waterfront commission established. 1. There is\nhereby created the New York waterfront commission, which shall be in the\nexecutive department of this state and may request, receive, and utilize\nfacilities, resources and data of any department, division, board,\nbureau, commission, agency or public authority of the state or any\npolitical subdivision thereof as it may reasonably request to carry out\nproperly its powers and duties.\n  2. The commission shall consist of the commissioner appointed by the\ngovernor with the advice and consent of the senate, and shall receive\ncompensation to be fixed by the governor of this state. The term of\noffice of such commissioner shall be for three years; provided, however,\nthat a commissioner serving on the bi-state commission at the time of\nits dissolution on the seventeenth of July two thousand twenty-three who\nwas appointed by the governor of New York to such position, may serve as\nacting commissioner of the New York waterfront commission until such\ntime as a commissioner is appointed by the governor, with the advice and\nconsent of the senate, pursuant to this subdivision. A commissioner\nshall hold office until that commissioner's successor has been appointed\nand qualified. Vacancies in office shall be filled for the balance of\nthe unexpired term in the same manner as original appointments.\n  3. A commissioner may, by written instrument filed in the office of\nthe commission, designate any officer or employee of the commission to\nact in that commissioner's place. A vacancy in the office of a\ncommissioner shall not impair such designation until the vacancy shall\nhave been filled.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>