<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="534-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-534-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_534_N">
        <num>534-N</num>
        <heading>Hearings, determinations and review</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_534_N__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commission may temporarily suspend a permit, license or\nregistration pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision until\nfurther order of the commission or final disposition of the underlying\ncase, where the permittee, licensee or registrant has been indicted for,\nor otherwise charged with, a crime which is equivalent to a felony in\nthe state of New York or any crime punishable by death or imprisonment\nfor a term exceeding three hundred sixty-four days or where the\npermittee or licensee is a security officer who is charged by the\ncommission pursuant to this section with misappropriating any other\nperson's property at or on a pier or other waterfront terminal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_534_N__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the case of a permittee, licensee or registrant who has been\nindicted for, or otherwise charged with, a crime, the temporary\nsuspension shall terminate immediately upon acquittal or upon dismissal\nof the criminal charge, unless in the opinion of the commission the\ncontinuance of any such permit, license or registration is inimical to\nthe public peace or safety.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_534_N__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person whose permit, license or registration has been\ntemporarily suspended may, at any time, demand that the commission\nconduct a hearing as provided for in this section. Within sixty days of\nsuch demand, the commission shall commence the hearing and, within\nthirty days of receipt of the administrative judge's report and\nrecommendation, the commission shall render a final determination\nthereon; provided, however, that these time requirements, shall not\napply for any period of delay caused or requested by the permittee,\nlicensee or registrant. Upon failure of the commission to commence a\nhearing or render a determination within the time limits prescribed\nherein, the temporary suspension of the licensee or registrant shall\nimmediately terminate. Notwithstanding any other provision of this\nsubdivision, if a federal, state, or local law enforcement agency or\nprosecutor's office shall request the suspension or deferment of any\nhearing on the ground that such a hearing would obstruct or prejudice an\ninvestigation or prosecution, the commission may in its discretion,\npostpone or defer such hearing for a time certain or indefinitely. Any\naction by the commission to postpone a hearing shall be subject to\nimmediate judicial review as provided in subdivision seven of this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_534_N__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commission may in addition, within its discretion, bar any\npermittee, licensee or registrant whose license or registration has been\nsuspended pursuant to this section, from any employment by a licensed\nstevedore or a carrier of freight by water during the period of such\nsuspension, if the alleged crime that forms the basis of such suspension\ninvolves the possession with intent to distribute, sale, or distribution\nof a controlled dangerous substance (controlled substance), or\ncontrolled dangerous substance analog (controlled substance analog),\nracketeering or theft from a pier or waterfront terminal.\n  5. The commission, or such officer, employee or agent of the\ncommission as may be designated by the commission for such purpose,\nshall have the power to issue subpoenas to compel the attendance of\nwitnesses and the giving of testimony or production of other evidence\nand to administer oaths in connection with any such hearing. It shall be\nthe duty of the commission or of any officer, employee or agent of the\ncommission designated by the commission for such purpose to issue\nsubpoenas at the request of and upon behalf of the licensee, registrant\nor applicant. The commission or such person conducting the hearing shall\nnot be bound by common law or statutory rules of evidence or by\ntechnical or formal rules of procedure in the conduct of such hearing.\n  6. Upon the conclusion of the hearing, the commission shall take such\naction upon such findings and determination as it deems proper and shall\nexecute an order carrying such findings into effect. The action in the\ncase of an application for a license or registration shall be the\ngranting or denial thereof. The action in the case of a licensee shall\nbe revocation of the license or suspension thereof for a fixed period or\nreprimand or a dismissal of the charges. The action in the case of a\nregistered longshore worker shall be dismissal of the charges, reprimand\nor removal from the longshore work...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>