<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-54"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-54"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="54"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-54/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-54/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-54/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-54/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_54">
        <num>54</num>
        <heading>Powers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 54. Powers. The state inspector general shall have the power to:\n  1. subpoena and enforce the attendance of witnesses;\n  2. administer oaths or affirmations and examine witnesses under oath;\n  3. require the production of any books and papers deemed relevant or\nmaterial to any investigation, examination or review;\n  4. notwithstanding any law to the contrary, examine and copy or remove\ndocuments or records of any kind prepared, maintained or held by any\ncovered agency;\n  5. require any officer or employee in a covered agency to answer\nquestions concerning any matter related to the performance of his or her\nofficial duties. No statement or other evidence derived therefrom may be\nused against such officer or employee in any subsequent criminal\nprosecution other than for perjury or contempt arising from such\ntestimony. The refusal of any officer or employee to answer questions\nshall be cause for removal from office or employment or other\nappropriate penalty;\n  6. monitor the implementation by covered agencies of any\nrecommendations made by state inspector general;\n  7. perform any other functions that are necessary or appropriate to\nfulfill the duties and responsibilities of office.\n  * 8. Appoint an independent monitor to provide guidance and technical\nassistance related to the policies, practices, programs and decisions of\nthe Orange county industrial development agency, as authorized in\nsubdivisions two, three, four and five of section nine hundred twelve of\nthe general municipal law.\n  * NB Repealed May 3, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>