<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="548-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_548_G">
        <num>548-G</num>
        <heading>Evaluation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 548-g. Evaluation. 1. The committee shall conduct two evaluations of\nthe implementation and effectiveness of this article: a compilation of\nindividual project evaluations to be conducted in accordance with\ncriteria established in paragraph d of subdivision one of section five\nhundred forty-eight-f of this article; and a comprehensive neighborhood\nbased initiatives evaluation.\n  a. Individual project evaluations shall be conducted pursuant to the\nrequirements of this article and submitted to the committee for review.\nThe committee shall forward its comments and criticisms to the approved\nprojects with recommendations of strategies for remediation of project\ndeficiencies. Further, the committee shall compile the evaluations and\nthe required comments and recommendations into a single document and\nshall submit such compilation to the governor and the legislature by\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred ninety-two.\n  b. The committee shall cause to be prepared a comprehensive\nneighborhood based initiatives evaluation, which shall assess the\nefficacy and impact of the unified contract, the authorization relating\nto waiver of regulations, and the statutory exemptions on the delivery\nof services enacted by the legislature. In addition, the committee shall\nassess the extent to which the initiative has:\n  i. accomplished the goals and objectives to be reported to the\nlegislature;\n  ii. improved the coordination of program development and service\nprovision by the agencies participating on the committee; and\n  iii. reduced or eliminated duplicative and conflicting regulations.\n  2. The committee shall submit to the governor and the legislature an\ninterim report, which shall include a compilation of the goals and\nobjectives of the approved projects, and shall supplement such\ncompilation with a statement of goals and objectives that relate\nspecifically to the state's role in policy development, administration,\nand delivery of services to the targeted communities not later than\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred ninety-two.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>