<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="548-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_548_F">
        <num>548-F</num>
        <heading>Administration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 548-f. Administration. 1. Responsibilities of the department. a.\nUnless otherwise prescribed, the department or its designee shall be\nresponsible for the administration of the provisions of this article.\n  b. In consultation with the committee, the department shall develop\nand disseminate a request for proposals on a statewide basis, provided\nhowever that during state fiscal year nineteen hundred\nninety-ninety-one, the committee may limit the locations for\ndissemination of such request for proposals based on relevant\ndemographic data and such other factors as may be determined by the\ncommittee. Not less than thirty days prior to dissemination of such\nrequests for proposals in such state fiscal year, the department shall\nnotify the temporary president of the senate and the speaker of the\nassembly of such proposed locations and the criteria for selection.\n  c. Not less than thirty days prior to approving an application\npursuant to the provisions of this article, the committee, through the\ndepartment, shall notify the temporary president of the senate and the\nspeaker of the assembly of its intent to approve a project. Such\nnotification shall identify the recipient and state the proposed\nlocation, the estimated project cost and a brief description of the\nproject. Upon completion of its review of an application and not less\nthan thirty days after the notification as provide for in this\nparagraph, the committee shall approve or disapprove such application\nand the department shall notify the applicant of its decision.\n  d. The commissioner of the department and the other members of the\ncommittee shall enter into such agreements as shall be necessary to\ndelineate their respective roles regarding the cooperative provision of\nprogram funding and technical assistance, and the review and monitoring\nof projects.\n  e. The department shall provide assistance to approved projects to\ndevelop an evaluation methodology appropriate to the goals and\nobjectives of the projects.\n  2. Neighborhood based initiatives unified contract. a. The department\nshall enter into a neighborhood based initiatives unified contract with\neach applicant approved by the committee. The provisions of such\ncontract shall include, but not be limited to: a description of project\nservices and activities, the action plan, the allowable project costs,\nthe specific sources of funds that will support the approved costs,\nincluding state funds, local funds, other governmental funds, and all\nnongovernmental funds or revenues that are proposed to be used in\nsupport of all project costs, and the allocation of costs by funding\nsource.\n  b. The form of the neighborhood based initiatives unified contract\nshall be developed in consultation with the division of the budget and\nthe department of audit and control.\n  3. The comptroller is authorized pursuant to a certificate of\nallocation submitted by the division of the budget to interchange or\ntransfer from appropriations made to the agencies of the committee or\nany other appropriation, as appropriate, such amounts as may be required\nto fulfill the obligations of the state pursuant to neighborhood based\ninitiatives unified contracts to the department for payment of such\nobligations. The division of the budget shall provide the chairmen of\nthe senate finance committee and the assembly ways and means committee\nwith quarterly reports of all interchanges and transfers which occur\npursuant to this subdivision.\n  4. Allowable costs for each project shall include, but not be limited\nto costs reasonably incurred for:\n  a. preparation of the action plan required in section five hundred\nforty-eight-c of this article;\n  b. services as approved in the project application;\n  c. evaluation of the approved project;\n  d. administration, provided however in every case, the support of\nadministrative costs pursuant to the contract shall be not more than the\nmaximum percentage authorized for each source of funding or the total\nmaximum dollars allowed for administrative costs for each funding\nsource; and\n  e. minor renovations to existing structures, except that in no case\nshall the state support of such costs exceed either twenty-five percent\nof the project contract or fifty percent of the total renovation costs,\nwhichever is less.\n  5. Funding made available through the contract shall not be used to\nsupplant local or other funds.\n  6. Not more than forty percent of funds appropriated and made avail-\nable specifically for neighborhood based initiatives shall be used for\nany single project.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>