<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="548-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-548-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_548_C">
        <num>548-C</num>
        <heading>Neighborhood based initiatives project; services and activities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 548-c. Neighborhood based initiatives project; services and\nactivities. 1. Project establishment. Neighborhood based initiative\nprojects shall be established pursuant to this article. Each approved\nproject shall have as its primary components an action plan, the\ncreation of a council, and the provision of programs and services as\ndescribed in this section.\n  2. Programs and services. a. Projects shall provide for coordinated,\naccessible services, which shall include:\n  i. comprehensive crisis intervention services on a twenty-four\nhour-a-day basis which shall provide for information and referral\nservices and case management services, and may provide for mental health\nservices, alcohol and substance abuse services, child care services,\npreventive services, and other services as identified by the project, to\nindividuals and families who are experiencing an emergency due to\nhomelessness, eviction, domestic violence, child abuse, alcohol or drug\nabuse, mental illness, or other emergency situations identified by the\nproject; and/or\n  ii. comprehensive case management services to assist clients in\naccessing quality services and to expedite and ensure the receipt of\nsuch services. In addition, two or more needed services as determined by\nthe applicant and approved in the project application, such as services\nlisted in paragraph b of this subdivision, shall be provided.\n  b. Projects also may include any other specific local initiatives\nwhich may be necessary to assist in stabilizing and improving the\nneighborhood such as early intervention services, education, employment\nand training services, intensive home based prevention services,\nparenting education, comprehensive prenatal care, alcohol and substance\nabuse prevention, treatment, and aftercare services.\n  3. Strategic neighborhood action plan. The council for each approved\nproject shall identify and quantify neighborhood needs on both a short\nand long range basis. Such plan shall include the council's assessment\nof the neighborhood's present and long range needs for economic\ndevelopment, job development, housing, and such other improvements and\nneeds as may be identified by the project. Such plan also shall include\na description of the actions and resources necessary to meet the needs\nas identified in the plan over the next five year period.  The plan\nsubsequently shall be submitted to the committee for review and the\ncommittee shall provide assistance as prescribed in section five hundred\nforty-eight-e of this article to the council to help enable the project\nto achieve its goals.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>