<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-554"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-554"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="554"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-554/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-554/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-554/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-554/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_554">
        <num>554</num>
        <heading>Codes of conduct</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 554. Codes of conduct. 1. The justice center shall adopt and amend,\nas appropriate, codes of conduct for all custodians as defined in\nsubdivision two of section four hundred eighty-eight of the social\nservices law who have or will have regular and direct contact with\nvulnerable persons who reside in or receive services from such\nfacilities or provider agencies. Such codes shall govern the conduct of\nsuch custodians with respect to the safety, dignity and welfare of\nvulnerable persons to whom they provide care. The justice center shall\nestablish a process by which each custodian is provided with a copy of\nthe applicable code of conduct and is required, at the time of his or\nher initial employment, and at least annually thereafter, to acknowledge\nthat he or she has read and understands such code of conduct. Such\nprocess shall also provide for the enforcement of such codes consistent\nwith appropriate collective bargaining agreements.\n  2. Minimum requirements for codes of conduct. Such codes of conduct\nshall include, at a minimum: a. Provisions regarding the responsibility\nof such custodians to support the emotional, physical and personal\nwell-being of the vulnerable persons they serve, including their\nprotection from abuse and neglect, and to seek guidance and advice to\nresolve issues as needed when making decisions relating to the persons\nthey serve.\n  b. Provisions regarding the responsibility of such custodians to\nassist the vulnerable persons they support to direct the course of their\nown lives, honoring, where appropriate, their right to assume risk in a\nsafe manner and recognizing their potential for lifelong learning and\ngrowth.\n  c. Provisions regarding the responsibility of custodians to\nparticipate in available, appropriate training to maintain their\ncompetency and skill-level, and to model and shape the behavior of their\nco-workers.\n  d. Provisions regarding the responsibility of such custodians to\npromote and practice justice, fairness and equity for the vulnerable\npersons they support, uphold and respect their human and civil rights\nand respect their human dignity and uniqueness.\n  e. Provisions regarding the responsibility of such custodians to\nassist, where appropriate, the vulnerable persons they support in\ndeveloping and maintaining relationships with families, friends and the\ncommunity-at-large.\n  f. Provisions regarding the responsibility of such custodians to\nadvocate with and/or on behalf of the vulnerable persons they support\nfor their needs, interest, justice, inclusion and full community\nparticipation.\n  g. Provisions requiring such custodians to report reportable incidents\nas required in section four hundred ninety-one of the social services\nlaw.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>