<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-558"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-558"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="558"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-558/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-558/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-558/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-558/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_558">
        <num>558</num>
        <heading>Access to records and facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The justice center must\nbe granted access at any and all times to any facility or provider\nagency as defined in subdivision four of section four hundred\neighty-eight of the social services law, and, consistent with federal\nlaw, to all books, records, and data pertaining to any such facility or\nprovider agency deemed necessary for carrying out the justice center's\nfunctions, powers and duties. The justice center or any employee of the\njustice center designated by the executive director may require from the\nofficers or employees of such facility or provider agency or from the\ncommissioners of the state oversight agencies as defined in subdivision\nfour-a of such section four hundred eighty-eight of the social services\nlaw, any information deemed necessary for the purpose of carrying out\nthe justice center's functions, powers and duties, including otherwise\nconfidential information and such entities shall be required to provide\nsuch requested information. The executive director or any employee of\nthe justice center designated by the executive director may require from\nany hospital, as defined under article twenty-eight of the public health\nlaw, any information, report or record necessary for the purpose of\ncarrying out the functions, powers and duties of the justice center\nrelated to the investigation of deaths and complaints of abuse or\nneglect concerning vulnerable persons who have been treated at such\nhospitals, and from any adult care facility as defined in subdivision\ntwenty-one of section two of the social services law, such information,\nreport or record, including access to such facility necessary for the\npurpose of carrying out the functions, powers and duties of the justice\ncenter related to the investigation of deaths concerning patients of\nmental hygiene facilities who resided at such residential care\nfacilities at the time of their death or were former residents of such\nresidential care facilities and the justice center determines...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The governor shall designate an independent public or\nprivate agency, hereinafter "independent agency", to conduct and\ncoordinate the protection and advocacy and client assistance programs,\nas established by federal law to provide federal oversight of the\nstate's system of care for individuals with disabilities, as defined in\nfederal laws and to assist such persons with accessing vocational\nrehabilitation services. For purposes of this subdivision, individuals\nwith disabilities shall have the same meaning as provided by federal\nlaws.  The agency designated must have professional experience in\nempowering, protecting and advocating on behalf of individuals with\ndisabilities.  Such agency shall be independent of any agency that\nprovides treatment, services or rehabilitation to individuals covered by\nsuch protection and advocacy and client assistance programs. To the\nextent permitted by federal law, the independent agency shall be\ngoverned by a board, a majority of the members of which shall be\nindividuals with disabilities, parents, family members, guardians,\nadvocates, or authorized representatives of individuals with\ndisabilities.\n  (ii) The independent agency shall conduct and coordinate the\nprotection and advocacy and client assistance programs, as established\nby federal law to provide oversight of the state's system of care for\nindividuals with disabilities and to assist such individuals with\naccessing vocational and rehabilitation services, including but not\nlimited to:\n  (A) Providing information, referrals and technical assistance to\naddress the needs of individuals with disabilities;\n  (B) Pursuing legal, administrative and other appropriate remedies or\napproaches to ensure the protection of and advocacy for the rights of\nindividuals with disabilities;\n  (C) Investigating incidents of abuse and neglect of individuals with\ndisabilities if the incidents are reported to the independent agency or\nif there is probable cause to believe...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one\nand paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_y">
          <num>(y)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section four hundred ninety-six\nof the social services law.\n  (iv) All records and documents received by the independent agency\nshall be received subject to any confidentiality requirements applicable\npursuant to state and federal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The governor shall be authorized to re-designate the agency\nimplementing the protection and advocacy program and client assistance\nprograms only if there is good cause for the re-designation and in\naccordance with federal requirements.\n  (vi) The independent agency may assist in the development of\nresidential councils at facilities and programs.\n  (vii) To the extent consistent with federal law, the independent\nagency shall make copies of any of its reports available to the\ngovernor, the temporary president of the senate and the speaker of the\nassembly.\n  (viii) The independent agency shall take affirmative steps to assure\nthat its programs and services are geographically representative of the\nstate and, to the extent practicable, ensure regional access, and\nreflect the diversity of the state with respect to race and ethnicity.\n  * NB Effective upon filing the Governor's final notice of\nre-designation\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the exercise of its functions, powers and duties, the executive\ndirector and any employee designated by him or her is authorized to\nissue and enforce a subpoena and a subpoena duces tecum, conduct\nhearings, administer oaths and examine persons under oath, in accordance\nwith and pursuant to civil practice law and rules.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any case where a person in charge or control of such facility\nor an officer or employee thereof shall fail to comply with the\nprovisions of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_558__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, the justice center may\napply to the supreme court for an order directed to such person\nrequiring compliance therewith. Upon such application the court may\nissue such order as may be just and a failure to comply with the order\nof the court shall be a contempt of court and punishable as such.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>