<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-561"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-561"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="561"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-561/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-561/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-561/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-561/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_561">
        <num>561</num>
        <heading>Advisory council</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_561__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>members of boards of visitors appointed pursuant to articles seven\nand thirteen of the mental hygiene law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_561__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>consumer representatives, including current or former service\nrecipients of an applicable facility or provider agency;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_561__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>parents, relatives or guardians of such service recipients;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_561__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>providers of services to vulnerable persons;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_561__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>directors of facilities, community services or members of\ncommunity services boards;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_561__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>current and former consumers of services for individuals with\nphysical disabilities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_561__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>members of organizations that advocate on behalf of vulnerable\npersons and individuals with disabilities; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_561__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an employee of a facility or provider agency as defined in\nsubdivision four of section four hundred eighty-eight of the social\nservices law.\n  2. Members shall be appointed for terms of three years provided,\nhowever, that of the members first appointed, one-third shall be\nappointed for one-year terms and one-third shall be appointed for\ntwo-year terms. A member may be removed by the governor for good cause\nafter notice and an opportunity to be heard on the charges. Vacancies\nshall be filled in the same manner as original appointments for the\nremainder of any unexpired term.\n  3. The governor shall designate one member of the council as its chair\nto serve as such at the pleasure of the governor.\n  4. Council members shall not receive compensation, but each member\nshall be entitled to receive his or her reasonable and necessary\nexpenses incurred in connection with his or her services as a member\nwithin the amounts appropriated therefor.\n  5. The council shall have an executive secretary designated by the\nexecutive director of the justice center. The executive director may\nalso assign such other employees of the justice center as the council\nmay from time to time require to assist it in the performance of its\nduties.\n  6. The council shall advise and assist the justice center in\ndeveloping policies, proposed regulations, plans and programs to carry\nout its functions, powers and duties pursuant to this section. The\ncouncil may consider any matter related to improving the quality of life\nof citizens of the state who have disabilities and shall advise the\njustice center on any such matter.\n  7. The council shall meet at least four times a year. The council\nshall meet at the request of its chair or the executive director of the\njustice center.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>