<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-602"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-602"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="602"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_602">
        <num>602</num>
        <heading>Certification required</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 602. Certification required. 1. On and after July first, two\nthousand six, no person or business entity shall manufacture, including\nthe manufacture outside the state of New York for sale into the state of\nNew York, sell, install or service any manufactured home in the state of\nNew York, unless such person or business entity has obtained the\nappropriate certification from the department pursuant to this article.\n  2. On and after July first, two thousand six, no manufactured home\nshall be installed or serviced unless at least one person certified by\nthe department to perform such work is present at the home site during\nthe installation or service.\n  3. a. Each manufacturing plant that delivers or sells manufactured\nhomes in this state, each retail sales location and each business entity\nselling, installing or performing service on manufactured homes must be\nseparately certified.\n  b. Each manufacturer, retailer, installer and mechanic shall employ at\nleast one person who has been certified by the department.\n  4. Manufacturers approved to construct manufactured homes by the\nUnited States department of housing and urban development shall be\nrequired to apply for, and obtain, certification pursuant to this\narticle. Any such manufacturer shall be deemed to meet the requirements\nfor certification under this article, except that the department may,\nafter a hearing, suspend or revoke the certification of any manufacturer\nas provided in subdivision seven of section six hundred four of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>