<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-609"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-609"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-11-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="609"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-609/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-609/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-609/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-609/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_609">
        <num>609</num>
        <heading>State administrative agency requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_609__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A manufacturer or retailer of manufactured housing who\nviolates any of the provisions set forth in this section relating to\nmanufactured housing or rules adopted by the department, including\nprovisions of the New York state uniform fire prevention and building\ncode relating to manufactured housing, is subject to a civil penalty not\nto exceed the maximum civil penalty established by 24 C.F.R. ยง 3282.10,\nas then in effect, for each violation. Each violation constitutes a\nseparate violation with respect to each manufactured housing unit,\nexcept that the maximum civil penalty may not exceed the maximum civil\npenalty established by 24 C.F.R. ยง 3282.10, as then in effect, for any\nrelated series of violations occurring within one year from the date of\nthe first violation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_609__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An individual or a director, officer, or agent of a corporation or\na principal on a business entity who knowingly and willfully violates 42\nUSC 5409 in a manner which threatens the health or safety of any\npurchaser shall be fined not more than the maximum criminal penalty\nestablished by 24 C.F.R. ยง 3282.10, as then in effect, or imprisoned not\nmore than one year or both.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_609__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_609__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department may enforce the provisions of this article and\nmay impose civil penalties administratively;\n  (ii) Nothing in this article shall limit the powers and duties of the\nattorney general, as defined in section sixty-three of this chapter; and\n  (iii) Nothing in this article shall diminish or limit any other right\nor cause of action existing under any other provision of law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>