<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-611"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-611"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="611"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-611/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-611/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-611/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-611/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_611">
        <num>611</num>
        <heading>Manufactured housing advisory council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 611. Manufactured housing advisory council. 1. There is hereby\nestablished within the department a manufactured housing advisory\ncouncil. The advisory council shall consist of fifteen members to be\nappointed as follows:\n  a. Four members shall be appointed by the governor; one of whom shall\nbe a member, officer, or employee of an installer, one of whom shall be\na member, officer, or employee of a park residence advocacy association,\none of whom shall be a member, officer, or employee of a retailer, and\none of whom shall be a member, officer, or employee of a trade\nassociation representing the manufactured home industry.\n  b. Four members shall be appointed by the temporary president of the\nsenate; one of whom shall be a member, officer, or employee of a\nmanufacturer, one of whom shall be a member, officer, or employee of the\nengineering industry involved in manufactured housing issues, one of\nwhom shall be a member, officer, or employee of a consumer advocacy\nassociation involved in manufactured housing issues, and one of whom\nshall be a manufactured housing resident owner.\n  c. Four members shall be appointed by the speaker of the assembly; one\nof whom shall be a member, officer, or employee of a manufacturer, one\nof whom shall be a member, officer, or employee of the banking industry\ninvolved in manufactured housing issues, one of whom shall be a member,\nofficer, or employee of a consumer advocacy association involved in\nmanufactured housing issues, and one of whom shall be a manufactured\nhousing resident owner.\n  d. One member shall be appointed by the minority leader of the senate;\nwho shall be a manufactured home resident owner.\n  e. One member shall be appointed by the minority leader of the\nassembly; who shall be a manufactured home resident owner.\n  2. The secretary shall be a member of the advisory council and shall\nserve as chair to the council.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>