<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-629"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-629"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="629"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-629/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-629/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-629/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-629/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_629">
        <num>629</num>
        <heading>Judicial review</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 629. Judicial review. 1. Within fifteen days after receipt of the\ncopy of the report containing the final decision of the office, the\ncomptroller shall, if in his judgment the award is illegal or excessive,\nnotify the office of his conclusion, state the reasons for that\nconclusion, and provide specific recommendations for modification. Upon\nreceiving such notification, the office shall have fifteen days within\nwhich to review and either modify or re-affirm its award. If after such\nmodification or reaffirmation the comptroller continues to adjudge the\naward to be illegal or excessive, he may within fifteen days after\nreceipt of such modification or reaffirmation, commence a proceeding in\nthe appellate division of the supreme court, third department, to review\nthe decision of the office. Such proceeding shall be heard in a summary\nmanner and shall have precedence over all other civil cases in such\ncourt. Any claimant aggrieved by a final decision of the office may\ncommence a proceeding to review that decision pursuant to article\nseventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules.\n  2. Any such proceeding shall be commenced in accordance with the civil\npractice law and rules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>