<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-63"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-63"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="63"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-63/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-63/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-63/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-63/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_63">
        <num>63</num>
        <heading>General duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision two of section three hundred sixty-six of the social\nservices law.\n  12. Whenever any person shall engage in repeated fraudulent or illegal\nacts or otherwise demonstrate persistent fraud or illegality in the\ncarrying on, conducting or transaction of business, the attorney general\nmay apply, in the name of the people of the state of New York, to the\nsupreme court of the state of New York, on notice of five days, for an\norder enjoining the continuance of such business activity or of any\nfraudulent or illegal acts, directing restitution and damages and, in an\nappropriate case, cancelling any certificate filed under and by virtue\nof the provisions of section four hundred forty of the former penal law\nor section one hundred thirty of the general business law, and the court\nmay award the relief applied for or so much thereof as it may deem\nproper. The word "fraud" or "fraudulent" as used herein shall include\nany device, scheme or artifice to defraud and any deception,\nmisrepresentation, concealment, suppression, false pretense, false\npromise or unconscionable contractual provisions. The term "persistent\nfraud" or "illegality" as used herein shall include continuance or\ncarrying on of any fraudulent or illegal act or conduct. The term\n"repeated" as used herein shall include repetition of any separate and\ndistinct fraudulent or illegal act, or conduct which affects more than\none person. Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, all monies\nrecovered or obtained under this subdivision by a state agency or state\nofficial or employee acting in their official capacity shall be subject\nto subdivision eleven of section four of the state finance law.\n  In connection with any such application, the attorney general is\nauthorized to take proof and make a determination of the relevant facts\nand to issue subpoenas in accordance with the civil practice law and\nrules. Such authorization shall not abate or terminate by reason of any\naction or pr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, in resolving,\nby agreed judgment, stipulation, decree, agreement to settle, assurance\nof discontinuance or otherwise, any claim or cause of action, whether\nfiled or unfiled, actual or potential, and whether arising under common\nlaw, equity, or any provision of law, a state agency or a state official\nor employee acting in their official capacity shall not have the\nauthority to include or agree to include in such resolution any term or\ncondition that would provide the state agency, official, or employee,\ntheir agent or designee, the settling party, or any third party with\ncontrol or discretion over how any moneys to be paid by the settling\nparty would be used, spent, or allocated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall not apply to any provision\nin the resolution of a claim or cause of action providing</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>moneys to\nbe distributed to the federal government, to a local government, or to\nany holder of a bond or other debt instrument issued by the state, any\npublic authority, or any public benefit corporation;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>moneys to be\ndistributed solely or exclusively as a payment of damages or restitution\nto individuals or entities that were specifically injured or harmed by\nthe defendant's or settling party's conduct and that are identified in,\nor can be identified by the terms of, the relevant judgment,\nstipulation, decree, agreement to settle, assurance of discontinuance,\nor relevant instrument resolving the claim or cause of action;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nmoneys recovered or obtained by the attorney general where application\nof paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision is prohibited by federal law, rule,\nor regulation, or would result in the reduction or loss of federal funds\nor eligibility for federal benefits pursuant to federal law, rule, or\nregulation;</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>moneys recovered or obtained by or on behalf of a public\nauthority, a public benefit corporation, the department of taxation and\nfinance, the workers' compensation board, the New York state higher\neducation services corporation, the tobacco settlement financing\ncorporation, a state or local retirement system, an employee health\nbenefit program administered by the New York state department of civil\nservice, the Title IV-D child support fund, the lottery prize fund, the\nabandoned property fund, or an endowment of the state university of New\nYork or any unit thereof or any state agency, provided that all of the\nmoneys received or recovered are immediately transferred to the relevant\npublic authority, public benefit corporation, department, fund, program,\nor endowment;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>moneys to be refunded to an individual or entity as\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an overpayment of a tax, fine, penalty, fee, insurance premium, loan\npayment, charge or surcharge; (ii) a return of seized assets; or (iii) a\npayment made in error;</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>moneys to be used to prevent, abate, restore,\nmitigate or control any identifiable instance of prior or ongoing water,\nland or air pollution; and/or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>state moneys received as part of any\nstatewide opioid settlement agreements as defined in section 25.18 of\nthe mental hygiene law, to be spent on eligible expenditures as defined\nin section 25.18 of the mental hygiene law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where an agreed judgment, stipulation, decree, agreement to\nsettle, assurance of discontinuance or other legal instrument resolves\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any claim or any cause of action asserted by a state agency or a\nstate official or employee acting in their official capacity and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any\nclaim or cause of action asserted by one or more foreign jurisdictions\nor third parties, paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall only apply to\nthe resolution of the claim or cause of action asserted by the state\nagency, official, or employee.\n  17. The attorney general may investigate and prosecute every person or\nentity charged with the commission of a criminal offense in violation of\nthe laws of this state applicable to any crime that affects the title\nto, encumbrance of, or the possession of real property, including but\nnot limited to deed theft, larceny, criminal possession of stolen\nproperty, offering a false instrument for filing, falsifying business\nrecords, residential mortgage fraud, or scheme to defraud. In all such\nproceedings, the attorney general may appear in person or by the\nattorney general's deputy before any court of record or any grand jury\nand exercise all the powers and perform all the duties in respect of\nsuch actions or proceedings which the district attorney would otherwise\nbe authorized or required to exercise or perform. Nothing herein shall\nin any way abrogate, supersede, or interfere with the authority of the\ndistrict attorney of a county in which an offense occurs to investigate,\ninitiate and/or prosecute any such crime.\n  18. Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, in any civil\nenforcement action initiated by the attorney-general, neither the\nattorney-general nor the department of law has, or shall be deemed to\nhave, possession, custody, or control of, or the right, authority, or\npractical ability to obtain documents, communications, other\ninformation, or personnel of any agency, entity, or authority other than\nthe department of law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>