<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-64"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-64"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="64"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_64">
        <num>64</num>
        <heading>Costs recovered</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 64. Costs recovered. Costs recovered by the attorney-general may be\napplied by him in payment of the expenses incurred by him in the action\nor proceeding in which they are received, or of any expenditure which he\nis authorized to incur not otherwise provided for. He shall, at the\nclose of each fiscal year, render to the comptroller an account of such\ncosts received, with vouchers of such expenditures. During the fiscal\nyear, the comptroller is authorized to transfer any amount available\nwithin the account dedicated for this purpose to the general fund, upon\nthe request of the director of the budget. In the event insufficient\ncash remains in such account to meet expenditures against available\nappropriations from such account, the comptroller is authorized to\ntransfer the amounts necessary to meet such expenditures from the\ngeneral fund; provided however that in no event shall the cumulative\nvalue of any such transfers from the general fund made to such account\nwithin a single fiscal year exceed ten percent of the value of the\nappropriations made in such fiscal year from such account or the\ncumulative balance of transfers from the account to the general fund.\nThe comptroller shall establish such accounts and records as are\nnecessary to provide an accurate accounting and reporting of the\ntransfers to or from the general fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>