<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-642-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-642-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="642-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-642-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-642-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-642-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-642-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_642_A">
        <num>642-A</num>
        <heading>Fair treatment of child victims as witnesses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_642_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, (ii) or (iii) of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_642_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\none thousand twelve of the family court act, sexual abuse of a child or\nthe death of a child.\n  2. Whenever practicable, the same prosecutor should handle all aspects\nof a case involving an alleged child victim.\n  3. To minimize the time during which a child victim must endure the\nstress of his involvement in the proceedings, the court should take\nappropriate action to ensure a speedy trial in all proceedings involving\nan alleged child victim. In ruling on any motion or request for a delay\nor continuance of a proceeding involving an alleged child victim, the\ncourt should consider and give weight to any potential adverse impact\nthe delay or continuance may have on the well-being of the child.\n  4. The judge presiding should be sensitive to the psychological and\nemotional stress a child witness may undergo when testifying.\n  5. In accordance with the provisions of article sixty-five of the\ncriminal procedure law, when appropriate, a child witness as defined in\nsubdivision one of section 65.00 of such law should be permitted to\ntestify via live, two-way closed-circuit television.\n  6. In accordance with the provisions of section 190.32 of the criminal\nprocedure law, a person supportive of the "child witness" or "special\nwitness" as defined in such section should be permitted to be present\nand accessible to a child witness at all times during his testimony,\nalthough the person supportive of the child witness should not be\npermitted to influence the child's testimony.\n  7. A child witness should be permitted in the discretion of the court\nto use anatomically correct dolls and drawings during his testimony.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>