<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-646"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-646"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="646"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-646/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-646/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-646/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-646/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_646">
        <num>646</num>
        <heading>Police reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_646__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of section\n20.40 of the criminal procedure law. Said local law enforcement agency\nshall take a police report of the matter and provide the complainant\nwith a copy of such report free of charge.\n  3. An individual who has been the victim in this state of a family\noffense as defined in subdivision one of section 530.11 of the criminal\nprocedure law or section eight hundred twelve of the family court act\nmay, upon alleging that it would be a hardship for him or her to make\nsuch complaint in the local jurisdiction in which such offense occurred,\nmake a complaint to any local law enforcement agency in the state\nregardless of where the act took place. Such local law enforcement\nagency shall take a police report of the matter, as well as prepare a\ndomestic violence incident report as defined in subdivision fifteen of\nsection eight hundred thirty-seven of this chapter and provide the\ncomplainant with a copy of such report free of charge. A copy of the\npolice report and completed domestic violence incident report shall be\npromptly forwarded to the appropriate law enforcement agency with\njurisdiction over the location where the incident is reported to have\noccurred for the purposes of further investigation.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 646's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>