<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-648"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-648"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="648"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-648/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-648/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-648/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-648/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_648">
        <num>648</num>
        <heading>Review; report and implementation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 648. Review; report and implementation. 1. The chief administrator\nof the unified court system shall review court practices, procedures,\nservices, regulations and laws to determine the adequacy and\nappropriateness of its services with respect to crime victims, including\nvictims with special needs, particularly the elderly, disabled or\nvictims of child abuse, domestic violence, sex trafficking or\nsex-related offenses. Such review shall include reasonable opportunity\nfor public comment and consultation with crime victims or their\nrepresentatives, and may include public hearings.\n  2. After the review, and not later than two hundred seventy days after\nthe effective date of this section, and no later than two hundred\nseventy days after the effective date of the chapter of the laws of two\nthousand fifteen which amended this section, and every five years\nthereafter, the chief administrator of the unified court system shall\nsubmit a report to the governor and the legislature, setting forth the\nfindings of the review, including a description of the services provided\nby the components of the unified court system and recommendations for\nchanges in its procedures, services, regulations and laws to improve its\nservices to crime victims and to establish and implement fair treatment\nstandards for crime victims.\n  3. Subject to the direction of the chief administrator, the components\nof the unified court system shall expeditiously implement the\nrecommendations of its report.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>