<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-654"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-654"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="654"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-654/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-654/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-654/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-654/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_654">
        <num>654</num>
        <heading>Actions by other officers, departments, boards, commissions or agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 654. Actions by other officers, departments, boards, commissions or\nagencies.  a. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, any\nstate officer, department, board, commission or agency, shall, upon\nwritten request from the director, take such administrative or other\naction as is necessary to implement and administer the provisions of any\nbinding agreement between the state and one or more employee\norganizations representing state employees pursuant to the public\nemployees' fair employment act, as amended. Such action may include,\nwithout limitation, the adoption, repeal or amendment of rules,\nregulations or other procedures. Without prejudice to the rights of an\nemployee organization under such agreement, the opinion of the attorney\ngeneral shall be conclusive in resolving any disagreement between the\ndirector and any such officer, department, board, commission or agency\nregarding any legal question arising out of such a request, including,\nwithout limitation, whether the agreement is binding, whether compliance\nwith the request is necessary to implement or administer the agreement\nand whether compliance with the request is legally possible.\n  b. All state officers, departments, boards, commissions and agencies\nare authorized and directed to provide such other and further\nassistance, services and data as may be necessary to allow the director\nproperly to carry out his functions, powers and duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>