<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-70-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-70-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="70-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-70-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-70-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-70-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-70-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_70_A">
        <num>70-A</num>
        <heading>Statewide organized crime task force</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To conduct investigations and prosecutions of organized crime\nactivities carried on either between two or more counties of this state\nor between this state and another jurisdiction;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To cooperate with and assist district attorneys and other local\nlaw enforcement officials in their efforts against organized crime.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the governor and the\nattorney general may, and without civil service examination, jointly\nappoint and employ, fix his compensation, and at pleasure remove, a\ndeputy attorney general in charge of the organized crime task force. The\nattorney general may, and without civil service examination, appoint and\nemploy, and at pleasure remove, such assistant deputies, accountants and\nother persons as he deems necessary, determine their duties and, with\nthe approval of the governor, fix their compensation. The payments of\nsalaries and compensation of such officers and employees shall be in the\nsame manner as is prescribed in subdivision eight of section sixty-three\nof this chapter.\n  3. The deputy attorney general in charge of the organized crime task\nforce may request and shall receive from the division of state police,\nthe state department of taxation and finance, the state department of\nlabor, the temporary state commission of investigation, and from every\ndepartment, division, board, bureau, commission or other agency of the\nstate, or of any political subdivision thereof, cooperation and\nassistance in the performance of his duties. Such deputy attorney\ngeneral may provide technical and other assistance to any district\nattorney or other local law enforcement official requesting such\nassistance in the investigation or prosecution of organized crime cases.\n  4. The deputy attorney general in charge of the organized crime task\nforce is empowered to conduct hearings at any place within the state, to\nadminister oaths or affirmations, subpoena witnesses, compel their\nattendance, examine them under oath or affirmation, and require the\nproduction of any books, records, documents or other evidence he may\ndeem relevant or material to an investigation. He is empowered to apply\nf...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>