<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-711"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-711"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="711"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-711/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-711/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-711/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-711/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_711">
        <num>711</num>
        <heading>Reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 711. Reports. 1. On or before January thirty-first of each year, the\ndirector shall appear before and deliver a report to representatives of\neach house of the legislature. The temporary president of the senate and\nthe speaker of the assembly shall each appoint four members of their\nrespective houses, and the minority leader of each house shall each\nappoint one member, to hear the director's report. The appointed members\nmay hear the report in a joint meeting of the members of the senate and\nassembly or in separate meetings attended by the members from one house.\nThe chief information security officer of the state office of\ninformation technology services shall participate in such joint or\nseparate meetings to supplement the report delivered by the director.\nThe report shall provide information including, but not limited to: the\nstate's current threat level, imminent threats to New York state, the\nstate's current threat posture and collaborative efforts among\nlocalities, regions and with other states to prepare for and defend\nagainst acts of terrorism. The chief information security officer of the\nstate office of information technology services shall supplement the\nreport delivered by the director with information on the state's cyber\nsecurity infrastructure and cyber security resiliency efforts.\n  2. The commissioner shall appear and give testimony before the annual\nlegislative hearing on public protection held jointly by the assembly\ncommittee on ways and means and the senate finance committee as provided\nfor in section three of article VII of the New York state constitution\nand section thirty-one of the legislative law.\n  3. The director shall report to the temporary president of the senate,\nspeaker of the assembly and/or their designees within five days of an\nelevation of the state homeland security advisory system threat level as\nto the circumstances of the elevation.\n  4. Before the receipt of any report issued pursuant to this section,\neach recipient of such report shall develop confidentiality protocols in\nconsultation with the director which shall be binding upon the recipient\nwho issues the protocols and anyone to whom the recipient shows the\nreport, for the maintenance and use of such report so as to ensure the\nconfidentiality of all sensitive information contained therein,\nprovided, however, that such protocols shall not be binding upon a\nperson who is provided access to such report or any information\ncontained therein pursuant to section eighty-nine of the public officers\nlaw after a final determination that access to such report or any\ninformation contained therein could not be denied pursuant to\nsubdivision two of section eighty-seven of the public officers law. The\ndirector shall also develop protocols for his or her office related to\nthe maintenance and use of the report so as to ensure the\nconfidentiality of all sensitive information contained in the report. On\neach copy of written reports, the director shall prominently display the\nfollowing statement: "This report may contain information that if\ndisclosed could endanger the life or safety of the public, and\ntherefore, pursuant to section seven hundred eleven of the executive\nlaw, this report is to be maintained and used in a manner consistent\nwith protocols established to preserve the confidentiality of the\ninformation contained herein in a manner consistent with law."\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>