<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-717"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-717"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="717"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-717/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-717/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-717/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-717/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_717">
        <num>717</num>
        <heading>Office of interoperable and emergency communications</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 717. Office of interoperable and emergency communications. 1. The\noffice of interoperable and emergency communications shall be the\nprincipal state agency for all interoperable and emergency\ncommunications issues and oversee and direct the development,\ncoordination and implementation of policies, plans, standards, programs\nand services related to interoperable and emergency communications,\nincluding those related to public safety land mobile radio\ncommunications. The office shall coordinate with federal, state, local,\ntribal, non-governmental and other appropriate entities.\n  2. The office shall be responsible for coordinating relevant grant\nprograms and other funding sources to enhance interoperable and\nemergency communications, as consistent with the mission of the\ndivision. The director shall make final determinations regarding the\ndistribution of grants, in consultation with the board.\n  3. The director of this office shall serve as the statewide\ninteroperable and emergency communications coordinator.\n  4. To ensure appropriate coordination and consultation with relevant\nentities, the director shall be the chairperson of the statewide\ninteroperable and emergency communication board as defined in section\nthree hundred twenty-seven of the county law, and whose duties shall\ninclude, but not be limited to all the duties regularly assigned to the\nboard as defined by section three hundred twenty-eight of the county\nlaw.\n  5. The commissioner, in consultation with the director of the office,\nshall promulgate rules and regulations which require municipalities to\nreport, no less than annually, on prior and planned expenditures to\ndevelop and operate interoperable and emergency communications. The\nregulations shall permit municipalities which participate in county or\nmulti-county regional coordinated interoperability efforts to submit a\nsingle report to the division for all participating municipalities, so\nlong as all expenses which would have been reported if the participating\nmunicipalities had submitted individual reports are contained in the\ncombined report. The regulations shall not require a municipality that\nincurred no relevant expenses and anticipates no relevant expenses to\nsubmit such a report. The division shall include a summary of such\ninformation in its annual report to the governor, temporary president of\nthe senate, and speaker of the assembly provided for in subdivision\nseven of section seven hundred nine of this article, as well as\nsubmitting such information at the same time to the state comptroller.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>