<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-74"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-74"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="74"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-74/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-74/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-74/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-74/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_74">
        <num>74</num>
        <heading>Welfare inspector general</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_74__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to have full and unrestricted access to all records, reports,\naudits, reviews, documents, papers, recommendations or other material\navailable to the department of social services and local social services\ndistricts relating to programs and operations with respect to which the\ninspector has responsibilities under this section;\n  (ii) to make such investigations relating to the administration of the\nprograms and operations of the department of social services as are, in\nthe judgment of the inspector, necessary or desirable; and\n  (iii) to request such information, assistance and cooperation from any\nfederal, state or local governmental department, board, bureau,\ncommission, or other agency or unit thereof as may be necessary for\ncarrying out the duties and responsibilities enjoined upon him by this\nsection. State and local agencies or units thereof are hereby authorized\nand directed to provide such information, assistance and cooperation.\n  b. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule or regulation to\nthe contrary, no person shall prevent, seek to prevent, interfere with,\nobstruct or otherwise hinder any investigation being conducted pursuant\nto this section. Section one hundred thirty-six of the social services\nlaw shall in no way be construed to restrict any person or governmental\nbody from cooperating and assisting the inspector or his employees in\ncarrying out their duties under this section. Any violation of this\nparagraph shall constitute cause for suspension or removal from office\nor employment.\n  5. Establishment period. The governor shall nominate the initial\ninspector as soon as is practicable but in no event later than sixty\ndays after the effective date of this section.\n  6. Reports required of the inspector. The inspector shall, no later\nthan February first of each year submit to the governor, the state\ncomptroller, the attorney general and the legislature a report\nsummarizing the activities of the office during the pre...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_74__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a part of any ongoing investigation; or\n  (ii) specifically prohibited from disclosure by any other provision of\nlaw.\n  b. Notwithstanding paragraph a of this subdivision, any report under\nthis section may be disclosed to the public in a form which includes\ninformation with respect to a part of an ongoing criminal investigation\nif such information has been included in a public record.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>