<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-740"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-740"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="740"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-740/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-740/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-740/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-740/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_740">
        <num>740</num>
        <heading>State board of social welfare</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 740. State board of social welfare. 1. The state board of social\nwelfare is the legal authority established by the constitution\nresponsible for the inspection and visitation of certain institutions\nand certain agencies and for the making of rules and regulations with\nrespect to all of the functions, powers and duties with which the board\nis charged, subject to the control of the legislature and pursuant to\nthis article and other provisions of law.\nIt shall be the major purposes of the board to review, report and make\nrecommendation concerning the policies and programs pertaining to child\nand adult care, including the implementation of such policies and\nprograms and the quality of supervision exercised by the responsible\nstate and local supervisory agencies; to advise the governor and the\nlegislature with respect to such matters; to conduct independent\nresearch, studies and analyses of state policies and programs affecting\nchild and adult care; to advocate the improvement of such programs and\npolicies; and to conduct special research, studies and analyses, at the\nrequest of the governor, with respect to any matter related to human\nservices generally.\nThe board as constituted shall continue as a division of the executive\ndepartment.\n  2. The board shall consist of fifteen members appointed by the\ngovernor by and with the consent of the senate. At the expiration of the\nterm of any member of the board his successor shall be appointed for a\nterm of five years.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>