<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8">
        <num>8</num>
        <heading>Registration of noncitizens</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8. Registration of noncitizens. Whenever a state of war exists\nbetween the United States and a foreign country, or, in the judgment of\nthe governor public safety or necessity requires such action, the\ngovernor may, by proclamation, direct every subject or citizen of such\nforeign countries as the governor may designate in such proclamation,\nwho are in this state, or who may from time to time come into the state,\nto appear within twenty-four hours after the date specified in such\nproclamation or after arrival within the state, before such public\nauthorities as the governor may designate in such proclamation, and\npersonally register his or her name, residence, business, length of stay\nand such other information as the governor shall prescribe. Such\nproclamation shall be published in such newspapers as the governor may\ndesignate. Every person to whom such proclamation is applicable shall\nalso comply with such rules or personal identification as the governor\nshall from time to time prescribe. The occupant of every private\nresidence, and the owner, lessee or proprietor, operating or managing\nevery hotel, inn, boarding or rooming house shall, within twenty-four\nhours after the date specified in such proclamation, notify such public\nauthorities of the presence therein of every subject or citizen of a\nforeign country to whom such proclamation is applicable, and shall each\nday thereafter notify such public authorities of the arrival thereat or\ndeparture therefrom of every such subject or citizen. A failure to\ncomply with any such proclamation or to perform any act required by this\nsection shall be a misdemeanor, punishable by a fine of not exceeding\none thousand dollars, or imprisonment for one year or both.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>