<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-803"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-803"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="803"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-803/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-803/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-803/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-803/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_803">
        <num>803</num>
        <heading>Adirondack park agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 803. Adirondack park agency. There is hereby created in the\nexecutive department, the Adirondack park agency, which shall consist of\nthe following members: the commissioner of environmental conservation,\nthe secretary of state, the commissioner of commerce and eight members\nto be appointed by the governor by and with the advice and consent of\nthe senate. The governor shall designate a chairman from among the\nmembers appointed to the agency, who shall serve at the governor's\npleasure.  None of the members appointed by the governor shall be\nofficers or employees of any state department or agency.\n  Five members appointed by the governor shall be full-time residents\nwithin the Adirondack park provided, however, that no two such members\nshall be residents of the same county except for such members initially\nappointed before January first, nineteen hundred seventy-three, who may\nbe reappointed for additional successive terms. Three members appointed\nby the governor shall be residents of the state outside the Adirondack\npark. Not more than five appointed members shall be of the same\npolitical party.\n  All appointments shall be made for terms of four years; provided that\nthe first member appointed by the governor pursuant to the increase of\nmembers from seven to eight shall be appointed for a term expiring on\nthe thirtieth day of June, nineteen hundred seventy-six. Each of such\nappointed members of the agency shall hold office for the term for which\nhe was appointed and until his successor shall have been appointed and\nqualified or until he shall resign or be removed in the manner provided\nby law. In the case of any vacancy other than one arising by expiration\nof term, an appointment to fill the vacancy shall be made for the\nremainder of the unexpired term.\n  The designated chairman shall receive an annual salary of thirty\nthousand dollars. The other members of the agency, except those who\nserve ex officio, shall receive one hundred dollars per diem, not to\nexceed five thousand dollars per annum compensation for their services\nas members of the agency. All members, except those who serve ex\nofficio, shall be allowed the necessary and actual expenses incurred in\nthe performance of duties under this article.\n  A majority of the members of the agency shall constitute a quorum for\nthe transaction of any business or the exercise of any power or function\nof the agency and affirmative vote by a majority of the members of the\nagency, except as is otherwise specifically provided in this article,\nshall be required to exercise any power or function of the agency. Votes\nof any member shall be cast in person and not by proxy. The agency may\ndelegate to one or more of its members, officers, agents and employees,\nsuch powers and duties as it deems proper.\n  The commissioner of environmental conservation and the commissioner of\ncommerce and the secretary of state may, by official authority filed in\ntheir respective agencies, and with the Adirondack park agency,\ndesignate a deputy or other officer to exercise his powers and perform\nhis duties, including the right to vote, on the agency.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>