<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-805"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-805"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="805"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-805/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-805/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-805/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-805/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_805">
        <num>805</num>
        <heading>Adirondack park land use and development plan</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>completed and\nsubmitted to the agency a current and comprehensive inventory and\nanalysis of the natural resource, open space, public, economic and other\nland use factors as may reflect the relative development amenability and\nlimitations of the lands within its entire jurisdiction, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nformally adopted after public hearing a comprehensive master plan\nprepared pursuant to section two hundred seventy-two-a of the town law\nor section 7-722 of the village law, after public hearing thereon and\nupon an affirmative vote of a majority of its members. If the agency\ngrants the amendment request in part, it shall not enter or file the\namendment or amendments for a period of sixty days thereafter, during\nwhich time the legislative body of the local government may withdraw its\nrequest.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any amendment to clarify the boundaries of the land use areas as\nshown on the plan map, to correct any errors on the map or effect other\ntechnical changes on the map, upon an affirmative vote of a majority of\nits members and without a public hearing thereon, unless the agency\ndetermines that a public hearing is appropriate, on its own motion or at\nthe request of the legislative body of a local government or at the\nrequest of any owner of record of the land involved.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before making any plan map amendment, except pursuant to\nsubparagraph four of this paragraph, the agency must find that the\nreclassification would accurately reflect the legislative findings and\npurposes of section eight hundred one of this article and would be\nconsistent with the land use and development plan, including the\ncharacter description and purposes, policies and objectives of the land\nuse area to which reclassification is proposed, taking into account such\nexisting natural resource, open space, public, economic and other land\nuse factors and any comprehensive master plans adopted pursuant to the\ntown or village law, as may reflect the relative development amenability\nand limitations of the land in question. The agency's determination\nshall be consistent with and reflect the regional nature of the land use\nand development plan and the regional scale and approach used in its\npreparation.\n  d. The agency may, after consultation with the Adirondack park local\ngove...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the chairman of the planning board, if any, and the clerk of each\nlocal government, and the chairman of the county planning agency, if\nany, and the clerk of each county, wholly or partially within the park;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the chairman of each regional planning agency whose jurisdiction\nis wholly or partially within the park; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the Adirondack park local government review board.\n  c. Hamlet areas.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character description. Hamlet areas, delineated\nin brown on the plan map, range from large, varied communities that\ncontain a sizeable permanent, seasonal and transient populations with a\ngreat diversity of residential, commercial, tourist and industrial\ndevelopment and a high level of public services and facilities, to\nsmaller, less varied communities with a lesser degree and diversity of\ndevelopment and a generally lower level of public services and\nfacilities.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Purposes, policies and objectives. Hamlet areas will serve as the\nservice and growth centers in the park. They are intended to accommodate\na large portion of the necessary and natural expansion of the park's\nhousing, commercial and industrial activities. In these areas, a wide\nvariety of housing, commercial, recreational, social and professional\nneeds of the park's permanent, seasonal and transient populations will\nbe met. The building intensities that may occur in such areas will allow\na high and desirable level of public and institutional services to be\neconomically feasible. Because a hamlet is concentrated in character and\nlocated in areas where existing development patterns indicate the demand\nfor and viability of service and growth centers, these areas will\ndiscourage the haphazard location and dispersion of intense building\ndevelopment in the park's open space areas. These areas will continue to\nprovide services to park residents and visitors and, in conjunction wit...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All land uses and development are considered compatible with the\ncharacter, purposes and objectives of hamlet areas.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No overall intensity guideline is applicable to hamlet areas.\n  d. Moderate intensity use area.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character description. Moderate\nintensity use areas, delineated in red on the plan map, are those areas\nwhere the capability of the natural resources and the anticipated need\nfor future development indicate that relatively intense development,\nprimarily residential in character, is possible, desirable and suitable.\n  These areas are primarily located near or adjacent to hamlets to\nprovide for residential expansion. They are also located along highways\nor accessible shorelines where existing development has established the\ncharacter of the area.\n  Those areas identified as moderate intensity use where relatively\nintense development does not already exist are generally characterized\nby deep soils on moderate slopes and are readily accessible to existing\nhamlets.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Purposes, policies and objectives. Moderate intensity use areas\nwill provide for development opportunities in areas where development\nwill not significantly harm the relatively tolerant physical and\nbiological resources. These areas are designed to provide for\nresidential expansion and growth and to accommodate uses related to\nresidential uses in the vicinity of hamlets where community services can\nmost readily and economically be provided. Such growth and the services\nrelated to it will generally be at less intense levels than in hamlet\nareas.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Guidelines for overall intensity of development. The overall\nintensity of development for land located in any moderate intensity use\narea should not exceed approximately five hundred principal buildings\nper square mile.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Classification of compatible uses:\n  Primary uses in moderate intensity use areas:\n  1. Single family dwellings.\n  2. Individual mobile homes.\n  3. Open space recreation uses.\n  4. Agricultural uses.\n  5. Agricultural use structures.\n  6. Forestry uses.\n  7. Forestry use structures.\n  8. Hunting and fishing cabins and hunting and fishing and other\nprivate club structures.\n  9. Game preserves and private parks.\n  10. Cemeteries.\n  11. Private roads.\n  12. Private sand and gravel extractions.\n  13. Public utility uses.\n  14. Accessory uses and structures to any use classified as a\ncompatible use.\n  Secondary uses in moderate intensity use areas:\n  1. Multiple family dwellings.\n  2. Mobile home courts.\n  3. Public and semi-public buildings.\n  4. Municipal roads.\n  5. Agricultural service uses.\n  6. Commercial uses.\n  7. Tourist accommodations.\n  8. Tourist attractions.\n  9. Marinas, boatyards and boat launching sites.\n  10. Campgrounds.\n  11. Group camps.\n  1...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character description. Low intensity\nuse areas, delineated in orange on the plan map, are those readily\naccessible areas, normally within reasonable proximity to a hamlet,\nwhere the physical and biological resources are fairly tolerant and can\nwithstand development at an intensity somewhat lower than found in\nhamlets and moderate intensity use areas. While these areas often\nexhibit wide variability in the land's capability to support\ndevelopment, they are generally areas with fairly deep soils, moderate\nslopes and no large acreages of critical biological importance. Where\nthese areas are adjacent to or near hamlets, clustering homes on the\nmost developable portions of these areas makes possible a relatively\nhigh level of residential units and local services.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Purposes, policies and objectives. The purpose of low intensity\nuse areas is to provide for development opportunities at levels that\nwill protect the physical and biological resources, while still\nproviding for orderly growth and development of the park. It is\nanticipated that these areas will primarily be used to provide housing\ndevelopment opportunities not only for park residents but also for the\ngrowing seasonal home market. In addition, services and uses related to\nresidential uses may be located at a lower intensity than in hamlets or\nmoderate intensity use areas.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Guidelines for overall intensity of development. The overall\nintensity of development for land located in any low intensity use area\nshould not exceed approximately two hundred principal buildings per\nsquare mile.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Classification of compatible uses:\n  Primary uses in low intensity use areas:\n  1. Single family dwellings.\n  2. Individual mobile homes.\n  3. Open space recreation uses.\n  4. Agricultural uses.\n  5. Agricultural use structures.\n  6. Forestry uses.\n  7. Forestry use structures.\n  8. Hunting and fishing cabins and hunting and fishing and other\nprivate club structures.\n  9. Game preserves and private parks.\n  10. Private roads.\n  11. Cemeteries.\n  12. Private sand and gravel extractions.\n  13. Public utility uses.\n  14. Accessory uses and structures to any use classified as a\ncompatible use.\n  Secondary uses in low intensity use areas:\n  1. Multiple family dwellings.\n  2. Mobile home courts.\n  3. Public and semi-public buildings.\n  4. Municipal roads.\n  5. Agricultural service uses.\n  6. Commercial uses.\n  7. Tourist accommodations.\n  8. Tourist attractions.\n  9. Marinas, boatyards and boat launching sites.\n  10. Golf courses.\n  11. Campgrounds.\n  12. Group ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character description. Rural use areas,\ndelineated in yellow on the plan map, are those areas where natural\nresource limitations and public considerations necessitate fairly\nstringent development constraints. These areas are characterized by\nsubstantial acreages of one or more of the following: fairly shallow\nsoils, relatively severe slopes, significant ecotones, critical wildlife\nhabitats, proximity to scenic vistas or key public lands. In addition,\nthese areas are frequently remote from existing hamlet areas or are not\nreadily accessible.\n  Consequently, these areas are characterized by a low level of\ndevelopment and variety of rural uses that are generally compatible with\nthe protection of the relatively intolerant natural resources and the\npreservation of open space. These areas and the resource management\nareas provide the essential open space atmosphere that characterizes the\npark.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Purposes, policies and objectives. The basic purpose and objective\nof rural use areas is to provide for and encourage those rural land uses\nthat are consistent and compatible with the relatively low tolerance of\nthe areas' natural resources and the preservation of the open spaces\nthat are essential and basic to the unique character of the park.\nAnother objective of rural use areas is to prevent strip development\nalong major travel corridors in order to enhance the aesthetic and\neconomic benefit derived from a park atmosphere along these corridors.\n  Residential development and related development and uses should occur\non large lots or in relatively small clusters on carefully selected and\nwell designed sites. This will provide for further diversity in\nresidential and related development opportunities in the park.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Guideline for overall intensity of development. The overall\nintensity of development for land located in any rural use area should\nnot exceed approximately seventy-five principal buildings per square\nmile.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Classification of compatible uses.\n  Primary uses in rural use areas:\n  1. Single family dwellings.\n  2. Individual mobile homes.\n  3. Open space recreation uses.\n  4. Agricultural uses.\n  5. Agricultural use structures.\n  6. Forestry uses.\n  7. Forestry use structures.\n  8. Hunting and fishing cabins and hunting and fishing and other\nprivate club structures.\n  9. Game preserves and private parks.\n  10. Cemeteries.\n  11. Private roads.\n  12. Private sand and gravel extractions.\n  13. Public utility uses.\n  14. Accessory uses and structures to any use classified as a\ncompatible use.\n  Secondary uses in rural use areas:\n  1. Multiple family dwellings.\n  2. Mobile home courts.\n  3. Public and semi-public buildings.\n  4. Municipal roads.\n  5. Agricultural service uses.\n  6. Commercial uses.\n  7. Tourist accommodations.\n  8. Marinas, boatyards and boat launching sites.\n  9. Golf courses.\n  10. Campgrounds.\n  11. Group camps.\n  12. Ski centers.\n  13. Commercial...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character description. Resource\nmanagement areas, delineated in green on the plan map, are those lands\nwhere the need to protect, manage and enhance forest, agricultural,\nrecreational and open space resources is of paramount importance because\nof overriding natural resource and public considerations. Open space\nuses, including forest management, agriculture and recreational\nactivities, are found throughout these areas.\n  Many resource management areas are characterized by substantial\nacreages of one or more of the following: shallow soils, severe slopes,\nelevations of over twenty-five hundred feet, flood plains, proximity to\ndesignated or proposed wild or scenic rivers, wetlands, critical\nwildlife habitats or habitats of rare and endangered plant and animal\nspecies.\n  Other resource management areas include extensive tracts under active\nforest management that are vital to the wood using industry and\nnecessary to insure its raw material needs.\n  Important and viable agri...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Purposes, policies and objectives. The basic purposes and\nobjectives of resource management areas are to protect the delicate\nphysical and biological resources, encourage proper and economic\nmanagement of forest, agricultural and recreational resources and\npreserve the open spaces that are essential and basic to the unique\ncharacter of the park.  Another objective of these areas is to prevent\nstrip development along major travel corridors in order to enhance the\naesthetic and economic benefits derived from a park atmosphere along\nthese corridors.\n  Finally, resource management areas will allow for residential\ndevelopment on substantial acreages or in small clusters on carefully\nselected and well designed sites.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Guidelines for overall intensity of development. The overall\nintensity of development for land located in any resource management\narea should not exceed approximately fifteen principal buildings per\nsquare mile.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Classification of compatible uses.\n  Primary uses in resource management areas:\n  1. Agricultural uses.\n  2. Agricultural use structures.\n  3. Open space recreation uses.\n  4. Forestry uses.\n  5. Forestry use structures.\n  6. Game preserves and private parks.\n  7. Private roads.\n  8. Private sand and gravel extractions.\n  9. Public utility uses.\n  10. Hunting and fishing cabins and hunting and fishing and other\nprivate club structures involving less than five hundred square feet of\nfloor space.\n  11. Accessory uses and structures to any use classified as a\ncompatible use.\n  Secondary uses in resource management areas:\n  1. Single family dwellings.\n  2. Individual mobile homes.\n  3. Hunting and fishing cabins and hunting and fishing and other\nprivate club structures involving five hundred square feet or more of\nfloor space.\n  4. Campgrounds.\n  5. Group camps.\n  6. Ski centers and related tourist accommodations.\n  7. Agricultural service uses.\n  8. Sawmills, chi...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Character description. Industrial use\nareas, delineated in purple on the plan map, include those areas that\nare substantial in size and located outside of hamlet areas and are\nareas</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>where existing land uses are predominantly of an industrial or\nmineral extraction nature or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>identified by local and state officials\nas having potential for new industrial development.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Purposes, policies and objectives. Industrial use areas will\nencourage the continued operation of major existing industrial and\nmineral extraction uses important to the economy of the Adirondack\nregion and will provide suitable locations for new industrial and\nmineral extraction activities that may contribute to the economic growth\nof the park without detracting from its character. Land uses that might\nconflict with existing or potential industrial or mineral extraction\nuses are discouraged in industrial use areas.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Classification of compatible uses.\n  Primary uses in industrial use areas:\n  1. Industrial uses.\n  2. Mineral extractions.\n  3. Mineral extraction structures.\n  4. Private sand and gravel extractions.\n  5. Commercial sand and gravel extractions.\n  6. Sawmills, chipping mills, pallet mills and similar wood using\nfacilities.\n  7. Forestry uses.\n  8. Forestry use structures.\n  9. Agricultural uses.\n  10. Agricultural use structures.\n  11. Private roads.\n  12. Open space recreation uses.\n  13. Hunting and fishing cabins and hunting and fishing and other\nprivate club structures.\n  14. Public utility uses.\n  15. Major public utility uses.\n  16. Accessory uses and structures to any use classified as a\ncompatible use.\n  Secondary uses in industrial use areas:\n  1. Commercial uses.\n  2. Agricultural service uses.\n  3. Public and semi-public buildings.\n  4. Municipal roads.\n  5. Sewage treatment plants.\n  6. Waste disposal areas.\n  7. Junkyards.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No overall intensity guideline is applicable to industrial use\nareas.\n  4. Development considerations. The following are those factors which\nrelate to potential for adverse impact upon the park's natural, scenic,\naesthetic, ecological, wildlife, historic, recreational or open space\nresources and which shall be considered, as provided in this article,\nbefore any significant new land use or development or subdivision of\nland is undertaken in the park. Any burden on the public in providing\nfacilities and services made necessary by such land use and development\nor subdivision of land shall also be taken into account, as well as any\ncommercial, industrial, residential, recreational or other benefits\nwhich might be derived therefrom:\n  a. Natural resource considerations.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Water\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Existing water quality.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Natural sedimentation of siltation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Eutrophication.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Existing drainage and runoff patterns.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Existing flow characteristics.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Existing water table and rates of recharge.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_f__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Land\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Existing topography.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Erosion and slippage.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Floodplain and flood hazard.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Mineral resources.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Viable agricultural soils.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Forest resources.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Open space resources.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Vegetative cover.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The quality and availability of land for outdoor recreational\npurposes.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Air\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Air quality.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Noise\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Noise levels.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Critical resource areas\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Rivers and corridors of rivers designated to be studied as wild,\nscenic or recreational in accordance with the environmental conservation\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Rare plant communities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Habitats of rare and endangered species and key wildlife habitats.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Alpine and subalpine life zones.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Wetlands.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Elevations of twenty-five hundred feet or more.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unique features, including gorges, waterfalls, and geologic\nformations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_g__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Wildlife\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fish and wildlife.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aesthetics\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Scenic vistas.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Natural and man-made travel corridors.\n  b. Historic site considerations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Historic factors\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Historic sites or structures.\n  c. Site development considerations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Natural site factors\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Geology.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Slopes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Soil characteristics.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Depth to ground water and other hydrological factors.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Other site factors\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adjoining and nearby land uses.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adequacy of site facilities.\n  d. Governmental considerations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Governmental service and finance factors\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Ability of government to provide facilities and services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Municipal, school or special district taxes or special district\nuser charges.\n  e. Governmental review considerations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_805__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Governmental control factors\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conformance with other governmental controls.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>