<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-806"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-806"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="806"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-806/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-806/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-806/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-806/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_806">
        <num>806</num>
        <heading>Shoreline restrictions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within thirty-five feet of the mean high-water mark not more than\nthirty percent of the trees in excess of six inches diameter at breast\nheight existing at any time may be cut over any ten-year period.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within six feet of the mean high-water mark no vegetation may be\nremoved, except that up to a maximum of thirty percent of the shorefront\nmay be cleared of vegetation on any individual lot. This provision shall\nbe adhered to in addition to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>above.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The above cutting standards shall not be deemed to prevent the\nremoval of diseased vegetation or of rotten or damaged trees or of other\nvegetation that present safety or health hazards.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_806__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The following minimum shoreline frontages shall be required in all\nland use areas for deeded or contractual access to all such lakes,\nponds, rivers or streams for five or more lots, parcels or sites or\nmultiple family dwelling units not having separate and distinct\nownership of shore frontage:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where five to twenty lots or multiple family dwelling units are\ninvolved, a total of not less than one hundred feet.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where more than twenty and not more than one hundred lots or\nmultiple dwelling units are involved, a minimum of three feet for each\nadditional lot or multiple dwelling unit in excess of twenty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where more than one hundred and not more than one hundred fifty\nlots or multiple dwelling units are involved, a minimum of two feet for\neach additional lot or multiple dwelling unit in excess of one hundred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where more than one hundred fifty lots or multiple dwelling units\nare involved, a minimum of one foot for each additional lot or multiple\ndwelling unit in excess of one hundred fifty.\n  b. In the case of all lakes, ponds, rivers and streams, the minimum\nsetback of any on-site sewage drainage field or seepage pit shall be one\nhundred feet from the mean high-water mark in all land use areas.\n  2. In all of the above restrictions, the term "mean high-water mark"\nshall mean the spillway elevation contour, which is at seven hundred\nseventy-one feet elevation above mean sea level, whenever the Great\nSacandaga Lake is involved.\n  3. a. Any person seeking a variance from the strict letter of the\nshoreline restrictions in connection with any new land use or\ndevelopment or subdivision of land proposed to be located in a land use\narea governed by an approved local land use program shall make\napplication therefor to the local government as provided in such\napproved local land use program. If a person is seeking such a variance\nin a land use area not governed by an approved local land use program,\nhe shall make application therefor to the agency whether or not the\nagency has project review jurisdiction over the new land use or\ndevelopment or subdivision of land involved.  Upon such application, and\nafter public hearing thereon, the local government or the agency shall,\nwhere there are practical difficulties or unnecessary hardships in the\nway of carrying out the strict letter of the restrictions, have\nauthority to vary or modify the application of such restrictions\nrelating to the use, construction or alteration of buildings or\nstructures, or the use of land, so that the spirit of such restrictions\nshall be observed, public safety and welfare secured and substantial\njustice done.\n  b. The local government shall act upon any application to it within\nthe time provided for in its local land use program. The agency shall\nact upon any application to it w...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>through</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsection three hundred two of the state administrative procedure act.\n  4. The shoreline restrictions shall not apply to any emergency land\nuse or development which is immediately necessary for the protection of\nlife or property as defined by the agency in its rules and regulations\ngoverning its procedures to review projects as authorized in section\neight hundred nine.\n  5. In order to encourage clustering of buildings and the maintenance\nof undeveloped shorelines, as an alternative to minimum lot widths of\nthe shoreline restriction, shoreline development may take place in the\nfollowing land use areas upon the following approximate overall\nintensities of principal buildings (other than boathouses) per linear\nmile of shoreline or proportionate fraction thereof:\n                                           Principal Buildings\n  Land Use Areas                             Per Linear Mile\n  Hamlet ............................................... 106\n  Moderate Intensity .................................... 53\n  Low Intensity ......................................... 42\n  Rural Use ............................................. 36\n  Resource Management ................................... 26\n  This alternative method of cluster shoreline development shall only be\nemployed where a single ownership or a group of two or more owners\nacting in concert is involved. In addition, approval of this method of\ndevelopment must carry with it provisions, whether by deed restriction,\nrestrictive covenant or other similar appropriate means, to insure the\nretention in open space of the undeveloped portions of shoreline\ndeveloped on a cluster basis. The agency, within its project review\njurisdiction, or a local government under an approved local land use\nprogram, may apply these optional shoreline clustering provisions.  Any\nperson proposing to undertake new land use or development or subdivision\nof land in a land use area not governed by an ap...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>