<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-809"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-809"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="809"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-809/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-809/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-809/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-809/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_809">
        <num>809</num>
        <heading>Agency administration and enforcement of the land use and development plan</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>through</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsection three hundred two of the state administrative procedure act.\n  d. If the agency determines to hold a public hearing on an application\nfor a permit, the agency shall notify the project sponsor of its\ndetermination by certified mail on or before sixty calendar days or, in\nthe case of a minor project, forty-five calendar days after the agency\nnotifies the project sponsor that the application is complete or after\nthe application is deemed complete pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection. The determination of whether or not to hold a public hearing on\nan application shall be based on whether the agency's evaluation or\ncomments of the review board, local officials or the public on a project\nraise substantive and significant issues relating to any findings or\ndeterminations the agency is required to make pursuant to this section,\nincluding the reasonable likelihood that the project will be disapproved\nor can be approved only with major modifications because the project as\nproposed may not meet statutory or regulatory criteria or standards. The\nagency shall also consider the general level of public interest in a\nproject. No project may be disapproved without a public hearing first\nbeing held thereon.\n  e. If the agency has notified the project sponsor of its determination\nto hold a public hearing, the sponsor shall not undertake the project\nduring the time period specified in paragraph c of this subdivision. The\nnotice of determination to hold a public hearing shall state that the\nproject sponsor has the opportunity within fifteen days to withdraw his\napplication or submit a new application. A public hearing shall commence\non or before ninety calendar days, or in the case of a minor project,\nseventy-five days, after the agency notifies the project sponsor that\nthe application is complete or after the application is deemed complete\npursuant to the provisions of this section. In addition to notice of\nsuch hearing b...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_809__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of a request which does not involve a material change\nin permit conditions, the applicable law, environmental conditions or\ntechnology since the date of issuance of the existing permit, the agency\nshall on or before fifteen calendar days after the receipt of a request\nmail a written determination to the permit holder of its decision on the\nrequest. If the decision is to deny the request, the permit holder shall\nbe afforded an opportunity for hearing and notice of such decision shall\nbe given by the agency in the next available issue of the environmental\nnotice bulletin.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_809__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of a request which may involve a material change as\ndescribed in subparagraph one of this paragraph, the agency shall on or\nbefore fifteen calendar days after the receipt of a request mail a\nwritten determination to the permit holder that the request shall be\ntreated as an application for a new permit.\n  If pursuant to subparagraph one or two of this paragraph, the agency\nfails to mail a written determination to the permit holder within such\nfifteen calendar day period, the provisions of subdivision six of this\nsection shall apply.\n  9. The agency shall not approve any class A regional project proposed\nto be located in a land use area governed by an approved local land use\nprogram, or grant a permit therefor, unless it first determines that\nsuch project meets all of the pertinent requirements and conditions of\nsuch approved local land use program and that the project would not have\nan undue adverse impact upon the natural, scenic, aesthetic, ecological,\nwildl...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bodies of water, such as lakes and ponds,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any\nland in the same ownership that is directly related to any principal\nbuilding in existence on August first, nineteen hundred seventy-three,\nwhich land is not included in the project, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_809__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, in the case of any\nprincipal building constructed after August first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-three, any land in the same or any other ownership that was\nincluded within the area of any previous project in order to comply with\nthe overall intensity guideline.\n  d. The project would comply with the shoreline restrictions if\napplicable. The agency may require a greater setback of any on-site\nsewage drainage field or seepage pit than required under the shoreline\nrestrictions if it determines that soils or other pertinent conditions\nrequire such greater setback to reasonably protect the water quality of\nthe water body involved.\n  e. The project would not have an undue adverse impact upon the\nnatural, scenic, aesthetic, ecological, wildlife, historic, recreational\nor open space resources of the park or upon the ability of the public to\nprovide supporting facilities and services made necessary by the\nproject, taking into account the commercial, industrial, residential,\nrecreational or other benefits that might be derived from the project.\nIn making this determination, as to the impact of the project upon such\nresources of the park, the agency shall consider those factors contained\nin the development considerations of the plan which are pertinent to the\nproject under review.\n  11. Where there are practical difficulties or unnecessary hardships in\nthe way of carrying out the strict letter of the provisions of the plan\nor the shoreline restrictions, the agency shall have authority in\nconnection with a project under its review to vary or modify, after\npublic hearing thereon, the application of any of such provisions or\nrestrictions relating to the use, construction or alteration of\nbuildings or structures, or the use of land, so that the spirit of the\nprovisions or restrictions shall be observed, public safety and welfare\nsecured and substantial justice done.\n  12. The agency may conduct such investigations, examinations tests and\nsite evalua...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>