<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-811"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-811"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="811"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-811/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-811/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-811/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-811/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_811">
        <num>811</num>
        <heading>Special provisions relating to agency project review jurisdiction and the shoreline restrictions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_811__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pre-existing subdivision of land,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_811__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any subdivision or\nportion of a subdivision that involves seventy-five or fewer lots,\nparcels or sites for the completion of which any or all permits and\nother approvals required by or pursuant to law were obtained after July\nfirst, nineteen hundred seventy-one and for which all such required\npermits were in full force and effect on July thirty-first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-three, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_811__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>individual single family dwelling or\nmobile home, erected or placed on any lot, parcel or site in any\nsubdivision referred to in clauses</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_811__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_811__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof which has been\napproved by the state department of health, shall not be subject to\nreview by the agency, provided, however, that a subdivision or portion\nof a subdivision described in clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_811__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof shall become subject to\nreview by the agency on August first, nineteen hundred seventy-four if\nsuch subdivision or portion is not in existence on said date. Any\nindividual single family dwelling or mobile home referred to in clause\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_811__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision hereof shall not be subject to the minimum lot\nwidth provisions of the shoreline restrictions.\n  4. With respect to any land use or development or subdivision of land\nor portion thereof approved by the agency under its interim project\nreview authority, in section eight hundred fifteen, such land use or\ndevelopment or subdivision or portion thereof may proceed in accordance\nwith the terms of the approval and shall not be subject to further\nreview by the agency so long as such land use or development or\nsubdivision or portion thereof is substantially commenced and/or\nmaterial expenditures and financial obligations have been incurred with\nregard to such land use or development or subdivision or portion thereof\nwithin two years of such approval.\n  5. Any existing land use or development, including any structure being\nrestored or rebuilt in whole or in part, being increased or expanded,\nwhether in successive stages or at one time, to a total of less than\ntwenty-five percent of its size or square footage at the date of\nenactment or when originally built or undertaken, whichever is later,\nshall not be subject to review by the agency.  Any material increase or\nexpansion thereafter shall constitute a reviewable land use or\ndevelopment if otherwise within the agency's review jurisdiction. In no\ncase shall any increase or expansion violate, or increase non-compliance\nwith, the minimum setback requirements of the shoreline restrictions.\nNotwithstanding the foregoing, a single family dwelling or mobile home\nmay always be enlarged or rebuilt to any extent provided that it\ncontinues to be used as such, provided, however, that no such increase\nor expansion shall violate, or increase any non-compliance with, the\nminimum setback requirements of the shoreline restrictions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>