<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-812"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-812"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="812"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_812">
        <num>812</num>
        <heading>Public hearings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 812. Public hearings. 1. Public hearings authorized or required by\nsection eight hundred nine to be held by the agency in connection with\nthe review of projects shall be conducted as provided in this section,\nthe applicable project review rules and regulations of the agency\nadopted under subdivision fourteen of such section, and the state\nadministrative procedure act.\n  2. Notice of such public hearings shall be given as required in\nsection eight hundred nine. Individual notices of hearing required under\nsuch section shall be served by mail in the manner required by section\neight hundred nine of this article to the last known address of such\nindividuals. Individual notice of hearing shall also be so served on any\nother person or agency, public or private, as may be required under the\nagency's project review rules and regulations.\n  3. Parties to a public hearing shall be the project sponsor and any\nperson or agency entitled to individual notice and any other person or\nagency as may be authorized under the agency's project review rules and\nregulations.\n  4. The public hearing may, if authorized by the agency's project\nreview rules and regulations, be conducted by any member or designee of\nthe agency, but any findings, decision, order, permit or certificate of\nthe agency shall be adopted by the agency, all members voting having\nfamiliarized themselves with the record.\n  5. The agency, or member or designee thereof presiding at the hearing\nshall have power to administer oaths and issue subpoenas to compel the\nattendance of witnesses and the production of relevant documents and\npapers, including witnesses and documents requested by the parties.\n  6. The parties shall be afforded the opportunity to present evidence\nand argument and, in the case of the project sponsor, any person or\nagency entitled by law to individual notice and any other public agency,\nto cross-examine witnesses on all relevant issues, but the member or\ndesignee presiding may impose reasonable limitations as to time and\nnumber of persons heard.\n  7. The agency shall keep a verbatim record of the proceedings and\ncertified copies shall be made available, and for such reasonable\ncharges, as may be provided by rule or regulation of the agency.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>