<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-815"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-815"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="815"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_815">
        <num>815</num>
        <heading>Interim development controls</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_815__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bona fide\nmanagement, including logging, of forests, woodlands or plantations or\nthe construction or maintenance of woodroads, landings or temporary\nstructures, directly associated with such management,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_815__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bona fide\nmanagement of land for agriculture, livestock raising, horticulture and\norchards and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_815__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any project involving less than five acres and fewer\nthan five lots, from review under this section.\n  5. Such rules and regulations shall set forth a procedure for the\ninformal discussion of preliminary and informal plans for a project and\nfor preliminary approval or recommendations by the agency with respect\nto the project. Such informal discussion shall be optional with the\nproject sponsor, and no such preliminary approval or recommendations by\nthe agency shall relieve any agency or person from complying with any\nprovision of this section.\n  6. This section shall not apply to any emergency project which is\nimmediately necessary for the protection of life or property as defined\nby the agency by rule and regulation.\n  7. A public or private agency or person proposing to undertake a\nproject subject to review under this section or the rules and\nregulations adopted hereunder, shall submit to the agency a description\nthereof, in such form and manner as shall be sufficient to enable the\nagency to make the findings and determinations required by this section.\nFor a period of ninety days following the submission of such description\nto the agency, or until such earlier time as the agency may specify,\nsuch agency or person shall not undertake or continue such project. The\nagency shall review such description to determine the effect of the\nproposed project upon the scenic, historic, ecological and natural\nresources of the park, and to assess the commercial, industrial,\nresidential, recreational or other benefits of the project.\n  8. If, on or before the conclusion of such ninety-day period and after\na public hearing is held on the project in accordance with subdivision\nnine the agency finds that the proposed project</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_815__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is not in\nsubstantial conformity with the policies of this article and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_815__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>would\nhave a substantial and lasting adverse impact upon such resources of the\npark, it may issue an order upon the project sponsor prohibiting the\ncommencement or continuation of the project until August first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-three. The findings and order of the agency shall be in\nwriting and notice of the findings and order shall be mailed to persons\nto whom it is directed at their last known address.\n  9. Notice of a formal hearing shall be given by conspicuous posting of\nthe land which is or will be subject to the agency action in question\nand by publication at least once in a newspaper of general circulation\nin the county or counties wherein such land is situated. In addition,\nindividual notice shall be given by depositing the same in the mails\naddressed at the last known address to:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_815__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The owner or owners of the\nland which is or will be subject to the agency order;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_815__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the public or\nprivate agency or person proposing to undertake the project; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_815__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the\nlocal government or local governments exercising jurisdiction over the\nland which is or will be subject to the agency order.\n  Notices shall be given at least seven days in advance of the hearing\nand shall contain a statement describing the matters to be considered at\nthe hearing, the time and place where further details may be obtained,\nand the time and place of the hearing.\n  10. Any review and determination made pursuant to this section shall\ntake into account existing local controls.\n  11. All orders made by the agency shall be enforceable by appropriate\nproceedings at law or in equity and any person who violates any\nprovision of this section or rules, regulations and orders adopted\npursuant thereto may be fined for not more than five hundred dollars or\nimprisoned not more than thirty days, or both. Each day the violation\ncontinues is hereby deemed to be a separate offense for purposes of\ndetermining the amount of such fines and length of imprisonment.\n  12. A p...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>