<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-816"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-816"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="816"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-816/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-816/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-816/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-816/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_816">
        <num>816</num>
        <heading>Master plan for management of state lands</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 816. Master plan for management of state lands. 1. The department of\nenvironmental conservation is hereby authorized and directed to develop,\nin consultation with the agency, individual management plans for units\nof land classified in the master plan for management of state lands\nheretofore prepared by the agency in consultation with the department of\nenvironmental conservation and approved by the governor. Such management\nplans shall conform to the general guidelines and criteria set forth in\nthe master plan. Until amended, the master plan for management of state\nlands and the individual management plans shall guide the development\nand management of state lands in the Adirondack park.\n  2. The master plan and the individual management plans shall be\nreviewed periodically and may be amended from time to time, and when so\namended shall as amended henceforth guide the development and management\nof state lands in the Adirondack park.  Amendments to the master plan\nshall be prepared by the agency, in consultation with the department of\nenvironmental conservation, and submitted after public hearing to the\ngovernor for his approval.\n  3. The agency and department are hereby authorized to develop rules\nand regulations necessary, convenient or desirable to effectuate the\npurposes of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>