<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-836"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-836"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="836"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-836/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-836/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-836/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-836/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_836">
        <num>836</num>
        <heading>Division of criminal justice services; commissioner, organization and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 836. Division of criminal justice services; commissioner,\norganization and employees. 1. There shall be in the executive\ndepartment a division of criminal justice services.\n  2. The head of the division shall be a commissioner, who shall be\nappointed by the governor, by and with the advice and consent of the\nsenate, and hold office at the pleasure of the governor by whom he was\nappointed and until his successor is appointed and qualified. The\ncommissioner shall be the chief executive officer of and in sole charge\nof the administration of the division. The commissioner shall receive an\nannual salary to be fixed by the governor within the amount available\ntherefor by appropriation; and he shall be entitled to receive\nreimbursement for expenses actually and necessarily incurred by him in\nthe performance of his duties.\n  3. The commissioner may, from time to time, create, abolish, transfer\nand consolidate bureaus and other units within the division not\nexpressly established by law as he may determine necessary for the\nefficient operation of the division, subject to the approval of the\ndirector of the budget.\n  4. The commissioner may appoint such deputies, directors, assistants\nand other officers and employees, committees and consultants as he may\ndeem necessary, prescribe their powers and duties, fix their\ncompensation and provide for reimbursement of their expenses within the\namounts appropriated therefor.\n  5. The commissioner may request and receive from any department,\ndivision, board, bureau, commission or other agency of the state or any\npolitical subdivision thereof or any public authority such assistance,\ninformation and data as will enable the division properly to carry out\nits functions, powers and duties.\n  6. The principal office of the division shall be in the county of\nAlbany.\n  7. The functions, powers and duties of the former division of\nprobation and correctional alternatives as established in article twelve\nof this chapter shall now be considered a function of the division of\ncriminal justice services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>