<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-U"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-U"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-U"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_U">
        <num>837-U</num>
        <heading>The division of criminal justice services, in conjunction with the chief administrator of the courts, shall collect data and report annua...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 837-u. The division of criminal justice services, in conjunction\nwith the chief administrator of the courts, shall collect data and\nreport annually regarding pretrial release and detention. Such data and\nreport shall contain information categorized by age, gender, racial and\nethnic background; regarding the nature of the criminal offenses,\nincluding the top charge of each case; the number and type of charges in\neach defendant's criminal record; whether the prosecutor requested that\nthe court fix bail, the amounts and forms of bail requested by the\nprosecutor, and the amounts and forms of bail set by the court; the\nnumber of individuals released on recognizance; the number of\nindividuals released on non-monetary conditions, including the\nconditions imposed; the number of individuals committed to the custody\nof a sheriff prior to trial; the rates of failure to appear and\nrearrest; the outcome of such cases or dispositions; whether the\ndefendant was represented by counsel at every court appearance regarding\nthe defendant's securing order; the length of the pretrial detention\nstay and any other such information as the chief administrator and the\ndivision of criminal justice services may find necessary and\nappropriate. Such annual report shall aggregate the data collected by\ncounty; court, including city, town and village courts; and judge. The\ndata shall be aggregated in order to protect the identity of individual\ndefendants. The report shall be released publicly and published on the\nwebsites of the office of court administration and the division of\ncriminal justice services. The first report shall be published eighteen\nmonths after this section shall have become a law, and shall include\ndata from the first twelve months following the enactment of this\nsection. Reports for subsequent years shall be published annually on or\nbefore that date thereafter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>