<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-10-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_M">
        <num>837-M</num>
        <heading>Reporting duties of law enforcement departments with respect to missing children and vulnerable adults</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 837-m. Reporting duties of law enforcement departments with\nrespect to missing children and vulnerable adults. The chief of every\npolice department, each county sheriff and the superintendent of state\npolice shall report, at least semi-annually, to the division with\nrespect to specified cases of missing children that are closed. Such\nreports shall be in the form and manner prescribed by the division and\nshall contain such information as the division deems necessary\nincluding, but not limited to, information regarding recovered children\nwho were arrested, children who were the victims of criminal activity or\nexploitation and children who were found deceased and information\nregarding the alleged abductor or killer of such children. Any law\nenforcement department referred to in this section may, in its\ndiscretion, include in such semi-annual reports information relating to\nmissing vulnerable adults as such term is defined in section eight\nhundred thirty-seven-f-one of this article.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 837-m's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>