<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_J">
        <num>837-J</num>
        <heading>Parking violations enforcement and disposition program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 837-j. Parking violations enforcement and disposition program. 1.\nThe commissioner and the commissioner of the department of motor\nvehicles may enter into an agreement to effect the enhanced collection\nof the mandatory surcharges imposed pursuant to section eighteen hundred\nnine-a of the vehicle and traffic law. The terms of such agreement shall\nauthorize the exchange between the division and the department of motor\nvehicles of information concerning outstanding fines, penalties and\nunpaid mandatory surcharges and identification information concerning\npersons with adjudicated parking violations subject to the imposition of\nsuch fines, penalties and mandatory surcharges.\n  2. The commissioner and the commissioner of the department of motor\nvehicles shall enter into any necessary joint enforcement agreements,\nwhich agreements shall be consistent with any agreement authorized by\nsubdivision one of this section.\n  3. The commissioner of the department of motor vehicles shall be\nauthorized to cooperate with traffic and law enforcement agencies of\nother states and of the United States, to obtain and furnish any\nassistance or information necessary for the enforcement and collection\nof fines, penalties and mandatory surcharges for parking violations.\n  4. The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of the\ndepartment of motor vehicles shall promulgate such rules and regulations\nas may be necessary to effect the purposes of this section.\n  * NB Repealed September 1, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>