<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_H">
        <num>837-H</num>
        <heading>Livery vehicle safety training program; standards; eligibility; reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the development of a training program curriculum which includes\ninstruction on:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>methods to maximize personal safety, including information on\navailable equipment and technologies;\n  (ii) effective passenger management and communications skills;\n  (iii) vehicular and pedestrian safety, including a review of the\napplicable provisions of the vehicle and traffic law; and\n  (iv) any other subject relevant to the public health and safety in the\noperation of livery vehicles;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the procedure by which the provider agencies make application to\nreceive funding to operate a program and the form of the application;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the procedure by which provider agencies report to the\ncommissioner regarding the provision of program services and the form of\nthe report;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the procedure for periodic monitoring and evaluation of the livery\nvehicle safety training program.\n  2. Each provider agency shall prepare a plan, to be approved by the\ncommissioner, for the provision of program services to eligible drivers.\nSuch plan shall include, at a minimum, the nature of the services to be\nrendered, how the services comply with the developed curriculum, the\ncost associated with rendering such services and a description of how\nthe services will enhance livery vehicle safety. For the purposes of\nthis section the term "provider agency" shall mean a county, municipal,\nlocal unit of government or a college or a university or a law\nenforcement agency or a not-for-profit entity.\n  3. Each provider agency shall furnish the commissioner a written\nreport in a format and at a time to be determined by the commissioner,\nsubject to standards promulgated pursuant to this section which shall,\nat a minimum contain:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of how the assistance provided, in accordance with\nthe program established herein, enhanced livery vehicle services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the nature and costs of program services provided.\n  4. For the purposes of this section the term "livery vehicle" shall\nhave the same meaning as the term "livery", as defined in section six\nhundred twenty-one of this chapter.\n  5. Nothing contained in this section shall impose liability upon the\ndivision or the state for death, injury or loss incurred by a driver by\nreason of that driver having participated in the livery vehicle safety\ntraining program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>