<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-F-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-F-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-04-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-F-2"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-F-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-F-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-F-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-F-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_F_2">
        <num>837-F-2</num>
        <heading>Missing adults</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 837-f-2. Missing adults. In the event that a police agency receives\na report that an adult person is missing from his or her normal and\nordinary place of residence and whose whereabouts cannot be determined\nby an individual whose relationship with such adult person would place\nsuch individual in a position to have knowledge of his or her\nwhereabouts, and that such missing adult person has a proven disability,\nor may be in physical danger, or is missing after a catastrophe, or may\nhave disappeared involuntarily, or is missing under circumstances where\nthere is a reasonable concern for his or her safety; and such missing\nadult person does not qualify as either a missing child pursuant to\nsection eight hundred thirty-seven-e of this article or a vulnerable\nadult pursuant to section eight hundred thirty-seven-f-1 of this\narticle, the police agency shall collect information necessary to file\nan electronic report regarding the missing adult person with the\nnational crime information center register and submit such electronic\nreport to the national crime information center register.\n  The division shall transmit the report of the missing adult to the\nNational Missing and Unidentified Persons System (NamUs) within thirty\ndays after entry of a report of a missing adult into the register\nwhenever circumstances indicate that the missing adult may be at\nimmediate risk of death or injury, or may be a match to a record\nmaintained in the NamUs unidentified person database and within one\nhundred eighty days in any other case.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>