<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_I">
        <num>837-I</num>
        <heading>Uniform parking ticket</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 837-i. Uniform parking ticket. 1. The commissioner, in cooperation\nwith the commissioner of the department of motor vehicles, and in\nconsultation with the chief executive officers of cities with a\npopulation in excess of one hundred thousand persons according to the\nnineteen hundred eighty United States census shall prescribe the form\nand content of uniform parking tickets for such cities in all cases\ninvolving a parking, standing or stopping violation as defined in\naccordance with the vehicle and traffic law, hereinafter referred to as\nparking violations, or of any local law, ordinance, rule or regulation\nadopted pursuant to the vehicle and traffic law relating to parking\nviolations. Upon written application of the chief executive officer of\nany such city, the commissioner, after consultation with the\ncommissioner of the department of motor vehicles, may authorize the use\nof a parking ticket other than the uniform parking ticket prescribed\npursuant to this section if he or she determines that use of such other\nparking ticket is not inconsistent with, and will not diminish the\neffectiveness of, the parking violations enforcement and disposition\nprogram established pursuant to section eight hundred thirty-seven-j of\nthis chapter, and may also authorize for a specified time period the use\nof a parking ticket which was used by such city on or before the\neffective date of this section.\n  2. The commissioner in consultation with the chief executive officers\nof cities with a population in excess of one hundred thousand persons\naccording to the nineteen hundred eighty United States census shall\nestablish a system to record and monitor the issuance and disposition of\nparking tickets, to monitor the collection of the mandatory surcharge\nrequired by section eighteen hundred nine-a of the vehicle and traffic\nlaw and to receive information from cities for this purpose. Each such\ncity shall report on such parking violations on a monthly basis in the\nform and manner prescribed by the commissioner including, but not\nlimited to, the parking tickets issued, the dispositions of such tickets\nand the amount of fines, penalties and mandatory surcharges collected.\nThe commissioner shall collect, process and analyze such information and\npresent periodic reports on the parking violations enforcement and\ndisposition program.\n  3. The commissioner shall have the power from time to time to adopt\nsuch rules and regulations as may be necessary to accomplish the\npurposes of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>