<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Y"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Y"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-06-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-Y"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_Y">
        <num>837-Y</num>
        <heading>New York state office of gun violence prevention</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Y__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Advance efforts to prevent, reduce, and address gun violence and\nits causes and consequences. "Gun violence" shall include, but is not\nlimited to, any attempted crime, crime, attempted suicide, suicide,\nintentional or unintentional injury, or death involving a firearm,\nrifle, or shotgun as defined in section 265.00 of the penal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Y__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Identify funding opportunities and other resources available\nrelated to gun violence prevention and reduction, and increase public\nawareness of such funding opportunities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Y__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Support efforts to improve the state's health and social service\nsystem capacity and capabilities to prevent and respond to gun violence\nincluding, but not limited to, state hospital-based violence prevention\nand intervention initiatives, in consultation with the department of\nhealth.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Y__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Coordinate and strengthen timely, accurate, and complete data\ncollection and research regarding firearm-related injuries, fatalities,\nand incidents by focusing on surveillance, prevention, and intervention\nof gun violence statewide.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Y__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Increase public awareness of gun violence causes and consequences\nand gun violence prevention efforts through public education campaigns\nor other educational efforts. Such campaigns and education efforts shall\ninclude but not be limited to adoption of best practices related to gun\nviolence prevention, the impacts of various types of gun violence on\nindividuals, families, and communities, and resources available to\nindividuals at risk of gun violence and individuals impacted by gun\nviolence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Y__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Collaborate with, and where practicable, facilitate, and assist\npolitical subdivisions of the state and not-for-profit organizations in\nthe development of local programs, services, and interventions to\nprevent, reduce, and address gun violence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Y__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before September first, two thousand twenty-five, develop\nand implement a public awareness campaign to educate the public on the\nsafe storage of firearms, rifles and shotguns and child access and\nprevention. The public awareness campaign shall include, but not be\nlimited to, educational materials, resources and information related to\nNew York state child access prevention laws and laws relating to the\nsafe storage and transport of firearms, rifles and shotguns including\nsections 265.45, 265.46, and 400.00 of the penal law, available methods\nfor the safe storage of firearms, rifles and shotguns designed to\nprevent child access, firearm violence prevention resources, and county\nand local specific laws and regulations related to child access\nprevention and storage of firearms, rifles and shotguns.\n  3. Annual report. The office shall issue an annual report including,\nbut not limited to, information on the status of gun violence in the\nstate, recommendations for policy and programmatic initiatives to\nprevent and reduce gun violence in the state, and a description of the\nefforts of the office to carry out the duties and objectives of the\noffice under this section. Such report shall be posted on the division's\nwebsite no later than one year after the effective date of this section,\nand annually thereafter.\n  4. Assistance to the office. Other state agencies and authorities\nshall provide cooperation and assistance, pursuant to subdivision five\nof section eight hundred thirty-six of this article, to the office in\nthe effective performance of its duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>