<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-03-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_S">
        <num>837-S</num>
        <heading>Search for sex offense conviction records of emergency medical technician and other first responder applicants</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 837-s. Search for sex offense conviction records of emergency\nmedical technician and other first responder applicants. 1. The chief\nofficer of any volunteer ambulance company, as such term is defined in\nsubdivision two of section three of the volunteer ambulance workers'\nbenefit law, any proprietary ambulance service, or any other ambulance\nor emergency medical service providing emergency medical care and\ntransportation of sick or injured persons to health care facilities,\nshall notify every new applicant for emergency medical technician,\nparamedic, certified first responder applicant, or any other applicant\nwho would be responsible for providing emergency medical care and\ntransportation of sick or injured persons to health care facilities,\nincluding applicants seeking to transfer from one ambulance company or\nservice to another, that their personally identifying information will\nbe checked against the public records of those individuals required to\nregister under article six-C of the correction law.\n  2. If such applicant desires to proceed, within ten business days of\nreceiving an application, the chief officer shall inquire of the\ndivision as to whether such applicant is required to register by calling\nthe special telephone number established pursuant to section one hundred\nsixty-eight-p of the correction law. Such chief officer may also check\nthe internet posting subdirectory of level two and three sex offenders\nestablished pursuant to section one hundred sixty-eight-q of the\ncorrection law.\n  3. Where such search reveals that an applicant is registered under\narticle six-C of the correction law, the chief officer of the ambulance\ncompany or service shall determine whether or not such person shall be\neligible to be elected or otherwise appointed as a member of such\nambulance company or service. Such determination shall be made\nconsistent with article twenty-three-A of the correction law and a copy\nof such article shall be provided to the applicant.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>