<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_B">
        <num>837-B</num>
        <heading>Duties of courts and peace officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 837-b. Duties of courts and peace officers. 1. It is hereby made the\nduty of the state administrator of the unified court system; and of\nevery sheriff, county or city commissioner of correction and head of\nevery police department, state, county, or local, and also railroad,\nsteamship, park, aqueduct and tunnel police and town constables, of\nevery district attorney, of every probation agency; and of head of every\ninstitution or department, state, county and local, dealing with\ncriminals and of every other officer, person or agency, dealing with\ncrimes or criminals or with delinquency or delinquents, to transmit to\nthe commissioner not later than the fifteenth day of each calendar\nmonth, or at such times as provided in the rules and regulations adopted\nby the commissioner, such information as may be necessary to enable him\nto comply with subdivision four of section eight hundred thirty-seven.\nSuch reports shall be made upon forms which shall be supplied by the\ncommissioner.\n  2. Such officers and agencies shall install and maintain records\nneeded for reporting data required by the commissioner and shall give\nhim or his accredited agents access to records for the purpose of\ninspection.\n  3. For every neglect to comply with the requirements of this section,\nthe commissioner may apply to the supreme court for an order directed to\nsuch person responsible requiring compliance. Upon such application the\ncourt may issue such order as may be just, and a failure to comply with\nthe order of the court shall be a contempt of court and punishable as\nsuch.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>