<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_P">
        <num>837-P</num>
        <heading>Criminal history records search for certain licenses and registrations in the county of Westchester</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Commission" shall mean the Westchester county solid waste\ncommission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Applicant" shall mean a person applying for a license or\nregistration pursuant to chapter eight hundred twenty-six-a of the laws\nof Westchester county which requires the submission of fingerprints.\n  2. As a condition of eligibility for such licenses and/or\nregistrations, the commission shall obtain two sets of the applicant's\nfingerprints and submit such fingerprints to the division for purposes\nof determining the criminal history of the applicant.\n  3. The first set of fingerprints received by the division shall be\nused to identify the applicant and to conduct a criminal history records\nsearch of the division's New York state files to determine whether or\nnot such applicant has a criminal history in this state. The division\nshall forward the second set of such applicant's fingerprints to the\nfederal bureau of investigation for the purpose of a nationwide criminal\nhistory record check to determine whether such applicant has a criminal\nhistory in any state or federal jurisdiction.\n  4. The division shall promptly transmit the reports of the New York\nstate criminal record search to the executive director of the\ncommission. The federal bureau of investigation reports of nationwide\ncriminal records searches shall be transmitted to the executive director\nof the commission by the most direct means authorized by federal law,\nrules and regulations. All such reports, when received by the\ncommission, shall be marked confidential and securely stored, and shall\nnot be disclosed to any person other than the applicant, although the\ncontents of the report may be disclosed to the members of the\ncommission.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each applicant shall sign a release authorizing the commission\nto submit such applicant's fingerprints to the division and the federal\nbureau of investigation, and for the executive director of the\ncommission to receive the results of such criminal history record\nsearches supplied by the division and the federal bureau of\ninvestigation. Such release shall also advise the applicant that a\ncriminal history record search will be conducted concerning the\napplicant and that he or she may obtain a copy of his or her criminal\nhistory record and seek correction of any information contained in such\nrecord pursuant to regulations promulgated by the division.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each such applicant shall, in advance, make payment to the\ncommission of the fee required pursuant to subdivision eight-a of\nsection eight hundred thirty-seven of this article and any fee imposed\nby the federal bureau of investigation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>