<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_D">
        <num>837-D</num>
        <heading>Soft body ballistic armor vests for police officers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Eligible police officer" means a police officer as defined in\nsubdivision thirty-four of section 1.20 of the criminal procedure law\nwhose regular duties are such as the commissioner determines may expose\nthe officer to serious physical injury which may result in death or\ndisability;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Vest" means a soft body ballistic armor vest;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Municipal corporation" means a county, city, town, village or\npolice district;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Public authority" means an independent autonomous public\ncorporation created by special act of the legislature;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Public benefit corporation" means a corporation organized to\nconstruct or operate a public improvement wholly within the state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"State agency" means a department, board, bureau, commission,\nagency or other division of state government;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Applicant" means a state agency, municipal corporation, public\nauthority, public benefit corporation, or the highest official thereof.\n  2. An applicant which is authorized to and employs police officers may\napply to the commissioner for reimbursement of funds expended for the\npurchase of vests for eligible police officers.\n  3. Reimbursement shall be made only for vests which at the time of\npurchase meet or exceed the minimum standards and specifications in\neffect on that date as prescribed by rules and regulations promulgated\npursuant to subdivisions six and six-a of this section, and shall be\nlimited to the total amount appropriated for such purpose. Reimbursement\nfor any vest shall not exceed an amount which in the judgment of the\ncommissioner would be the cost of a vest conforming to minimum standards\nand specifications in effect at the time the vest was purchased.\nSelection of vests shall be a determination to be made by the applicant\nin accordance with rules and regulations promulgated by the\ncommissioner. Such rules and regulations shall provide that, subject to\nthe provisions of subdivisions six and six-a of this section, the\napplicant may select from a range of vests including those commonly\nknown or classified as type I, type II-A, type II or type III-A in such\nstandard classification systems as the national institute of justice\nstandards for ballistic resistance of police body armor.\n  4. The commissioner shall require any applicant seeking reimbursement\nfor vests to apply for any available federal funds. Any applicant\nfailing to do so shall not be entitled to reimbursement under this\nsection. The commissioner may waive such failure for good cause. The\ncommissioner shall maintain a public record of all such waivers and the\nreasons therefor. Reimbursement may be withheld pending the\ndetermination of an application for federal funds.\n  4-a. An applicant for reimbursement pursuant to this section shall\nreport the name of each e...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the maximum total weight of a vest which provides adequate\nprotection against ballistic penetration and trauma, and which may be\nworn in comfort throughout an eight hour tour of duty;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the ballistic specifications which the vest or any part thereof\nmust be capable of defeating which shall include, but not be limited to,\nthe ballistic specifications of any firearms considered to be standard\nissue to eligible police officers;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the testing procedures appropriate to determining the\neffectiveness of such vests;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the labeling requirements for the vests and component parts\nthereof; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the commercial availability of conforming vests.\n  6-a. In the evaluation of an application for reimbursement, the\ncommissioner shall, at the request of the applicant, give consideration\nto the ballistic specifications of any firearm or firearms considered by\nthe applicant to be standard issue to its police officers.\n  7. The contract specifications for bid for the sale of vests shall\nrequire that a certificate of insurance evidencing that liability\ninsurance providing a minimum coverage of at least five hundred thousand\ndollars per occurrence for injury or death suffered as a result of a\ndefect in the manufacture shall be and remain in effect for the\nprojected life of any vest purchased.\n  8. Neither the state nor the applicant or any employee thereof shall\nbe liable to a police officer or officer's heirs, executors,\nadministrators or assigns, for the death of or injury to the officer\nresulting from any defect or deficiency in a vest for which\nreimbursement is made pursuant to this section.\n  9. A police officer who suffers an injury or death as a result of the\nofficer's failure to wear a vest for which reimbursement is made\npursuant to this section, and officer's heirs, executors, administrators\nor assigns shall not suffer any loss or be denied any benefit or right\nto which they are otherwise entitled; provided, however, that nothing\ncontained herein shall prevent the officer from being subject to a\ndisciplinary proceeding for failure to obey a lawful order of a superior\nofficer requiring the officer to wear a vest.\n  10. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to prohibit\nan applicant from expending its own funds for vests in amounts exceeding\nthe established state reimbursement limitations.\n  11. The commissioner is authorized to promulgate rules and regulations\nto provide for the orderly effectuation of the provisions of this\nsection.\n  12. The commissioner shall establish and maintain a record containing\nthe name of ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>