<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Z"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Z"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="837-Z"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-837-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_837_Z">
        <num>837-Z</num>
        <heading>Law enforcement peer support program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Law enforcement agency" means any department, division, agency,\nboard, commission, or public authority of the state or any subdivision\nthereof that employs police officers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Police officer" means a police officer as defined in section 1.20\nof the criminal procedure law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Peer support communication" includes:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an oral or written communication made in the course of a peer\nsupport counseling session;\n  (ii) a note or report arising out of a peer support counseling\nsession; or\n  (iii) a record of a peer support counseling session.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Peer support counseling program" means a program provided by a\nlaw enforcement agency that provides counseling services from a peer\nsupport specialist to a police officer of the law enforcement agency.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Peer support counseling session" means any counseling formally\nprovided through a peer support counseling program between a peer\nsupport specialist and one or more police officers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Peer support participant" means a police officer who receives\ncounseling services from a peer support specialist.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Peer support specialist" means a police officer who:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has received training in peer support counseling, including\nproviding emotional and moral support to police officers who have been\ninvolved in or exposed to an emotionally traumatic experience in the\ncourse of employment; and\n  (ii) is designated by a law enforcement agency to provide the services\ndescribed in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph.\n  2. Confidentiality. Except as provided in subdivision three of this\nsection, a peer support specialist or peer support participant shall not\ndisclose the contents of a peer support communication to an individual\nwho was not a party to such peer support communication.\n  3. Exceptions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A peer support specialist or peer support participant may disclose\nthe contents of a peer support communication that contains or reveals:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a specific threat of suicide, an expression of suicidal ideation,\nor engagement in self-harm;\n  (ii) a threat of bodily harm or death; or\n  (iii) information relating to the abuse or neglect of a child.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A peer support specialist or peer support participant shall\ndisclose the contents of a peer support communication:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that is required by law to be reported;\n  (ii) that contains an admission of criminal conduct; or\n  (iii) as ordered by a court of competent jurisdiction.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_837_Z__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A peer support participant may at any time give their consent to a\npeer support specialist or peer support participant to disclose the\ncontents of their own peer support communication.\n  4. Written notice. Before the initial peer support counseling session\nof a peer support participant, a peer support specialist shall inform\nthe peer support participant in writing of the confidentiality\nrequirement under subdivision two of this section and the exceptions to\nthat requirement under subdivision three of this section.\n  5. Rules and regulations. The division shall promulgate rules and\nregulations necessary to effectuate this section and shall be empowered\nto identify minimum certifications required of trained members, approved\ntraining courses, record keeping requirements, and retraining\nrequirements.\n  * NB Effective March 18, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>