<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-838"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-838"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-09-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="838"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-838/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-838/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-838/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-838/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_838">
        <num>838</num>
        <heading>Identification of unknown dead and missing persons</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When any person makes a report of a missing person to a law\nenforcement authority, the authority shall request a member of the\nfamily or next of kin of the missing person to authorize the release to\nthe division of the dental records of the person reported missing. The\nrelease shall be on a form supplied by the division. If the person\nreported missing is still missing thirty days after the report is made,\nthe law enforcement authority shall deliver the release to the dentist\nor dentists of the missing person, and request the dentist or dentists\nto deliver such records, including dental x-rays, to the division within\nten days. The form of such request shall also include means by which the\nlaw enforcement authority shall be notified of the delivery of such\nrecords.\n  (ii) When the person reported missing has not been found within thirty\ndays and no family or next of kin exists or can be located, the law\nenforcement authority may execute a written declaration, stating that an\nactive investigation seeking the location of the missing person is being\nconducted, and that the dental records are necessary for the exclusive\npurpose of furthering the investigation. Such written declaration,\nsigned by a peace officer, is sufficient authority for the dentist or\ndentists to release the missing person's dental records, including\ndental x-rays, to the division.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receipt of a properly executed release and request or\ndeclaration, the dentist or dentists shall forward the dental records,\nincluding dental x-rays, to the division, where a file shall be\nmaintained concerning persons reported to it as missing and who have not\nbeen reported to it as found. The file shall contain dental records and\nsuch other information as the division finds to be relevant to assisting\nin the location of a missing person. The law enforcement authority shall\nbe notified of the delivery of such records.\n  6. The division shall compare the dental records received from the\ncounty medical examiners or coroners to dental records of missing\npersons on file with the division. The division shall submit the results\nof the comparison to the appropriate medical examiner or coroner and if\na tentative or positive identification is made, to the law enforcement\nauthority which submitted the report of the missing person.\n  7.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a person previously reported missing has been found, the\nsuperintendent of state police, sheriff, chief of police, coroner or\nmedical examiner, or other law enforcement authority shall erase all\nrecords with respect to such person and/or destroy any documents which\nare maintained pursuant to this section and shall report to the division\nthat the person has been found and that the records and documents have\nbeen so erased or destroyed. After receiving such a report, the division\nshall erase all records with respect to such person and/or destroy any\ndocuments which are maintained pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall be construed as\nprohibiting law enforcement agencies from maintaining case files\nrelating to vulnerable adults, as defined in section eight hundred\nthirty-seven-f-one, who were reported missing, provided, however, that\nany DNA, fingerprints and/or dental records acquired in the course of\nsuch investigation shall be erased and/or destroyed in accordance with\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision after the person previously reported\nmissing has been found.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, if a vulnerable adult, as defined in section eight hundred\nthirty-seven-f-one of this article, previously reported missing has been\nfound, the division shall maintain a sealed record of the case file for\na period of ten years, after which it shall be erased and/or destroyed.\nThe sealed record shall be unsealed if the individual to whom the record\npertains is reported missing on a subsequent occasion or if needed for\nevidentiary purposes in any civil litigation against the division or its\npersonnel that arises from the investigation. However, in the event that\nthere are grounds for a criminal action arising from the investigation,\nnothing in this subdivision shall be interpreted as prohibiting the\ndivision from allowing such records to remain unsealed until such\ncriminal action is concluded or otherwise resolved.\n  (ii) The division shall establish rules and regulations relating to\nthe unsealing of records. Such rules and regulations shall require that,\npursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_838__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph, the process of unsealing\nsuch records shall take no longer than two hours from the time the\ndivision receives a report that a vulnerable adult, for whom there is a\nprevious record, is missing.\n  8. The information contained in the division's missing person files\nshall be made available by it to law enforcement agencies attempting to\nlocate missing persons.\n  9. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no criminal justice\nagency shall establish or maintain any policy which requires the\nobservance of a waiting period before accepting and investigating a\nmissing child report. Upon receipt of a report of a missing child,\ncriminal justice agencies shall make entries of such report to the\nregister in the manner provided by section eight hundred thirty-seven-e\nof this article.\n  10. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no criminal justice\nagency shall establish or maintain any policy that requires the\nobservance of a waiting period before accepting and investigating a\nreport of a missing vulnerable adult as defined in section eight hundred\nthirty-seven-f-one of this article. Upon receipt of a report of such\nmissing vulnerable adult, criminal justice agencies shall make entries\nof such report in the manner provided by subdivision eleven of this\nsection.\n  11. Whenever a criminal justice agency determines that a person is a\nmissing vulnerable adult, as defined in section eight hundred\nthirty-seven-f-one of this article, or that an unidentified living\nperson may be a missing vulnerable adult, such criminal justice agency\nshall enter the report of such missing vulnerable adult in any database\nof missing persons maintained by the division and the federal\ngovernment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>