<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-839"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-839"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-10-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="839"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-839/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-839/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-839/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-839/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_839">
        <num>839</num>
        <heading>Municipal police training council</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be appointed by the governor who shall be a full-time\nfaculty member of a college or university who teaches in the area of\ncriminal justice or police science;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be appointed by the governor from a list of at least six\nnominees submitted by the New York state sheriffs' association, who\nshall be incumbent sheriffs in the state having at least two years of\nservice on the law enforcement training committee of such association or\nhaving other specialized experience in connection with police training\nwhich, in the opinion of the chairman of such law enforcement training\ncommittee, provides the sheriff with at least an equivalent background\nin the field of police training; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be appointed by the governor from a list of at least six\nnominees submitted by the New York state association of chiefs of\npolice, who shall be incumbent chiefs of police or commissioners of\npolice of a municipality in the state having at least two years of\nservice on the police training committee of such association or having\nother specialized experience in connection with police training which,\nin the opinion of the chairman of such training committee, provides the\nchief of police or commissioner of police with at least an equivalent\nbackground in the field of police training; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be the commissioner of police of the city of New York or\na member of his department, designated by such commissioner and approved\nby the governor; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be the superintendent of the state police; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be appointed by the governor who shall be an incumbent\nchief of police or commissioner of police from a municipality in the\nstate with a police department consisting of more than one hundred\nofficers; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be appointed by the governor who shall be an incumbent\nsheriff in the state from an agency with more than one hundred deputy\nsheriffs; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be appointed by the governor who shall be a\nrepresentative of victims of crime; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be appointed by the governor who shall be a\nrepresentative from a community with high numbers of police and\ncommunity interactions; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one shall be appointed by the governor who shall be an incumbent\nexecutive from a peace officer employing agency or municipality.\n  2. The governor shall designate from among the members of the council\na chairman who shall serve during the pleasure of the governor.\n  3. All members of the council appointed by the governor shall be\nappointed for terms of two years, such terms to commence on April first,\nand expire on March thirty-first. Any member chosen to fill a vacancy\ncreated otherwise than by expiration of term shall be appointed for the\nunexpired term of the member whom he is to succeed. Vacancies caused by\nexpiration of a term or otherwise shall be filled in the same manner as\noriginal appointments. Any member may be reappointed for additional\nterms.\n  4. Any member of the council appointed pursuant to paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_839__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this section as an incumbent sheriff, chief of\npolice or commissioner of police, as the case may be, shall immediately\nupon the termination of his holding of said office or employment, cease\nto be a member of the council.\n  5. The council shall meet at least four times in each year. Special\nmeetings may be called by the chairman and shall be called by him at the\nrequest of the governor or upon the written request of six members of\nthe council. The council may establish its own requirements as to quorum\nand its own procedures with respect to the conduct of its meetings and\nother affairs; provided, however, that all recommendations made by the\ncouncil to the governor pursuant to subdivision one of section eight\nhundred forty of this chapter shall require the affirmative vote of six\nmembers of the council.\n  6. Membership on the council shall not constitute the holding of an\noffice, and members of the council shall not be required to take and\nfile oaths of office before serving on the council. The council shall\nnot have the right to exercise any portion of the sovereign power of the\nstate.\n  7. The members of the council shall receive no compensation for their\nservices but shall be allowed their actual and necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of their functions hereunder.\n  8. No member of the council shall be disqualified from holding any\npublic office or employment, nor shall he forfeit any such office or\nemployment, by reason of his appointment hereunder, notwithstanding the\nprovisions of any general, special or local law, ordinance or city\ncharter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>