<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-841"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-841"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="841"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-841/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-841/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-841/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-841/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_841">
        <num>841</num>
        <heading>Functions, powers and duties of the commissioner with respect to the council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 841. Functions, powers and duties of the commissioner with respect\nto the council. In addition to the functions, powers and duties\notherwise provided by this article, the commissioner shall, with the\ngeneral advice of the council, and, in the case of subdivisions one, two\nand three of this section, only in accordance with rules and regulations\npromulgated by the governor pursuant to section eight hundred forty-two\nof this article:\n  1. Approve police training schools administered by municipalities and\nissue certificates of approval to such schools, and revoke such approval\nor certificate;\n  1-a. Approve correctional training programs administered by\nmunicipalities and issue certificates of approval to such programs, and\nrevoke such approval or certificate;\n  2. Certify, as qualified, instructors at approved police training\nschools and issue appropriate certificates to such instructors;\n  2-a. Certify, as qualified, instructors at approved correctional\ntraining programs and issue appropriate certificates to such\ninstructors;\n  3. Certify police officers and peace officers who have satisfactorily\ncompleted basic training programs and issue certificates to such police\nofficers and peace officers, including the issuance of equivalency\ncertificates for basic training certificates issued to peace officers,\nwhere such officers received a certificate for successful completion of\na basic training for police officers program or an approved course for\nstate university of New York public safety officers during a period in\nwhich such peace officer was not employed as a police officer, upon\ndemonstration of adequate equivalent training, the completion of\nsupervised field training, requisite job-related law enforcement\nexperience as determined by the commissioner, and if deemed necessary,\nthe successful completion of relevant police officer training courses\npursuant to section two hundred nine-q of the general municipal law;\n  3-a. Certify correction officers who have satisfactorily completed\nbasic correctional training programs and issue certificates to such\ncorrection officers;\n  4. Cause studies and surveys to be made relating to the establishment,\noperation and approval of municipal police training schools and\ncorrectional training programs;\n  5. Consult with and cooperate with municipal police training schools\nand correctional training programs for the development of advanced\nin-service training programs for police officers, peace officers, and\ncorrection officers and issue appropriate certificates to police\nofficers, peace officers, and correction officers, attesting to their\nsatisfactory completion of such advanced training programs;\n  6. Consult with and cooperate with universities, colleges and\ninstitutes in the state for the development of specialized courses of\nstudy for police officers, peace officers, and correction officers in\npolice science, police administration, and criminal justice;\n  7. Consult with and cooperate with other departments and agencies of\nthe state concerned with police officer and peace officer training;\n  7-a. Consult with and cooperate with the state commission of\ncorrection and other departments and agencies of the state concerned\nwith correction officer training;\n  7-b. Take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that all police\nofficers and peace officers certified pursuant to subdivision three of\nthis section receive appropriate instruction regarding section 60.49 of\nthe criminal procedure law relating to the introduction of opioid\nantagonists into evidence in certain cases.\n  8. Report to the council at each regular meeting of the council and at\nsuch other times as may be appropriate; and\n  9. Prepare, update and distribute to appropriate law enforcement\nofficials the form and content of the written notice required to be\ngiven to victims of family offenses pursuant to subdivision five of\nsection eight hundred twelve of the family court act and subdivision six\nof section 530.11 of the criminal procedure law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>