<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-843"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-843"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="843"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-843/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-843/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-843/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-843/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_843">
        <num>843</num>
        <heading>Division homepage on the internet</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Internet" shall mean an international computer network of both\nfederal and non-federal interoperable packet switched data networks\nwhich users may access through a service provider.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Homepage" shall mean an individual site or address of a document\nor file where particular information can be located.\n  2. The commissioner shall construct, operate and maintain a homepage\non the internet for the purpose of providing a mechanism for the wide\ndissemination of information relating to criminal justice issues.\n  3. The homepage directed to be created by this section shall include\npictures and such other information as the commissioner deems necessary\npertaining to missing children who resided in New York at the time of\ntheir disappearance or whose parent, parents or legal guardian currently\nreside in New York state.\n  4. Such homepage shall also contain pictures and information regarding\nthe ten most wanted criminals in New York state as determined by the\nsuperintendent of state police.\n  5. Such homepage shall also contain the subdirectory maintained\npursuant to section one hundred sixty-eight-q of the correction law.\n  6. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations necessary\nto carry out the provisions of this section. Such rules and regulations\nshall include procedures for determining whether issues of\nconfidentiality or constitutionality exist with regard to any\ninformation proposed to be included on the homepage created by the\ndivision. Where there is a question as to whether the dissemination of\ncertain information by the state would be a violation of confidentiality\nor of an individual's constitutional rights, such information shall not\nbe included on the division's homepage.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>