<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-844-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-844-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-10-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="844-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-844-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-844-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-844-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-844-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_844_B">
        <num>844-B</num>
        <heading>New York state committee for the coordination of police services to elderly persons</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The committee shall consist of a\nrepresentative of the commissioner, representative of the superintendent\nof the New York state police, two representatives of the New York state\nsheriffs association, two representatives of the New York state\nassociation of chiefs of police, two representatives of the New York\nstate district attorneys' association, a representative of the attorney\ngeneral, a representative of the director of the office of victim\nservices, a representative of the director of the state office for the\naging, a representative of the commissioner of social services, a\nrepresentative of the commissioner of the New York city police\ndepartment, a representative of the New York state crime prevention\ncoalition and two elderly representatives one to be appointed by the\ntemporary president of the senate and the other by the speaker of the\nassembly. The commissioner shall make appointments to the committee in\naccordance with nominations submitted by the relevant agencies or\norganizations. Each member of the committee shall be appointed by the\ncommissioner to serve a two year term. Any member appointed by the\ncommissioner may be reappointed for additional terms. Any vacancies\nshall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment and\nvacancies created otherwise than by expiration of term shall be filled\nfor the remainder of that unexpired term.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the performance of its functions, the committee shall, to the\nextent possible, solicit the participation and involvement of retired\nlaw enforcement personnel.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The representative of the commissioner and the superintendent of\nthe state police shall serve as co-chairpersons of the committee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Membership of the committee shall not constitute the holding of a\npublic office, and members of the committee shall not be required to\ntake and file oaths of office before serving on the committee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members of the committee shall receive no compensation for\ntheir services as members.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No member of the committee shall be disqualified from holding any\npublic office or employment, nor shall any member forfeit any employment\nor office by reason of his or her membership on the committee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The committee shall meet as often as deemed necessary, but in no\nevent less than two times per year.\n  3. Duties and responsibilities.  The committee shall advise the\ndivision, the state police, county sheriffs and other local law\nenforcement agencies, and senior advocates chosen in consultation with\nthe state office for the aging, in the study and evaluation of effective\nresponses, including "Triad Programs," to the problems of crime against\nelderly persons. The committee may also consult with experts, service\nproviders and representative organizations engaged in the protection of\nthe elderly and may recommend the development of programs, including\n"Triad Programs", in the state of New York to assist the elderly to\navoid criminal victimization through the coordinated efforts of state\nand local law enforcement agencies and organizations which provide\nservices for the elderly. The committee may also recommend policies and\nprograms to assist law enforcement agencies to implement such programs,\nincluding training and prevention standards and technical assistance.\nSuch recommendations may include the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the establishment of statewide and central clearinghouse for\ninformation and education materials;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the development of innovative community police programs for the\nelderly;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>providing assistance to the municipal police training council in\nthe development and delivery of training to law enforcement\nprofessionals involved in the "Triad Programs" including, but not\nlimited to, the subjects of:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>crimes against the elderly and the protection of elderly persons;\n  (ii) police sensitivity to the needs of elderly persons as victims and\nwitnesses;\n  (iii) social and human services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>providing assistance to state and local law enforcement officials\nand to not-for-profit corporations, organizations with respect to\neffective policies and responses to crimes against elderly persons;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>promoting and facilitating cooperation among state agencies and\nlocal units of government;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>effective advocacy of services to protect elderly persons and\nelderly victims of crime;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>evaluating the relationship between crimes against elderly persons\nand other problems confronting elderly persons, and making\nrecommendations for effective policy response;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the collection of statistical data and research; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_844_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the\npurposes of this section.\n  3-a. Reports. On or before March first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight\nand annually thereafter the committee shall report to the temporary\npresident of the senate, the speaker of the assembly, the chair of the\nassembly committee on aging and the chair of the senate committee on\naging, on the incidence of reports of abuse of elderly persons. Such\nreport shall consist of information from reports forwarded to the\ncommittee by local law enforcement agencies pursuant to section 140.10\nof the criminal procedure law including number of reported incidents,\nages of victims and alleged offenders, circumstances of the incident\nwhether arrests were made and the sentence, if any, of the offenders.\nSuch report shall also recommend policies and programs to aid law\nenforcement agencies, the courts and the New York state office of victim\nservices in efforts to assist elder victims of domestic violence. The\nreport shall also include recommendations designed to assist law\nenforcement agencies in implementing "Triad Programs".\n  4. Definition. As used in this section, the term "Triad Program" shall\nmean the triad cooperative model developed by the American Association\nof retired Persons, the National Sheriffs' Association and the\nInternational Association of Chiefs of Police which calls for the\nparticipation of the sheriff, at least one police chief, and a\nrepresentative of at least one senior citizens' organization within a\ncounty and may include participation by general service coalitions of\nlaw enforcement, victim service, and senior citizen advocate\norganizations.\n  If there is not both a sheriff and a police chief in a county or if\nthe sheriff or a police chief do not participate, a Triad may include in\nthe place of the sheriff or police chief another key law enforcement\nofficial in the county such as a district attorney.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>