<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-11-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="845-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_845_A">
        <num>845-A</num>
        <heading>Presentment of flags lowered to half-staff in memorial of the death of any police officer or peace officer</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 845-a. Presentment of flags lowered to half-staff in memorial of the\ndeath of any police officer or peace officer. In the event the governor\norders the flags of the United States and the State of New York to be\nlowered to half-staff, in memorial of the death of any police officer or\npeace officer identified in the central state registry of police\nofficers and peace officers established pursuant to section eight\nhundred forty-five of this article, the commissioner shall, in\ncooperation with the office of general services, arrange for the\nprocurement of a flag of the United States and a flag of the State of\nNew York, which were flying over the capitol building at the time such\nflags were lowered to half-staff in compliance with the governor's\norder. Upon the procurement of such flags, the commissioner, or his or\nher representative, shall offer the presentment of such flags, without\ncost, to the person designated to dispose of the remains of the officer,\nin whose honor such flags were lowered in memorial.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>