<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-10-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="845"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-845/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_845">
        <num>845</num>
        <heading>Central state registry of police officers and peace officers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_845__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each head of a state or local agency, unit of local government,\nstate or local commission, public authority or other organization which\nemploys police officers or peace officers shall transmit to the\ndivision, no later than the fifteenth day of January annually, and in a\nform and manner prescribed by the division, a list containing the name\nof every police officer or peace officer employed by his or her agency,\ngovernment, commission, authority or organization indicating with\nrespect to each officer his or her date of birth, social security\nnumber, rank or title, employer, and whether he is employed full-time or\npart-time. In addition to such annual list, each such head, whenever\nofficers have been newly appointed or have ceased to serve, shall\nimmediately transmit to the division, in a form and manner prescribed by\nthe division, a list containing the names of such officers which, in the\ninstance of new appointees, shall include all the information required\nto be furnished in the annual listing.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_845__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever officers have ceased to serve, each such head shall\nimmediately transmit to the division, in a form and manner prescribed by\nthe division, notification that any such officer has ceased to serve due\nto a leave of absence, resignation, removal, removal for cause, or\nremoval during a probationary period.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_845__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The division shall establish rules and regulations to provide\nfor a permanent system of identification for each police and peace\nofficer, which shall include procedures for updating the registry upon\nan officer's failure to complete required training within the time\nlimitations established in law or regulation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_845__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such rules and regulations shall also establish procedures, in\naccordance with the state administrative procedure act, for a process as\ndescribed in this paragraph. When it shall appear to the commissioner or\nthe commissioner's designee that a notification of the reason such an\nofficer ceased to serve, received by the commissioner pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_845__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section, is inaccurate in a\nmaterial respect, the commissioner shall attempt to resolve such\ndiscrepancy by contacting the head of the office that submitted such\nnotification. If such informal efforts do not resolve the discrepancy\npromptly, the commissioner may issue a notice to such head and the\nofficer who is the subject of such notification of an inquiry into the\naccuracy of such record. After notice and an opportunity for each to be\nheard, if the commissioner finds such record to be inaccurate with\nrespect to such matter in a material respect, the commissioner shall\nprovide notice of such determination to each of them and, pursuant to\nsuch determination, may correct such record. The commissioner shall\nmaintain a clear documentary record of both the original record and the\ncorrection made.\n  4. Upon the failure or refusal to comply with the requirements of\nsubdivision two of this section, the commissioner may apply to the\nsupreme court for an order directed to the person responsible requiring\ncompliance. Upon such application the court may issue such order as may\nbe just, and a failure to comply with the order of the court shall be a\ncontempt of court and punishable as such.\n  5. The division shall cooperate with the division of state police in\nmaking the information in the central registry of police and peace\nofficers available for the purpose of verifying transactions involving\nfirearms.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>