<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="846-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_846_J">
        <num>846-J</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 846-j. Legislative findings. Motor vehicle theft and motor vehicle\ninsurance fraud is a major problem in this state costing honest motor\nvehicle policyholders billions of dollars annually. As the cost of motor\nvehicle insurance continues to rise, this essential coverage has become\nless affordable and more out of reach for many New Yorkers. Between\nnineteen hundred eighty-five and nineteen hundred ninety-two, New York\nhas seen over a fifty percent increase in the number of motor vehicle\nthefts. Over one hundred sixty thousand motor vehicles are stolen\nannually in this state at a cost of over seven hundred million dollars.\nBetween nineteen hundred eighty-six and nineteen hundred ninety-two, New\nYork has also seen a one hundred sixty-six percent increase in the\nnumber of reported fraudulent claims; estimates have put the cost to\npolicyholders for fraudulent activities at ten percent of premiums paid.\nThe legislature acknowledges a direct relationship between the incidence\nof motor vehicle theft, motor vehicle insurance fraud and the cost of\nmotor vehicle insurance premium rates. The legislature finds, therefor,\nthat to reduce the overall cost of motor vehicle insurance in this\nstate, measures must be enacted which specifically address the incidence\nof motor vehicle theft and motor vehicle insurance fraud. This\nlegislation creates the motor vehicle theft and insurance fraud\nprevention demonstration program, the goals of which are as follows: to\nprovide an integrated means to prevent, deter and reduce the incidence\nof motor vehicle theft and motor vehicle insurance fraud by developing\nand providing funding for demonstration programs which include education\non motor vehicle theft and insurance fraud prevention, programs on motor\nvehicle theft and insurance fraud prevention and specialized law\nenforcement units to combat motor vehicle theft and insurance fraud.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>