<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="846-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_846_D">
        <num>846-D</num>
        <heading>Payments to companies for the performance of company activities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 846-d. Payments to companies for the performance of company\nactivities. 1. Each contract entered into with a company shall provide\nfor payment to such company for approved activities to be performed by\nit.\n  2. Payment to companies pursuant to this article shall be restricted\nto sums required for the payment of salaries and wages of employees, and\nfor the purchase of necessary equipment for the execution of approved\nactivities. Nothing contained herein shall be interpreted to authorize\nexpenditures leading to the possession, utilization, carrying, or\ndissemination of firearms or other deadly weapons, regardless of whether\nthe appropriate license has been issued for same. Qualifying equipment\nexpenditures may include, but shall not be limited to, locks and audio\nwarning devices for use by financially needy, victim-prone residents,\npatrol vehicles (for the exclusive use of volunteers), radios, signs,\ngasoline, support services for crime victims, publicity and office\nsupplies. Authorized expenditures may not include salaries of, or fees\nfor, the hiring of private guards or charges for or expenses incurred\nfor the use of vehicles for private guards.\n  3. Payments shall be made by the division to a company, not less\nfrequently than quarter-annually to compensate such company for the\ncompany activities which it shall undertake to perform.\n  4. No company receiving payments from any other funds of the state for\nactivities performed by it under the contract shall receive or be\neligible to receive payments pursuant to this article. To the extent\nother state funds are received in violation of this subdivision payments\notherwise due under this article shall be accordingly reduced.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>