<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="846-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_846_B">
        <num>846-B</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 846-b. Definitions. As used in this article, the following words and\nphrases shall have the following meanings:\n  1. "Commissioner" shall mean the commissioner of the division of\ncriminal justice services.\n  2. "Division" shall mean the division of criminal justice services.\n  3. "Municipality" shall mean any city, town or village, incorporated\nor unincorporated, within the state of New York.\n  4. "Company" shall mean any organization, incorporated or\nunincorporated, organized exclusively for a purpose or purposes, not for\npecuniary profit or financial gain and no part of the assets, income or\nprofit of which is distributable to, or inures to the benefit of, its\nmembers, directors (or their equivalent) or officers except to the\nextent permitted by law, and which is engaged in one or more of the\ncompany activities specified in subdivision five of this section.\n  5. "Company activities" shall mean activities of neighborhood\npreservation crime prevention, geared towards the heightened awareness\nand practice of community members in techniques stressing the reduction\nof opportunities for crimes to occur and the increased possibility of\npolice apprehension of criminals. Company activities should also seek to\ndevelop and strengthen a sense of neighborhood identity and a\nconstructive attitude in that neighborhood. Activities may include, but\nnot be limited to, tenant-lobby patrols, auto patrols, street-foot\npatrols, home and business security surveys, and dispersal of crime\nprevention literature and equipment; provided, however, that nothing\ncontained herein shall be interpreted to authorize the possession,\ncarrying, use or dissemination of firearms or other deadly weapons\nregardless of whether the appropriate license has been issued for such\nactivity.  Activities may also include the involvement of senior\ncitizens and youth in escort services, auxiliary police services and the\nutilization of community outreach through publicity of approved\nanti-crime techniques. All activities must have prior approval from the\ndivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>