<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="846-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-846-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_846_M">
        <num>846-M</num>
        <heading>Plan of operation and grant award process</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_846_M__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The moneys received by the fund shall be expended in a manner\nthat is consistent with the plan of operation, pursuant to\nappropriation, only to reimburse costs incurred by provider agencies for\npilot program activities relating to the detection, prevention or\nreduction of motor vehicle theft and motor vehicle insurance fraud.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_846_M__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Activities eligible for funding include, but are not limited to,\nthe following: prosecution and adjudication services; law enforcement\nservices; neighborhood or community based programs designed to reduce\nthe incidence of motor vehicle theft and motor vehicle insurance fraud;\neducational programs designed to inform owners of motor vehicles\nconcerning activities designed to prevent the incidence of theft of\nmotor vehicles and fraudulent claims practices; and programs designed to\nexamine, evaluate and make recommendations relating to the efficacy of\nmotor vehicle theft prevention devices or methods including, but not\nlimited to, passive tracking devices designed to identify the location\nof a motor vehicle at any given point in time and window glass etching\nwith vehicle identification numbers or any other unique identifying\nsymbol including decal programs such as New York city's operation combat\nauto theft (C.A.T.). Funds provided under this program shall be used to\naugment, and not to supplant, the provider agency's current funding, if\nany, for motor vehicle theft and insurance fraud detection, prevention,\nor reduction activities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_846_M__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In allocating the moneys for the program, the commissioner, upon\nrecommendation of the board, shall, to the greatest extent possible,\ntake into account the geographic incidence of motor vehicle theft and\ninsurance fraud, whereby localities with the greatest incidence of motor\nvehicle theft and insurance fraud shall be targeted for the purposes of\nthis program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_846_M__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state comptroller shall conduct an audit of all moneys\nreceived and expended by the fund as well as all other funds expended\nfrom any other source for the purposes of this program, and shall submit\na written report detailing such audit to the governor and legislature on\nor before March first of each year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>