<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="847-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_847_B">
        <num>847-B</num>
        <heading>Tug Hill commission; continuation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 847-b. Tug Hill commission; continuation. There is hereby continued\nthe Tug Hill commission, hereinafter referred to as the commission, to\nconsist of nine members to be appointed as follows: three by the\ngovernor, three by the temporary president of the senate and three by\nthe speaker of the assembly. All of the appointees of each such officer\nshall be residents of the Tug Hill region, which includes, in Jefferson\ncounty, the towns of Adams, Champion, Lorraine, Rodman, Rutland,\nWatertown and Worth; in Lewis county, the towns of Denmark, Harrisburg,\nLewis, Leyden, Lowville, Martinsburg, Montague, Osceola, Pinckney, Turin\nand West Turin; in Oneida county, the towns of Annsville, Ava,\nBoonville, Camden, Florence, Floyd, Forestport, Lee, Remsen, Steuben,\nTrenton, Vienna and Western; and in Oswego county, the towns of Albion,\nAmboy, Boylston, Constantia, Hastings, Orwell, Parish, Redfield, West\nMonroe and Williamstown. At least two commissioners shall be selected\nfrom each of the four counties respectively. The commission shall choose\nfrom among its members a chairman, vice-chairman and secretary. The\nmembers of the Tug Hill commission serving on the effective date of this\narticle shall continue in office and shall be deemed and held to\nconstitute the members of the Tug Hill commission until their terms\nexpire on August first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight. Thereafter, the\nterm of office of each member appointed shall be for five years. Each\nmember shall hold office until a successor has been appointed and\nqualified.  Vacancies in membership of the commission occurring from any\ncause shall be filled by the officer authorized to make the original\nappointment of the member whose office becomes vacant.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>