<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="847-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-847-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_847_C">
        <num>847-C</num>
        <heading>Tug Hill commission powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 847-c. Tug Hill commission powers and duties. The commission shall\nhave the following powers and duties:\n  1. To adopt and use a seal; to sue and be sued; to appoint and remove\nofficers, agents and employees and determine their qualifications,\nduties and compensation; to acquire, hold and dispose of personal\nproperty; to retain or employ counsel, private consultants, and\nindependent contractors; to make and execute contracts and all other\ninstruments necessary or convenient for the exercise of its powers and\nfunctions under this article.\n  2. To prepare, publish and disseminate information or reports to\nhighlight for state agencies, local governments, and the general public\nissues, problems, and opportunities relevant to the Tug Hill region, in\nconcert with state and federal agencies and others.\n  3. To stimulate action by public and private organizations on\nregionwide issues, problems and opportunities that affect the Tug Hill\nregion, with primary emphasis on possible solutions at the local level\nand with attention to the ways in which information developed and\nexperience gained in the Tug Hill region may be usefully shared\nelsewhere in New York state.\n  4. To request and receive from any department, division, office,\nboard, bureau, commission, agency, or instrumentality of the state and\nfrom any political subdivision or agency thereof, such assistance and\ndata as will enable it to conduct its studies and investigations\nhereunder.\n  5. To assist local governments and other appropriate state and local\norganizations to plan and work for a positive future, and to do this, as\nfar as possible, through intermunicipal cooperation and through\ntechnical assistance, including planning assistance, legal assistance,\ntraining, citizen education and participation assistance, and assistance\nin preparation of grant applications to other entities.\n  6. To serve a coordinating role in utilizing the capabilities of other\norganizations to carry out the duties prescribed in this section.\n  7. To establish a central clearinghouse for technical studies, which\nmay be used by members of the public, local governments, and state\nagencies in addressing state and regionwide resource conservation and\ndevelopment issues.\n  8. To develop agreements with local, county, or regional agencies to\nprovide staff services; through grants or contracts to help finance\nservices for intermunicipal cooperation; to provide planning services in\nconjunction with county planning departments and regional planning\nboards, and to provide supplementary technical assistance and\neducational services through public or private groups.\n  9. To apply for and receive from the federal and state government and\npublic and private agencies, funds to accomplish the purposes of the\ncommission and to solicit, receive and utilize gifts and donations of\nany kind from any source.\n  10. To assist municipalities in preparing and adopting comprehensive\nplanning programs, including appropriate laws, ordinances and codes.\n  11. To enter into agreements for the extension of its powers and\nduties to other local governments, in concert with local, state and\nfederal agencies and others.\n  12. To lease and manage real property, solely for the purpose of\nproviding for the official offices of said commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>