<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-875"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-875"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="875"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-875/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-875/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-875/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-875/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_875">
        <num>875</num>
        <heading>Declaration of purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 875. Declaration of purpose. The legislature finds and determines\nas follows:\n  1. Increasing regulation of business in the state has been accompanied\nby a proliferation of permits entailing multiple requirements,\njurisdictional overlaps, and business uncertainties. More than\nthirty-five state agencies issue permits affecting business. Permits\nnumber in the hundreds in statute with still more in rules and\nregulations.  Business moves in a maze of permits, licenses, and\napprovals.\n  2. The public interest will be served by overcoming the delays and\nburdensome permit requirements which too often accompany business\nregulation and by fixing responsibility for continuing and comprehensive\naction designed to consolidate, simplify, or expedite the permit\nprocedures of state agencies.\n  3. Accomplishment of these purposes will be facilitated through the\nestablishment of an office for business permits and a program of\nbusiness permit assistance in state government which will provide\ncomprehensive permit information, one-stop service for permit\napplicants, and the coordination of permit processing and review.\n  4. It is the intent of the legislature that the program of business\npermit assistance will be directed to commercial, or non-profit,\nbusiness undertakings, projects, and activities rather than to the\nroutine issuance of licenses and permits for individual privileges,\nincluding the occupational licenses for practicing a trade or\nprofession, licenses for operating a motor vehicle and amateur sporting\nlicenses, such as for hunting and fishing.\n  5. It is the further intent of the legislature that the program of\nbusiness permit assistance focus primarily on those business\nundertakings needing special help with state agency requirements and\nprocedures and, generally improve the delivery of governmental services\nto businesses locating or expanding in the state.\n  6. The program of business permit assistance will thereby constitute\nan economic advantage to the state and facilitate such undertakings as\ncommercial, industrial and residential developments; medical, social,\nand educational installations; industrial location or expansion; changes\nin manufacturing, production, and distribution processes; local\ngovernment projects; and general construction.\n  * NB Authority of office terminated per ยง 893 December 31, 1995\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>