<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-877"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-877"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="877"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-877/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-877/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-877/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-877/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_877">
        <num>877</num>
        <heading>Office of business permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 877. Office of business permits. 1. There is hereby created in the\nexecutive department an office of business permits. The head of the\noffice shall be the director of business permits who shall be appointed\nby the governor, by and with the advice and consent of the senate, and\nwho shall hold office at the pleasure of the governor.\n  2. The director shall devote his whole time and capacity to his duties\nas director. He shall receive an annual salary to be fixed by the\ngovernor within the amount made available therefor by appropriation and\nshall be allowed his actual and necessary expenses in the performance of\nhis duties.\n  3. The director shall direct the work of the office and shall be the\nchief executive officer of the office. The director may appoint such\nofficers and employees as he may deem necessary, prescribe their duties,\nfix their compensation, and provide for the reimbursement of their\nexpenses, all within amounts made available therefor by appropriation.\n  4. The director shall report to the secretary to the governor on the\nactivities of the office to ensure their consistency with the overall\neconomic development policies of the state.\n  5. The secretary to the governor, working with state agency heads\nconcerned with economic affairs shall assure that the activities of the\noffice are fully coordinated with related activities of state agencies\nproviding related services.\n  * NB Authority of office terminated per ยง 893 December 31, 1995\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>