<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-878"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-878"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="878"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-878/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-878/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-878/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-878/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_878">
        <num>878</num>
        <heading>General functions, powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 878. General functions, powers and duties. The office of business\npermits, by and through the director or his duly authorized officers and\nemployees, shall have the following functions, powers and duties:\n  1. To provide comprehensive information on permits required for\nbusiness undertakings, projects, and activities in the state and to make\nsuch information available to applicants and generally to any person.\n  2. To develop a master application procedure to expedite the\nidentification and processing of such permits.\n  3. To assist applicants in obtaining timely and efficient permit\nreview and the resolution of issues arising therefrom.\n  4. To consolidate hearings required pursuant to permit applications\nwhen feasible and advantageous.\n  5. To provide the conceptual review of business undertakings at an\nearly stage of planning to provide interested persons with an official\nopinion as to the general acceptability of such undertakings.\n  6. To encourage and facilitate the participation of federal and local\ngovernment agencies in permit coordination.\n  7. To make recommendations for eliminating, consolidating,\nsimplifying, expediting, or otherwise improving permit procedures\naffecting business undertakings.\n  14. To assist any person in the preparation of a petition for a\ndeclaratory ruling to be submitted pursuant to section two hundred six\nof the state administrative procedure act.\n  15. To monitor agency compliance with section two hundred six of the\nstate administrative procedure act and to make recommendations to\nagencies for improving such compliance.\n  17. To adopt such rules and regulations, procedures, instructions, and\nforms as are required to carry out the functions, powers, and duties\nimposed upon the office by this article.\n  * NB Authority of office expired per ยง 893 December 31, 1995\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>