<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-885"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-885"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="885"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-885/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-885/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-885/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-885/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_885">
        <num>885</num>
        <heading>Consolidated hearings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 885. Consolidated hearings. 1. Any applicant for permits required\nfor a business undertaking, project, or activity, or any state agency\nhaving jurisdiction of the required permits, may request the office to\ncoordinate any public hearings. The office may consolidate such hearings\ninsofar as may be feasible.\n  2. A consolidated hearing shall be conducted in a manner consistent\nwith the state administrative procedure act.  The director or his\ndesignee shall be the presiding officer and shall establish an agenda\nfor, and regulate, the course of the hearing. A representative of each\nstate agency within whose jurisdiction a specific application lies shall\nconduct that portion of the hearing pertaining to the submission of\ninformation and data relating to such application.  The hearing may be\ncontinued by the presiding officer when appropriate and shall be\nrecorded in a suitable manner.\n  3. The office, with the consent of the state agencies having permit\njurisdiction, may provide for a pre-hearing conference to assist in the\ndisposition of the type, time, place, and parties of the consolidated\nhearing, the simplification of the issues, the stipulations as to agreed\nfacts and necessary documents, and any other relevant matters.\n  * NB Authority of office terminated per ยง 893 December 31, 1995\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>