<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-887"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-887"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="887"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-887/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-887/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-887/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-887/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_887">
        <num>887</num>
        <heading>Implementation of services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 887. Implementation of services. 1. Not later than six months from\nthe effective date of this article, the office shall establish the\npermit information, coordination, and assistance services provided for\nin section eight hundred eighty through section eight hundred\neighty-five of this article, except as otherwise provided in subdivision\nthree of this section.\n  2. Services so rendered by the office shall be made available without\ncharge, provided that nothing contained herein shall relieve an\napplicant of any part of the fees or charges established for the review\nand approval of permit applications or relieve an applicant of any of\nthe apportioned costs of a consolidated hearing conducted under section\neight hundred eighty-five of this article.\n  3. Under its rules the office shall provide for the implementation of\nthe master application procedure contained in section eight hundred\neighty-one of this article and shall specify the permits to which the\nmaster application procedure is applicable. Prior to the adoption of any\nrule relating to the inclusion, exclusion, or addition of permits to\nwhich the master application procedure is applicable, the office shall\ngive notice of such rule and hold a public hearing thereon.\n  4. Each state agency having jurisdiction of any permit to which the\nmaster application procedure is applicable shall designate an officer or\nemployee to act as permit liaison officer to cooperate with the office\nin carrying out the provisions of this article.\n  * NB Authority of office terminated per ยง 893 December 31, 1995\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>