<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-889-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-889-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="889-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-889-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-889-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-889-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-889-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_889_A">
        <num>889-A</num>
        <heading>Business permit assistance in empire zones</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_889_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the\ndesignation of an empire zone pursuant to article eighteen-B of the\ngeneral municipal law, the office, by and through the director or his\nduly authorized officers and employees, shall establish a business\npermit assistance program to provide in such empire zone the business\npermit assistance services authorized in this article. Such program\nshall enable an applicant for a permit for a business undertaking,\nproject or activity in an empire zone to confer with the office to\nobtain on-site assistance in the empire zone in the prompt and efficient\nprocessing and review of applications for such permits.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_889_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In providing such on-site permit assistance, the director may\ndesignate one or more officers or employees of the office to act as\npermit assistance managers to fulfill, with respect to empire zones, the\npurposes set forth in subdivision two of section eight hundred\neighty-four of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_889_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The director may request and shall receive the assistance of any\nstate agency having jurisdiction over any business permits to be issued\nin an empire zone in designating an officer or employee of such agency\nto coordinate agency efforts in cooperation with the office in providing\na business permit assistance program for such empire zone.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_889_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any state agency having jurisdiction of any business permits to be\nissued in an empire zone shall, to the maximum extent feasible,\nestablish procedures to expedite applications for business permits in an\nempire zone.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_889_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To the extent provided for in any agreement between the office and\na county, city, town or village, as authorized by article eighteen-B of\nthe general municipal law, the office may provide a business permit\nassistance program to applicants for permits required by such county,\ncity, town or village for a business undertaking, project or activity in\nan empire zone.\n  * NB Authority of office terminated per ยง 893 December 31, 1995\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>