<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-897"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-897"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="897"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-897/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-897/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-897/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-897/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_897">
        <num>897</num>
        <heading>General functions, powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 897. General functions, powers and duties. The office of urban\nrevitalization by and through the director or his duly authorized\nofficers and employees, shall have the following functions, powers and\nduties;\n  1. To provide comprehensive information on existing state, federal and\nlocal urban development and revitalization programs upon request to any\nlocal agency located in distressed urban area of the state.\n  2. To receive notification from all state agencies engaged in urban\ndevelopment and revitalization programs of program descriptions,\nappropriation data, application procedures and local agencies or\ncommunity non-profit organizations receiving state assistance for such\nprograms. The office shall, upon receipt of such notification, make\navailable a listing of existing programs and assure that all related\nlocal agencies are notified of their existence.\n  3. To assist, upon request, applicant local agencies located in\ndistressed urban areas in obtaining timely and efficient responses from\nstate and federal agencies, to assist such applicants in consideration\nof alternative program grant strategies and to assist state and federal\nagencies in cooperative approaches to address the needs of such\napplicants.\n  4. To review application procedures formulated by state agencies and\nto recommend improvements designed to increase the efficiency of these\nprocedures and to enhance the probability for the success of such\napplications from local agencies located in distressed urban areas.\n  5. To make available to local agencies, individuals and corporations\nlocated in distressed urban areas assistance concerning grant\napplications procedures and techniques and job development opportunities\nand to encourage the assistance of the private sector in effectuating\nthe revitalization of distressed urban areas.\n  6. To administer local assistance programs authorized by the\nlegislature pursuant to statute, within amounts appropriated therefor,\ndesigned to encourage revitalization of distressed urban areas.\n  7. To assist the governor, the cabinet and the legislature in the\ncoordination, consolidation and improvement of state policy for\ndistressed urban areas, through the establishment, as far as is\npractical, of offices in such areas, through the holding of public\nhearings and to represent the governor before federal agencies on\nmatters of importance to coordinate policy for the revitalization of\nsuch areas.\n  8. To apply for and receive, consistent with the appropriation,\nnotification, and approval requirements of the state finance law, grants\nor financial assistance from federal agencies.\n  9. To adopt such rules and regulations, procedures, instructions, and\nforms as are required to carry out the functions, powers and duties\nimposed upon the office by this article.\n  10. To serve as staff for the cabinet in the formation of agendas for\nregular meetings, the preparation of minutes of such meetings, the\ndevelopment of policy papers and assuring the implementation of policies\nand programs proposed by the cabinet and adopted by the governor.\n  * NB Expired March 31, 1985\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>