<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="903"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_903">
        <num>903</num>
        <heading>Temporary assignment or permanent transfer of personnel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 903. Temporary assignment or permanent transfer of personnel.  The\ndirector, in consultation with the head of the state agency concerned\nand with the approval of the director of the budget, may provide for the\ntemporary or permanent assignment or transfer of officers and employees\nof state agencies to the office employees permanently transferred shall\nbe transferred without further examination or qualification and shall\nretain their respective civil service classification and status. Any\nemployee who, at the time of such transfer, has a temporary or\nprovisional appointment shall be transferred subject to the same right\nof removal, examination or termination as though such transfer had not\nbeen made. No existing right or benefit, including retirement benefits\nor remedy of any character, shall be lost, impaired or affected by\nreason of this article. The director of the budget shall be responsible\nfor timely notification of all such assignments and transfers to the\nchairman of the senate finance committee and the chairman of the\nassembly ways and means committee. Transfer of employees pursuant to\nthis article shall be governed solely and exclusively by the provisions\nhereof notwithstanding other provisions of the law.\n  * NB Expired March 31, 1985\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>