<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-910"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-910"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="910"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-910/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-910/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-910/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-910/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_910">
        <num>910</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 910. Legislative findings. The legislature hereby finds that New\nYork state's coastal area and inland waterways are unique with a variety\nof natural, recreational, industrial, commercial, ecological, cultural,\naesthetic and energy resources of statewide and national significance.\n  The resources of the state's coastal areas and inland waterways are\nincreasingly subject to the pressures of population growth and economic\ndevelopment, which include requirements for industry, commerce,\nresidential development, recreation and for the production of energy.\nThese competing demands result in the loss of living marine resources\nand wildlife, the diminution of open space areas, shoreline erosion,\npermanent, adverse changes to ecological systems and a loss of economic\nopportunities.\n  The social and economic well-being and the general welfare of the\npeople of the state are critically dependent upon the preservation,\nenhancement, protection, development and use of the natural and man-made\nresources of the state's coastal area and inland waterways.\n  The legislature further finds that it is in the interest of the people\nof the state that coordinated and comprehensive policy and planning for\npreservation, enhancement, protection, development and use of the\nstate's coastal and inland waterway resources take place to insure the\nproper balance between natural resources and the need to accommodate the\nneeds of population growth and economic development.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>