<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-911"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-911"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="911"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_911">
        <num>911</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_911__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state's coastal waters, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_911__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe adjacent shorelands, including landlocked waters and subterranean\nwaters, to the extent such coastal waters and adjacent lands are\nstrongly influenced by each other including, but not limited to,\nislands, wetlands, beaches, dunes, barrier islands, cliffs, bluffs,\ninter-tidal estuaries and erosion prone areas. The coastal area extends\nto the limit of the state's jurisdiction on the water side and inland\nonly to encompass those shorelands, the uses of which have a direct and\nsignificant impact on the coastal waters. The coastal area boundaries\nare as shown on the coastal area map on file in the office of the\nsecretary of state as required in section nine hundred fourteen of this\narticle.\n  2. "Coastal area boundaries" shall mean the boundaries prepared by the\nsecretary of state pursuant to section forty-seven of chapter four\nhundred sixty-four of the laws of nineteen hundred seventy-five.\n  3. "Coastal waters" means lakes Erie and Ontario, the St. Lawrence and\nNiagara rivers, the Hudson river south of the federal dam at Troy, the\nEast river, the Harlem river, the Kill von Kull and Arthur Kill, Long\nIsland sound and the Atlantic ocean, and their connecting water bodies,\nbays, harbors, shallows and marshes.\n  4. "Inland waterways" shall mean</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_911__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state's major inland lakes\nconsisting of lakes Baldwin, Ballston, Big Tupper, Black, Brant,\nCampfire, Canadarago, Canandaigua, Carmel, Casse, Cazenovia, Cayuga,\nChamplain, Charles, Chateaugay, Chautauqua, Chazy, Conesus, Cranberry,\nDean Pond (in the county of Putnam), Drew, East Caroga, Dickiebusch,\nEcho (in the county of Westchester), George, Gilead, Glencoma, Great\nSacandaga, Honeoye, Indian, Journeys End, Junior (in the county of\nWestchester), Furnace Brook, Katonah, Kentwood, Keuka, Kirk, Kitchawan,\nLittle Wolf (in the county of Franklin), Lincolndale, Long, Lost (in the\ncounty of Putnam), Meahagh, Mirror, MacGregor, Mahopac, Minerva,\nMohegan, Nimham, Neatahwanta, Northville, Oceola, Oneida, Onondaga,\nOscaleta, Ossi, Otisco, Otsego, Owasco, Palmer, Paradox, Peach,\nPeekskill, Placid, Purdys, Putnam, Raquette, Rippowam, Ronkonkoma,\nRound, Sacandaga, Saratoga, Schroon, Secor, Seneca, Shenorock,\nSkaneateles, Silver (in the county of Wyoming), Sagamore, Saranac, Seven\nHills, Simon (in the county of Franklin), Sparkle, Tibet, Tonetta,\nTeakettle Spout, Truesdale, Waccabuc, West Caroga, White (in the county\nof Sullivan) and Wixon, and the Fulton chain of lakes;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_911__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state's\nmajor rivers comprised of the Allegheny, Ausable, Battenkill, Black,\nBoquet, Bronx, Canisteo, Chaumont (including Chaumont bay), Chemung,\nChenango, Cohocton, Delaware, Deer, Genesee, Grasse, Great Chazy,\nHoosic, Hudson north of the federal dam at Troy, Indian, Little (in the\nAdirondack park), Little Ausable, Little Salmon (including north and\nsouth branches), Mad, Mettowee, Mohawk, Oswegatchie, Oswego, Pocantico,\nRacquette, Sacandaga, Salmon, Saranac, Saw Mill, Schroon, St. Regis,\nSusquehanna, Tenmile, Tioga, Tioughnioga, Wallkill and Buffalo rivers,\nand the north and middle branches of the Moose river;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_911__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state's\nmajor creeks comprised of the 18 Mile Creek located in Erie county,\nChittenango Creek, Bash Bish and Kinderhook Creek located in Columbia\ncounty, Kinderhook Creek located in Rensselaer county, Basher Kill,\nBushkill, Cattaraugus, Cayadutta, North Chuctanunda, Cincinnati, East\nKill, Esopus (including upper and lower branches), Ferguson, Fish\n(including east and west branches), Gooseberry, Great Valley, Kennyetto,\nLittle Sandy, Moodna, Moyer, Mud Creek located in Oneida county,\nNinemile Creek, Onondaga, Oriskany, Peekskill Hollow, Reall, Roeliff\nJansen Kill, Rondout, Sandy, Sauquoit, Schoharie, Shawangunk Kill, Six\nMile Creek, South Sandy, Oatka, Tonawanda, West Kill, Scajaquada,\nWappinger, Webatuck, Wassaic, Willsey in the village of Wurtsboro, Wood\nCreek located in Herkimer county, Wood Creek located in Oneida county,\nBlack Creek located in Monroe county, Black Creek located in Genesee and\nWyoming counties, Ellicott Creek located in Erie county, Wynantskill,\nClaverack, Taghkanic, Agawamuck, Wyomanock, and Ley Creek and Butternut\nCreek located in Onondaga county, Nanticoke and Sawkill (in Ulster\ncounty), Fishkill Creek, Saw Kill and Fall Kill located in Dutchess\ncounty, Otter Kill Creek located in Orange county, Black Meadow Creek\nlocated in Orange county, and the Silver Lake Outlet located in Wyoming\ncounty;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_911__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the Barge Canal System as defined in section two of the\ncanal law; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_911__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the adjacent shorelands to the extent that such\ninland waters and adjacent lands are strongly influenced by each other\nincluding, but not limited to, islands, wetlands, beaches, dunes,\nbarrier islands, cliffs, bluffs and erosion prone areas.\n  5. "State agency" means any department, bureau, commission, board,\npublic authority or other agency of the state, including any public\nbenefit corporation any member of which is appointed by the governor.\n  6. "Comprehensive harbor management plan" shall mean a plan to address\nthe problems of conflict, congestion and competition for space in the\nuse of harbors, surface waters and underwater lands of the state within\na city, town or village or abounding a city, town or village to a\ndistance of fifteen hundred feet from shore. A harbor management plan\nmust consider regional needs and, where applicable, must consider the\ncompeting needs of commercial shipping and recreational boating,\ncommercial and recreational fishing and shellfishing, aquaculture and\nwaste management, mineral extraction, dredging, public access,\nrecreation, habitat and other natural resource protection, water\nquality, open space, aesthetic values and common law riparian or\nlittoral rights, and the public interest in such lands underwater.\n  7. "Water dependent use" means an activity which can only be conducted\non, in, over or adjacent to a water body because such activity requires\ndirect access to that water body, and which involves, as an integral\npart of such activity, the use of the water.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>