<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-913"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-913"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="913"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-913/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-913/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-913/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-913/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_913">
        <num>913</num>
        <heading>Functions; powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 913. Functions; powers and duties. The secretary shall have the\nfollowing functions, powers and duties:\n  1. To advise the governor and agencies of state government concerning\nplanning, programs and policies for the achievement of wise use of the\nland and water resources of coastal areas and inland waterways, giving\nfull consideration to ecological, cultural, historic, aesthetic values\nand the needs for economic development and to encourage public and\nprivate institutions to preserve, protect, enhance, develop and use\ncoastal and inland waterway resources in a manner consistent with the\npurposes and policies of this article.\n  2. To evaluate and make recommendations on federal, state and local\nprograms and legislation relating to coastal and inland waterway\nresources issues;\n  3. To review and approve acceptable waterfront revitalization programs\nas herein provided;\n  4. To review, evaluate and issue recommendations and opinions\nconcerning programs and actions of state agencies which may have the\npotential to affect the policies and purposes of this article, including\nbut not limited to, programs within the jurisdiction of the departments\nof state, agriculture and markets, environmental conservation, public\nservice, commerce and transportation, the offices of energy and parks\nand recreation and the office of general services.\n  5. To enter into contracts with any person, firm, corporation,\nmunicipality or governmental agency;\n  6. To adopt, amend or rescind such rules and regulations as may be\nnecessary or convenient to the performance of the functions, powers and\nduties of the secretary; and\n  7. To do all other things necessary or convenient to carry out the\nfunctions, powers and duties expressly set forth in this article or as\nmay from time to time be confined upon the secretary by the legislature\nof the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>