<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-916"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-916"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="916"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-916/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-916/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-916/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-916/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_916">
        <num>916</num>
        <heading>Benefits of approved waterfront revitalization programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 916. Benefits of approved waterfront revitalization programs. In\nrecognition of the state policy set forth in this article to encourage\nthe revitalization of waterfront areas in a manner consistent with local\nobjectives, the following benefits shall apply where a local government\nwaterfront revitalization program has been approved pursuant to section\nnine hundred fifteen or section nine hundred fifteen-a of this article.\n  1. a. The secretary shall examine programs operated by state agencies\nwhich may have the potential to affect the policies and purposes of an\napproved waterfront revitalization program. Such examination shall\ninclude programs which involve issuance of permits, licenses,\ncertifications and other forms of approval of land use or development,\nthe provision of grants, loans and other funding assistance which leads\nto or influences land use or development, directly undertaken land use\nor development and planning activities. The secretary shall, within\nsixty days after approval of a waterfront revitalization program,\nidentify actions under such state agency programs which are likely to\naffect the achievement of the policies and purposes of such approved\nprogram, and shall notify the affected state agency. The secretary may\nat any time identify additional actions and notify the affected state\nagencies thereof.\n  b. The state agency program actions so identified shall be undertaken\nin a manner which is consistent to the maximum extent practicable with\nthe approved waterfront revitalization program. Reviews by state\nagencies of proposed actions to determine consistency with approved\nwaterfront revitalization programs shall be coordinated with and made a\npart of other agency procedures, including reviews conducted under the\nstate environmental quality review act as provided in article eight of\nthe environmental conservation law.\n  2. The office of business permits shall conduct continuing studies of\nmeans of expediting development called for in approved programs. The\nsecretary shall assist the office of business permits in the conduct of\nsuch studies, which should address the consolidation, simplification,\nexpediting or otherwise improving permit procedures which may affect\ndevelopment called for in such areas taking into account the state\npolicy set forth in this article to provide consistency of program\nactions at all levels of government for such areas.\n  3. The secretary shall consult and work with state agencies,\nincluding, but not limited to, the urban development corporation, the\njob development authority, the environmental facilities corporation, the\noffice of parks, recreation and historic preservation and the\ndepartments of economic development and transportation, to seek to\nidentify additional means of effectuating approved waterfront\nrevitalization programs. The secretary shall make recommendations to\nlocal, state and federal agencies and the legislature, as appropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>