<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-919"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-919"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="919"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_919">
        <num>919</num>
        <heading>Coordination of state actions and programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 919. Coordination of state actions and programs. 1. Actions directly\nundertaken by state agencies within the coastal area including grants,\nloans or other funding assistance, land use and development, or\nplanning, and land transactions shall be consistent with the coastal\narea policies of this article. Provided, however, that nothing in this\narticle shall be construed to authorize or require the issuance of any\npermit, license, certification, or other approval or the approval of any\ngrant, loan or other funding assistance which is denied by the state\nagency having jurisdiction, pursuant to other provisions of law or which\nis conditioned by such agency pursuant to other provisions of law until\nsuch conditions are met.\n  2. The secretary shall review actions proposed by state agencies which\nmay affect the achievement of the policies of this article and shall\nmake recommendations to such agencies with respect to achievement of\nsuch policies.\n  3. The commissioner of environmental conservation shall amend the\nregulations promulgated pursuant to article eight of the environmental\nconservation law as necessary and appropriate to assure adequate\nconsideration of impacts on the use and conservation of coastal\nresources.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>