<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-922"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-922"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="922"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-922/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-922/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-922/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-922/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_922">
        <num>922</num>
        <heading>Comprehensive harbor management plans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_922__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Municipalities on lakes, other than those lakes identified in\nsubdivision four of section nine hundred eleven of this article, may,\npursuant to this section, develop cooperative lakewide local waterfront\nrevitalization programs and harbor management plans.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_922__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where no local waterfront revitalization program and harbor\nmanagement plan exists which has been cooperatively prepared by all of\nthe municipalities which border the shores of such a lake, no local law\nor ordinance adopted by one such municipality pursuant to a harbor\nmanagement plan shall be approved without a finding by the secretary of\nstate that the local law or ordinance is consistent as well with the\nmanagement of the lake by, and interests of, the lake residents and its\nmunicipalities as a whole.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_922__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where an organization or entity has been created by statute to\nprovide lakewide planning or regulation, such local laws or ordinances\nshall be consistent with the plans developed by such organization or\nentity pursuant to the procedures required in such statute.\n  4. No provision of this chapter shall be deemed to diminish the\nauthority of any city, town or village pertaining to the regulation of\nharbors, surface waters and underwater lands granted by any other law,\ncharter, patent or other instrument. Nor shall it be read to authorize\nlocal harbor management plans displacing conforming water-dependent\nbusinesses in existence on the effective date of this section.\n  5. Any conveyances of interests pursuant to subdivision seven of\nsection seventy-five of the public lands law and any permits issued\npursuant to subdivision one of section 15-0503 of the environmental\nconservation law shall be consistent, insofar as possible, with approved\ncomprehensive harbor management plans adopted pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>