<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-93-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-93-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-01-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="93-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-93-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-93-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-93-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-93-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_93_A">
        <num>93-A</num>
        <heading>Examination of reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 93-a. Examination of reports. The secretary of state shall examine\nall reports required to be filed with the department of state pursuant\nto article seven-A of this chapter in order to determine the nature and\nextent of the in-kind support provided by any covered entity to one or\nmore recipient entities, as such terms are defined in section one\nhundred seventy-two-e of this chapter, and the nature and extent of\ncovered communications by any covered entity, as such terms are defined\nin section one hundred seventy-two-f of this chapter. Notwithstanding\nany inconsistent provision of law, whenever the secretary of state, in\nconsultation with the department of taxation and finance or the\ndepartment of law, determines that the nature and extent of a covered\nentity's in-kind support to other entities or the nature and extent of a\ncovered entity's spending on covered communications is inconsistent with\nthe charitable purposes of such covered entity, the secretary shall\ncause the reports required by article seven-A of this chapter filed by\nsuch entity to be published on the website of the department of state\nupon such finding. Provided, however, that such publishing shall not\ninclude the names and addresses of individual donors to covered entities\nnor shall such publishing include the covered entity's Internal Revenue\nService Form 990 Schedule B. The secretary shall report to the governor,\nthe temporary president of the senate and the speaker of the assembly,\nby December thirty-first, two thousand twenty-two, and annually\nthereafter, on topics including but not limited to: the nature and\nextent of in-kind support provided by covered entities to recipient\nentities, as such terms are defined in section one hundred seventy-two-e\nof this chapter and the nature and extent of expenditures for covered\ncommunications. The secretary may request the assistance of the\ndepartment of taxation and finance or the department of law in order to\ncomplete this report. Provided however that such report shall not\ninclude the names and addresses of individual donors to covered entities\nnor shall such report include the covered entity's Internal Revenue\nService Form 990 Schedule B.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>