<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="94-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_94_B">
        <num>94-B</num>
        <heading>Office for new Americans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Create a network of neighborhood-based opportunity centers;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Increase access to English-for-speakers-of-other-languages (ESOL)\ntraining, including by engaging not-for-profit organizations and other\nqualified providers of ESOL training services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Assist immigrants in matters relating to immigration status,\nincluding but not limited to assisting with the naturalization process\nand applications for deferred action for childhood arrivals;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Connect immigrants to business resources that harness their\nskills, employment referral programs, and other workforce development\nprograms;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Develop and leverage the skills of immigrants to benefit their\ncommunities and the state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Strengthen the connections between immigrants and their\ncommunities through civic engagement;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Reduce exploitation of immigrants;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establish a toll-free multi-lingual hotline and a website for\npurposes including but not limited to dissemination of information about\nthe programs and services offered by the office for new Americans,\nreferral for services, and receipt of complaints relating to fraud and\nother related crimes against immigrants;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Ensure that individuals referred by the office are directed to\nservice providers who are in compliance with article twenty-eight-C of\nthe general business law or providers certified by the bureau of\nimmigration appeals;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Using information developed by the office through the hotline,\nassist law enforcement in combatting crimes against immigrants;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Advise the governor and secretary concerning matters affecting\nimmigrants in the state in order to promote and encourage the full\nparticipation of immigrants in the state's civic and economic life;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Coordinate with other state agencies and otherwise marshal the\nresources of the state to serve the needs of immigrants;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Encourage and assist local governments in the development of\nactivities to enhance civic engagement among immigrants and in immigrant\ncommunities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Beginning in two thousand fifteen, by June fifteenth of each year,\nproduce a report to the governor, the speaker of the assembly, and the\ntemporary president of the senate describing the activities of the\noffice, including but not limited to, summarizing calls received through\nthe hotline and website, information on ESOL training services provided\nby the office, the number of immigrants assisted through the opportunity\ncenters, or an estimation thereof, the status of any workforce\ndevelopment programs, and any other relevant information;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Encourage the development of and provide for the establishment of\na state military immigrant family legacy program liaison, as provided in\nsection twenty-nine-b of the veterans' services law; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_p">
          <num>(p)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Request individuals seeking assistance from the office answer the\nfollowing questions: "Have you served in the United States military?"\n"Has someone in your family served in the United States military?"\nIndividuals identifying themselves or a family member as "intended\nrecipients" of the staff sergeant Alex R. Jimenez New York state\nmilitary immigrant family legacy program as such term is defined in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section twenty-nine-b of the\nveterans' services law, shall be advised of such program. In addition,\nsuch individuals shall be informed that the department of veterans'\nservices and local veterans' service agencies established pursuant to\nsection seventeen of the veterans' services law provide assistance to\nuniformed service members, veterans and their families regarding\nbenefits available under federal and state law. Information regarding\nveterans and military status provided by assisted individuals shall be\nprotected as personal confidential material, and used only to identify\nsuch individuals as "intended recipients" of the staff sergeant Alex R.\nJimenez New York State military immigrant family legacy program, and to\nassist such individuals in matters relating to immigration status and\ncitizenship, and in referring such individuals to the department of\nveterans' services or local veterans' service agencies for information\nand assistance with regard to benefits and entitlements under federal\nand state law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>