<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="94-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-94-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_94_D">
        <num>94-D</num>
        <heading>New York Asian American and Pacific Islander commission</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is hereby established within the department of state the New\nYork Asian American and Pacific Islander commission. The commission\nshall consist of thirteen members representative of Asian American and\nPacific Islander communities which may include, but not be limited to:\nthe Bangladeshi, Bhutanese, Cambodian, Chinese, Filipino, Hmong, Indian,\nIndonesian, Japanese, Korean, Laotian, Malaysian, Mongolian, Nepalese,\nPakistani, Singaporean, Sri Lankan, Taiwanese, Thai, and Vietnamese\ncommunities. Such members shall have experience advocating on behalf of\ntheir community, and shall be appointed as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_94_D__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>seven members shall be appointed by the governor;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_94_D__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>two members shall be appointed by the temporary president of the\nsenate;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_94_D__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>two members shall be appointed by the speaker of the assembly;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_94_D__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>one member shall be appointed by the minority leader of the\nsenate; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_94_D__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>one member shall be appointed by the minority leader of the\nassembly.\n  The secretary of state, or their designee, shall serve as chair of the\ncommission.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each member of the commission shall serve a term of three years,\nexcept that in making the first appointments to the commission, four\nmembers shall be appointed to serve for one year, four for two years,\nand five for three years. The first appointments made by the temporary\npresident of the senate and speaker of the assembly shall be allocated\nequally between the one-year and two-year terms of service. The first\nappointments made by the minority leaders shall serve for three years.\nThe first appointments made by the governor shall be as follows: two\nmembers shall be appointed to serve for one year, two members shall be\nappointed to serve for two years, and three members shall be appointed\nto serve for three years. The members shall be eligible for\nreappointment and shall serve until their successors are appointed and\nqualified, and the term of the successor of any incumbent shall be\ncalculated from the expiration of the term of that incumbent. A vacancy\noccurring other than by expiration of term shall be filled in the same\nmanner as the original appointment, but for the unexpired term only.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A majority of the members of the commission shall constitute a\nquorum for the purpose of conducting the business thereof and a majority\nvote of all the members in office shall be necessary for action.\n  2. The commission shall make recommendations regarding the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>policies to improve the community, economic and social well-being,\nand the health and educational needs important to Asian American and\nPacific Islander communities in the state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>statewide programs, recognizing the continuing contributions of\nAsian American and Pacific Islander individuals in the state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>public education campaigns regarding Asian American and Pacific\nIslander issues and culture;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_94_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ways to increase the awareness among Asian American and Pacific\nIslander individuals of state and local resources that may benefit Asian\nAmerican and Pacific Islander individuals and communities as a whole.\n  3. The members of the commission shall serve without compensation, but\nthey shall be entitled to reimbursement for all necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of their duties.\n  4. The commission shall submit an annual report on its activities to\nthe governor and the legislature.\n  * NB Repealed November 17, 2028\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>