<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-941"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-941"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-11-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="941"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-941/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-941/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-941/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-941/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_941">
        <num>941</num>
        <heading>Council on professional career opportunity</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 941. Council on professional career opportunity.  * 1. There is\nhereby created within the executive department a council on professional\ncareer opportunity consisting of eleven members as follows:  the\ncommissioner of education, the commissioner of health, the chancellor of\nthe state university of New York, the chancellor of the city university\nof New York, and the president of the higher education services\ncorporation or their designees under written designation; and six\nadditional members to be appointed by the governor, including two\nmembers appointed upon the recommendation of the temporary president of\nthe senate and two members appointed upon the recommendation of the\nspeaker of the assembly. The council shall include at least one\nrepresentative of an independent institution of higher education. Due\nconsideration shall be given to the appointment of members recognized\nfor their expertise in the fields of education and minority group\nissues. The governor shall designate one of the appointive members as\nchairperson to serve as such at the pleasure of the governor. The\ncouncil shall terminate March thirty-first, two thousand three.\n  * NB State council terminated 3/31/2003\n  2. The council shall meet once each annual quarter and as frequently\nas its business may require. The appointed members of the council shall\nbe reimbursed for their reasonable and necessary traveling and other\nexpenses incurred in the performance of their official duties. No\nadditional compensation for services rendered pursuant to this chapter\nshall be received by members of the council.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>