<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-950"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-950"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="950"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-950/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-950/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-950/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-950/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_950">
        <num>950</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 950. Definitions. As used in this article, the following terms shall\nhave the following meanings:\n  1. "Internal control". A process that integrates the activities,\nplans, attitudes, policies, systems, resources and efforts of the people\nof an organization working together, and that is designed to provide\nreasonable assurance that the organization will achieve its objectives\nand mission. The objectives of an internal control system include, but\nare not limited to: the safeguarding of assets; checking the accuracy\nand reliability of accounting data and financial reporting; promoting\nthe effectiveness and efficiency of operations; ensuring compliance with\napplicable laws and regulations; and encouraging adherence to prescribed\nmanagerial policies. Internal control review processes are used\nperiodically to evaluate the ongoing internal control system and to\nassess and monitor the implementation of necessary corrective actions.\n  2. "Internal audit". An appraisal activity established by the\nmanagement of an organization for the review of operations as a means of\nassuring conformance with management policies and the effectiveness of\ninternal control, and conducted in conformance with generally accepted\nstandards for internal auditing.\n  3. "State agency". Any state department, state university of New York,\ncity university of New York, board, bureau, division, commission,\ncommittee, council, office or other governmental entity performing a\ngovernmental or proprietary function for the state, or any combination\nthereof as provided in subdivision two of section nine hundred fifty-one\nof this article, except any public authority or public benefit\ncorporation, the judiciary or the state legislature.\n  4. "Judiciary". The courts and court-related programs, including the\noffice of court administration, of the state-funded portion of the\nunified court system and all components thereof as provided in\nsubdivision two of section two hundred forty-nine-a of the judiciary\nlaw.\n  5. "State legislature". The legislature of the state of New York,\nincluding all components thereof as provided in subdivision two of\nsection ninety of the legislative law.\n  6. "Covered authority". Any public authority or public benefit\ncorporation, other than a bi-state authority or public benefit\ncorporation, a majority of whose members are appointed by the governor\nor serve as members by virtue of holding state offices to which they\nwere appointed by the governor, or any combination thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>