<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="96-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_A">
        <num>96-A</num>
        <heading>Fees for services rendered pursuant to the uniform commercial code</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 96-a. Fees for services rendered pursuant to the uniform commercial\ncode. 1. In case of conflict between this section and any other\nprovision of law, this section shall control.\n  2. The secretary of state shall determine the type and amount of all\nfees to be collected by the department of state and other filing offices\nfor services rendered by said department or office pursuant to the\nprovisions of the uniform commercial code and article ten-A of the lien\nlaw. Such fees, referred to as processing fees, shall be non-refundable\nfees paid to the department of state or office at the time that\ndocuments are presented to the department of state or office for filing,\nand will be paid whether or not the documents are accepted for filing.\nSuch fees shall be subject to the approval of the director of the budget\nand shall be promulgated in the official rules and regulations of the\ndepartment of state in accordance with the provisions of the state\nadministrative procedure act. Nothing contained in this subdivision\nshall preclude the secretary of state from periodically changing such\nfees, subject to the approval of the director of the budget, and from\nperiodically amending the official rules and regulations of the\ndepartment of state in accordance with the provisions of the state\nadministrative procedure act.\n  3. Consistent with the provisions of article nine of the uniform\ncommercial code and article ten-A of the lien law, the department of\nstate and other filing offices shall produce or reproduce the content of\nany informational systems maintained pursuant to such laws. The\nsecretary of state and other filing offices shall establish reasonable\nfees for information so produced or reproduced. Notwithstanding any\nother provisions of law, the availability of such information shall be\ndetermined solely by the provisions of the uniform commercial code.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>