<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="96"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-96/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96">
        <num>96</num>
        <heading>Fees and refunds</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing under the general associations law or any\ncorporation law, except the business corporation law and not-for-profit\ncorporation law: a certificate of incorporation, one hundred twenty-five\ndollars; a certificate or report of voluntary dissolution, including the\nissuance of duplicate certificates by the secretary of state, and a\ncertified copy of an order or judgment of dissolution, sixty dollars;\nthe statement and designation of a foreign corporation, including the\nissuance of a certificate of authority, two hundred twenty-five dollars;\na certificate of designation or change of address or any certificate of\nchange of mailing address or office of a foreign corporation, other than\na moneyed corporation, thirty dollars; any other certificate or\ninstrument, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing under the business corporation law and the\nnot-for-profit corporation law as set forth in those chapters.\n  10. For service of process on the secretary of state, acting as agent\nfor a third party pursuant to law, except as otherwise specifically\nprovided by law, forty dollars. No fee shall be collected for process\nserved on behalf of a county, city, town or village or other political\nsubdivision of the state. The fees paid the secretary of state shall be\na taxable disbursement.\n  11.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the special handling of requests made to the division of\ncorporations of the department of state for any service for which a fee\nis collected as prescribed by law, twenty-five dollars. For the purposes\nof this section the term "special handling" shall mean the completion of\nthe request within twenty-four hours of receipt of the request, except\nin those cases where the twenty-four hour period shall end on a\nSaturday, Sunday, holiday or day on which the division of corporations\nof the department of state is not open for business, in which case the\ntwenty-four hour period shall be extended to the appropriate hour of the\nnext succeeding business day on which such division is open for\nbusiness.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the same day expedited handling of requests made to the\ndivision of corporations of the department of state for any service for\nwhich a fee is collected as prescribed by law, seventy-five dollars. For\nthe purposes of this section the term "same day expedited handling"\nshall mean the completion of the request on the same day as the day of\nrequest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the two hour priority handling of requests made to the\ndivision of corporations of the department of state for any service for\nwhich a fee is collected as prescribed by law, one hundred fifty\ndollars. For the purposes of this section the term "two hour priority\nhandling" shall mean the completion of the request within two hours on\nthe same day as the day of the request.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For handling of non-expedited requests made to the division of\ncorporations of the department of state for any service for which a fee\nis collected as prescribed by law, the completion of such request shall\nbe accomplished within seven business days.\n  12. For the filing, recording or registering of any certificate,\nnotice or other paper required to be filed, recorded or registered, the\nfee for which is not otherwise prescribed by law, twenty-five dollars.\n  13. Except as otherwise specifically provided by law, the department\nof state may refund, within three years from the date of payment and\nupon audit of the state comptroller, any fee or portion of a fee paid\npursuant to any of the statutes which the department is charged by law\nto administer, in any case in which:\n  a. the license, permit, or certificate applied for is not issued, or\ndoes not take effect, or\n  b. the filing or certification requested is not made, or\n  c. the service requested is not rendered, or\n  d. the payment made is in excess of the amount prescribed by such\nstatute, or\n  e. the licensee has entered the active armed services of the United\nStates in which event the refund shall be such proportion of the license\nfee paid as the number of full months remaining unexpired of the license\nperiod bears to the total number of months in such period.\n  14. No fee shall be collected for copies of records furnished to state\nofficers as defined in the public officers law, section two, for use in\ntheir official capacity.\n  15. The department of state shall on or before the tenth day of each\nmonth, out of the moneys collected during the preceding month pursuant\nto subdivision nine of this section, pay over to each county clerk in\nwhose office a certified copy of a corporation certificate or other\ninstrument relating to a domestic or foreign corporation shall have been\nfiled by the department during the preceding month pursuant to law the\nsum of six dollars for each such copy o...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>