<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-962"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-962"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="962"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-962/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-962/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-962/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-962/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_962">
        <num>962</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 962. Definitions. As used in this article, the following terms shall\nmean and include:\n  1. "Council" shall mean the Long Island South Shore Estuary reserve\ncouncil created by section nine hundred sixty-four of this article.\n  2. "Department" shall mean the secretary of state or his or her\ndesignee.\n  3. "Estuary" shall mean all or part of the mouth of a river or stream\nor any body of water having an unimpaired natural connection with the\nopen sea and within which sea water is measurably diluted with\nfresh-water derived from land drainage, including associated aquatic\necosystems and those portions of tributaries draining into the estuary\nup to the historic height of migration of anadromous fish or the\nhistoric head of tidal influence, whichever is higher.\n  4. "Long Island South Shore Estuary Reserve" or "Reserve" shall mean\nall the water and underwater lands comprising the South Shore Estuary\nand the lands which gather and transmit precipitation as either\ngroundwater or run-off into such system and which are designated on a\nmap prepared by a designated planning entity and adopted by the council.\n  5. "South Shore Estuary" shall mean the Estuary located on the South\nShore of Long Island between the western boundary of the Town of\nHempstead and the Eastern Boundary of Shinnecock Bay.\n  6. "Plan" shall mean the comprehensive management plan created\npursuant to section nine hundred sixty-six of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>