<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="964-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_964_B">
        <num>964-B</num>
        <heading>Duties of the council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 964-b. Duties of the council. The council shall have the following\nduties:\n  1. To meet not less than once every two months until the adoption of\nthe plan and to encourage attendance at such meeting of representatives\nof local governments and interested parties affected by the\ndeliberations of the council;\n  2. To send copies of the minutes of each meeting to each town and\nvillage within the reserve, the county executive of the county of\nNassau, the county executive of the county of Suffolk, the members of\nthe Assembly and Senate representing areas within the reserve, and any\nother interested party upon request;\n  3. To hold public hearings pursuant to section nine hundred sixty-six\nof this article;\n  4. To designate land and water bodies to be included in the reserve as\ndefined in subdivision four of section nine hundred sixty-two of this\narticle and to adopt and publish a map and written description\ndelineating the boundary of the reserve;\n  5. To make appointments to the advisory committees authorized pursuant\nto section nine hundred sixty-five of this article, and to create other\nadvisory committees as necessary;\n  6. To review and evaluate existing studies, modeling, methodologies,\ndata and recommendations for their application to the plan;\n  7. To adopt a comprehensive management plan for the Long Island South\nShore Estuary Reserve which the state and local governments may\nimplement. Estuary segmentation or partitioning of the estuary into\nspatial units may be necessary at times for summarizing data for\ngeographic areas, for the development of certain scientific models, or\nfor interim management measures. The council shall prioritize problems\nand opportunities within the estuary based upon use impairments,\nresource management needs and areas experiencing intense recreational\nuse;\n  8. To identify funding mechanisms for the preparation and\nimplementation of the plan;\n  9. To identify specific tasks or studies and the amount of funding\nnecessary to carry out the provisions of this article and report such\nfindings to the governor and the legislature;\n  10. To prepare interim reports and recommendations;\n  11. To prepare or cause to be prepared educational materials designed\nto inform the public about the value of the Estuary, its appropriate\nuses and methods to protect it;\n  12. To consider designation of the South Shore Estuary into the\nFederal National Estuary program pursuant to section three hundred\ntwenty of the Federal Clean Water Act. Development of a nomination\napplication for federal designation of the South Shore Estuary may be\nconcurrent with the development of the comprehensive management plan;\n  13. To encourage, and where feasible, facilitate implementation of the\nrecommendations of the plan;\n  14. To encourage individuals, corporations, associations, and public\nentities to protect and preserve the unique resources of the reserve;\nand\n  15. To biannually review the plan and the effectiveness of its\nimplementation, and where necessary, revise the plan and submit such\nrevision to each town and village within the reserve, the governor, the\nlegislature and any other interested party upon request.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>