<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="964"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-964/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_964">
        <num>964</num>
        <heading>Long Island South Shore Estuary reserve council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 964. Long Island South Shore Estuary reserve council. 1. There is\nhereby established a Long Island South Shore Estuary reserve council to\nassist in the development, advise in the implementation, and review the\neffectiveness of a comprehensive management plan for the Long Island\nSouth Shore Estuary Reserve that the state and local governments may\nimplement.\n  2. The council shall consist of twenty-three voting members: the\nsecretary of state, who shall be the chair; the county executive of the\ncounty of Nassau; the county executive of the county of Suffolk; the\nsupervisor of the city of Long Beach, the supervisors of the towns of\nHempstead, Oyster Bay, Babylon, Islip, Brookhaven and Southampton; a\nmayor, appointed by the conference of mayors, from a village bordering\nthe South Shore Estuary to represent the villages within the South Shore\nEstuary Reserve, all of the aforementioned whom may appoint a designee;\nthe chair of the citizens advisory committee; the chair of the technical\nadvisory committee; a member of the Great South Bay Audubon Society, the\ndean of the Marine Sciences Research Center at Stony Brook or his or her\ndesignee, a member of the New York Sportsfishing Federation, a\nrepresentative of the Long Island Association, and a representative of\nthe Long Island Builders Institute, Incorporated, however, if any of the\nprevious five member organizations decline to serve on the council, a\nreplacement organization which represents the same interests as the\norganization that is vacating shall be nominated by a majority of the\nremaining voting members of the council and appointed by the secretary\nof state; the secretary of state shall appoint one member who shall be a\nrepresentative of a property owner association from a community or\ncommunities bordering the South Shore Estuary to represent the interests\nof property owners within the South Shore Estuary Reserve; the county\nexecutive of the county of Nassau shall appoint two members, one of whom\nshall be a representative of the marina industry and one of whom shall\nbe a representative of a regional environmental organization; the county\nexecutive of the county of Suffolk shall appoint two members, one of\nwhom shall be a representative of a local baymen's association and one\nof whom shall be a representative of the charter or party boat industry.\nAll members shall reside in Nassau or Suffolk county and shall have\ndemonstrated expertise in the functional areas to be addressed by the\ncouncil.\n  3. The department shall convene and conduct the council's meetings and\nrecord and prepare minutes.\n  4. Terms of appointment. The terms of all members who are elected\npublic officials shall be concurrent with their terms of office. All\nother members shall serve for a term of four years or thereafter until a\nsuccessor is appointed. An appointment to fill a vacancy shall be made\nfor the remainder of the affected term in the same manner as the\noriginal appointment was made. Such appointment shall be made within\nsixty days of the date the position becomes vacant.\n  5. Thirteen voting members shall constitute a quorum. Any action\nrequiring a vote or any adoption by the council shall require an\naffirmative vote of at least a majority of all the voting members.\n  6. If any member of the council fails to attend at least sixty percent\nof the meetings during a period of twelve consecutive months, the\ndepartment shall notify the designating authority.\n  7. The members of the council shall serve without compensation and\nshall not be reimbursed for personal expenses.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>