<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-965"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-965"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="965"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-965/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-965/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-965/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-965/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_965">
        <num>965</num>
        <heading>Advisory committees to the council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 965. Advisory committees to the council. The council shall establish\nadvisory committees to make recommendations and provide guidance to the\ncouncil for the preparation and implementation of the comprehensive\nmanagement plan. A citizens advisory committee, technical advisory\ncommittee, management advisory committee, and a local government\nadvisory committee shall be formed. The committees may prepare reports,\nrecommend studies and submit findings and recommendations to the\ncouncil. The council shall make the initial appointments to the advisory\ncommittees. Each appointed member shall be a voting member of the\nadvisory committee. The advisory committees shall meet and elect a\nchair. Once a chair is elected, the committee can appoint other voting\nmembers with expertise related to the function of the committee.\n  1. The citizens advisory committee shall be comprised of\nrepresentatives of citizens or civic groups, environmental groups, user\ngroups, and business organizations.  The purpose of the committee shall\nbe to integrate citizens' and user groups' concerns in the planning and\ndecision-making process and to encourage public education and\ninvolvement. The committee membership shall include but not be limited\nto a representative of the Fire Island Association, a representative of\nBluepoints Company Incorporated, a representative of a recreational\nboating association, a member of the Tribal council of the Shinnecock\nIndian Reservation, and a member of the Long Island Farm Bureau.\n  2. The technical advisory committee shall be comprised of individuals\nwith technical expertise, including but not limited to scientists,\nengineers and planners. The purpose of the committee shall be to review\nand oversee studies, interpret and evaluate existing and new data to\ndetermine causes and effects of environmental problems, and provide\ntechnical support for the development of management measures and\npolicies. The committee membership shall include but not be limited to\nthe director of the Marine Science Center at the Long Island University\nat Southampton; the executive director of the Long Island Regional\nPlanning Board; the director of the New York Sea Grant Institute and the\ndirector of the Long Island Maritime Museum, all of the aforementioned\nwhom may appoint a designee.\n  3. The management advisory committee shall be comprised of\nrepresentatives of government agencies associated with developing\npolicy, regulating activities or enforcing laws and regulations\naffecting the South Shore Estuary Reserve. The purpose of the committee\nshall be to analyze existing laws, regulations and management programs\nand to make recommendations for improvements thereof. The committee\nmembership shall include but not be limited to the secretary of state,\nthe director of region one of the department of environmental\nconservation, the director of the Long Island region office of parks,\nrecreation and historic preservation, the commissioner of the department\nof economic development, the commissioner of the Suffolk county\ndepartment of health services and the commissioner of the Nassau county\ndepartment of health, all of the aforementioned whom may appoint a\ndesignee. The council shall request the participation of the director of\nregion two of the federal environmental protection agency, the secretary\nof the United States department of the interior, and the director of the\nFire Island National Seashore, all of whom may appoint a designee.\n  4. The local government advisory committee shall be comprised of\nrepresentatives of towns, cities and villages. The purpose of the\ncommittee is to provide input regarding land use issues, zoning,\nplanning and local implementation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>