<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-972"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-972"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="972"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-972/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-972/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-972/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-972/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_972">
        <num>972</num>
        <heading>Job training and special services plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 972. Job training and special services plan. 1. In developing the\njob training and special services plan required by section one hundred\ntwenty-one of the act, the governor shall provide guidelines and\ncriteria for coordinating the activities to be funded with moneys under\nthe act with related activities of the state education department, local\nschool districts including the boards of cooperative educational\nservices, the state vocational education advisory council, the\ndepartment of social services and the local social services districts,\nthe department of labor including the job service, the office of\nvocational rehabilitation, the department of commerce, the division for\nyouth, post-secondary institutions in the state particularly community\ncolleges and other institutions providing technical training\nopportunities, the department of commerce and other state and local\nagencies and authorities involved in economic development activities.\n  2. All such agencies shall provide the governor with such assistance\nand information as he may need in preparing, implementing, and\nevaluating the implementation of the plan.\n  3. The plan shall set forth performance goals for programs funded\nunder the act and criteria to be used in awarding the incentive grants\navailable under the act. Such goals and criteria shall be designed to\nfoster greater coordination among the workforce preparation programs\nfunded under the act and among these and other workforce preparation\nprograms.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>