<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-981"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-981"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="981"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-981/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-981/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-981/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-981/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_981">
        <num>981</num>
        <heading>Program implementation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 981. Program implementation. 1. On or before September first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine and every September first thereafter, each\nstate agency administratively responsible for workforce preparation\nactivities shall prepare a separate program plan for each workforce\npreparation program that such agency administers. Each plan shall\ninclude a description of proposed program activities, a description of a\nmechanism for funding distribution, program objectives, population to be\nserved, institutions eligible to receive funds, and a description of the\ncoordination and linkages between this program and other program\nactivities funded separately. Such plan shall also include an evaluation\ncomponent as part of the implementation of each program which shall\ndescribe how the agency will monitor the delivery of services under the\nprogram and which shall set forth the measure of effectiveness of the\nservices being provided.\n  2. Program plans shall be submitted to the job training coordinating\ncouncil, as defined in subdivision two of section nine hundred\nseventy-one of this chapter, the speaker of the assembly, the temporary\npresident of the senate, and the chair of the legislative commission on\nskills development and career education for review and comment.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not exempt any agency from\nrequirements relating to the preparation and submission of program plans\npursuant to any other provision of law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>