<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-990"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-990"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="990"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-990/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-990/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-990/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-990/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_990">
        <num>990</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 990. Legislative findings. 1. The legislature finds that the\nchildren of this state are at the same time both our most important\nresource and our most vulnerable citizens. Children best develop their\nunique potential in a caring and healthy family environment either with\ntheir birth parents or other relatives or in an adoptive family, with\nsupport from other nurturing environments, especially the schools and\nthe community. As such, children need a special state policy to ensure\nthe strength and viability of their families.\n  2. The legislature further finds that there is a critical lack of\nservices available to families and that the shortage of such services is\nexacerbated by a lack of coordination of the many existing programs and\npolicies of state and local governments that impact on children and\nfamilies. The legislature also finds that the planning and provision of\nservices for children and their families would be enhanced by the\nestablishment of a family policy to ensure that all state and local\nplanning and provision of services are effectuated in a manner that\nmaximizes support and strengthening of the family structure. Such\nactions also must be directed toward stemming the human and financial\ncosts of the unnecessary placement of children outside their homes,\nwhile ensuring the safety and well-being of children by providing needed\nservices to them and their families and, when appropriate, toward\nsupporting permanency planning for children through adoption or other\nmeans.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>