<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-991"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-991"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="991"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-991/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-991/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-991/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-991/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_991">
        <num>991</num>
        <heading>Family policy guidelines</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 991. Family policy guidelines. All state and local government\nprograms should be guided by the following principles:\n  1. Families are best served by comprehensive programs which are\ndirected towards all aspects of individual and family development.\n  2. Families who are the consumers of services should be partners in\nthe planning, delivery and evaluation of those services.\n  3. Families needs can be met best by developing and nurturing their\ninherent strengths.\n  4. Families deserve a realistic level of economic security.\n  5. Families receive the greatest benefit from flexible, accessible and\ncomprehensive services which are delivered in a manner which is\nculturally and linguistically sensitive to their needs.\n  6. Families are best served when intervention occurs as early as\npossible and is designed to give priority to prevention of family\ndisintegration. Primary emphasis should be given to establishing safe,\nnurturing environments which support the healthy growth of all family\nmembers.\n  7. Families who have members placed in care settings outside the\nnuclear family must be provided with services to help them reunite. If\nreturn is not possible, plans for alternative permanent care must be\nmade by agencies caring for the child.\n  8. Families deserve services which are coordinated and where special\nattention is paid to ongoing accessibility to multiple services.\n  9. Families receive the greatest benefit from effective services\ndelivered by a qualified, trained workforce.  This workforce, especially\ndirect caregivers, must receive professional recognition, support and\nappropriate compensation.\n  10. Families need public and voluntary human services systems which\nwork together and are accountable to society, each other and the people\nthey serve.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>