<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-995-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-995-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="995-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-995-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-995-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-995-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-995-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_995_A">
        <num>995-A</num>
        <heading>Commission on forensic science</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the commissioner\nof the division of criminal justice services who shall be chair of the\ncommission and the commissioner of the department of health or his or\nher designee, who shall serve as an ex-officio member of the commission;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>twelve members appointed by the governor.\n  2. Of the members appointed by the governor,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member shall be the chair of the New York state crime\nlaboratory advisory committee;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member shall be the director of a forensic laboratory located\nin New York state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member shall be the director of the office of forensic\nservices within the division of criminal justice services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two members shall be a scientist having experience in the areas of\nlaboratory standards or quality assurance regulation and monitoring and\nshall be appointed upon the recommendation of the commissioner of\nhealth;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member shall be a representative of a law enforcement agency\nand shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the commissioner of\ncriminal justice services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member shall be a representative of prosecution services who\nshall be appointed upon the recommendation of the commissioner of\ncriminal justice services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member shall be a representative of the public criminal\ndefense bar who shall be appointed upon the recommendation of an\norganization representing public defense services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member shall be a representative of the private criminal\ndefense bar who shall be appointed upon the recommendation of an\norganization of such bar;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two members shall be members-at-large, one of whom shall be\nappointed upon the recommendation of the temporary president of the\nsenate, and one of whom shall be appointed upon the recommendation of\nthe speaker of the assembly; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_995_A__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member, who shall be an attorney or judge with a background in\nprivacy issues and biomedical ethics, shall be appointed upon the\nrecommendation of the chief judge of the court of appeals.\n  3. Of the members appointed by the governor, each member shall be\nappointed to serve a three year term. Any member appointed by the\ngovernor may be reappointed for additional three year terms.\n  4. Any member chosen to fill a vacancy created otherwise than by\nexpiration of term shall be appointed by the governor for the unexpired\nterm of the member he or she is to succeed. Any such vacancy shall be\nfilled in the same manner as the original appointment.\n  5. The commission shall meet at least four times each year and may\nestablish its own rules and procedures concerning the conduct of its\nmeetings and other affairs not inconsistent with law.\n  6. No member of the commission on forensic science shall be\ndisqualified from holding any public office or employment, nor shall he\nor she forfeit any such office or employment, by reason of his or her\nappointment hereunder, and members of the commission shall not be\nrequired to take and file oaths of office before serving on the\ncommission.\n  7. Members of the commission shall receive no compensation for their\nservices but shall be allowed their actual and necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of their functions hereunder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>