<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EXC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-996"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-996"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="996"/>
          <FRBRname value="EXC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-996/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-996/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-996/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/exc/section-996/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_996">
        <num>996</num>
        <heading>Community advisory board for the modernization and revitalization of SUNY Downstate health sciences university</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be established the advisory board for\nthe modernization and revitalization of SUNY Downstate (hereinafter\nreferred to as "the advisory board"). The advisory board shall review\nand examine a variety of options to strengthen SUNY Downstate and\npromote longer term viability for its dual education and healthcare\nmission. In conducting its study, the advisory board will consider the\nfollowing factors:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Overall healthcare service delivery trends and models;\n  (ii) Historic and projected financials for the hospital and the\ncampus;\n  (iii) Current state of building infrastructure and capital needs;\n  (iv) Community healthcare needs, outcomes, and health disparities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Existing inpatient and outpatient service offerings and health\noutcomes;\n  (vi) Capacity and availability of inpatient and outpatient services in\nthe broader primary and secondary service areas;\n  (vii) Efficiency of operations and quality of healthcare services\nbenchmarking; and\n  (viii) Training needs for students and employment outcomes.\n  2. Advisory board members. The advisory board shall consist of the\nfollowing members:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the commissioner of the department of health;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\none representative of organized labor representing employees at the\nstate university of New York pursuant to article fourteen of the civil\nservice law, who shall be appointed by the governor upon recommendation\nof the president of the union representing the greatest number of\nemployees at SUNY Downstate;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member appointed by the temporary\npresident of the senate;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member appointed by the speaker of the\nassembly;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>three members appointed by the governor;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member\nappointed by the governor upon the joint recommendation of Brooklyn\ncommunity boards 9 and 17; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the chancellor of the state\nuniversity of New York.\n  3. Outreach. The advisory board shall solicit recommendations from\nhealthcare experts, county health departments, community-based\norganizations, state and regional healthcare industry associations,\nlabor unions, experts in hospital operations, and other interested\nparties. The advisory board shall hold no less than three public\nhearings with requisite public notice to solicit input and\nrecommendations from any interested party.\n  4. Compensation. The members of the advisory board shall receive no\ncompensation for their service as members, but shall be allowed their\nactual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their\nduties.\n  5. Recommendations and report.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The advisory board shall complete a\nstudy and provide written recommendations to prioritize healthcare\nservices provided in the SUNY Downstate service area. The written\nrecommendations shall include a reasonable, scalable and fiscally\nresponsible plan for the financial health, viability and sustainability\nof SUNY Downstate; provided, however, that such plan shall incorporate\nutilization of all available state and federally available appropriated\namounts, and shall not exceed more than two hundred fifty percent of\nsuch amounts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_996__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A report of the advisory board's recommendations shall be provided\nto the governor, the temporary president of the senate, and the speaker\nof the assembly no later than April first, two thousand twenty-five.\n  6. Certificate of need. The public health and health planning council\nand the commissioner of health are prohibited from reviewing or\napproving any certificate of need application related to a reduction in\ninpatient services pursuant to any article of law or regulation that may\naffect a change to inpatient services at SUNY Downstate health sciences\nuniversity until at least April first, two thousand twenty-five.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>