<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11">
        <num>11</num>
        <heading>Assessment of certain expenses of administration of the department of civil service</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "expenses of administration" means the total cost of\nadministration of the department, excluding costs of providing services\nto municipalities and costs of administration of the health benefit\nplan, and excluding costs of special programs or activities of the\ndepartment as may be determined by the president, subject to approval of\nthe director of the budget, which do not serve generally all state\ndepartments and agencies under the jurisdiction of the department;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "public authority" means a public authority or public\nbenefit corporation under the jurisdiction of the department of civil\nservice;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "position" means an office or position, other than a\nseasonal or temporary position, in the classified service under the\njurisdiction of the department of civil service.\n  2. A fractional share of the expenses of administration, as determined\npursuant to subdivision three of this section, shall be charged against\nand payable from the following sources:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the salary or compensation of ten or more positions in any\ndepartment or agency of the state is payable from a special or\nadministrative fund, other than the state purposes fund or the local\nassistance fund or the capital construction fund of the general fund of\nthe state, or an income fund of the state university, or the mental\nhygiene services fund, such fractional share shall be charged against\nand payable from such special or administrative fund;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the salary or compensation of ten or more positions in any\ndepartment or agency of the state is payable from an appropriation\nassessed or to be collected or refunded pursuant to law, such fractional\nshare shall be included in and payable from such appropriation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such fractional share shall be payable by each public authority\nhaving ten or more positions.\n  3. For the purpose of computing the fractional share of the expenses\nof administration for any fiscal year to be payable from a source\nspecified in subdivision two of this section, the numerator of such\nfraction shall be the number of positions the salary or compensation of\nwhich is payable from such source and the denominator shall be the total\nnumber of positions in the service of the state and public authorities.\nThe numbers of positions shall be the numbers of positions existing as\nof October thirty-first in such fiscal year.\n  4. As soon as practicable after the close of the fiscal year ending\nMarch thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-seven, and thereafter as soon\nas practicable after the close of each fiscal year, the president shall\ndetermine the amount representing the share of expenses of\nadministration for such fiscal year chargeable to each source specified\nin subdivision two of this section, and shall certify such amount to the\nappropriate department or agency of the state or public authority. Such\nsums shall be payable to the commissioner of taxation and finance at the\nbeginning of the fiscal year following such certification.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>