<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="130"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_130">
        <num>130</num>
        <heading>Salary grades; minimum and maximum salaries</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision\nof this chapter, effective April twenty-eighth, nineteen hundred\neighty-eight, for employees on the administration payroll and May fifth,\nnineteen hundred eighty-eight, for employees on the institution payroll,\nan employee holding a position in the collective negotiating unit\ndesignated as the security services unit allocated to a salary grade\ndescribed in paragraph b of subdivision one of this section shall be\nentitled to a longevity payment upon the completion of ten years of\ncontinuous service in a title or a combination of titles which exist or\nhave existed in the security services/supervisors occupational title\nseries. Such employee shall be entitled to an additional longevity\npayment upon the completion of fifteen years of such service and an\nadditional longevity payment upon completion of twenty years of such\nservice. The longevity amount shall be as specified in the current\nsalary schedule for the salary grade for the position which the employee\nholds upon completion of the prescribed service requirements or, in the\ncase of the twenty year longevity payment, half of the performance\nadvance amount for such grade for such position. Effective April first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine, the twenty year longevity payment shall be\nthree-quarters of the performance advance amount for such grade for such\nposition and, effective April first, nineteen hundred ninety, the twenty\nyear longevity payment shall be equal to the performance advance amount\nfor such grade for such position. The longevity amount shall not exceed\nthe longevity maximum, and shall be added to the employee's basic salary\neffective on the first day of the payroll period which next begins\nfollowing completion of such service; provided, however, that an\nemployee's basic annual salary may not exceed the longevity maximum of\nthe salary grade of the employee's current position as a result of a\nlongevity payment. Notwithstanding the for...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this chapter,\neffective April twenty-eighth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight for\nemployees on the administration payroll and May fifth, nineteen hundred\neighty-eight for employees on the institution payroll, an employee\nholding a position in the collective negotiating unit designated as the\nsecurity supervisors unit allocated to a salary grade prescribed in\nparagraph b of subdivision one of this section shall be entitled to a\nlongevity payment upon the completion of ten years of continuous service\nin a title or a combination of titles which exist or have existed in the\nsecurity services/supervisors occupational title series. Such employee\nshall be entitled to an additional longevity payment upon the completion\nof fifteen years of such service and an additional longevity payment\nupon completion of twenty years of such service. The longevity amount\nshall be as specified in the salary schedule for the current salary\ngrade for the position which the employee holds upon completion of\nprescribed service requirements or in the case of the twenty year\nlongevity payment half of the performance advance amount for such grade\nfor such position. Effective April first, nineteen hundred eighty-nine,\nthe twenty year longevity payment shall be three-quarters of the\nperformance advance amount for such grade for such position and,\neffective April first, nineteen hundred ninety, the twenty year\nlongevity payment shall be equal to the performance advance amount for\nsuch grade for such position. The longevity amount shall not exceed the\nlongevity maximum and shall be added to the employee's basic annual\nsalary effective on the first day of the payroll period which next\nbegins following completion of such service; except that the twenty year\nlongevity payment shall be for the salary grade for the position which\nthe employee presently holds and shall be added to the employee's basic\nsalary effective on the first day of...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this subdivision, the term continuous service\nshall mean uninterrupted service in the classified service. An employee\nwho has been on a preferred list pursuant to section eighty-one of this\nchapter, or section two hundred forty-three of the military law, or who\nhas been on leave of absence, or who has resigned and who has been\nreinstated, or who has been on workers' compensation leave, shall be\ndeemed to have continuous service; provided, however, that such employee\nshall not receive credit for other than paid service or time spent on\nworkers' compensation leave, but the failure to receive credit for\nservice shall not constitute an interruption of continuous service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Effective on and after April first, nineteen hundred seventy-nine\nthat portion of the basic annual salary of an employee to whom the\nprovisions of this subdivision apply which exceeds the job rate of the\nsalary grade to which his position is allocated, and any additions to\nhis basic annual salary paid in accordance with the provisions of\nparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall be considered to be\nlongevity payment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where, and to the extent that, an agreement between the state\nand an employee organization entered into pursuant to article fourteen\nof this chapter on behalf of officers and employees serving in positions\nin the administrative services unit, institutional services unit,\noperational services unit or division of military and naval affairs unit\nso provides officers and employees to whom paragraph a of subdivision\none of this section applies who, on or after April first, two thousand\nsixteen, on their anniversary date have five or more years, but less\nthan ten years, of continuous service as defined by paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision at a basic annual salary rate equal to or in excess of\nthe job rate or maximum salary of their salary grade, shall receive a\nlump sum payment in the amount of one thousand two hundred fifty\ndollars. Effective April first, two thousand nineteen, such lump sum\npayment shall increase to one thousand five hundred dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Effective until March thirty-first, two thousand twenty, where,\nand to the extent that, an agreement between the state and an employee\norganization entered into pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter\non behalf of officers and employees serving in positions in the\nadministrative services unit, institutional services unit, operational\nservices unit or division of military and naval affairs unit so provides\nofficers and employees to whom paragraph a of subdivision one of this\nsection applies who, on or after April first, two thousand sixteen, on\ntheir anniversary date have ten or more years of continuous service as\ndefined by paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision at a basic annual salary\nrate equal to or in excess of the job rate or maximum salary of their\nsalary grade shall receive a lump sum payment in the amount of two\nthousand five hundred dollars which, effective April first, two thousand\nnineteen, such lump sum payment shall be increased to three thousand\ndollars. Effective April first, two thousand twenty, where, and to the\nextent that, an agreement between the state and an employee organization\nentered into pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter on behalf of\nofficers and employees serving in positions in the administrative\nservices unit, institutional services unit, operational services unit or\ndivision of military and naval affairs unit so provides officers and\nemployees to whom paragraph a of subdivision one of this section applies\nwho, on or after April first, two thousand twenty, on their anniversary\ndate have ten or more years, but less than fifteen years, of continuous\nservice as defined by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision at a basic\nannual salary rate equal to or in excess of the job rate or maximum\nsalary of their salary grade shall receive a lump sum payment in the\namount of three thousand dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Effective April first, two thousand twenty, where, and to the\nextent that, an agreement between the state and an employee organization\nentered into pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter on behalf of\nofficers and employees serving in positions in the administrative\nservices unit, institutional services unit, operational services unit or\ndivision of military and naval affairs unit so provides officers and\nemployees to whom paragraph a of subdivision one of this section applies\nwho, on or after April first, two thousand twenty, on their anniversary\ndate have fifteen or more years of continuous service as defined by\nparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision at a basic annual salary rate equal to\nor in excess of the job rate or maximum salary of their salary grade\nshall receive a lump sum payment in the amount of four thousand five\nhundred dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such lump sum payment, as provided by this paragraph, shall be in\naddition to and not part of the employee's basic annual salary, provided\nhowever that any amount payable by this paragraph shall be included as\ncompensation for overtime and retirement purposes. Such lump sum\npayment, as provided by this paragraph, shall be payable in April of\neach fiscal year, or as soon as practicable thereafter, for those\neligible employees who have achieved five or more, or ten or more, or\nfifteen or more years of continuous service as defined by paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision at a basic annual salary rate equal to or in excess\nof the job rate or maximum salary of their salary grade during the\nperiod October first through March thirty-first of the previous fiscal\nyear. Such lump sum payment, as provided by this paragraph, shall be\npayable in October of each fiscal year, or as soon as practicable\nthereafter, for those eligible employees who have achieved five or more,\nor ten or more, or fifteen or more years of continuous service as\ndefined by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision at a basic annual salary\nrate equal to or in excess of the job rate or maximum salary of their\nsalary grade during the period April first through September thirtieth\nof that same fiscal year.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Effective April first, two thousand twenty-five, where, and to the\nextent that, an agreement between the state and an employee organization\nentered into pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter on behalf of\nofficers and employees serving in positions in the administrative\nservices unit, institutional services unit, operational services unit or\ndivision of military and naval affairs unit so provides officers and\nemployees to whom paragraph a of subdivision one of this section applies\nwho, on or after April first, two thousand twenty-five, on their\nanniversary date have twelve or more years, but less than seventeen\nyears, of continuous service within one or any of the collective\nbargaining units, shall receive a lump sum payment in the amount of one\nthousand five hundred dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Effective April first, two thousand twenty-five, where, and to the\nextent that, an agreement between the state and an employee organization\nentered into pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter on behalf of\nofficers and employees serving in positions in the administrative\nservices unit, institutional services unit, operational services unit or\ndivision of military and naval affairs unit so provides officers and\nemployees to whom paragraph a of subdivision one of this section applies\nwho, on or after April first, two thousand twenty-five, on their\nanniversary date have seventeen or more years but less than twenty-two\nyears of continuous service within one or any of the collective\nbargaining units shall receive a lump sum payment in the amount of three\nthousand dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Effective April first, two thousand twenty-five, where, and to the\nextent that, an agreement between the state and an employee organization\nentered into pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter on behalf of\nofficers and employees serving in positions in the administrative\nservices unit, institutional services unit, operational services unit or\ndivision of military and naval affairs unit so provides officers and\nemployees to whom paragraph a of subdivision one of this section applies\nwho, on or after April first, two thousand twenty-five, on their\nanniversary date have twenty-two or more years of continuous service\nwithin one or any of the collective bargaining units shall receive a\nlump sum payment in the amount of four thousand five hundred dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such lump sum payment, as provided by subparagraphs five, six and\nseven of this paragraph, shall be in addition to and not part of the\nemployee's basic annual salary, provided however that any amount payable\nby this paragraph shall be included as compensation for overtime and\nretirement purposes.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such lump sum payment, as provided by subparagraphs five, six and\nseven of this paragraph, shall be payable in April of each fiscal year,\nor as soon as practicable thereafter, for those eligible employees who\nhave achieved the continuous service required for a specific payment\nduring the period October first through March thirty-first of the\nprevious fiscal year. Such lump sum payment, as provided by subparagraph\nfive, six or seven of this paragraph, shall be payable in October of\neach fiscal year, or as soon as practicable thereafter, for those\neligible employees who have achieved the continuous service, as defined\nby this section, required for a specific payment during the period April\nfirst through September thirtieth of that same fiscal year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_c__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Effective April first, two thousand twenty-five, no employee\nshall receive a longevity payment pursuant to subparagraph one, two or\nthree of this paragraph. All employees, to the extent eligible, shall\nreceive a longevity payment pursuant to subparagraph five, six or seven\nof this paragraph.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, officers and employees otherwise eligible to receive the\nlongevity payments provided by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision who, on\ntheir eligibility date, are serving in a higher graded position</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on a\ntemporary basis or on a probationary or a permanent basis and\nsubsequently fail the probationary period or accept a voluntary demotion\nwhich is not a consequence or settlement of a disciplinary action or are\ndemoted as a result of the abolition of positions and (ii) return to a\nposition in a lower salary grade and (iii) remain in such lower salary\ngrade for at least six payroll periods shall be eligible for such\nlongevity payments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Officers and employees to whom the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision apply who were serving at an annual salary rate equal\nto or in excess of the job rate or maximum salary of the salary grade of\ntheir position as of July first, nineteen hundred seventy-nine, and who\nwere in full employment status on a full-time basis for the period April\nfirst, nineteen hundred seventy-nine through June thirtieth, nineteen\nhundred seventy-nine, shall be considered to have been paid at the\nannual salary rate equal to or above the job rate for their grade for\nthat period in determining fulfillment of the service requirements\nspecified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. The provisions of this\nparagraph apply solely for the purpose of implementation of the\nprovisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Officers and employees to whom the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision apply who were serving at an annual salary rate equal\nto or in excess of the job rate or maximum salary of the salary grade of\ntheir position and who were appointed or promoted to a position of\nequivalent or higher salary grade at an annual salary rate equal to or\nin excess of the job rate or maximum annual salary shall be entitled to\nhave such service in each such position considered as eligible service\nin determining fulfillment of the service requirements specified in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any foregoing provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision to the contrary, officers and employees to whom the\nprovisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision apply who were serving\nat an annual salary rate equal to or in excess of the job rate or\nmaximum salary of the salary grade of their position and whose annual\nsalary rate was subsequently less than the job rate or maximum salary of\ntheir position as a result of the mechanics of salary computation upon\nreallocation shall, solely for the purpose of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, be entitled to have service at such lower salary rate\ndeemed to be service at the job rate and considered as eligible service\nin determining fulfillment of the service requirements specified in such\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provided the actual annual salary rate of such officers or\nemployees is equal to or in excess of the job rate on their anniversary\ndates.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to provide for the officers and employees to whom this\nsubdivision applies who are not allocated to salary grades, increases\nand payments pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision in proportion\nto those provided to persons to whom this applies who are allocated to\nsalary grades, the director of the budget is authorized to add\nappropriate adjustments and/or payments to the compensation which such\nofficers and employees are otherwise entitled to receive. The director\nof the budget shall issue certificates which shall contain schedules of\npositions and the salaries and/or payments thereof for which adjustments\nand/or payments are made pursuant to the provisions of this paragraph\nand a copy of each such certificate shall be filed with the state\ncomptroller, the department of civil service, the chairman of the senate\nfinance committee and the chairman of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee.\n  4. Increased hiring salaries. Whenever the director shall determine\nthat it is impracticable to recruit for a position at its then hiring\nsalary in one or more or all areas or locations, he, subject to the\napproval of the director of the budget, may increase the hiring salary\nof the salary grade of such position with respect to which such\ndetermination shall have been made, but not to exceed the job rate of\nthe salary grade of such position. Such new hiring salary shall remain\nin effect until he shall prescribe a different hiring salary pursuant to\nthis subdivision or restore the hiring salary to the hiring salary set\nforth in this section. When any such increase is made with respect to\none or more or all areas or locations, all incumbents of such positions\nwho are employed in any state department, state institution or other\nstate agency, in the particular area or areas or location or locations\naffected, who are receiving less than such new hiring salary shall have\ntheir salaries brought up to such hiring salary. For the purpose of\ncomputing future performance advances such incumbents and new employees\nin such positions shall be credited with the amount of performance\nadvances in such positions which correspo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The incumbent of any such position, for which an increased hiring\nsalary is prescribed under the provisions of this subdivision, who is\nappointed, transferred or reinstated to the same titled position in an\narea or location to which the same increased hiring salary does not\napply shall receive, upon such appointment, transfer or reinstatement,\nthe salary he would have received had he been originally employed in\nsuch area or location to which he is appointed, transferred or\nreinstated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The incumbent of any such position for which an increased hiring\nsalary is prescribed under the provisions of this subdivision, who is\nappointed, transferred, reinstated or demoted to another position in the\nsame or a lower salary grade, for which an increased hiring salary is\nnot prescribed, shall receive, upon such appointment, transfer,\nreinstatement or demotion, the rate of compensation which he would be\nentitled to receive had his service for the period of time during which\nhe held the position from which he is appointed, transferred, reinstated\nor demoted, been rendered in the position to which he is appointed,\ntransferred, reinstated or demoted.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The incumbent of any such position for which an increased hiring\nsalary is prescribed under the provisions of this subdivision, who is\nappointed, transferred, reinstated or demoted to another position in the\nsame or a lower salary grade for which an increased hiring salary is\nalso prescribed under the provisions of this subdivision, shall receive,\nupon such appointment, transfer, reinstatement or demotion, the rate of\ncompensation which he would be entitled to receive had his service for\nthe period of time during which he held the position from which he is\nappointed, transferred, reinstated or demoted, been rendered in the\nposition to which he is appointed, transferred, reinstated or demoted.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The incumbent of any such position for which an increased hiring\nsalary is prescribed under the provisions of this subdivision, who is\nappointed or promoted to another position in a higher salary grade,\nshall receive, upon such appointment or promotion, a salary as\ndetermined pursuant to the provisions of subdivision two of section one\nhundred thirty-one of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The incumbent of a position for which an increased hiring salary\nis not prescribed under the provisions of this subdivision, who is\nappointed, transferred, demoted or reinstated to a position in the same\nor a lower salary grade for which an increased hiring salary is\nprescribed shall receive, upon such appointment, transfer, demotion or\nreinstatement, the hiring salary of the grade of such new position as\nprescribed in subdivision one of this section plus the number of annual\nincrements and the percentage value of performance advances actually\nreceived in the positions from which and to which he is appointed,\ntransferred, demoted or reinstated; provided, however, that he shall\nreceive at least the increased hiring salary of such new position as\nprescribed under the provisions of this subdivision and not more than\nthe job rate of the grade of such new position.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where an increased hiring salary prescribed under the provisions\nof this subdivision for any position is reduced or discontinued, the\nsalary of a then incumbent of such position shall not be reduced.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Applications to director. Any employee, employee\nrepresentative, or appointing officer, with respect to any position or\npositions in his department or agency, may apply to the director, on a\nform prescribed and furnished by him, for a review of such position or\npositions to determine whether a pay differential should be authorized\npursuant to this section. The director may consolidate applications\npertaining to a particular position or positions. The director may\ndesignate an officer or employee of the division to conduct a hearing\nwith relation to any application for a pay differential. Such\napplications shall not include any matter involving an employee's rate\nof compensation which is presently provided for under sections one\nhundred twenty and one hundred twenty-one of the civil service law, or\nany other matter which is otherwise reviewable pursuant to law or any\nrule or regulation having the force and effect of law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Appeals. Any employee, employee representative or appointing\nofficer aggrieved by a determination of the director may appeal from\nsuch determination to the commission. Such appeal must be made within\nsixty days after receipt of a written notice of such determination.\nDeterminations of the commission shall be subject to the same\nconditions, restrictions and limitations provided in this section for\nthe determinations of the director. The commission shall transmit its\ndecision to the director of the budget, the director of the division of\nclassification and compensation and the employees, employee\nrepresentative or department heads affected thereby.\n  6. Shift pay differentials. Whenever the director finds that under\nprevailing wage practices in private or other public employment in the\nstate, employees in a given occupation receive a higher rate of pay or\nwage differential for a work shift other than that which is paid to\nemployees in the same occupation, the director may, subject to the\napproval of the director of the budget, authorize a pay differential to\nbe paid to those employees in positions in the same or related\noccupations in the state service and who are assigned to an equivalent\nor substantially equivalent work shift, on a statewide basis, provided\nhowever, where the director finds that in a particular geographical area\nor areas wage practices would warrant a shift differential for employees\nin a particular occupation then the director may grant a work shift pay\ndifferential for such employees, subject to the approval of the director\nof the budget. In determining whether to authorize a pay differential\nthe director shall consider the various duties on each shift, in\nrelation to the normal day shift. A pay differential under this\nsubdivision shall be a percentage of basic salary, an hourly rate, an\nannual rate, or a fixed dollar amount per pay period, as prescribed in\neach case by the director of the classification and compensatio...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this\nsubdivision shall apply to the following full-time state officers and\nemployees in salary grades M/C 17 and below:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>officers and employees\nwhose positions are designated managerial or confidential pursuant to\narticle fourteen of this chapter;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>civilian state employees of the\ndivision of military and naval affairs in the executive department whose\npositions are not in, or are excluded from representation rights in, any\nrecognized or certified negotiating unit;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>officers and employees\nexcluded from representation rights under article fourteen of this\nchapter pursuant to rules or regulations of the public employment\nrelations board.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Effective April first, two thousand nineteen longevity payments\nshall be made in the amount of one thousand five hundred dollars to\nofficers and employees as defined herein who on their anniversary date\nhave five or more years of continuous service as defined by paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of this section at a basic annual salary rate\nequal to or in excess of the job rate or maximum salary of their salary\ngrade, and in the amount of three thousand dollars to officers and\nemployees as defined herein who on their anniversary date have ten or\nmore years of continuous service as defined by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of this section at a basic annual salary rate equal to\nor in excess of the job rate or maximum salary of their salary grade.\nAdditionally, effective April first, two thousand twenty, such officers\nand employees to whom the provisions of this subdivision apply whose\nbasic annual salary equals or exceeds the job rate of the salary grade\nof their position who on their anniversary date have fifteen or more\nyears of continuous service as defined by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\nthree of this section at a basic annual salary rate equal to or in\nexcess of the job rate or maximum salary of their salary grade shall on\nsuch anniversary date receive a longevity payment in the amount of four\nthousand five hundred dollars. Such payments shall be made in addition\nto and shall not be considered part of basic annual salary and shall be\nmade by separate check as soon as practicable following the anniversary\ndate upon which the required service is attained.\n  Effective April first, two thousand twenty-five, officers and\nemployees to whom paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision applies who, on or\nafter April first, two thousand twenty-five, on their anniversary date\nhave twelve or more years, but less than seventeen years, of continuous\nservice in the state, shall receive a lump sum payment in the amount of\none thousand five hundred dollars. Effective April first, two thousand\ntwenty-five, officers and employees to whom this subdivision applies\nwho, on or after April first, two thousand twenty-five, on their\nanniversary date have seventeen or more years but less than twenty-two\nyears of continuous service in the state shall receive a lump sum\npayment in the amount of three thousand dollars. Effective April first,\ntwo thousand twenty-five, officers and employees to whom paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision applies who, on or after April first, two thousand\ntwenty-five, on their anniversary date have twenty-two or more years of\ncontinuous service in the state shall receive a lump sum payment in the\namount of four thousand five hundred dollars. Such lump sum payment\nshall be in addition to and not part of the employee's basic annual\nsalary, provided however that any amount payable shall be included as\ncompensation for overtime and retirement purposes. Such lump sum payment\nshall be paid as authorized by the director of the budget. No employee\nshall receive more than one longevity payment and, to the greatest\nextent possible, employees shall receive the longevity payment under the\ncontinuous years of service in the state except that no employee shall\nlose a longevity payment if they have previously received one by virtue\nof the years at job rate service calculation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The increases in salary payable pursuant to this subdivision shall\napply on a prorated basis to officers and employees, otherwise eligible\nto receive an increase in salary pursuant to this subdivision, who are\npaid on an hourly or per diem basis, employees serving on a part-time or\nseasonal basis and employees paid on any basis other than at an annual\nsalary rate; except that the provisions of this subdivision shall not\napply to employees serving on a seasonal basis, except as determined by\nthe director of the budget.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this subdivision,\nofficers and employees who are otherwise eligible to receive such\nlongevity payment but who on the anniversary eligibility date are\nserving in a higher graded position</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on a temporary basis or on a\nprobationary or permanent basis and subsequently fail the probationary\nperiod or accept a voluntary demotion during the probationary period or\nare demoted as a result of the abolition of positions and (ii) return to\na position in their former salary grade within one year of such\neligibility date and (iii) remain in their former salary grade for at\nleast six payroll periods shall be eligible for such longevity payment,\nexcept that officers and employees who return to their former salary\ngrade as a result of a disciplinary action or who accept a voluntary\ndemotion after successful completion of the probationary period shall\nnot be eligible for such longevity payment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Officers and employees to whom the provisions of this subdivision\napply who were serving at an annual salary rate equal to or in excess of\nthe job rate or maximum salary of the salary grade of their position and\nwhose annual salary rate was during some subsequent period less than the\njob rate or maximum salary of the salary grade of their position as a\nresult of an increase in the job rate or maximum salary, shall be\nconsidered to have been paid at the annual salary rate equal to or in\nexcess of the job rate for their grade for such period in determining\nfulfillment of the service requirements specified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, provided the officers and employees were in full-time\nemployment status. The provisions of this paragraph apply solely for the\npurpose of implementation of the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Officers and employees to whom the provisions of this subdivision\napply who were serving at an annual salary rate equal to or in excess of\nthe job rate or maximum salary of the salary grade of their position and\nwho were appointed or promoted to a position of equivalent or higher\nsalary grade at an annual salary rate equal to or in excess of the job\nrate or maximum annual salary shall be entitled to have such service in\neach such position considered as eligible service in determining\nfulfillment of the service requirements specified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any foregoing provisions of this subdivision to\nthe contrary, officers and employees to whom the provisions of this\nsubdivision apply who were serving at an annual salary rate equal to or\nin excess of the job rate or maximum salary of the salary grade of their\nposition and whose annual salary rate was subsequently less than the job\nrate or maximum salary of the salary grade of their position as a result\nof the mechanics of salary computation upon reallocation, shall, solely\nfor the purpose of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, be entitled to\nhave service at such lower salary rate deemed to be service at the job\nrate and considered as eligible service in determining fulfillment of\nthe service requirements specified in such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provided the\nactual annual salary rate of such officers or employees is equal to or\nin excess of the job rate of the salary grade of their position on the\nanniversary date upon which eligibility for a longevity payment provided\npursuant to this subdivision is attained.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amounts provided pursuant to this subdivision, unless\notherwise expressly provided herein, shall be in addition to and shall\nnot be part of the employee's basic annual salary; provided, however,\nthat any amounts payable pursuant to this subdivision shall be included\nas compensation for retirement purposes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Officers and employees whose basic annual salary is or was less\nthan the job rate of the salary grade of their position but was not or\nis not less than ninety-eight percent of such job rate shall for the\npurpose of this subdivision be deemed to be or have been at the job rate\nas appropriate.\n  9. Hazardous duty differentials.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where, and to the extent that, an\nagreement between the state and an employee organization entered into\npursuant to article fourteen of this chapter so provide, on behalf of\nemployees serving in positions in a collective negotiating unit\nrepresented by such employee organization, and for employees designated\nmanagerial or confidential pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter\nand civilian state employees of the division of military and naval\naffairs of the executive department whose positions are not in, or are\nexcluded from representation rights in, any recognized or certified\nnegotiating unit, whenever the director determines that an employee who\nis serving in a position at a particular work location or as a result of\na temporary work assignment is exposed to an unavoidable, clear and\ndirect risk and hazard to safety and health, the director may, subject\nto the approval of the director of the budget, authorize a hazardous\nduty differential for the employee assigned to such position or\ntemporary work assignment. Except for such managerial or confidential\nemployees and such civilian state employees of the division of military\nand naval affairs whose positions are not in, or are excluded from\nrepresentation rights in, any recognized or certified negotiating unit,\nsuch differentials determined by the director during the term of such\nagreement shall only be payable from an amount which is collectively\nnegotiated for such purposes pursuant to the terms of such an agreement\nbetween the state and an employee organization representing such\nemployees; thereafter such differentials shall continue for those\nemployees assigned to such position or temporary work assignment unless\nterminated or revoked in accordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A hazardous duty differential under this subdivision shall be a\npercentage or a fixed dollar amount, as prescribed by the director of\nclassification and compensation, subject to the approval of the director\nof the budget. Such differentials shall be in addition to and shall not\nbe part of an employee's basic annual salary, and shall not affect or\nimpair any performance advancement payments, performance awards,\nlongevity payments or other rights or benefits to which an employee may\nbe entitled under the provisions of this chapter, provided, however,\nthat any differential payable pursuant to this subdivision shall be\nincluded as compensation for retirement purposes. A hazardous duty\ndifferential shall be terminated for any employee who ceases to be\nemployed in the position or assignment for which the pay differential\nwas authorized; or upon revocation of such differential or upon\ncessation of the temporary hazardous duty as determined by the director\nof classification and compensation. The director of the budget may adopt\nregulations to carry out the provisions of this subdivision.\n  10. Performance based payments for certain state officers and\nemployees in the rent regulation services negotiating unit.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The\nprovisions of this subdivision shall apply to full-time officers and\nemployees in the rent regulation services negotiating unit established\npursuant to article fourteen of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, officers and\nemployees to whom paragraph e of subdivision one of this section applies\nwho, on or after April first, two thousand ten, on their anniversary\ndate have five or more years of continuous service as defined by\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of this section at a basic annual\nsalary rate equal to or in excess of the job rate or maximum salary of\ntheir salary grade, shall receive a lump sum payment in the amount of\none thousand two hundred fifty dollars. Effective April first, two\nthousand nineteen, such lump sum payment shall increase to one thousand\nfive hundred dollars. Officers and employees to whom paragraph e of\nsubdivision one of this section applies who, on or after April first,\ntwo thousand ten, on their anniversary date have ten or more years of\ncontinuous service as defined by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of\nthis section at a basic annual salary rate equal to or in excess of the\njob rate or maximum salary of their salary grade shall receive a lump\nsum payment in the amount of two thousand five hundred dollars.\nEffective April First, two thousand nineteen, such lump sum payment\nshall be increased to three thousand dollars.\n  Officers and employees to whom paragraph e of subdivision one of this\nsection applies who, on or after April first, two thousand twenty, on\ntheir anniversary date have fifteen or more years of continuous service\nas defined by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of this section at a\nbasic annual salary rate equal to or in excess of the job rate or\nmaximum salary of their salary grade shall receive a lump sum payment in\nthe amount of four thousand five hundred dollars.\n  Such lump sum payment shall be in addition to and not part of the\nemployee's basic annual salary, provided however that any amount payable\nherein shall be included as compensation for overtime and retirement\npurposes.\n  Such lump sum payment shall be payable in April of each fiscal year,\nor as soon as practicable thereafter, for those eligible employees who\nhave achieved five or more, ten or more or fifteen or more years of\ncontinuous service as defined by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of\nthis section at a basic annual salary rate equal to or in excess of the\njob rate or maximum salary of their salary grade during the period\nOctober first through March thirty-first of the previous fiscal year.\nSuch payment shall be payable in October of each fiscal year, or as soon\nas practicable thereafter, for those eligible employees who have\nachieved five or more, ten or more or fifteen or more years of\ncontinuous service as defined by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of\nthis section at a basic annual salary rate equal to or in excess of the\njob rate or maximum salary of their salary grade during the period April\nfirst through September thirtieth of that same fiscal year. All\ncompensation already included in an employee's basic annual salary shall\nremain included in such basic annual salary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, officers and employees otherwise eligible to receive the\nlongevity payments provided by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision who, on\ntheir eligibility date, are serving in a higher graded position</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on a\ntemporary basis or on a probationary or a permanent basis and\nsubsequently fail the probationary period or accept a voluntary demotion\nwhich is not a consequence or settlement of a disciplinary action or are\ndemoted as a result of the abolition of positions and (ii) return to a\nposition in a lower salary grade and (iii) remain in such lower salary\ngrade for at least six payroll periods shall be eligible for such\nlongevity payments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Officers and employees to whom the provisions of this subdivision\napply who were serving at an annual salary rate in excess of the job\nrate of their salary grade as of March thirty-first, nineteen hundred\neighty-five, shall be deemed to have been paid at the annual salary rate\nequal to or above the job rate for their salary grade for a period of\nfive years for the purpose of determining fulfillment of the service\nrequirements specified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. The\nprovisions of this paragraph apply solely for the purpose of\nimplementation of the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Officers and employees to whom the provisions of this subdivision\napply who were serving at an annual salary rate equal to or in excess of\nthe job rate or maximum salary of the salary grade of their position and\nwho were appointed or promoted to a position of equivalent or higher\nsalary grade at an annual salary rate equal to or in excess of the job\nrate or maximum salary of the salary grade of their position shall be\nentitled to have such service in each such position considered as\neligible service in determining fulfillment of the service requirements\nspecified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any foregoing provisions of this subdivision to\nthe contrary, officers and employees to whom the provisions of this\nsubdivision apply who were serving at an annual salary rate equal to or\nin excess of the job rate or maximum salary of the salary grade of their\nposition and whose annual salary rate was subsequently less than the job\nrate or maximum salary of their position as a result of the mechanics of\nsalary computation upon reallocation, shall, solely for the purpose of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, be entitled to have service at such\nlower salary rate deemed to be service at the job rate and considered as\neligible service in determining fulfillment of the service requirements\nspecified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision provided the actual\nannual salary rate of such officers or employees is equal to or in\nexcess of the job rate on March thirty-first, two thousand three, or on\ntheir anniversary dates for the purpose of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision.\n  11-a. Performance awards; longevity increases and salary review.\nNotwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of this section or any other\nlaw and where, and to the extent that, an agreement between the state\nand an employee organization entered into pursuant to article fourteen\nof this chapter so provides on behalf of employees serving in positions\nin a collective negotiating unit represented by such employee\norganization and for employees designated managerial or confidential\npursuant to such article of this chapter and civilian state employees in\nthe division of military and naval affairs whose positions are not in or\nare excluded from representation rights in any recognized or certified\nnegotiating unit, effective April first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven,\nofficers and employees who are eligible for longevity step increases,\nperformance award increases or bonuses, or any other increases or\nbonuses based on length of service at or above the job rate of their\nsalary grade, who were receiving a salary equal to or in excess of the\njob rate of the grade and who have been promoted, appointed or otherwise\nadvanced to a position in a higher salary grade and whose former\nposition has been reallocated to a higher salary grade as a result of\nthe implementation of the system developed pursuant to the provisions of\nsection seventeen of chapter three hundred two, subdivision eleven of\nsection nineteen of chapter three hundred six, section six of chapter\nthree hundred three, or section eleven of chapter three hundred eight of\nthe laws of nineteen hundred eighty-five and who are serving in a\nposition allocated to the salary grade to which such former position has\nbeen reallocated shall, solely for the purpose of determining\neligibility for any such increases or bonuses, be entitled to have all\nservice in such position or positions to which promoted, appointed or\notherwise advanced credited as if it were service at the job rate...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>