<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-151"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-151"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="151"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-151/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-151/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-151/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-151/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_151">
        <num>151</num>
        <heading>Leaves of absence for participation in certain athletic competitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_151__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "public employee" means any person holding a position by\nappointment or employment in the service of a public employer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_151__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "public employer" means</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_151__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state of New York, (ii) a\ncounty, city, town, village or any other political subdivision or civil\ndivision of the state, (iii) a school district or any governmental\nentity operating a public school, college or university, (iv) a public\nimprovement or special district,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_151__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a public authority, commission, or\npublic benefit corporation, or (vi) any other public corporation, agency\nor instrumentality or unit of government which exercises governmental\npowers under the laws of the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_151__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "team" means any group leader, coach, official or athlete\nwho comprises the official delegation of the United States to world, Pan\nAmerican or Olympic competition.\n  2. A public employee who qualifies as a member of a United States team\nfor athletic competition on the world, Pan American or Olympic level, in\na sport contested in either Pan American or Olympic competitions, shall\nat the discretion of the public employer be granted a leave of absence\nfrom employment without loss of pay or diminution of any other\nprivilege, benefit or right arising out of such employment and in\naccordance with the provisions of this section.\n  3. Such leave shall be available only for the purpose of preparing for\nand engaging in either or both such competitions and in no event shall\nthe total of all such leave granted to a public employee exceed the\nperiod of the official training camp and competition combined or ninety\ncalendar days a year, whichever is less.\n  4. The electing public employer shall pay at the employee's regular\nrate of pay for each week of leave granted in the amount the employee\nwould receive for a standard work week. The employee shall not be\nentitled to receive compensation for any day spent in camp or\ncompetition for which compensation would not ordinarily be paid.\n  5. The president of the civil service commission shall promulgate\nappropriate rules necessary to effectuate the provisions of this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>