<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-158"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-158"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="158"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-158/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-158/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-158/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-158/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_158">
        <num>158</num>
        <heading>Group term life insurance plan and group accident and health benefit plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 158. Group term life insurance plan and group accident and health\nbenefit plan. 1. The president, subject to the provisions of this\nsection, is hereby empowered to establish regulations relating to, and\nto enter into and administer contracts providing for, a group term life\ninsurance plan, and a group accident and health benefit plan on behalf\nof legislators, employees of the legislature hired on an annual basis,\njudges and justices of the unified court system, and state employees and\nretired employees who, for the purposes of article fourteen of this\nchapter, have been for a period of time prescribed by the regulations\nand, except for such retirees, continue to be in positions designated as\nmanagerial or confidential positions. The president may authorize the\ninclusion in the plan of such employees and retired employees of other\ngovernments or public employers as defined in subdivision six of section\ntwo hundred one of this chapter. The president may adopt whatever other\nregulations which may be necessary to fulfill the intentions of this\nsection. No regulation shall be adopted, repealed or amended, and no\nother action taken with respect to such employees affecting the amount\nof, or eligibility for, benefits or rates of contribution under this\nsection without the approval of the director of employee relations.\n  The full costs of any insurance program or programs established\npursuant to this subdivision, excluding administrative costs, shall be\nborne by insureds and retirees. Any interest earned by the moneys in the\nlife insurance fund shall be added to such fund, become a part of such\nfund, be used for the purpose of such fund, and be available without\nfiscal year limitation.\n  2. The regulations of the president authorized by this section shall\nprovide that the entire cost of premiums or subscription charges for\ncoverage under the insurance plans established pursuant to such\nregulations shall be borne by the employees electing such coverage. Such\nregulations may provide for the allocation of any administrative\nexpenses, other than those of the insurer, among employers or employees\nor retired employees participating in such coverage.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>