<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-161-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-161-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="161-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-161-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-161-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-161-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-161-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_161_A">
        <num>161-A</num>
        <heading>Implementation of negotiated agreements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 161-a. Implementation of negotiated agreements. 1. Where, and to the\nextent that, an agreement between the state and an employee organization\nentered into pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter provides for\nhealth benefits, the president, after receipt of written directions from\nthe director of employee relations, shall implement the provisions of\nsuch agreement consistent with the terms thereof and to the extent\nnecessary shall adopt regulations providing for the benefits to be\nthereunder provided. The president, with the approval of the director of\nthe budget, may extend such benefits, in whole or in part, to employees\nnot subject to the provisions of such agreement.\n  2. Insofar as the provisions of this section are inconsistent with any\nother act, general or special, or any rule or regulation adopted\nthereunder, the provisions of this section shall be controlling and\ninsofar as the regulations promulgated by the president pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section are inconsistent with any rule or\nregulation, the provisions of such regulations shall be controlling.\n  3. There is hereby created a council on employee health insurance to\nsupervise the administration of changes to the health benefit plan\nnegotiated in collective negotiations and to provide continuing policy\ndirection to insurance plans administered by the state the provisions of\nany other law to the contrary notwithstanding. The council shall consist\nof the president, the director of the division of the budget, and the\ndirector of employee relations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>