<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-163-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-163-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="163-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-163-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-163-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-163-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-163-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_163_A">
        <num>163-A</num>
        <heading>Supplementary plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 163-a. Supplementary plan. 1. For the purposes of this section, the\nterm "supplementary plan" shall mean a health benefit plan which\nprovides an adjustment to the deductible or co-insurance liability or to\nthe benefits provided by the statewide health benefit plan purchased\npursuant to section one hundred sixty-two of this article.\n  2. The president may require the insurer of a supplementary plan to\nthe statewide health benefit plan, provided as a result of a\ncollectively negotiated agreement pursuant to article fourteen of this\nchapter, to make a comparable supplementary plan available to\nparticipating employers as of the implementation date of the state\nemployees' supplementary plan. The comparable supplementary plan shall\nbe experience rated as to those participating employers electing it,\nwith the costs thereof allocated equitably among them.\n  3. Every participating employer which, on or before July first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-five, entered into a collectively negotiated\nagreement pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter with employee\norganizations representing its employees to provide the statewide health\nbenefit plan shall provide such comparable supplementary plan on the\ndate established by the president until the expiration of such\nnegotiated agreement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>