<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-167"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-167"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="167"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-167/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-167/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-167/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-167/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_167">
        <num>167</num>
        <heading>Contributions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_167__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The full cost of premium or subscription\ncharges for the coverage of retired state employees who are enrolled in\nthe statewide and the supplementary health benefit plans established\npursuant to this article and who retired prior to January first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-three shall be paid by the state. Nine-tenths of\nthe cost of premium or subscription charges for the coverage of state\nemployees and retired state employees retiring on or after January\nfirst, nineteen hundred eighty-three who are enrolled in the statewide\nand supplementary health benefit plans shall be paid by the state.\nThree-quarters of the cost of premium or subscription charges for the\ncoverage of dependents of such state employees and retired state\nemployees shall be paid by the state.  Except as provided in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_167__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the state shall contribute toward the premium\nor subscription charges for the coverage of each state employee or\nretired state employee who is enrolled in an optional benefit plan and\nfor the dependents of such state employee or retired state employee the\nsame dollar amount which would be paid by the state for the premium or\nsubscription charges for the coverage of such state employee or retired\nstate employee and his or her dependents if he or she were enrolled in\nthe statewide and the supplementary health benefit plans, but not in\nexcess of the premium or subscription charges for the coverage of such\nstate employee or retired state employee and his or her dependents under\nsuch optional benefit plan. For purposes of this subdivision, employees\nof the state colleges of agriculture, home economics, industrial labor\nrelations, and veterinary medicine, the state agricultural experiment\nstation at Geneva, and any other institution or agency under the\nmanagement and control of Cornell university as the representative of\nthe board of trustees of the state university of New York, and employees\nof the state college of ceramics under the management and control of\nAlfred university as the representative of the board of trustees of the\nstate university of New York, shall be deemed to be state employees\nwhose salaries or compensation are paid directly by the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_167__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Effective January first, nineteen hundred eighty-nine,\nnotwithstanding any other law, rule or regulation, and where, and to the\nextent that, an agreement between the state and an employee organization\nentered into pursuant to article fourteen of this chapter so provides or\nwhere and to the extent the employee health insurance council so directs\nwith respect to any other state employees and for retired state\nemployees retiring on or after January first, nineteen hundred\neighty-three, the state shall contribute nine-tenths of the cost of\npremiums or subscription charges for coverage of each such state\nemployee or retired state employee who is enrolled in an optional\nbenefit plan and three-fourths of such premium or subscription charges\nfor dependents of such state employees or retired state employees\nenrolled in such optional benefit plan; provided, however, effective\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred ninety-six, the contribution rates for\nthe hospitalization and medical components of each optional benefit plan\nshall not exceed one hundred percent of the dollar amount of the state's\ncontribution toward the hospitalization and medical components of\nindividual and dependent coverage, respectively, in the Empire Plan. In\nthe case of state employees retiring prior to January first, nineteen\nhundred eighty-three, the state shall contribute one hundred percent of\nthe individual premium and three-fourths of such premium for dependents\nof such retired employees enrolled in such optional benefit plan;\nhowever, these contribution rates shall not exceed one hundred percent\nof the employer dollar amount contribution for individual and dependent\ncoverage respectively in the Empire Plan.\n  2. Each participating employer shall be required to pay not less than\nfifty percentum of the cost of premium or subscription charges for the\ncoverage of its employees and retired employees who are enrolled in the\nstatewide only or the statewide and comparable supplementa...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>