<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-168"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-168"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="168"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-168/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-168/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-168/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-168/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_168">
        <num>168</num>
        <heading>Assessment of certain costs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_168__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the salary or compensation of any justices, judges, officers\nand employees of the supreme court, surrogate's court, county court,\nfamily court, civil court of the city of New York, criminal court of the\ncity of New York and district court in any county, officers and\nemployees of the office of probation for the courts of New York city is\nnot paid in whole or in part from the treasury of the state, but is paid\ndirectly from the treasury of a civil division, such civil division\nshall be required to pay the employer's share of the premium charges for\nthe coverage of such justices, judges, officers and employees under the\nstate health benefit plan. The appropriate fiscal officer of such civil\ndivision shall deduct from the salary or wages paid to such justices,\njudges, officers and employees the sums required to be paid by them\nunder such plan. Such deductions and the corresponding employer's share\nof premium charges shall be paid, at such times as required by the\npresident, to the commissioner of taxation and finance and shall be\ncredited to the health insurance fund.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_168__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the salary or compensation of any retired justices, judges,\nofficers and employees of the supreme court, surrogate's court, county\ncourt, family court, civil court of the city of New York, criminal court\nof the city of New York and district court in any county, officers and\nemployees of the office of probation for the courts of New York city\nprior to retirement was not paid in whole or in part from the treasury\nof the state but was paid directly from the treasury of a civil\ndivision, such civil division shall be required to pay the employer's\nshare of the premium charges for the coverage of such retired justices,\njudges, officers and employees under the state health benefit plan. If\nsuch retired justices, judges, officers and employees are receiving\nretirement allowances from a pension or retirement plan or system\nadministered by such civil division, the amounts required to be paid by\nsuch retired justices, judges, officers and employees as their share of\npremium charges shall be deducted from their retirement allowances. Such\ndeductions and the employer's share of premium charges shall be paid, at\nsuch times as required by the president, to the commissioner of taxation\nand finance and shall be credited to the health insurance fund.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_168__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any civil division required by this subdivision to pay the\nemployer's share of the premium charges for the coverage of active or\nretired justices, judges, officers and employees of the supreme court,\nsurrogate's court, county court, family court, civil court of the city\nof New York, criminal court of the city of New York and district court\nin any county, officers and employees of the office of probation for the\ncourts of New York city shall also be assessed and required to pay a\nproportionate share of the expenses of administration of the health\nbenefit plan in such amounts and at such times as determined by the\npresident. Such sums shall be payable to the commissioner of taxation\nand finance and shall be applied to the reimbursement of funds\npreviously advanced for the expenses of administration of the health\nbenefit plan.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>