<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-17"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-17"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17">
        <num>17</num>
        <heading>Jurisdiction</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 17. Jurisdiction. 1. County civil service commission or personnel\nofficer. The civil service commission or personnel officer of a county\nshall administer the provisions of this chapter with respect to the\noffices and employments in the classified service of such county and the\ncivil divisions therein including school districts, except cities which\nare operating under one of the optional forms of civil service\nadministration provided in section fifteen of this chapter and the city\nschool districts of such cities.\n  2. City or suburban town civil service commission or personnel\nofficer.  Except as otherwise provided by special law enacted by the\nlegislature, the civil service commission or personnel officer of a city\nor suburban town described in subdivision four of section two of this\nchapter shall administer the provisions of this chapter with respect to\nthe offices and employments in the classified service of such suburban\ntown or city, including the city school districts of such city.\n  3. Regional civil service commission or regional personnel officer. A\nregional civil service commission or regional personnel officer shall\nadminister the provisions of this chapter with respect to the offices\nand employments which would otherwise be subject to the jurisdiction of\nthe civil service commissions or personnel officers of the respective\ncounties and cities under the jurisdiction of such regional civil\nservice commission or regional personnel officer.\n  4. Each municipal commission and personnel officer shall have power at\nits own expense to conduct examinations and establish eligible lists for\nany position within its jurisdiction.\n  5. Administration of certain director of facility positions.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of this section, chapter or any\nprovisions to the contrary contained in any general, special, or local\nlaws, the department shall develop a statewide exam for the positions of\ndirector of facilities I, II, &amp; III in school districts throughout the\nstate. Such administration shall include the development of eligibility\ncriteria for examination of potential candidates for the positions of\ndirector of facilities I, II, &amp; III based on qualifications and\nexperience in accordance with section fifty of this chapter. Such\nstatewide examinations shall not affect the ability of municipal civil\nservice commissions to determine promotion qualifications, announce\npromotion examinations and establish promotion eligible lists for these\npositions, consistent with statewide eligibility criteria as determined\nby the department. Any such promotion examination shall use the\nstatewide examination developed by the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>