<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-172"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-172"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="172"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-172/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-172/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-172/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-172/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_172">
        <num>172</num>
        <heading>Long term care insurance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 172. Long term care insurance. 1. The president is hereby authorized\nand directed to establish a long term care insurance plan for state\nofficers and employees and their dependents and officers and employees\nof the state colleges of agriculture, home economics, industrial labor\nrelations and veterinary medicine, the state agricultural station at\nGeneva, and any other institution or agency under the management and\ncontrol of Cornell University as the representative of the board of\ntrustees of the state university of New York, and the state college of\nceramics under the management and control of Alfred University as the\nrepresentative of the board of trustees of the state university of New\nYork and their dependents, and for the employees and retired employees\nof public authorities, public benefit corporations, school districts,\nspecial districts, district corporations, municipal corporations\nexcluding active employees and retired employees of cities having a\npopulation of one million or more inhabitants whose compensation is or\nwas before retirement paid out of the city treasury, or other\nappropriate agencies, subdivisions or quasi-public organizations of the\nstate and their dependents as defined by the regulations of the\npresident, which, subject to the conditions and limitations contained in\nthis article, and in the regulations of the president, will provide for\ninsurance against the financial costs of long term care.\n  2. Participation in the long term care insurance plan shall be at the\noption of the employee and shall be paid for solely by the employee in\naccordance with this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>