<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-204-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-204-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="204-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-204-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-204-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-204-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-204-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_204_A">
        <num>204-A</num>
        <heading>Agreements between public employers and employee organizations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 204-a. Agreements between public employers and employee\norganizations.  1. Any written agreement between a public employer and\nan employee organization determining the terms and conditions of\nemployment of public employees shall contain the following notice in\ntype not smaller than the largest type used elsewhere in such agreement:\n  "It is agreed by and between the parties that any provision of this\nagreement requiring legislative action to permit its implementation by\namendment of law or by providing the additional funds therefor, shall\nnot become effective until the appropriate legislative body has given\napproval."\n  2. Every employee organization submitting such a written agreement to\nits members for ratification shall publish such notice, include such\nnotice in the documents accompanying such submission and shall read it\naloud at any membership meeting called to consider such ratification.\n  3. Within sixty days after the effective date of this act, a copy of\nthis section shall be furnished by the chief fiscal officer of each\npublic employer to each public employee. Each public employee employed\nthereafter shall, upon such employment, be furnished with a copy of the\nprovisions of this section.\n  4. The terms of any current or expired agreement or interest\narbitration award between any public employer and any public employee\norganization representing firefighters relating to the discipline of any\nfirefighters shall be deemed valid and enforceable from the effective\ndate of this subdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>