<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-26"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-26"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="26"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-26/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-26/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-26/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-26/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_26">
        <num>26</num>
        <heading>Reports; inspections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 26. Reports; inspections. 1. Reports. Each municipal civil service\ncommission shall submit a report to the state civil service commission\nannually on or before the first day of March of the manner in which this\nchapter and the rules established thereunder have been and are\nadministered, and the results of such administration under the\njurisdiction of such municipal commission and shall from time to time\nsubmit to the state civil service commission such other reports as to\nsuch other matters as the commission may require. A copy of the roster\nof the classified civil service of such municipality shall be\ntransmitted to the state civil service commission whenever it shall\nrequest the same, and shall be filed in the office of the state civil\nservice commission as a public record.\n  2. Inspections. All examinations conducted by a municipal civil\nservice commission shall be publicly announced and all rules governing\nsuch examinations shall be made public. All the proceedings and papers\nconnected with such examinations or any of the functions or activities\nof such municipal commission shall be at all times subject to the\ninspection of the state civil service commission and its agents.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>