<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-52"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-52"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-09-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="52"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-52/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-52/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-52/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-52/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52">
        <num>52</num>
        <heading>Promotion examinations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purpose of this subdivision, the term\n"administrative positions" shall include competitive class positions in\nthe state service in law, personnel, budgeting, methods and procedures,\nmanagement, records analysis, and administrative research, as determined\nby the state civil service department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in section fifty-one, vacancies in\nadministrative positions shall be filled, so far as practicable, by\npromotion as prescribed in subdivision one of this section, which may be\nmade from among persons holding administrative positions in lower grades\nwithout regard to the specialties of their lower grade positions. The\ncivil service department, upon the request of an appointing officer\nstating the reasons why the filling of administrative positions in grade\nfourteen or higher under his jurisdiction from an interdepartmental\npromotion list or a promotion list including persons employed in other\nunits of government would be in the best interests of the state service,\nor upon its own initiative whenever it finds that the filling of\nadministrative positions in grade fourteen or higher in any department\nfrom such an interdepartmental or intergovernmental promotion list would\nbe in the best interests of the state service, may certify such an\ninterdepartmental or intergovernmental promotion list for filling such\npositions, without preference to departmental lists or to eligibles\nholding lower grade positions in the department or promotion unit in\nwhich such positions exist.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Transfers shall be allowed between administrative positions in the\nsame or related or collateral specialties which involve substantially\nequivalent tests or qualifications, subject to such conditions and\nlimitations as the state civil service department may prescribe.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this subdivision shall be applicable and\ncontrolling, notwithstanding any other provisions of this section or\nchapter or any other law.\n  7. Promotion by non-competitive examination. Whenever there are no\nmore than three persons eligible for examination for promotion to a\nvacant competitive class position, or whenever no more than three\npersons file application for examination for promotion to such position,\nthe appointing officer may nominate one of such persons and such\nnominee, upon passing an examination appropriate to the duties and\nresponsibilities of the position may be promoted, but no examination\nshall be required for such promotion where such nominee has already\nqualified in an examination appropriate to the duties and\nresponsibilities of the position.\n  8. Limitation upon promotion. No promotion shall be made from one\nposition or title to another position or title unless specifically\nauthorized by the state civil service department or municipal\ncommission, nor shall a person be promoted to a position or title for\nwhich there is required, by this chapter or the rules, an examination\ninvolving essential tests or qualifications different from or higher\nthan those required for the position or title held by such person unless\nhe has passed the examination and is eligible for appointment to such\nhigher position or title.\n  9. Increase in salary as a promotion. For the purposes of this section\nan increase in the salary or other compensation of any person holding an\noffice or position within the scope of the rules in force hereunder,\nbeyond the limit fixed for the grade in which such office or position is\nclassified, shall be deemed a promotion.\n  10. Credit for provisional service. a. No credit in a promotion\nexamination shall be granted to any person for any time served as a\nprovisional appointee in the position to which promotion is sought or in\nany similar position, provided, however, such provisional appointee ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsection eighty-five of this chapter and who provide documented evidence\nthat they meet the definition of disabled veteran prescribed by\nsubdivision one of such section.\n  14. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in a city containing\nmore than one county, the municipal civil service commission may, for\ntitles designated by it, extend to employees in the service of a civil\ndivision or public authority under its jurisdiction who are holding a\nposition in the non-competitive class or the labor class of such service\nthe same opportunities as employees in the competitive class to take\npromotional examinations for which such non-competitive class or labor\nclass service is determined by the municipal civil service commission to\nbe appropriate preparation.\n  15. Promotion eligibility of person transferred to the office of\ninformation technology services. Notwithstanding any other provision of\nthis chapter, the names of permanent employees transferred from a state\nagency or department to the office of information technology services\nshall remain on any promotion eligible list for appointment in the\nagency or department from which such employees were transferred, for a\nperiod of one year or until the expiration of such list, whichever\noccurs first. Further, where the promotion eligible list on which such\nemployees' names appear is established in the office of information\ntechnology services, the names of employees so transferred shall be\nadded to such promotion eligible list.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>