<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="59-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_59_C">
        <num>59-C</num>
        <heading>State employment of persons and veterans with disabilities study</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_59_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of persons with a letter of eligibility under sections\nfifty-five-b and fifty-five-c of this title that have received a civil\nservice appointment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_59_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of persons at the time of the report who have received\na letter of eligibility from the department certifying they are eligible\nto be appointed in accordance with sections fifty-five-b and\nfifty-five-c of this title;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_59_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of persons with a physical or mental disability\nappointed in accordance with sections fifty-five-b and fifty-five-c of\nthis title that have taken a promotional examination including the\nnumber of such persons that have taken a promotional examination within\nthe last five years;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_59_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a determination as to whether the state is underutilizing the\nprovisions of such sections based on such findings from the report;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_59_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an assessment of whether the state offers any additional programs\nrun by the state with the mission to increase the employment of people\nwith disabilities, including, but not limited to: Adult Career and\nContinuing Ed Services (ACCES-VR) within the education department and\nthe office for people with developmental disabilities' supported\nemployment services programs; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_59_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>recommendations based on the findings from the report as to\nwhether the state can take additional action to market or inform the\npublic of state job opportunities for persons and veterans with\ndisabilities and if so, what specific actions should be taken.\n  3. For the purposes of this section, the president may conduct such\nstudy in conjunction with any other department, division, board, bureau,\ncommission, agency, or public authority of the state deemed necessary.\nTo the maximum extent feasible, the president shall be authorized to\nrequest, receive, and utilize such resources and data of any other\ndepartment, division, board, bureau, commission, agency, or public\nauthority of the state as he or she may reasonably request to properly\ncarry his or her powers and duties pursuant to this section.\n  4. The president shall promulgate rules and regulations as may be\nnecessary to effectuate the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>