<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="59"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-59/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_59">
        <num>59</num>
        <heading>Placement of county sheriffs' personnel in classified service</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_59__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section thirteen of article thirteen of\nthe New York state constitution brings appointees of a county sheriff\ninto the classified service of the civil service; that to require\ncompetitive examination for valid appointment of appointees of the\ncounty sheriff within the classified service would irreparably\ndisorganize county sheriffs' departments and endanger the public safety,\ninterrupt the continuance and performance of the important services\nperformed by such sheriff's departments, and place an undue financial\nburden on their respective counties.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter or any provisions to\nthe contrary contained in any general, special, or local laws, all\nlawful appointees of a county sheriff employed as of the effective date\nof this section whose employments hereinbefore were considered not to be\nsubject to the civil service law, shall continue to hold their positions\nwithout further examination or qualification and shall have all the\nrights and privileges of the jurisdictional classification to which such\npositions may be allocated in the classified service of the county in\nwhich they are employed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>