<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-75-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-75-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-75-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-75-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-75-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-75-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75_A">
        <num>75-A</num>
        <heading>Civil service proceeding; commencement upon alleged violation of certain provisions of the labor law relating to police officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 75-a. Civil service proceeding; commencement upon alleged violation\nof certain provisions of the labor law relating to police officers. 1.\nAny police officer alleging a violation of section two hundred fifteen-a\nof the labor law may institute a proceeding pursuant to the provisions\nof his collective bargaining agreement. If no such agreement exists a\ncomplaint may be filed by a police officer with the state or a municipal\ncivil service commission alleging a violation of section two hundred\nfifteen-a of the labor law; as a condition of entertaining such\ncomplaint the commission may require a police officer to exhaust all\nremedies available to such employee pursuant to the provisions of a\ncollective bargaining agreement and the rules and regulations of the\nemployer.  Upon the filing of such complaint or upon its own initiative\nthe commission having jurisdiction may investigate and upon finding an\nimproper transfer or other penalty in violation of such section, enforce\nthe provisions of such section. The commission may exercise any powers\nheretofore granted to it by provision of this chapter or by any other\nprovision of law necessary for the enforcement of the provisions of\nsection two hundred fifteen-a of the labor law.\n  2. Nothing in this section shall be construed to abrogate, impair,\nalter, or in any way modify any right of action in law that an employee,\nalleged to have been penalized, may have.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>