<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-77"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-77"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="77"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-77/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-77/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-77/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-77/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_77">
        <num>77</num>
        <heading>Compensation of officers and employees reinstated by court order</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 77. Compensation of officers and employees reinstated by court\norder.  Any officer or employee who is removed from a position in the\nservice of the state or of any civil division thereof in violation of\nthe provisions of this chapter, and who thereafter is restored to such\nposition by order of the supreme court, shall be entitled to receive and\nshall receive from the state or such civil division, as the case may be,\nthe salary or compensation which he would have been entitled by law to\nhave received in such position but for such unlawful removal, from the\ndate of such unlawful removal to the date of such restoration, less the\namount of any unemployment insurance benefits he may have received\nduring such period. Such officer or employee shall be entitled to a\ncourt order to enforce the payment of such salary or compensation. Such\nsalary or compensation shall be subject to the provisions of sections\nfour hundred seventy-four and four hundred seventy-five of the judiciary\nlaw for services rendered, but otherwise shall be paid only directly to\nsuch officer or employee or his legal representatives.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>