<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-80"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-80"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="80"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-80/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-80/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-80/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-80/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_80">
        <num>80</num>
        <heading>Suspension or demotion upon the abolition or reduction of positions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>members of the police department employed as auxiliary policewomen,\npolice officers, police dispatchers or communications technicians,\npolice lieutenants, chief communications officer, or police captains;\n(ii) members of the fire department employed as firefighters, fire alarm\noperators, fire captains, battalion fire chiefs or master mechanic-chief\nof apparatus; and (iii) all other employees of the city of Niagara\nFalls, in the competitive class.\n  5. Units for suspension or demotion in the state service. The\npresident may, by regulation, designate as separate units for suspension\nor demotion under the provisions of this section any state hospital,\ninstitution or facility or any division of any state department or\nagency or specified hospitals, institutions and facilities of a single\nstate department or agency within a particular geographic area as\ndetermined by the president. Upon the abolition or reduction of\npositions in the same jurisdictional class in the state service,\nsuspension or demotion, as the case may be, shall be made from among\nemployees holding the same or similar positions in the department\nwherein such abolition or reduction occurs, except that where such\nabolition or reduction occurs in a separate unit for suspension or\ndemotion designated by regulation of the president, suspension or\ndemotion shall be made from among incumbents holding the same or similar\npositions in such separate unit.\n  6. Displacement in civil divisions. A permanent incumbent of a\nposition in a civil division in a specific title to which there is a\ndirect line of promotion who is suspended or displaced pursuant to this\nsection, together with all other such incumbents suspended or displaced\nat the same time, shall displace, in the inverse order of the order of\nsuspension or demotion prescribed in subdivisions one and two of this\nsection, incumbents serving in positions in the same layoff unit in the\nnext lower occupied title in direct line of promo...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the service of the displacing incumbent while in such\nformer title was satisfactory and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the position of the junior\nincumbent is in</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the competitive, noncompetitive or labor class,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe layoff unit from which the displacing incumbent was suspended or\ndisplaced, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a lower salary grade than the position from which the\ndisplacing incumbent is suspended or displaced; provided, however, that\nno incumbent shall displace any other incumbent having greater retention\nstanding in the same jurisdictional class. Refusal of appointment to a\nposition afforded by this subdivision constitutes waiver of rights under\nthis subdivision with respect to the suspension or displacement on\naccount of which the refused appointment is afforded. The municipal\ncivil service commission shall promulgate rules to implement this\nsubdivision including rules which may provide adjunctive opportunities\nfor displacement either to positions in direct line of promotion or to\nformerly held positions; provided, however, that no such rule shall\npermit an incumbent to displace any other incumbent having greater\nretention standing in the same jurisdictional class. For the purpose of\nacquiring preferred list rights, displacement pursuant to this\nsubdivision is the equivalent of suspension or demotion pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section.\n  7. Displacement in the state service. A permanent incumbent of a\nposition in the state service in a specific title to which there is a\ndirect line of promotion who is suspended or displaced pursuant to this\nsection, together with all other such incumbents suspended or displaced\nat the same time, shall displace, in the inverse order of the order of\nsuspension or demotion prescribed in subdivisions one and two of this\nsection, incumbents serving in positions in the same layoff unit in the\nnext lower occupied title in direct line of promotion who shall be\ndisplaced in the order of suspension or demotion prescribed in\nsubdivisions one and two of this section; provided, however, that no\nincumbent shall displace any other incumbent having greater retention\nstanding in the same jurisdictional class. If a permanent incumbent of a\nposition in the state service is suspended or displaced from a position\nin a t...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the service of the displacing incumbent while in such\nformer title was satisfactory and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the position of the junior\nincumbent is in</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the competitive, noncompetitive or labor class,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe layoff unit from which the displacing incumbent was suspended or\ndisplaced, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a lower salary grade than the position from which the\ndisplacing incumbent is suspended or displaced; provided, however, that\nno incumbent shall displace any other incumbent having greater retention\nstanding in the same jurisdictional class. Refusal of appointment to a\nposition afforded by this subdivision constitutes waiver of rights under\nthis subdivision with respect to the suspension or displacement on\naccount of which the refused appointment is afforded. The state civil\nservice commission shall promulgate rules to implement this subdivision\nincluding rules which may provide adjunctive opportunities for\ndisplacement either to positions in direct line of promotion or to\nformerly held positions; provided, however, that no such rule shall\npermit an incumbent to displace any other incumbent having greater\nretention standing in the same jurisdictional class. For the purpose of\nacquiring preferred list rights, displacement pursuant to this\nsubdivision is the equivalent of suspension or demotion pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section.\n  7-a. Certain suspensions in cities of one million or more for reasons\nof economy.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general or\nlocal law, administrative code or ordinance to the contrary, in cities\nhaving a population of one million or more, any of the uniformed force\nof the department of sanitation of such city who was suspended on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred ninety, because of economy measures\ntaken by such city and who returns to such service, shall be deemed to\nhave been in continuous service in determining length of service for\nretirement purposes if the duration of such suspension did not exceed\nthirty-three months; provided, however, that for retirement purposes, a\nmember receiving such service credit shall pay, by deductions from his\nor her compensation for each and every payroll period, subject to the\nmember contributions prescribed by subparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pursuant to such method of payment, such member shall pay, as\nadditional member contributions payable besides the ordinary member\ncontributions due for their current service:\n  (A) the ordinary member contributions which would have been done for\nsuch period of suspension if they had actually been in service during\nsuch period; and\n  (B) (if such member has elected the twenty-year retirement program\nprovided for by section six hundred four-a of the retirement and social\nsecurity law), the additional member contributions which they would have\nbeen required to make under the provisions of that section for the\nperiod from the starting date of such program to the date next preceding\nthe date on which such member became a participant in such retirement\nprogram, if they had become such a participant on such starting date;\nand\n  (C) additional member contributions of two per centum of their\ncompensation for the period beginning with the first full payroll period\nwhich includes ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The deduction for the additional contribution referred to in items\n(A) and (B) of subparagraph one of this paragraph shall be made in\naccordance with such equitable method and over such equitable period of\ntime as shall be prescribed by the executive director of the affected\nretirement system with the approval of its board of trustees.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional member contributions referred to in item (A) of\nsubparagraph one of this paragraph shall be paid into the retirement\nsystem's member contributions accumulation fund which is required to\nreceive the ordinary member contributions of such member. The additional\nmember contributions referred to in item (B) of such subparagraph shall\nbe paid into the contingent reserve fund of such retirement system and\nshall be subject to the provisions of such section six hundred four-a of\nthe retirement and social security law governing additional member\ncontributions. The additional member contributions referred to in item\n(C) of such subparagraph shall be paid into the contingent reserve fund\nof such retirement system and shall not be subject to any retirement\nsystem right or privilege of such member, unless such right or privilege\nis granted by other provisions of law which specifically refer to\nadditional member contributions made pursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At any time prior to completion of the deduction for the\nadditional contributions referred to in items (A) and (B) of\nsubparagraph one of this paragraph, payment of the remainder of the\ntotal of such additional contribution due may be made in a lump sum,\nprovided further that such member shall pay into the contingent reserve\nfund of the retirement system two percent of his or her earnings in each\nyear until the earlier of his or her date of retirement or his or her\ncompletion of thirty years of service. In addition, if such member\nelected to be covered by the provisions of section six hundred four-a of\nthe retirement and social security law, he or she shall also pay into\nsuch contingent reserve fund the contributions that would have been\nrequired had he or she made such election as of the starting of the\ntwenty-year retirement program.\n  7-b. Certain suspensions in cities of one million or more for reasons\nof economy.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general or\nlocal law, administrative code or ordinance to the contrary, in cities\nhaving a population of one million or more, any member of the uniformed\nforce of the department of correction of such city who was suspended on\nor after May first, two thousand three, because of economy measures\ntaken by such city and who returns to such service prior to July first,\ntwo thousand four, shall be deemed to have been in continuous service in\ndetermining length of service for retirement purposes if the duration of\nsuch suspension did not exceed thirteen months; provided, however, that\nfor retirement purposes, a member receiving such service credit shall\npay, by deductions from his or her compensation, subject to the method\nprescribed by subparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pursuant to such method of payment, such member shall pay, as\nadditional member contributions payable besides the ordinary member\ncontributions due for his or her current service:\n  (A) the ordinary member contributions which would have been paid for\nsuch period of suspension if he or she had actually been in service\nduring such period; and\n  (B) if such member is covered by the twenty-year retirement program\nprovided for by section five hundred four-a of the retirement and social\nsecurity law, the additional member contributions which he or she would\nhave been required to make under the provisions of that section for such\nperiod of suspension if he or she had actually been in service during\nsuch period.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The deduction for the additional contributions referred to in\nclauses (A) and (B) of subparagraph one of this paragraph shall be paid\nin accordance with such equitable method and over such equitable period\nof time as shall be prescribed by the executive director of the affected\nretirement system with the approval of its board of trustees.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional member contributions referred to in clause (A) of\nsubparagraph one of this paragraph shall be paid into the retirement\nsystem's member contributions accumulation fund which is required to\nreceive the ordinary member contributions of such member. The additional\nmember contributions referred to in clause (B) of such subparagraph\nshall be paid into the contingent reserve fund of such retirement system\nand shall be subject to the provisions of such section five hundred\nfour-a of the retirement and social security law governing additional\nmember contributions.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At any time prior to completion of the deduction for the\nadditional contributions referred to in clauses (A) and (B) of\nsubparagraph one of this paragraph, payment of the remainder of the\ntotal of such additional contributions due may be made in a lump sum. In\naddition, if such member is covered by the provisions of section five\nhundred four-a of the retirement and social security law, he or she\nshall also pay into the contingent reserve fund of the retirement system\nthe contributions required to be made pursuant to such section.\n  7-c. Certain suspensions in cities of one million or more for reasons\nof economy.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general or\nlocal law, administrative code or ordinance to the contrary, in cities\nhaving a population of one million or more, any employee in the title of\ncarpenter or supervisory carpenter of such city who was suspended on or\nafter June first, nineteen hundred ninety-one because of economy\nmeasures taken by such city and who returns to such service prior to\nJuly first, nineteen hundred ninety-three, shall be deemed to have been\nin continuous service in determining length of service for retirement\npurposes if the duration of such suspension did not exceed twenty-five\nmonths; provided, however, that for retirement purposes, a member\nreceiving such service credit shall pay, by deductions from his or her\ncompensation, subject to the method prescribed by subparagraph two of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pursuant to such method of payment, such member shall pay the\nordinary member contributions due for his or her current service which\nwould have been paid for such period of suspension if he or she had\nactually been in service during such period.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The deduction for the additional contributions referred to in\nsubparagraph one of this paragraph shall be paid in accordance with such\nequitable method and over such equitable period of time as shall be\nprescribed by the executive director of the affected retirement system\nwith the approval of its board of trustees.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional member contributions referred to in subparagraph\none of this paragraph shall be paid into the retirement system's member\ncontributions accumulation fund which is required to receive the\nordinary member contributions of such member.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At any time prior to completion of the deduction for the\nadditional contributions referred to in subparagraph one of this\nparagraph, payment of the remainder of the total of such additional\ncontributions due may be made in a lump sum.\n  7-d. Certain suspensions in cities of one million or more for reasons\nof economy.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general or\nlocal law, administrative code or ordinance to the contrary, in cities\nhaving a population of one million or more, any employee of the\ndepartment of parks of such city who had been employed as a climber and\npruner who was suspended on or after July first, nineteen hundred\nninety-one, because of economy measures taken by such city and who\nreturned to such service prior to July first, nineteen hundred\nninety-five, shall be deemed to have been in continuous service in\ndetermining length of service for retirement purposes if the duration of\nsuch suspension did not exceed twenty-five months; provided, however,\nthat for retirement purposes, a member receiving such service credit\nshall pay, by deductions from his or her compensation for each and every\npayroll period, subject to the member contributions prescribed by\nsubparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pursuant to such method of payment, such member shall pay, as\nadditional member contributions payable besides the ordinary member\ncontributions due for his or her current service:\n  (A) the ordinary member contributions which would have been paid for\nsuch period of suspension if he or she had actually been in service\nduring such period; and\n  (B) if such member is covered by the optional twenty-five year early\nretirement program for certain New York city members provided by section\nsix hundred four-c of the retirement and social security law, as added\nby chapter ninety-six of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-five, the\nadditional member contributions which he or she would have been required\nto make under the provisions of that section for such period of\nsuspension if he or she had actually been in service during such period.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The deduction for the additional contribution referred to in items\n(A) and (B) of subparagraph one of this paragraph shall be paid in\naccordance with such equitable method and over such equitable period of\ntime as shall be prescribed by the executive director of the affected\nretirement system with the approval of its board of trustees.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional member contributions referred to in item (A) of\nsubparagraph one of this paragraph shall be paid into the retirement\nsystem's member contributions accumulation fund which is required to\nreceive the ordinary member contributions of such member. The additional\nmember contributions referred to in item (B) of such subparagraph shall\nbe paid into the contingent reserve fund of such retirement system and\nshall be subject to the provisions of section six hundred four-c of the\nretirement and social security law, as added by chapter ninety-six of\nthe laws of nineteen hundred ninety-five, governing additional member\ncontributions.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_80__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At any time prior to completion of the deduction for the\nadditional contributions referred to in items (A) and (B) of\nsubparagraph one of this paragraph, payment of the remainder of the\ntotal of such additional contribution due may be made in a lump sum. In\naddition, if such member is covered by the provisions of section six\nhundred four-c of the retirement and social security law, as added by\nchapter ninety-six of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-five, he or\nshe shall also pay into such contingent reserve fund the contributions\nrequired to be made pursuant to this section.\n  8. Certain suspensions in cities of one million or more for reasons of\neconomy. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general or local\nlaw, administrative code or ordinance, in cities having a population of\none million or more, any member employed in the uniformed or\nnon-uniformed services of such city who was suspended on or after July\nfirst, nineteen hundred seventy-five, because of econom...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The use of artificial intelligence systems as defined by\nsection one hundred three-e of the state technology law and automated\ndecision-making tools as defined by section five hundred one of the\nstate technology law shall not affect</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the existing rights of\nemployees pursuant to an existing collective bargaining agreement, or\n(ii) the existing representational relationships among employee\norganizations or the bargaining relationships between the employer and\nan employee organization.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The use of such artificial intelligence systems and automated\ndecision-making tools shall not result in the:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>discharge,\ndisplacement or loss of position, including partial displacement such as\na reduction in the hours of non-overtime work, wages, or employment\nbenefits, or result in the impairment of existing collective bargaining\nagreements; or\n  (ii) transfer of existing duties and functions currently performed by\nemployees of the state or any agency or public authority thereof to an\nartificial intelligence system or automated decision-making tool.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The use of such artificial intelligence system and automated\ndecision-making tool shall not alter the rights or benefits, and\nprivileges, including but not limited to terms and conditions of\nemployment, civil service status, and collective bargaining unit\nmembership status of all existing employees of the state or any agency\nor public authority thereof shall be preserved and protected.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2028\n  * NB There are 2 sb 10's\n  * 10. Effect of collective bargaining agreements. Nothing contained in\nthis section shall modify, replace or supersede any provision of a\ncollective bargaining agreement that provides for greater rights than\nrequired by this section.\n  * NB There are 2 sb 10's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>