<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-81"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-81"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="81"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_81">
        <num>81</num>
        <heading>Preferred lists; certification and reinstatement therefrom</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the occurrence of a vacancy in an appropriate position in the\nservice of a civil division, except in a city having a population of one\nmillion or more, the names of persons on the preferred list shall be\ncertified to fill such vacancy in the following order:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_81__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>persons\nsuspended from or demoted in the department or agency within which such\nvacancy occurs; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_81__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>persons suspended from or demoted in other\ndepartments and agencies in such civil division.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the occurrence of a vacancy in an appropriate position in the\nstate service, or in the service of a city having a population of one\nmillion or more, the names of persons on the preferred list shall be\ncertified to fill such vacancy in the following order:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_81__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>persons\nsuspended from or demoted in the department in which such vacancy\nexists, except that where such vacancy exists in a separate suspension\nand demotion unit, the names of persons suspended from or demoted in\nsuch unit, and not those suspended from or demoted in the entire\ndepartment, shall be certified first; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_81__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>all other persons on such\npreferred list.\n  3. Eligibility and order of certification for reinstatement of persons\nsuspended from or demoted in the service of a county in a city wholly\nincluding within its limits two or more counties. Any person suspended\nor demoted from a position in the service of a county in a city wholly\nincluding within its limits two or more counties, where the compensation\nof such position is paid directly from the treasury of such city, shall\nbe eligible for certification and reinstatement from the preferred list\nto the same or similar position, or a similar position in a lower grade\nin the same occupational field, in the service of any county within such\ncity.  Upon the occurrence of a vacancy in an appropriate position in\nthe service of any such county, the names of persons on the preferred\nlist shall be certified to fill such vacancy in the following order:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons suspended from or demoted in the particular county office in\nwhich such vacancy occurs;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons suspended from or demoted in\nother county offices in the same county in which such vacancy occurs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_81__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons suspended from or demoted in county offices in other\ncounties within such city.\n  4. Certification of probationers from preferred list.  Notwithstanding\nthe provisions of subdivisions two and three of this section, no person\nsuspended or demoted prior to the completion of his probationary term\nshall be certified for reinstatement until the exhaustion of the\npreferred list of all other eligibles thereon.  Upon reinstatement, such\nprobationer shall be required to complete his probationary term.\n  5. Effect of failure or refusal to accept reinstatement. The state and\nmunicipal civil service commissions shall adopt rules providing for the\nrelinquishment of eligibility for reinstatement upon failure or refusal\nto accept reinstatement from a preferred list.\n  6. Salary upon reinstatement. A person reinstated from a preferred\nlist to his former position or a similar position in the same grade\nshall receive at least the same salary such person was receiving at the\ntime of suspension or demotion.\n  7. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the civil\nservice department or appropriate municipal commission may disqualify\nfor reinstatement and remove from a preferred list the name of any\neligible who is physically or mentally disabled for the performance of\nthe duties of the position for which such list is established, or who\nhas been guilty of such misconduct as would warrant his dismissal from\nthe public service, except that a partially physically handicapped\nperson, who is suspended pursuant to section eighty of this chapter\nbecause of lack of work, but who, within six months of the date of his\nsuspension, is certified for reinstatement to any job item having the\nsame physical requirements as the job item from which the person was\nsuspended shall not be disqualified because of his physical handicap\nunless a medical examination discloses that because his handicap has\nbecome greater he would not be able to satisfactorily perfo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>