<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-82-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-82-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-10-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="82-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-82-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-82-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-82-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-82-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_82_C">
        <num>82-C</num>
        <heading>Civil air patrol volunteers; paid leave</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 82-c. Civil air patrol volunteers; paid leave. Notwithstanding any\nother provisions of law to the contrary, public officers and employees\nof the state who are members of the United States Air Force Auxiliary\nCivil Air Patrol or the United States Coast Guard Auxiliary Pilots shall\nbe granted leave from work with pay to participate in emergency services\nduring a declared state of emergency upon a written request from a unit\ncommander and the approval of the chief administrative officer of the\nstate agency, department or bureau for which the public officer or\nemployee serves. The public officer or employee shall be compensated at\nhis or her regular rate of pay for those regular work hours during which\nthe public officer or employee is absent from work while participating\nin emergency services missions during a declared state of emergency.\nSuch leave shall be provided without loss of seniority, compensation,\nsick leave, vacation leave or other overtime compensation to which the\nvolunteer is otherwise entitled and shall not exceed twenty days in any\ncalendar year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>