<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-83-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-83-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="83-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-83-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-83-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-83-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvs/section-83-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_83_F">
        <num>83-F</num>
        <heading>Procedures</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 83-f. Procedures. a. In making recommendations for the appropriate\nrank to which present police officers will be assigned to the\nconsolidated department, consideration will be given to the examination\nfrom which the present incumbents received their permanent civil service\nstatus, the length of time served in their present position and other\nrelated factors which will be established and promulgated by the board.\n  b. Where there may not be sufficient vacancies in the organization of\nthe consolidated police department for all persons to be assigned to\ntheir rank as determined by the board, the board will determine the\npersons to be selected for existing vacancies in accordance with\ncriteria established by the board.  Those persons not selected to the\nrank to which their previous position has been declared equivalent will\nbe placed on a preferred list for that specific rank.  Such persons will\nhave priority in appointment for the next lower rank position in the\norganization.  Such appointment will not affect their status on the\npreferred list in the higher rank when subsequent vacancies develop.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>