<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="100"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_100">
        <num>100</num>
        <heading>Construction of chapter</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 100. Construction of chapter.  a. This chapter shall not be\nconstrued to repeal or in any manner affect article six of the railroad\nlaw, except so far as such article would, if this chapter had not been\npassed, authorize the appointment hereafter of any commissioners applied\nfor as provided in section two hundred twenty of such law in any city or\nauthorize any commissioners already appointed pursuant to such section\nin any such city to fix, determine or locate any new route pursuant to\nthe provisions of such article of the railroad law.\n  b. This chapter shall not repeal or in any manner affect the railroad\nlaw, except as expressly provided, or except so far as the provisions\nthereof conflict with the provisions of this chapter. But nothing in\nthis section shall prevent the board of transportation from laying out a\nroute for a railroad and constructing and operating a railroad, and such\nboard shall have the right to lay out such route and construct and\noperate such railroad over, under, along or across any street in, along,\nunder or over which there shall be any existing railroad, provided that\nthe routes so laid out by the board and the railroad so constructed by\nit shall so pass over or under or at the side of such existing railroad\nas not to interfere with its operation.\n  c. This chapter shall not be construed in any manner to affect the\nexercise or enjoyment at any time of any right acquired, exercised or\nenjoyed before the thirty-first day of January, eighteen hundred\nninety-one by any corporation duly incorporated and organized before\nsuch date or deriving powers and rights under the laws of this state.\n  d. This chapter shall not affect or impair the exercise or enjoyment\nof any right or rights possessed before the thirty-first day of January,\neighteen hundred ninety-one or acquired or authorized to be acquired,\nexercise or enjoyed by any street surface railroad corporation before\nsuch date, except as herein otherwise expressly provided.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>