<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-14"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-14"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14">
        <num>14</num>
        <heading>Offices, assistants and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14. Offices, assistants and employees.  a. The board of\ntransportation may rent such offices for a period not to exceed\ntwenty-one years and employ such deputy commissioners, engineers,\nattorneys and other persons, from time to time, as, in its discretion,\nit may deem necessary to the proper performance by it of its duties as\nprescribed in this chapter.\n  b. The board of transportation is empowered to organize an operating\ndivision for the operation and maintenance of a publicly owned and\noperated railroad, separate and distinct from the organization engaged\nin planning and supervising the construction and equipment of railroads\nprior to operation, and is hereby authorized to establish and specify\nthe duties and the regulations which shall govern the work and conduct\nof employees in such division and the penalties which may be imposed for\ndisobedience of or violation of such regulations. Appointments and\npromotion to any position in any class of employment in such division\nshall be subject to the provisions of the civil service law.  Employees\nholding positions in such operating division shall be notified in\nwriting of any charge or accusation of dereliction of duty which is to\nbe considered by the board of transportation, and shall be allowed at\nleast five days for answering such charge in writing and be entitled to\na hearing thereon, at which he shall be entitled to be represented by a\nperson of his own choosing. If in the judgment of the board such charges\nof delinquency or misconduct are sustained, such employee may be\nsuspended without pay for a period not to exceed thirty days, or may be\ndismissed from such employment as provided in section twenty-two of the\ncivil service law. The board may temporarily suspend without pay any\nsuch employee charged with dereliction of duty pending hearing on any\nsuch charges, but if the board shall determine that such charges are not\nsustained by the evidence adduced at the hearing thereon, the employee\nso suspended shall be entitled to pay for the time of such temporary\nsuspension.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>