<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-16-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-16-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-16-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-16-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-16-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-16-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_A">
        <num>16-A</num>
        <heading>Sick leave</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 16-a. Sick leave.  1. Subject to the limitations hereinafter set\nforth, the New York city transit authority, successor to the board of\ntransportation of the city of New York under title fifteen of article\nseven of the public authorities law and hereinafter referred to as the\nauthority, shall grant to every employee under its supervision, other\nthan a member of the uniformed force of the New York city transit\npolice, who shall have been in its employ for at least one year, sick\nleave with pay on each working day when he is unfit for work on account\nof illness, up to a total, in any one year, of twelve days plus the\nnumber of days, not exceeding eighty-four, by which the total amount of\nsick leave with pay allowed to such employee by the board of\ntransportation and the authority in prior years since the thirtieth day\nof April, nineteen hundred forty-one, shall have been less than one day\nper month of employment during such prior years, but in no event shall\nthe authority be required to allow any employee sick leave with pay for\nmore than a total of ninety-six working days in any one year. To every\nemployee in its employ less than one year, the authority, subject to the\nlimitations herein set forth, shall grant sick leave with pay on each\nworking day when such employee is unfit for work on account of illness,\nup to a total of one day for each calendar month during which, or the\nmajor part of which, the employee shall have been in such employ. The\nterm "year", as used in this section, shall mean a period of twelve\nmonths beginning on the first day of May and ending on the following\nthirtieth day of April. For the purpose of this section an employee\nshall not be deemed to have been in the employ of the board of\ntransportation or the authority during a period of leave of absence\nwithout pay excepting where such leave of absence is for ordered\nmilitary duty. For any day on which sick leave with pay is required by\nthis section to be granted to an employee, the pay to be allowed him\nshall be the same as if he had worked in accordance with his regular\nwork schedule on that particular day. Sick leave with pay shall not run\nconcurrently with any vacation.\n  Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section, the\nauthority shall not be required to pay an employee for the first working\nday in any period of leave of absence for illness unless such leave of\nabsence shall reach a total of nine or more consecutive working days, in\nwhich event the employee shall receive pay for the total leave up to the\nallowable limit.\n  2. The authority may grant to a member of the uniformed force of the\nNew York city transit police, who shall have been in its employ for at\nleast six months, sick leave with pay at the rate of one-half of his\nrate of pay for the first three working days of illness and full pay on\nand after the fourth consecutive working day on which he is unfit for\nwork on account of illness, until such illness shall have continued for\none year. If such member of the uniformed force of the New York city\ntransit police shall become temporarily disabled for performance of duty\nas a natural and proximate result of service as such member, he may be\ngranted sick leave with full pay from the date of such disability until\nhe recovers therefrom and is restored to duty. In the event the\nauthority determines not to grant to members of the uniformed force of\nthe New York city transit police the sick leave benefits contemplated in\nthis subdivision, or having granted such sick leave benefits\ndiscontinues such benefits, then such members shall be considered\nemployees of the transit authority subject to the provisions of\nsubdivision one of this section, notwithstanding the exception as to\nsuch members set forth in subdivision one hereof.\n  3. The authority may adopt rules and regulations within the specific\nlimitations of this act to implement this section. No waiting period in\nexcess of one working day shall be required of any employee before he\nshall be granted a leave of absence once he shall have become unfit for\nwork on account of illness.  The authority may require that an employee\nsubmit satisfactory medical evidence of illness and further the\nauthority may require that an employee submit to physical examination by\na physician employed by the authority, provided such physical\nexamination is without charge or loss of compensation to said employee,\nas a condition of the granting of sick leave with pay. The authority may\ngrant sick leave with pay to any employee for a period of time beyond\nthat required by this section if, after a physical examination by a\nphysician employed by the authority, and in the opinion and judgment of\nsuch authority, the duties, position or length of service of the\nemployee, or other circumstances surrounding his employment, warrant\nsuch additional sick leave with pay.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>