<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-17"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-17"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-17/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-17/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17">
        <num>17</num>
        <heading>Advertising for proposals</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 17. Advertising for proposals.  The board of transportation before\nawarding any contract except where there is an extraordinary emergency\ninvolving danger to life or property or where the estimated expense of a\ncontract does not exceed twenty-five thousand dollars shall advertise\nfor proposals for such contract by a notice to be printed once a week\nfor two successive weeks in no less than two of the daily newspapers\npublished in such city, and in such newspapers published elsewhere than\nin such city as such board shall determine. Such notice shall set forth\nand state the points within the city, between which such road is to run,\nthe general method of construction, the route to be followed, the term\nof years for which it is proposed to make such contract, and such other\ndetails and specifications as the board shall deem to be proper. Such\nnotice shall state the time and place at which such proposals will be\nopened. The board shall attend at the time and place so specified, and\nshall publicly open all proposals that shall have been received, but the\nboard shall not be bound to accept any proposals so received, but may\nreject all such proposals and readvertise for proposals in the manner\nprovided in this chapter, or may accept any of such proposals as, in the\njudgment of such board, will best promote the public interest, and award\na contract accordingly. All such contracts must before execution be\napproved as to form by the corporation counsel and consented to by the\nboard of estimate and the mayor of such city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>