<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_A">
        <num>21-A</num>
        <heading>Construction and equipment of a rapid transit railroad tunnel or tunnels</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 21-a. Construction and equipment of a rapid transit railroad tunnel\nor tunnels.  a. The city of New York and the New York city transit\nauthority, acting under and pursuant to the provisions of this chapter\nand of title nine of article five of the public authorities law, are\nhereby authorized to effect the construction and equipment of a rapid\ntransit railroad tunnel or tunnels between the boroughs of Manhattan and\nQueens in the city of New York, along the following route:\n  A route lying wholly within the boroughs of Manhattan and Queens which\nshall begin at a point on East Sixty-third street at the westerly line\nof York avenue in the borough of Manhattan where a connection can\nconveniently be made to other future rapid transit railroads; thence\nextending easterly along East Sixty-third street under York avenue and\nFranklin D. Roosevelt drive; thence continuing easterly under the West\nchannel of the East river, Welfare island and the East channel of the\nEast river to the borough of Queens; thence continuing easterly under\nQueens bridge park and Vernon boulevard to a point on Forty-first avenue\nat the easterly line of Vernon boulevard where a connection can\nconveniently be made with other future rapid transit railroads.\n  b. For the purposes of this chapter, such rapid transit railroad\ntunnel or tunnels shall be deemed to be a rapid transit railroad.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>