<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-21-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_B">
        <num>21-B</num>
        <heading>Construction and equipment of a rapid transit railroad line</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 21-b. Construction and equipment of a rapid transit railroad line.\n1. The New York city transit authority, acting under and pursuant to the\nprovisions of this chapter and of title nine of article five of the\npublic authorities law, is hereby authorized to effect the construction\nand equipment of a rapid transit line in the borough of Queens in the\ncity of New York, along the following route:\n  A route lying wholly within the borough of Queens beginning at a point\nunder Forty-first avenue at or near Twenty-ninth street, where a\nconnection can conveniently be made with the tracks at the easterly end\nof the Sixty-third street line; thence curving and extending\nnortheasterly to a point under Northern boulevard across Fortieth\navenue, Thirty-first street, Thirty-ninth avenue, Honeywell street,\nThirty-second street, and Thirty-third street to a point under\nThirty-fourth street and Northern boulevard.\n  2. Notwithstanding any defect, irregularity or omission of any lawful\nrequirement or lack of statutory authority therefore, the acts and\nproceedings heretofore taken by the New York city transit authority in\nadopting, approving or consenting to plans and conclusions, general plan\nof construction, route or any other matters, with respect to the rapid\ntransit line provided for in this section, are hereby legalized,\nratified, validated and confirmed.\n  3. Notwithstanding any other state or local law, this section shall\nconstitute the sole state or local governmental authority required for\nthe construction and equipment of the route set forth in subdivision one\nof this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>