<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-34"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-34"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-06-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="34"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-34/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-34/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-34/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-34/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34">
        <num>34</num>
        <heading>Issue of bonds by city</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 34. Issue of bonds by city. a. For the purpose of providing the\nnecessary means for such construction, or equipment, or both, as the\ncase may be, or acquiring by purchase, at the public expense, of any\nsuch road or subsurface structures, and the necessary means to pay for\nproperty rights which shall be acquired by the city for the purposes of\nthe construction or the operation of any such road as provided in this\nchapter, and the necessary means to pay awards made as provided in this\nchapter for damages for change of grade on any street and to pay the\nexpenses of proceedings to determine such damages, and of meeting the\ninterest on obligations, issued for the purposes of this section,\naccruing thereon prior to the completion and readiness for operation of\nthe portion of such road, and such sub-surface structures, for the\npurchase, construction, or equipment of which such obligations shall\nhave been respectively issued, the mayor, from time to time, as the same\nshall be necessary, upon the requisition of the board of transportation,\nshall make available such sums as may be necessary, upon vouchers\ncertified by the board of transportation. In case any person shall claim\nto be entitled to any money on account of a contract entered into under\nthe terms of this chapter, for the construction of any part of a\nmunicipal railroad and the board of transportation shall fail, neglect\nor refuse to certify a proper or sufficient voucher for the payment of\nthe money so claimed, a proper or sufficient voucher shall not be a\ncondition precedent to the liability of the city, but an action may be\nbrought directly against the city for the recovery of such money as such\nperson may be entitled to. This section shall not affect the powers of\nthe board or its engineers, as set forth in this chapter or as they may\nbe prescribed in any contract entered into pursuant thereto, or to\nchange or alter in any respect the existing rules of law as to the force\nor effect of any certificate which shall have been or may hereafter be\nmade under any contract. This section shall be deemed to apply also to\nany such actions instituted before May sixth, nineteen hundred\ntwenty-one. If bonds are issued by the city for the purposes of this\nsection they may be made payable out of a sinking fund to be established\nand created out of the annual rentals or revenues of such road,\nincluding sub-surface structures, as provided in this chapter. In case\nthe board shall request the mayor to have any part of the work of\nrestoration of street surfaces or property incidental to the\nconstruction of any such road performed by or under the direction of any\nhead of an agency of such city or any subdivision of such city, the\nmayor may set apart out of any appropriation theretofore made under the\nforegoing provisions of this section such amount as the board of\ntransportation may specify and shall make such amount available for the\nuse of such head of such agency for the purposes of such restoration of\nstreet surfaces or property.\n  b. A contract for the construction of such road shall not be made\nunless and until the mayor shall have consented thereto and prescribed a\nlimit to the amount of funds available for the purposes of this section\nwhich shall be sufficient to meet the requirements of such contract in\naddition to all obligations theretofore incurred and to be satisfied\nfrom such funds. The board of transportation of the city of New York, in\nits discretion, may request the mayor to make available either such\namounts from time to time as it shall deem the progress of the work to\nrequire, or the full amount sufficient to pay the entire estimated\nexpenses of executing any contract made pursuant to this chapter. The\ncertificate of the comptroller, mentioned in section 93c-3.0 of the\nadministrative code of the city of New York shall not be necessary to\nmake any such contract binding on the city. Before finally fixing the\nterms and conditions of any contract for any of the purposes contained\nand set forth in this chapter, the board of transportation may set a\ndate or dates for a public hearing upon the proposed terms and\nconditions thereof, at which citizens shall be entitled to appear and be\nheard. No such hearing shall be held, however, until notice thereof\nshall have been published for at least two weeks immediately prior\nthereto in the city record, or other official publication of the city,\nand at least twice in two daily newspapers published in the city. In any\ncase where such a public hearing has been scheduled, it shall be the\nduty of the board of transportation to cause as many copies of a draft\nof the proposed contract to be printed at least two weeks in advance of\nsuch hearing as may be necessary. Such notice of such public hearing\nshall state where copies of such drafts may be obtained upon payment of\na fee, to be fixed by such board, but not to exceed one dollar for each\ncopy. The board, after the hearing to be held as above required, may\nalter, modify or amend such draft contract in any manner in its\ndiscretion.\n  c. A railroad owned or to be owned by the city, and for the\nconstruction of which with public money in whole or in part a contract\nwas or is authorized by this chapter to be entered into as aforesaid,\nshall be a local improvement the cost of which railroad may be met in\nwhole or in part by assessment on the property benefited. The board,\nwith the approval of the board of estimate and of the mayor, shall have\npower to determine whether all or any, and if any, what portion of the\ncost and expense necessary to be incurred for any such road shall be\nassessed upon property benefited thereby, and whether all or any, and if\nany, what portion of the cost and expense necessary to be incurred, or\nwhich shall have been already necessarily incurred, for the acquisition\nof any property for the construction or operation of such railroad shall\nbe assessed upon property benefited by such railroad. An assessment upon\nthe property so benefited may be laid, confirmed, enforced and collected\nin accordance with such determination and pursuant to the provisions of\nthe charter, administrative code of such city and other laws respecting\nassessments for local improvements in such city.\n  d. At any time after the consents have been obtained for any such\nrailroad and the detailed plans and specifications therefor have been\nprepared as authorized and directed by this chapter, the board may\ncertify and transmit to such board of estimate an estimate of the cost\nand expense necessary to be incurred for the construction of such\nrailroad, and for the acquisition of any property, including equipment\nother than rolling stock, that shall be necessary either for the\nconstruction or the operation of such railroad, or from time to time an\nestimate of the cost and expense necessary to be incurred or a statement\nof the cost and expense which has been necessarily incurred for the\nacquisition of any property for the construction or operation of such\nrailroad. With such estimate or statement the board of transportation\nshall transmit a statement which shall show:\n  1. The proportion of such cost and expense, together with the amount\nthereof in money, which should be assessed upon the property benefited;\n  2. The boundaries of the district in such city upon which an\nassessment aggregating such amount should in the opinion of the board be\nlevied, and\n  3. The amount so to be levied in every such district.\nThereupon the board with the approval of the board of estimate and of\nthe mayor, shall have power to, and, if in their judgment the interests\nof the public so require, after publishing a notice at least one week in\nadvance in the City Record and in such other newspapers published in\nsuch city as such board of estimate with the approval of the mayor,\nshall designate as sufficient, stating the time, place and subjects to\nbe considered, and after a joint hearing, pursuant to such notice by and\nbefore the board of transportation and the board of estimate, which may\nbe adjourned from time to time, in accordance with the charter, code,\nand laws aforesaid, they shall fix and determine the boundaries of the\ndistrict upon which such assessment shall be levied, the whole amount or\nproportion of any such cost and expense to be assessed upon property\nbenefited by such improvement, and the amount or proportion of such\nwhole assessment to be levied in such district benefited by such\nimprovement, and take such other and further proceedings as shall be\nnecessary to levy and collect such assessment. Such decision of the\nboard of transportation so approved by the board of estimate and the\nmayor, shall be final as to each matter so fixed and determined and\nshall not be subject to review.\n  e. The board of estimate, with the approval of the mayor, shall\ncertify to the board of assessors of such city the amount of such cost\nand expense so directed to be assessed upon property benefited in each\nsuch district. Such board of assessors shall thereupon proceed forthwith\nto levy and assess such amount upon the real property within the\ndistrict benefited thereby in proportion to the amount of such benefit\nand shall not be limited in the levying of such assessment to one-half\nof the fair value of any house or lot or improved or unimproved land.\nSuch assessment when laid shall be subject to, and protected by, all\nprovisions of the charter and administrative code of such city\napplicable to assessments for local improvements levied pursuant to such\ncharter and code.\n  f. An assessment levied against any property in accordance with this\nsection shall be payable as follows, namely: one-tenth thereof within\nsixty days from the date of the confirmation and entry of each\nassessment and the remainder of such assessment in nine installments as\nnearly equal in amount as may be with intere</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>