<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-35"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-35"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="35"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_35">
        <num>35</num>
        <heading>Vehicular tunnels and other means of transportation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 35. Vehicular tunnels and other means of transportation.  a.\nNotwithstanding any provisions to the contrary contained in any city\ncharter, administrative code, or in any general, special or local law,\nthe board of transportation may act as the agent of any such city, at\nthe request of the mayor thereof, to prepare and submit to such mayor a\nplan for the building and construction of a tunnel under any stream or\nwaterway within or adjoining the limits of such city and the approaches\nthereto, or a vehicular tunnel or two or more vehicular tunnels,\ntogether with the necessary approaches thereto, between the several\nboroughs of the city of New York, or between two points in the same\nborough, and as such agent of such city, with like request and approval,\nmay proceed with the construction and equipment or enter into contracts\nfor the construction and equipment of such part or section of any such\ntunnel as such mayor shall require. The advertising and award of any and\nall contracts entered into pursuant to this section shall be subject to\nthe provisions of section seventeen of this chapter. The city, from time\nto time, on requisition duly made by the board of transportation, may\nappropriate such sums of money as it may deem requisite and necessary to\nenable the board of transportation to prepare such plans or to carry on\nsuch construction and equipment. Such sums shall be paid out and\nexpended for such purposes upon vouchers certified by such board of\ntransportation. If bonds are issued for such purposes, they may be made\npayable at maturity out of a sinking fund to be established and created\nout of the rates and charges fixed by the board of estimate for the use\nof any such tunnel by pedestrians and vehicles. Upon the completion\nthereof the commissioner of public works or other like officer of such\ncity shall have cognizance and control of the management, maintenance,\noperation and repair of every such tunnel and the approaches thereto.\n  b. The board of transportation, with like request and approval of the\nmayor, may conduct such hearings and investigations with respect to\nstreets, tunnels or other ways, railroads, ferries or other methods or\nmeans for the transportation of passengers or property within the limits\nof any such city as such mayor shall require, and make reports and\nrecommendations with respect thereto, from time to time, as shall\nlikewise be required.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>