<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-53"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-53"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="53"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53">
        <num>53</num>
        <heading>Corporation counsel to acquire property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 53. Corporation counsel to acquire property.  a. Whenever and as\noften as the board of transportation shall deem it to be necessary and\nproper that the city should acquire any such property and shall have\ncaused such maps or plans and memoranda specifying and defining the\nproperty to be acquired, or to which are appurtenant the property rights\nto be acquired or extinguished, to be made and shall have certified,\nfiled and transmitted the several copies of such maps or plans as\nprescribed in section fifty-two of this chapter, such board may direct\nthe corporation counsel to take legal proceedings to acquire the same\nfor the city, and the corporation counsel shall thereupon take legal\nproceedings as provided in this chapter.\n  b. The corporation counsel, either in person or by such counsel as he\nshall designate for the purpose, shall appear for and protect the\ninterests of the city in all such proceedings. He shall furnish the\ncourt with such necessary clerks and other employees as it may require.\nAll necessary expenses incurred by the corporation counsel in and about\nthe proceedings provided for by this chapter for the proper presentation\nand defense of the interests of the city, shall be paid by the\ncomptroller out of the funds referred to in section sixty-nine of this\nchapter. Property owners appearing in proceedings under this chapter\nshall not be entitled to recover counsel fees, costs, disbursements or\nallowances.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>