<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-57"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-57"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="57"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-57/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-57/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-57/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-57/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_57">
        <num>57</num>
        <heading>Procedure in case property is situated in two or more counties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 57. Procedure in case property is situated in two or more counties.\nIf the property to be acquired or extinguished in any proceeding be\nsituated in two or more counties, the maps or plans and memoranda\nrequired to be filed by section fifty-four of this chapter shall be so\nfiled in the respective offices therein provided in each county in which\nsuch property or any part thereof is situated, and the application to\ncondemn such property may be made to the supreme court at any special\nterm thereof held in any judicial district in which any one of such\ncounties is situated. If the property to be acquired or extinguished in\nany proceeding be situated in two judicial districts the application to\ncondemn such property may be made in either judicial district. The order\ngranting the application to condemn in any such proceeding shall be\nentered, and the final decree therein shall be filed in the office of\nthe clerk of any one of the counties in which a part of the property to\nbe thereby acquired or extinguished is situated, as directed by the\ncourt, and a certified copy of the order granting the application to\ncondemn and a certified copy of the final decree shall be filed in the\noffice in which instruments affecting real property are required to be\nrecorded in each county in which any part of the property thereby\nacquired or extinguished is situated. In all other respects the\nproceeding shall be conducted in the same manner as a proceeding\naffecting property situated in only one county.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>