<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-67"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-67"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="67"/>
          <FRBRname value="RAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-67/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-67/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-67/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rat/section-67/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_67">
        <num>67</num>
        <heading>Payment of awards and expenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 67. Payment of awards and expenses.  Within four calendar months\nafter the date of the filing of the final decree of the court, the city\nshall pay to the parties entitled thereto the respective sums of money\ndetermined in their favor as set forth in the final decree, with legal\ninterest thereon from the date of the entry of the order granting the\napplication to condemn.  In case of neglect or default in the payment\nthereof within the time aforesaid, the respective persons in whose favor\nthe same shall be so determined, after application to the comptroller\nfor payment thereof, may sue for and recover the same, with lawful\ninterest as aforesaid and costs of suit. No fees or expenses incurred by\nthe city or the corporation counsel in connection with any proceeding\ninstituted under this chapter shall be paid until they shall have been\ntaxed by the court upon five days' notice to the corporation counsel and\nupon proof of the nature and extent of the services rendered and\ndisbursements charged. No unnecessary costs or charges shall be allowed.\nAll costs, fees, expenses or disbursements to be taxed shall be stated\nin detail in the bill of costs and shall be accompanied by such proof of\nthe reasonableness and necessity thereof as is required by law and the\npractice of the court upon taxation of costs and disbursements in other\nspecial proceedings or actions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>