<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="201"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_201">
        <num>201</num>
        <heading>Office for the aging; director</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 201. Office for the aging; director. 1. There is hereby created\nwithin the executive department an office for the aging.\n  2. The head of such office shall be a director, who shall be appointed\nby the governor, by and with the advice and consent of the senate, and\nshall hold office during the pleasure of the governor. The director\nshall receive an annual salary to be fixed by the governor within the\namount available therefor by appropriation. The director shall also be\nentitled to receive reimbursement for expenses actually and necessarily\nincurred by him or her in the performance of his or her duties.\n  3. The director may appoint such officers, employees, agents,\nconsultants and special committees as he or she may deem necessary,\nprescribe their duties, fix their compensation and provide for\nreimbursement of their expenses within the amounts available therefor by\nappropriation. The director, with the advice of the advisory committee\nfor the aging, may promulgate, adopt, amend or rescind rules and\nregulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this article.\n  4. In carrying out its powers and duties under this title, the office\nis organized and operated to have as a primary purpose informing and\ninstructing the public, especially the elderly themselves, on subjects\nbeneficial to the community which relate to the needs, abilities,\nresources, opportunities, rights, entitlements, and other issues\naffecting older people in New York state.\n  5. For the purposes of this chapter, "office" shall refer to the state\noffice for the aging created pursuant to this section, and "director"\nshall refer to the director of the state office for the aging\nestablished by this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>