<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="203"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Programs for the aging</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>coordination and community planning;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>information services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>counselling services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>home care and protection services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>operation of multi-service centers; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>retired senior volunteer programs.\n  3. The director, with the advice of the advisory committee for the\naging, shall make appropriate rules and regulations governing the\nsubmission and approval of applications for the operation of programs\nfor the aging pursuant to subdivision two of this section. If an\napplication is disapproved, the applicant, upon request, shall be\nafforded a hearing before the director or his or her designee.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As required by the office, each county, city, town, village,\nschool district or public or private nonprofit corporation, association,\ninstitution or agency operating a program for the aging pursuant to\nsubdivision two of this section shall submit to the office</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_203__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a\nquarterly estimate of anticipated expenditures for operation and\nmaintenance of such program, including rental of buildings, purchase of\nequipment, administrative expenses, miscellaneous personal expenses of\nolder persons incurred in the provision of volunteer services, and\napproved expenditures for minor alterations or repairs, not less than\nthirty days before the first day of the months of April, July, October\nand January, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_203__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a verified accounting of the financial operations\nof such program during the preceding calendar quarter, together with a\nclaim for reimbursement as provided in this title, on or before the\nthirtieth day of April, July, October and January. The director may\npermit the submission of such accountings with respect to periods\nexceeding three months, but not exceeding one year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After receipt of a satisfactory quarterly estimate and verified\naccounting pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the director\nshall certify to the comptroller, for payment by the state to each such\ncounty, city, town, village, school district or public or private\nnonprofit corporation, association, institution or agency, the\nexpenditures thereof, approved by the office, as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of federal funds, if any, properly received for such\nexpenditures; and\n  (ii) up to fifty percentum of such expenditures, after first deducting\ntherefrom any federal funds properly received with respect to such\nexpenditures.\n  5. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision four of this section,\nbut subject to and in the manner specified in this subdivision, the\noffice, in its discretion, may entertain and approve applications for\ninterim payments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such an application may be approved by the office, upon being\nsatisfied that the requirement for filing a verified accounting of the\nfinancial operation of a program during the preceding calendar quarter\nbefore a claim for reimbursement based on the expenditures for such\nquarter may be made, is likely to cause a financial hardship to the\napplicant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such an application may be made at the time of filing the\nquarterly estimate of anticipated expenditures as specified in\nsubdivision four of this section or at such other time as the office\nshall specify.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After receipt of a satisfactory quarterly estimate, the office may\ndirect the director to certify to the comptroller for payment an interim\npayment in such amount as the office shall specify.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amount of the interim payment which the office may authorize\nshall not exceed an amount equal to one-third of the amount which the\napplicant may reasonably be entitled to receive in accordance with the\nprovisions of subdivision four of this section, for the three month\nperiod for which a satisfactory quarterly statement has been filed,\nbased on such satisfactory quarterly estimate. The amount of an interim\npayment received by the applicant shall be subtracted from the amount\npayable to the applicant for such three-month period.\n  6. The director is hereby authorized, within amounts appropriated\ntherefor, to make grants-in-aid to existing foster grandparent grantee\nagencies for the engagement of foster grandparents in qualified\nresidential group homes for neglected and disadvantaged children, in\nprivate homes, day care centers, special education classes in public\nschools, or other public or private nonprofit institutions or agencies\nproviding care for neglected and disadvantaged children who lack close\npersonal relationships. Up to twenty percent of such grants-in-aid may\nbe expended for the administrative purposes of such grantee agencies,\nwith the approval of the office. Such grants shall be for a period of\ntwelve months or less, shall not be used to match other state funds,\nshall not be used as a substitute for federal allocations, and shall be\nmade in a manner which does not conflict with federal law, rule or\nregulation pursuant to title II of the United States domestic volunteer\nservices act of nineteen hundred seventy-three, as amended. Grants may\nbe used to match federal funds but must be used for expansion of\nexisting federal programs, not as a substitute for presently required\nnon-federal shares. Each grantee shall file reports at such time and\ncontaining such information as the office shall require. For the purpose\nof administering such grants-in-aid the office may make such agreements\nwith other public agencies as are deemed...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The director shall develop a list of programs and services\noffered by local area agencies on aging along with contact information\nfor the local area agencies on aging and NYConnects organized by county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The information developed pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision shall be made available on the office's website and provided\nto hospital discharge coordinators located in the state.\n  12.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The director is hereby authorized to implement private pay\nprotocols for programs and services administered by the office. These\nprotocols may be implemented by area agencies on aging at their option\nand such protocols shall not be applied to services for a participant\nwhen being paid for with federal funds or funds designated as federal\nmatch, or for individuals with an income below two hundred and fifty\npercent of the federal poverty level. All private payments received\ndirectly by an area agency on aging or indirectly by one of its\ncontractors shall be used to supplement, not supplant, funds by state,\nfederal, or county appropriations. Such private pay payments shall be\nset at a cost to the participant of not more than twenty percent above\neither the unit cost to the area agency on aging to provide the program\nor service directly, or the amount that the area agency on aging pays to\nits contractor to provide the program or service. Private pay payments\nreceived under this subdivision shall be used by the area agency on\naging to first reduce any unmet need for programs and services, and then\nto support and enhance services or programs provided by the area agency\non aging. No participant, regardless of income, shall be required to pay\nfor any program or service that they are receiving at the time these\nprotocols are implemented by the area agency on aging. This subdivision\nshall not prevent cost sharing for the programs and services established\npursuant to section two hundred fourteen of this title. Consistent with\nfederal and state statute and regulations, when providing programs and\nservices, area agencies on aging and their contractors shall continue to\ngive priority for programs and services to individuals with the greatest\neconomic or social needs. In the event that the capacity to provide\nprograms and services is limited, such programs and services shall be\nprovided to individuals with incomes below two hundred and fifty percent\nof ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_203__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Area agencies on aging participating in the private pay protocol\nshall annually report to the office the unmet need, if any, for all\nprograms and services offered, the number of participants that privately\npaid for each program or service for that year, the rates participants\nwere charged for each program or service provided, and how unmet need\nfor programs or services offered by the area agency on aging were\naffected by revenue from the private pay protocol. Such annual report\nshall also be shared with the Temporary President of the Senate and the\nSpeaker of the Assembly no later than July first, two thousand\ntwenty-one and shall be updated and reissued on an annual basis\nthereafter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>