<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="204"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Records of available space</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 204. Records of available space. 1. The office shall have the\nresponsibility to compile and maintain an inventory of space available\nfor placing eligible aged citizens in facilities under the jurisdiction\nof the dormitory authority; the office shall also take whatever action\nnecessary to locate those aged citizens of New York, who, according to\nstandards to be promulgated by the office, are available for residence\nin facilities under the jurisdiction of the dormitory authority; the\noffice shall initiate, assist, coordinate, supervise, and approve the\nplan of relocation of such aged citizens, in facilities under the\njurisdiction of the dormitory authority, by any not-for-profit\ncorporation or political subdivision of the state or the state, or in\nthe absence of the foregoing entities, by the office itself; in\naddition, the office shall carry out the purposes of the public\nauthorities law pertaining to the use of dormitory authority facilities\nfor the aged.\n  2. In carrying out the duties and responsibilities under this title,\nthe office shall periodically review existing aged residents' use of\ndormitory authority facilities, and to establish and enforce such rules\nand regulations as may be necessary to assure the office that the needs\nof aged residents, as determined by the office, are being met.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>