<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="210"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_210">
        <num>210</num>
        <heading>Advisory committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 210. Advisory committee.  1. There shall be within the office an\nadvisory committee for the aging, consisting of not more than\nthirty-five members, appointed by the governor. In making such\nappointments, the governor shall give due consideration to\nrepresentation from the major regions of the state. One member of the\nadvisory committee shall be designated as chairperson by the governor\nand shall serve as chairperson at the pleasure of the governor. The\nadvisory committee shall meet from time to time at the call of such\nchairperson or the director. The director shall seek the advice of the\nadvisory committee with respect to the needs of the aging and, if so\nrequested by the director, such committee shall make particular studies\nrelating to the aging.\n  2. The members of the advisory committee shall serve without salary,\nbut each member shall be entitled to reimbursement for his or her actual\nand necessary expenses incurred in the performance of his or her\nofficial duties.\n  3. All members of the advisory committee shall be appointed for terms\nof three years provided, however, that of the members first appointed,\none-third shall be appointed for one-year terms, and one-third shall be\nappointed for two-year terms. Any member chosen to fill a vacancy\ncreated otherwise than by expiration of term shall be appointed for the\nunexpired term of the member he or she is to succeed.\n  4. Sixty percent of the members of the advisory committee appointed on\nand after the effective date of this subdivision shall be sixty years of\nage or over.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>