<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-217-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-217-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="217-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-217-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-217-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-217-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-217-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_217_A">
        <num>217-A</num>
        <heading>Long term care insurance education and outreach program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_217_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>educational and informational materials in print, audio, visual,\nelectronic or other media;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_217_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>public service announcements, advertisements, media campaigns,\nworkshops, mass mailings, conferences or presentations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_217_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establishment of a toll-free telephone hotline and electronic\nservices to provide information; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_217_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establishment of long term care insurance resource centers within\neach area agency on aging.\n  5. Long term care insurance resource centers shall, within amounts\navailable, provide the general public with the following items or\nservices:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_217_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>educational and informational materials in print, audio, visual,\nelectronic or other media;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_217_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>public service announcements, advertisements, media campaigns,\nworkshops, mass mailings, conferences or presentations; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_217_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>counseling, information, referral services, and direct assistance\nin choosing and obtaining long term care insurance. Direct assistance\nshall, within amounts available, include but not be limited to\nassistance with the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_217_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>planning for the financing of long term care;\n  (ii) understanding policy options, benefits and appeal rights;\n  (iii) obtaining the coverage needed and the appropriate benefits; and\n  (iv) avoiding or reporting illegal billing, fraudulent practices or\nscams.\n  Each long term care insurance resource center shall be responsible,\nwithin amounts available, for providing a sufficient number of staff\npositions (including volunteers) necessary to provide and carry out the\nservices of the long term care insurance education and outreach program,\nprovided that at least one position shall be filled by an individual who\nis employed full time and paid by the area agency on aging. The long\nterm care insurance resource center shall be responsible for ensuring\nthat its staff persons have no conflict of interest in providing the\nservices described in subdivision four of this section.\n  6. Annually, in order to receive funding, each area agency on aging\nshall submit a service plan and proposed budget for the operation of a\nlong term care insurance resource center to the state program\ncoordinator for approval. An area agency on aging shall be eligible to\nreceive funds in an amount of up to fifty thousand dollars, except that\nan area agency on aging located within a city of one million or more\nshall be eligible to receive funds in an amount of up to one hundred\nthousand dollars.\n  7. The department of health shall produce, post on its website, make\navailable to others for reproduction, or contract with others to develop\nsuch materials required by this section. The material produced pursuant\nto this section shall be culturally and linguistically appropriate for\nthe communities served by the long term care insurance resource centers.\nThese materials shall be made available to the public free of charge.\n  8. In exercising any of their powers under this section, the\ncommissioner of health and/or the director of the office for the aging\nmay consult with approp...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>