<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-224"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-224"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-10-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="224"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_224">
        <num>224</num>
        <heading>Informal caregivers in the workplace program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 224. Informal caregivers in the workplace program. 1. The office\nshall, in conjunction with the department of labor, and in consultation\nwith community based organizations representing the interests of\ninformal caregivers around the state, develop and update on a yearly\nbasis a guide for businesses in the state that contains current best\npractices for retaining employees who are also informal caregivers and\ninformation for supporting such employees so they can achieve\neffectiveness both in and out of the workplace.\n  2. Such guide shall be available on the websites of the office, the\ndepartment of labor and the department of state. Businesses that obtain\ncertification or licensure from the department of labor or department of\nstate shall be provided with a link to the guide provided for in\nsubdivision one of this section, or a paper copy upon request, when the\nbusiness applies for such certification or licensure. A nominal fee may\nbe charged for paper copies provided to individuals who are not business\nowners.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>