<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-225"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-225"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-07-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225">
        <num>225</num>
        <heading>Elder abuse enhanced multidisciplinary team program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 225. Elder abuse enhanced multidisciplinary team program. 1. The\noffice is hereby authorized, subject to appropriation of funds for the\nprogram, to establish an elder abuse enhanced multidisciplinary team\nprogram consisting of teams at the regional or county level for complex\ncases of elder abuse, including but not limited to financial\nexploitation, physical abuse, psychological abuse, sexual abuse, and\nneglect, involving a victim sixty years of age or older.\n  2. Such elder abuse enhanced multidisciplinary teams shall consist of\nrepresentation by professionals generally authorized to make decisions\non behalf of their agency from public, private, and voluntary agencies.\nRepresented professions may include, but are not limited to,\nhealth/medical, mental health, aging, protective services, human\nservices, social work, banking/financial institutions, legal services,\ndistrict attorney's offices, law enforcement agencies, and forensic\naccounting.\n  3. Teams will also consist of a coordinator who will provide case\nconsultation, triage cases, facilitate elder abuse enhanced\nmultidisciplinary team meetings, monitor progress, and facilitate\ncoordination and cooperative action in the provision of appropriate\nservices to an individual identified as being a victim of elder abuse,\nas well as other duties associated with the role.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, members\nof an elder abuse enhanced multidisciplinary team may share with other\nteam members client-identifiable information concerning victims of elder\nabuse as appropriate to facilitate team activities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>