<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-250"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-250"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="250"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-250/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-250/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-250/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-250/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_250">
        <num>250</num>
        <heading>Reimbursement to participating provider pharmacies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Multiple source covered drugs. Except for brand name drugs that\nare required by the prescriber to be dispensed as written, the allowed\namount for a multiple source covered drug shall equal the lower of:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_250__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The pharmacy's usual and customary charge to the general public,\ntaking into consideration any quantity and promotional discounts to the\ngeneral public at the time of purchase, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_250__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The upper limit, if any, set by the centers for medicare and\nmedicaid services for such multiple source drug, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_250__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Average wholesale price discounted by twenty-five percent, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_250__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The maximum allowable cost, if any, established by the\ncommissioner of health pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision nine of\nsection three hundred sixty-seven-a of the social services law.\n  Plus a dispensing fee for drugs reimbursed pursuant to subparagraphs\ntwo, three, and four of this paragraph, as defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Other covered drugs. The allowed amount for brand name drugs\nrequired by the prescriber to be dispensed as written and for covered\ndrugs other than multiple source drugs shall be determined by applying\nthe lower of:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_250__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Average wholesale price discounted by sixteen and twenty-five one\nhundredths percent, plus a dispensing fee as defined in paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, or\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_250__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The pharmacy's usual and customary charge to the general public,\ntaking into consideration any quantity and promotional discounts to the\ngeneral public at the time of purchase.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As required by paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, a\ndispensing fee of four dollars fifty cents will apply to generic drugs\nand a dispensing fee of three dollars fifty cents will apply to brand\nname drugs.\n  2. For purposes of determining the amount of reimbursement which shall\nbe paid to a participating provider pharmacy, the commissioner of health\nshall determine or cause to be determined, through a statistically valid\nsurvey, the quantities of each covered drug that participating provider\npharmacies buy most frequently. Using the result of this survey, the\ncontractor shall update every thirty days the list of average wholesale\nprices upon which such reimbursement is determined using nationally\nrecognized and most recently revised sources. Such price revisions shall\nbe made available to all participating provider pharmacies. The\npharmacist shall be reimbursed based on the price in effect at the time\nthe covered drug is dispensed.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, the program\nfor elderly pharmaceutical insurance coverage shall reimburse for\ncovered drugs which are dispensed under the program by a provider\npharmacy only pursuant to the terms of a rebate agreement between the\nprogram and the manufacturer (as defined under section 1927 of the\nfederal social security act) of such covered drugs; provided, however,\nthat:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_250__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any agreement between the program and a manufacturer entered into\nbefore August first, nineteen hundred ninety-one, shall be deemed to\nhave been entered into on April first, nineteen hundred ninety-one; and\nprovided further, that if a manufacturer has not entered into an\nagreement with the department before August first, nineteen hundred\nninety-one, such agreement shall not be effective until April first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-two, unless such agreement provides that rebates\nwill be retroactively calculated as if the agreement had been in effect\non April first, nineteen hundred ninety-one; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_250__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the program may reimburse for any covered drugs pursuant to\nsubdivisions one and two of this section, for which a rebate agreement\ndoes not exist and which are determined by the commissioner to be\nessential to the health of persons participating in the program; and\nlikely to provide effective therapy or diagnosis for a disease not\nadequately treated or diagnosed by any other covered drug.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The rebate agreement between such manufacturer and the program for\nelderly pharmaceutical insurance coverage shall utilize for covered\ndrugs the identical formula used to determine the rebate for federal\nfinancial participation for drugs, pursuant to section 1927</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the\nfederal social security act, to determine the amount of the rebate\npursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amount of rebate pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision\nshall be calculated by multiplying the required rebate formulas by the\ntotal number of units of each dosage form and strength dispensed. The\nrebate agreement shall also provide for periodic payment of the rebate,\nprovision of information to the program, audits, verification of data,\ndamages to the program for any delay or non-production of necessary data\nby the manufacturer and for the confidentiality of information.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The program in providing utilization data to a manufacturer (as\nprovided for under section 1927</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the federal social security act)\nshall provide such data by zip code, if requested, for the top three\nhundred most commonly used drugs by volume covered under a rebate\nagreement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_250__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any funds collected pursuant to any rebate agreements entered into\nwith a manufacturer pursuant to this subdivision, shall be deposited\ninto the elderly pharmaceutical insurance coverage program premium\naccount.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, entities which offer\ninsurance coverage for provision of and/or reimbursement for\npharmaceutical expenses, including but not limited to, entities\nlicensed/certified pursuant to article thirty-two, forty-two,\nforty-three or forty-four of the insurance law (employees welfare funds)\nor article forty-four of the public health law, shall participate in a\nbenefit recovery program with the elderly pharmaceutical insurance\ncoverage (EPIC) program which includes, but is not limited to, a\nsemi-annual match of EPIC's file of enrollees against the entity's file\nof insured to identify individuals enrolled in both plans with claims\npaid within the twenty-four months preceding the date the entity\nreceives the match request information from EPIC. Such entity shall\nindicate if pharmaceutical coverage is available from the entity for the\ninsured persons, list the copayment or other payment obligations of the\ninsured persons applicable to the pharmaceutical coverage, and (after\nreceiving necessary claim information from EPIC) list the amounts which\nthe entity would have paid for the pharmaceutical claims for those\nidentified individuals and the entity shall reimburse EPIC for\npharmaceutical expenses paid by EPIC that are covered under the contract\nbetween the entity and its insured in only those instances where the\nentity has not already made payment of the claim. Reimbursement of the\nnet amount payable (after rebates and discounts) that would have been\npaid under the coverage issued by the entity will be made by the entity\nto EPIC within sixty days of receipt from EPIC of the standard data in\nelectronic format necessary for the entity to adjudicate the claim and\nif the standard data is provided to t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>