<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELD">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-261"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-261"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-09-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="261"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELD"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-261/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-261/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-261/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eld/section-261/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_261">
        <num>261</num>
        <heading>Guidelines for identifying and reporting suspected self neglect, abuse and maltreatment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 261. Guidelines for identifying and reporting suspected self\nneglect, abuse and maltreatment. The director, in conjunction with the\ncommissioner of the department of health and the commissioner of the\noffice of children and family services, shall develop guidelines to\nassist healthcare providers and others working in healthcare settings to\nidentify suspected self neglect, abuse and maltreatment of an older\nadult. Such guidelines may be tailored to specific healthcare providers\nor industries and shall include, but shall not be limited to:\n  1. Common signs and symptoms of self neglect, abuse and maltreatment;\n  2. Screening questions and tools that can be used during a visit to\nhelp detect whether self neglect or abuse and maltreatment may be\noccurring;\n  3. Training materials for distribution to healthcare providers and\nothers working in healthcare settings regarding appropriate\ninterventions and suggestions for discussing the possibility of self\nneglect, abuse and maltreatment with older adults; and\n  4. Information regarding options for reporting suspected cases of self\nneglect or abuse and maltreatment and available resources for older\nadult victims.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>