<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="106"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_106">
        <num>106</num>
        <heading>Preparation, filing and review of tentative and preliminary budgets</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 106. Preparation, filing and review of tentative and preliminary\nbudgets. 1. The budget officer, upon receipt of the estimates of the\nvarious administrative units, shall review the estimates and may confer\nwith the head of any such unit in regard to such estimates. He may\nrequire the head of any such unit to furnish information and to answer\ninquiries pertinent to such review.\n  2. Upon the completion of the review of the estimates, the budget\nofficer shall prepare a tentative budget which shall include his\nrecommendations and which shall be in the form prescribed in and in\nconformance with section one hundred seven of this article. He may also\nprepare a budget message explaining the main features of the tentative\nbudget and containing such additional information as he may deem\nadvisable. On or before the thirtieth day of September, or in towns in\nWestchester and Monroe counties on or before the thirtieth day of\nOctober, he shall file in the office of the town clerk the tentative\nbudget, the budget message, if any, and the estimates and schedules.\n  3. The town clerk shall present the tentative budget to the town board\nat a regular or special meeting to be held on or before the fifth day of\nOctober. In towns in Westchester and Monroe counties the town clerk\nshall present the tentative budget to the town board at a regular or\nspecial meeting to be held on or before the tenth day of November. The\ntown board may call upon the head of any administrative unit and the\nbudget officer to discuss the tentative budget and the estimates as\noriginally submitted. The head of any administrative unit may request in\nwriting that he be permitted to explain his estimates to the town board.\nThe town board shall review the tentative budget and may make such\nchanges, alterations and revisions as it shall consider advisable and\nwhich are consistent with law.\n  4. Upon the completion of such review, the tentative budget and any\nmodifications thereof as approved by the town board, shall become the\npreliminary budget. The preliminary budget shall be filed in the office\nof the town clerk and the town clerk shall reproduce for public\ndistribution as many copies as the town board may direct.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>