<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-109"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-109"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="109"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_109">
        <num>109</num>
        <heading>Final revision and adoption of budget</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 109. Final revision and adoption of budget. 1. After the public\nhearing, the town board may further change, alter and revise the\npreliminary budget, subject, however, to the requirements of subdivision\none of section one hundred seven of this chapter.\n  2. The preliminary budget as submitted or amended shall be finally\nadopted by resolution of the town board not later than the twentieth day\nof November, except that in towns in Westchester and Monroe counties not\nlater than the twentieth day of December. The preliminary budget as\nadopted shall be known as the annual budget for the town for the fiscal\nyear beginning on the first day of January next succeeding, and it shall\nbe entered in the minutes of the town board.\n  3. Upon the adoption of the resolution required by this section the\namounts proposed to be appropriated shall thereupon be appropriated. In\nthe event that the town board shall fail to adopt a budget as of the\ntwentieth day of November, or in towns in Westchester and Monroe\ncounties as of the twentieth day of December, the preliminary budget,\nwith such changes, alterations and revisions, if any, as shall have been\nmade by the town board, shall constitute the budget for the ensuing\nfiscal year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>