<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="130"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_130">
        <num>130</num>
        <heading>Town ordinances</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nRegulating the use of streets, highways, sidewalks and public places by\npedestrians, animals, motor and other vehicles, including local and\ninterurban street cars; restricting parking of all vehicles therein;\nregulating parades and public assemblages therein; regulating or\nprohibiting coasting therein; and, subject to the approval of the\ndepartment of transportation, requiring railroad companies to employ and\nmaintain competent flagmen and erect gates at any street or highway\ncrossing; prohibiting the deposit of any dirt, filth, waste or rubbish\nin any street, highway, sidewalk, that part of any waterway within its\njurisdiction or public place or incumbering thereof by any encroachment\nof buildings, structures, excavation or otherwise; regulating the manner\nin which excavation may be made in or under the streets, highways,\nsidewalks or public places and requiring an indemnity bond as a\ncondition precedent thereto or the town board may require as the\ncondition precedent thereto, the deposit in cash of such an amount as\nthe board may determine necessary to cover the probable expense to the\ntown of the replacement by the town of the street, highway, sidewalk or\npublic place, and the unexpended balance, if any, shall be refunded to\nthe depositor; providing for the removal of snow and ice therefrom;\nprohibiting the use by owners and occupants of property abutting on\npublic streets or grounds of barbed wire or similar fences along the\nboundaries of such street or grounds.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the front or other exterior wall of any building erected on or\nbefore the first day of January, nineteen hundred forty, in any town\nencroaches not more than six inches upon any street or highway, no\naction or proceeding to compel the removal of such wall shall be\ninstituted or maintained by or on behalf of the town, or by or on behalf\nof any person claiming an easement in or title to the portion of the\nstreet or highway on which such wall encroaches, unless such action or\nproceeding be commenced within the period of one year from the time this\nact takes effect, and unless within such period a notice of the pendency\nof such action or proceeding, describing the property on which said\nbuilding stands and indexed against the owner thereof, be filed in the\noffice of the clerk of the county in which the property lies.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the front or other exterior wall of any building erected after\nthe first day of January, nineteen hundred forty, in any town encroaches\nnot more than six inches upon any street or highway, no action or\nproceeding to compel the removal of such wall shall be instituted or\nmaintained by or on behalf of the town, or by or on behalf of any person\nclaiming an easement in or title to the portion of the street or highway\non which such wall encroaches, unless such action or proceeding be\ncommenced within the period of one year from the time of the serving of\na notice as hereinafter provided, and unless within such period a notice\nof the pendency of such action or proceeding, describing the property on\nwhich said building stands and indexed against the owner thereof, be\nfiled in the office of the clerk of the county in which the property\nlies. Any person having any interest in the property on which such\nbuilding stands may serve a notice on the town clerk, town supervisor or\non such town officer as the town board shall authorize and direct to\ndefend or appear in any action or legal proceeding against said town, of\nthe town in which said property lies, setting forth a brief description\nof the property, his interest therein, and the existence of an\nencroachment on the street or highway. Such notice, together with proof\nor admission of service thereof, shall be filed in the office of the\nclerk of the county in which such property lies. The clerk shall index\nand record such notice as if it were a notice of the pendency of an\naction and shall collect the usual fees for recording and indexing a\nnotice of the pendency of an action.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If no action be brought within the period hereby limited therefor\nthe owners and encumbrancers of such property shall be deemed to have an\neasement for the maintenance of the encroaching wall so long as the said\nwall shall stand, and no longer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the front or other exterior wall of any building erected on or\nbefore the first day of January, nineteen hundred sixty-five in any town\nencroaches not more than six inches upon any town street or town\nhighway, the local legislative body of any town may authorize the\nmaintenance of such encroachment by ordinance during the period of time\nthe encroaching wall is in existence; provided, however, that such\nauthorization shall not confer any right or claim to be asserted against\nsuch town or the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The owner of real property upon which the front or exterior wall\nof any building thereon encroaches upon any town street or highway, may\nsubmit a request, in writing, to the town board of such town for\nauthorization to maintain such front or exterior wall during the time\nsuch wall is in existence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon presentation of such request, notice thereof shall be given\nto the town highway superintendent, who shall recommend to the town\nboard the proposed action on such request. Within thirty days of the\npresentation of such request, the town board shall determine if the\ngranting of such request shall adversely impact upon the users of the\ntown street or highway. In the event a determination is made that such\nencroachment does adversely impact upon the use of the town street or\nhighway, such request shall be denied. In the event a preliminary\ndetermination is made that such encroachment may have no adverse impact\nupon the use of the town street or highway, the town board shall within\nthirty days after the issuance of such preliminary finding, hold a\npublic hearing upon such request, which public hearing shall be\nconducted upon not less than ten days notice to the public. In addition\nto such public notice, the owners of property, as determined from the\nlast completed assessment roll, within five hundred feet of the property\nas measured from the intersections of the property lines with the town\nstreet or highway shall be given notice by certified mail of such public\nhearing.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If, upon the completion of the public hearing, the town board\ndetermines that such front or exterior wall does not interfere or impede\nthe right of the public to use such town street or highway, the town\nboard may grant to the owner of such property a license to continue to\nmaintain such front or exterior wall during the period such wall is in\nexistence; provided however, such town shall have the authority to\nrevoke such license at any time in the event the town board determines\nthat such town street or highway will be improved and as a result of\nsuch improvement the front or exterior wall will then impede, interfere\nwith or obstruct traffic or the use of the town street or highway;\nprovided, further, that such license shall not confirm any right or\nclaim against such town. In such event the owner of the property shall\nbe given notice of the proposed action and shall, within the time set\nforth in the notice, remove such front or exterior wall from the town\nstreet or highway.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the abandonment of the building or in the event such\nbuilding, because of a lack of care enters a state of disrepair, the\nowner thereof shall remove such front or exterior wall upon notice from\nthe town board.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority granted to a town pursuant to paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision may, by local law, be assigned to any\ndepartment or agency of the town.\n  7-a. Location and construction of driveways. Regulating the location\nand manner in which driveway entrances and exits may be constructed by\nowners and occupants of property abutting on town highways; provided,\nhowever, that such regulations shall not deny access from abutting\nproperty upon town highways, when such abutting property is a legal lot\nin accordance with existing statutes and ordinances.\n  8. Smoke, gases and wastes. Regulating and prohibiting the unnecessary\nemission of smoke, noxious gases, deposits, dusts, trade wastes and\nother pollutions from buildings, engines, locomotives and other sources,\nand regulating, restricting and prohibiting the unnecessary use of\nbituminous coal within the town or any portion thereof, when such use\nwould affect the public health.\n  9. Animals. Regulating the keeping of calves; regulating and\nprohibiting the keeping of swine and mink, restraining the running at\nlarge of horses, cattle, sheep, unmuzzled dogs, whether licensed or not,\nfowls and other animals and authorizing the impounding and sale of the\nsame for the costs of keeping, proceedings and penalty, or the killing\nof unmuzzled dogs.\n  10. Malicious mischief. Punishing the wilful and malicious breaking,\nmarring, injuring, removing or defacing of any building or structure,\nfence, awning, sign board, tree, crop, shrubbery or other property; the\ntearing down of notices lawfully posted; the removal or alteration or\nany unlawful interference with stakes set out by engineers, surveyors or\notherwise to indicate boundaries or other lines.\n  11. Peace, good order and safety. Preserving the public peace and good\norder; preventing and suppressing vice, immorality, disorderly and\ngambling houses and houses of ill-fame, riots and tumultuous\nassemblages, unnecessary crowds upon the streets, or in doorways or\nstairways adjacent thereto, or loitering about suc...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a. Regulating the speed and regulating and\nrestricting the operation of vessels, personal watercraft and specialty\nprop-craft and, in the counties of Westchester, Saratoga, Warren and\nSuffolk the size and horse power of inboard and outboard motors, while\nbeing operated or driven upon any waters within or bounding the town to\na distance of fifteen hundred feet from the shore except that in Nassau\nand Suffolk counties, towns may regulate and restrict the speed and\nregulate and restrict the operation of vessels in all tidal waters upon\nlands within the geographic boundaries of such town and those tidal\nwaters contiguous with the town to a distance of fifteen hundred feet\nfrom shore and not within any other town. With respect to personal\nwatercraft and specialty prop-craft, regulations may include a\nprohibition of their use provided such prohibition does not prevent\naccess to federally maintained and designated channels and,\nnotwithstanding any other provision of law, such pr...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to waters\nwithin or bounding an incorporated village to a distance of fifteen\nhundred feet from the shore, jurisdiction with respect to which is\nvested in the board of trustees of a village by the provisions of\nsubdivision one of section forty-six-a of the navigation law.\n  18. Shellfish. a. Regulating the taking and the manner of taking\nclams, oysters, scallops and other shellfish from the lands of or from\nwaters over the lands of\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a town vested with the title to, or holding a lease on, lands\nunder tidewater in any harbor, bay or creek, and vested with the right\nof fishing, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the trustees of the freeholders and commonalty of a town in which\nsuch trustees are vested with title to such lands and the right of\nfishing, provided that such trustees shall file with the town clerk an\napplication in writing therefor.\n  b. Such ordinance in either case shall not be less restrictive than\nthe environmental conservation law or, where such law authorizes the\ndepartment to establish lesser restrictions, the regulations made\npursuant to such law, and may provide\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that no dredge or scrape shall be used for such purpose except by\na lessee upon lands held by such lessee under lease;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that no dredge or scrape shall be on board of any boat except that\nof a lessee while upon water covering lands held by such lessee under\nlease and while navigating between the dock, anchorage or moorage used\nby such lessee and such leased land;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that no dredge or scrape shall be on board of any boat while used\nfor taking shellfish from such lands except by a lessee of lands as in\nthis subdivision provided;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that each person upon a boat upon which there is a dredge or\nscrape except as in such ordinance permitted by a lessee shall be a\nviolator of such ordinance;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>That no person shall take any shellfish from such lands, except a\nlessee from lands held by such lessee under lease, unless such person\nshall have received from the proper and duly constituted authority a\nwritten license or permit permitting such person to take such shellfish,\nand a license or permit granted to any person shall upon such person's\nconviction of a violation of such ordinance, be terminated and void; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that any person making unlawful entries upon such lands may be\nproceeded against by injunction to restrain a continuing trespass as\nwell as for violation of said ordinance.\n  c. Such ordinance shall not apply to the use of a dredge or scrape by\nthe owner, the town or such trustees, for the purpose of removing\ndiseased or blighted shellfish from such lands or to any operation by a\ntown or such trustees incident to transplanting shellfish within such\ntown.\n  19. Trespass. Prohibiting trespass to public and private property, for\nthe purpose of protection and preservation of the property of the town\nand of its inhabitants and of peace and good order.\n  20. Hotels, inns, boarding houses, etc. Regulating hotels, inns,\nboarding houses, rooming houses, lodging houses, associations, clubs or\nany building or part of a building used in the business of renting\nrooms, individual or several, and also private sanatoriums, convalescent\nhomes, homes for aged or indigent persons, day nurs...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>