<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-133"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-133"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="133"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_133">
        <num>133</num>
        <heading>When ordinance shall take effect</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 133. When ordinance shall take effect. Every ordinance and every\namendment to an ordinance hereafter adopted or approved by the town\nboard of a town to which the provisions of this article are applicable,\nshall be entered in its minutes except that it shall not be necessary to\nenter in its minutes any map adopted or approved in connection with a\nzoning ordinance or amendment. The ordinance or amendment, or a summary\nor abstract thereof, shall be published in the official newspaper of the\ntown or, if there is none, in a newspaper designated by the town board\nhaving general circulation in the town, once, and the affidavit of such\npublication shall be filed with the town clerk. Such ordinance or\namendment shall take effect ten days after such publication; but such\nordinance or amendment shall take effect from the date of its service as\nagainst a person served personally with a copy thereof, certified by the\ntown clerk under the corporate seal of the town; and showing the date of\nits passage and entry in the minutes. No ordinance or amendment\npreviously adopted or approved by any town board of a town to which the\nprovisions of this article are applicable shall be void for failure of\nposting and/or filing affidavits of posting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>