<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-136"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-136"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="136"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-136/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-136/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-136/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-136/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_136">
        <num>136</num>
        <heading>Licensing and regulating occupations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 136. Licensing and regulating occupations. The town board may\nprovide by ordinance for the licensing and otherwise regulating of:\n  1. Auctioneers, employment agencies, collateral loan brokers, junk\ndealers and dealers in second hand articles; the running of public\ncarriages, cabs, hacks, carts, drays, express wagons, automobiles or\nother vehicles for the transportation of persons or property over or\nupon the streets of a town for hire, and soliciting either on private\nproperty or on the public highway or running therefor, or for hotels,\nboats, lodging houses or garages; auctioneering, hawking and peddling,\nexcept the peddling of meats, fish, fruit and farm produce by farmers\nand persons who produce such commodities.\n  2. The doing of a retail business in the sale of goods of any\ndescription within the limits of the town from canal boats, in the\ncanals, or from the lands by the side of such canals and within the\nboundary lines thereof, or from boats on a lake or river, except\nproducts of the farm and unmanufactured products of the forest.\n  3. Circuses, theatres, motion picture houses, shows or other\nexhibitions or performances, the keeping of billiard or pool rooms,\nbowling alleys, shooting galleries, skating rinks, amusement parks and\nother similar places of amusement, for money or hire; or the giving of\nexhibitions, performances or entertainments in any place within the\ntown.\n  4. The use of any public hall or opera house; but such place shall not\nbe licensed unless it has suitable and safe means of ingress and egress\nin case of panic or fire.\n  5. The running of restaurants, eating places, lunch counters, soft\ndrink counters or similar places for the sale for consumption upon the\npremises of beverages of any class or description.\n  6. The use of any hall or place other than private homes for dancing\nwhether in connection with some other use of the premises or otherwise,\nwhether or not such dancing is open to the general public.\n  7. In a town of the first or second class, the doing of plumbing,\nheating, ventilating and electrical work; provided, however, that\nemployees of public service corporations shall not require a license\nwhile engaged in the work of such corporations.\n  8. The collection of garbage.\n  9. In any town in a county having a population of more than seven\nhundred fifty thousand, other than a county wholly included in a city,\nthe running, operation or conducting the business of a laundromat,\nlaunderette or other coin operated machine establishment for clothes\nwashing, drying or dry cleaning or any combination of such operations.\n  10. The running of hotels, inns, boarding houses, rooming houses,\nlodging houses and associations or clubs furnishing services ordinarily\nfurnished in hotels, inns, boarding houses, rooming houses and lodging\nhouses.\n  11. The running, operation or conducting business of house trailer\ncamps, tourist camps, or similar establishments.\n  12. In any town in the counties of Cortland, Erie, Monroe and Suffolk,\nor in a county adjoining a city having a population of one million or\nmore, or in any town adjacent to such a county, the operation and use of\nany lands or premises for the excavation of sand, gravel, stone or other\nminerals and the stripping of top soil therefrom.\n  13. The running, operation or conducting the business of riding\nstables, riding academies, or similar establishments.\n  14. The running, operation or conducting the business of raising mink.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>