<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-137"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-137"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="137"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-137/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-137/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-137/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-137/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_137">
        <num>137</num>
        <heading>Issuing of licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 137. Issuing of licenses. If any such trade, occupation or use of\npremises shall be prohibited without a license, the town board shall\nestablish uniform fees for the issuance of such licenses and may require\napplicants for licenses to submit written applications supplying under\naffidavit such information as the town board may require.\n  Upon receipt of the license fee therefor, the town clerk, or the\nbuilding inspector as provided in section one hundred thirty-eight of\nthis chapter, shall issue a license specifying the trade, occupation or\nuse of premises thereby authorized and such license shall become\neffective from the date thereof and shall continue in force for the term\nspecified therein but shall not be transferable. Such a license shall\nnot be issued for a longer term than one year from the date thereof.\nThe town board may by resolution provide for the staggering of licensing\nperiods. Should such action result in a licensing period which is\nshorter than the regular licensing period, the town clerk shall adjust\nthe fee proportionately. A license may be refused if the applicant shall\nhave been convicted of a misdemeanor or felony, which in the judgment of\nthe town clerk or the building inspector renders the applicant unfit or\nundesirable to carry on the trade or occupation involved. The town clerk\nor the building inspector may also refuse a license to any person who in\nhis judgment shall be an undesirable person or incapable of properly\nconducting the trade or business desired. Any applicant who has been\nrefused a license by the town clerk or the building inspector may apply\nto the town board therefor, and the same may be granted or refused by\nthe board, except as prohibited herein. After a public hearing thereon\nat which the licensee shall have an opportunity to be heard, the town\nboard may revoke any license issued under authority of this article to\nany applicant whom the town board shall determine to be an undesirable\nperson or incapable of properly conducting the trade or business\npreviously licensed. The granting, refusal or revocation of such license\nby the town board shall be subject to review by certiorari.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>