<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-138"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-138"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="138"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-138/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-138/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-138/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-138/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_138">
        <num>138</num>
        <heading>Building inspector</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 138. Building inspector. The town board of any town which shall have\nadopted a building code, plumbing code, electrical code, housing code,\nor ordinances, rules and regulations for fire prevention, or for the\nremoval or repair of unsafe buildings or collapsed structures, or for\nany of such purposes, pursuant to the provisions of this article, may\nappoint a town building inspector, and in a town of the first class such\nassistants thereto as the town board may determine necessary, and fix\nthe compensation thereof. Such inspector shall have charge of the\nenforcement of such codes, ordinances, rules and regulations of the town\nand of the zoning ordinance of the town, if there be one, and for such\npurposes such inspector, and his assistants, if any, shall have the\nright to enter and inspect at any time any building, structure or\npremises and to perform any other act necessary for the enforcement of\nsuch codes, ordinances, rules or regulations, or any of them. In any\nsuch town, the town board may appoint a deputy building inspector to\nassist the building inspector in the duties of his office. Such deputy\nbuilding inspector and assistant building inspectors shall perform such\nduties not inconsistent with law as shall be assigned to them,\nrespectively, by the building inspector and in the performance thereof\nshall have the same right to enter and inspect any building and perform\nother necessary acts as hereinbefore conferred upon the building\ninspector.\n  Any license or permit required, under the provisions of the building\ncode, plumbing code, electrical code or housing code shall be issued by\nthe building inspector or deputy building inspector. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of subdivision one of section thirty-seven of this chapter,\nthe town board may direct that fees for licenses and permits issued by\nthe building inspector or deputy shall be payable to and collected by\nsuch inspector.\n  All charges and expenses, including salaries, incurred by the building\ninspector and his deputy and assistants in connection with his duties\nunder this section, less fees, collected if any, shall be a charge upon\nthe taxable property of that part of the town outside of any\nincorporated village and shall be assessed, levied and collected\ntherefrom in the same manner as other town charges levied on property\noutside of villages.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>