<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-142"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-142"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="142"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-142/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-142/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-142/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-142/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142">
        <num>142</num>
        <heading>Charges for use of self-supporting improvements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 142. Charges for use of self-supporting improvements. The town board\nof any town in Suffolk county and of any suburban town, may, by\nordinance, rule, or regulation after a public hearing held on notice\npublished at least once in a newspaper circulating in the town, not less\nthan ten days prior to such hearing, establish or revise charges for the\nuse or enjoyment of any self-supporting improvement. Such town board\nshall establish charges for the use or enjoyment of any such improvement\nfor a daily, hourly or single use of such improvement. In addition to\nsuch daily, hourly or single use charges, the town board of any such\ntown may establish weekly, seasonal or annual charges for the use or\nenjoyment of any self-supporting improvement. Applications for weekly,\nseasonal or annual permits to use such self-supporting improvement shall\nbe made on forms supplied by the officer or employee placed in charge\nthereof by the town board of such town, and the charges therefor shall\nbe paid upon the issuance of such permits. Such charges shall be used\nonly for the purpose of operating, maintaining and improving such\nself-supporting improvement, including reserves and the payment of\nprincipal and interest on any bonds, notes or other obligations issued\nfor the acquisition, construction, lease, purchase, improvement or\nreconstruction of any such self-supporting improvement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>