<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-157"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-157"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="157"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-157/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-157/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-157/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-157/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_157">
        <num>157</num>
        <heading>Absentee leave</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 157. Absentee leave. Every member of such police department shall be\nentitled, in addition to any vacation or absentee leave now prescribed\nby law, to one day of rest in seven. The chief or acting chief of the\npolice department shall keep a time book showing the name and shield\nnumber of each member of the department and the hours worked by each of\nsuch police officers in each day. The town board may make a variation\nfrom the above prescribed hours of vacation, provided the member shall\nreceive during each year the actual number of days absentee leave to\nwhich he or she is entitled. The town board, at its option, may, in\naddition to the days of rest hereinbefore provided, grant an annual\nvacation with pay. Whenever the town board shall designate any police\nofficer to attend police school, such attendance shall be deemed in the\ncourse of duty and when so attending he or she shall receive his or her\nusual pay and reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses. Sick\nleave with full pay may be granted whenever such sickness or disability\nhas been incurred without the delinquency of the police officer.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>