<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-171"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-171"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="171"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-171/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-171/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-171/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-171/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_171">
        <num>171</num>
        <heading>Petition and hearing</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether the petition is signed, and acknowledged or proved, or\nauthenticated as required by law and is otherwise sufficient;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether all the property and property owners within the proposed\ndistrict or extension are benefited thereby;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether all the property and property owners benefited are\nincluded within the limits of the proposed district or extension;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether it is in the public interest to grant in whole or in part\nthe relief sought.\n  If the town board shall determine that the petition is not signed, and\nacknowledged or proved, or authenticated as required by law or that it\nis otherwise insufficient, or if it is determined that it be not in the\npublic interest to grant in whole or in part the relief sought, the town\nboard shall deny the petition.\n  If the town board shall determine that the petition is signed, and\nacknowledged or proved, or authenticated as required by law and is\notherwise sufficient and that it is in the public interest to grant the\nrelief sought, either in whole or in part, but shall find that any part\nor portion of the property or property owners within the proposed\ndistrict or extension are not benefited thereby or that certain property\nor property owners benefited thereby have not been included therein, the\ntown board shall specify the necessary changes of the boundaries of the\nproposed district or extension to be made in order that all of the\nproperty and property owners and only such property and property owners\nas are benefited shall be included within such proposed district or\nextension, and the board shall call a further hearing at a definite\nplace and time not less than fifteen nor more than twenty-five days\nafter such determination. Notice of such further hearing shall be\nposted, published and mailed in the manner provided in this section\nexcept that such notice shall also specify the manner in which it is\nproposed to alter the boundaries of the proposed district or extension.\nSuch further hearing shall be conducted in the same manner as an\noriginal hearing upon a petition. If and when the town board shall\ndetermine in the affirmative all of the questions set forth in this\nsubdivision, the board may adopt a resolution approving the\nestablishment or extension of the district as the boundaries shall be\nfinally determined, but no such resolution so approvin...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>