<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="172-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_172_E">
        <num>172-E</num>
        <heading>Change of name of fire district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 172-e. Change of name of fire district. The name of a fire district\nmay be changed upon a resolution of the board of fire commissioners of\nsuch fire district after a public hearing thereon. Such public hearing\nshall be held prior to the first day of September in any year. The\nnotice of such hearing shall state the proposed new name and shall be\npublished and posted, and such hearing shall be held, in the manner\nprovided in this article for a hearing upon the establishment of a fire\ndistrict upon petition. After such hearing and upon the evidence given\nthereat, the board of fire commissioners shall determine by resolution\nwhether it be in the public interest to change the name of such fire\ndistrict. If it be so determined, the board of fire commissioners, by an\napproving vote of not less than three-fifths of the voting strength of\nthe board, shall adopt a resolution establishing the new name for the\nfire district to take effect on the first day of January of the next\nfiscal year of the fire district. Within ten days after the passage of\nsuch resolution, the fire district secretary shall file a certified copy\nof such resolution (1) in the office of the town clerk of each town in\nwhich such district is situated, (2) in the office of the county clerk\nof each county in which such district is situated, (3) in the office of\nthe clerk of the board of supervisors of each county in which such\ndistrict is situated, and (4) in the office of the state department of\naudit and control at Albany, New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>