<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="172-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_172_C">
        <num>172-C</num>
        <heading>Alteration of boundaries of fire protection district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 172-c. Alteration of boundaries of fire protection district. The\ntown board of a town in which any fire protection district has been\nestablished, or if established in two or more towns, the town boards of\nsuch towns acting jointly by a majority vote of the members of each of\nsuch town boards, upon petition and after a public hearing, or upon the\nmotion of such town board or town boards after a public hearing, may\nalter the boundaries of such fire protection district in accordance with\nsuch petition or motion and exclude from the district territory\npreviously located therein. Such petition, if any, shall be signed by\nresident taxpayers owning taxable real property aggregating at least\none-half of the assessed valuation of all the taxable real property\nowned by resident taxpayers in the territory to be excluded and at least\none-half of the assessed valuation of all the taxable real property\nowned by resident taxpayers in the remaining territory of the district.\nThe assessed valuations in either case shall be the assessed valuations\nof the taxable real property as shown by the latest completed\nassessment-roll of the town. Such petition, if any, shall be signed, and\nacknowledged or proved in the same manner as a deed to be recorded, or\nauthenticated in the manner provided by the election law for the\nauthentication of nominating petitions.  Notice of such hearing shall be\ngiven and such hearing held and the subject matter thereof determined in\nthe manner provided herein for hearings upon the establishment of fire\nprotection districts, except that the notice of hearing shall state in\ngeneral terms the purposes of the hearing and the manner in which it is\nproposed to alter the boundaries of the district. Any resolution\naltering the boundaries of such fire protection district made upon\nmotion of the town board or town boards without a petition shall be\nsubject to a permissive referendum as provided in article seven of this\nchapter. For the purposes of this section, the boundaries of such fire\nprotection district shall be deemed to be altered pursuant to petition\nof resident taxpayers and the territory described in the notice\nexcluded, upon the adoption by the town board or town boards of the\nresolution providing therefor, unless such resolution shall specify some\nother date for such purpose, in which case such boundaries shall be\ndeemed to be altered and such territory excluded on the date so\nspecified, and such alteration of boundaries upon motion of the town\nboard or town boards without a petition shall become effective as\nprovided in section ninety-one of this chapter.  Unless renegotiated,\nany existing contract for the supplying of fire protection to any such\nfire protection district shall be carried out in the same manner as if\nsuch boundaries had not been altered or territory excluded from the\ndistrict.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>