<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="172-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-172-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_172_A">
        <num>172-A</num>
        <heading>Alteration of boundaries of fire districts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_172_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether all the property and property owners within the districts\nare benefited by such change.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether all the property and property owners within the area of\nsuch boundary change are benefited thereby.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_172_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether it is in the public interest to grant the boundary line\nchanges as set forth in the memorandum of proposed change.\n  If and when the boards of fire commissioners shall determine in the\naffirmative all of the questions set forth in this subdivision, the\nboards may adopt a resolution jointly approving the boundary line\nchanges. Such joint resolution and memorandum of proposed change shall\nbe filed with the town clerk of the town or towns in which such\ndistricts are wholly located and with the assessor of such town or\ntowns.\n  4. The proposed change of boundaries shall be deemed to have been\napproved pursuant to this section in the event that no action is taken\nby the town board or town boards, either approving or disapproving,\nwithin thirty days of receipt of the memorandum of proposed change by\nthe town clerk or clerks. If the town board or town boards approve such\nproposed change, such alteration of boundaries shall be deemed effective\nupon the date of such adoption. If the town board of any one of the two\nor more town boards in which the fire district is located disapprove\nsuch proposed change of boundaries, then, within ten days after the\nadoption of such resolution disapproving such change of boundaries the\ntown clerk of the town disapproving such change shall notify the fire\ndistricts involved. Any fire district believing itself aggrieved may\nwithin thirty days of receipt of notification commence an appropriate\nproceeding in the supreme court of the state of New York in accordance\nwith article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, naming\nthe town board or town boards as respondents.\n  5. In the event that the boundaries of a district having indebtedness,\neither bonded or temporary, shall be altered pursuant hereto, such\ndistrict shall continue in law as it existed immediately prior to such\nchange of boundaries for the purpose of paying such indebtedness, and\nthere shall be annually assessed and levied upon and co...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>