<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-175-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-175-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="175-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-175-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-175-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-175-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-175-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_175_C">
        <num>175-C</num>
        <heading>Notice of hearings and elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 175-c. Notice of hearings and elections. 1. In addition to any other\nnotice or posting requirement, every fire district secretary shall cause\na notice of any upcoming hearing or election to be posted on the fire\ndistrict website, if one exists. Such notice shall be posted for at\nleast fifteen days prior to such hearing or election and shall not be\nposted any sooner than twenty days before such hearing or election. If\nthe fire district maintains a sign board, a copy of such notice shall\nalso be posted on the sign board.\n  2. Every fire district secretary shall provide, in a timely manner, a\nnotice of any upcoming hearing or election to be posted on the municipal\nwebsite of any town located within the geographic boundaries of the\ndistrict, or any town or fire district with which the district\ncontracts. Such posting shall only be required if such a website exists.\nSuch notice shall be posted for at least fifteen days prior to such\nhearing or election and shall not be posted any sooner than twenty days\nbefore such hearing or election. In addition, the town clerk shall post\nor cause to be posted on the bulletin board in his or her office a copy\nof such notice and on the sign board maintained by him or her pursuant\nto subdivision six of section thirty of this chapter. The town clerk\nshall cooperate with the fire district to ensure the timely notification\nof the upcoming hearing or election.\n  3. The notice required by this section shall specify the time when and\nthe place where such hearing or election will be held, and, with respect\nto elections, the officers to be elected, their terms of office, and\ndetails regarding other matters to be voted on, as well as the hours\nduring which the polls will be open for the receipt of ballots.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>