<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="176-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_176_B">
        <num>176-B</num>
        <heading>Volunteer members of fire district fire companies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that he or she plans to change his or her residence to\nterritory which is not in the fire district and is not protected by the\nfire department of the district, or any fire company thereof, pursuant\nto a contract for fire protection, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that by reason of his or her\nresidence in the vicinity or his or her usual occupation he or she will\nbe available to render active service as a volunteer firefighter in the\nfire district or in territory outside the fire district which is\nafforded fire protection pursuant to a contract for fire protection by\nthe fire department of the fire district, or a fire company thereof.\nSuch authorization shall be pursuant to the by-laws, if any, of the fire\ncompany of which he or she is a member, otherwise by a three-fourths\nvote of the members of such fire company present and voting at a regular\nor special meeting thereof. Such authorization shall not become\neffective unless approved by resolution of the board of fire\ncommissioners. Such authorization shall be deemed to have been approved\npursuant to this subdivision in the event that no action is taken by the\nboard of fire commissioners, either approving or disapproving, within\nforty days after service of written notice of such authorization shall\nhave been made by the secretary of the fire company upon the secretary\nof the board of fire commissioners, either personally or by mail. Any\nmembership continued pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision\nshall terminate when the member cannot meet either the requirements of\nthis subdivision or the residence requirements of subdivision three of\nthis section. In the case of a fire district which adjoins another\nstate, the term "vicinity", as used in this subdivision, includes\nterritory in this state and territory in the adjoining state.\n  6. A person who cannot meet the residence requirements of subdivision\nthree of this section may be elected to membership as a volunteer member\nof any fire company of the fire department if by reason of his or her\nresidence in the vicinity or his or her usual occupation he or her will\nbe available to render active service as a volunteer firefighter in the\nfire district or in territory which is afforded fire protection...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The membership of any volunteer firefighter shall not be\ncontinued pursuant to subdivision five of this section, and persons\nshall not be elected to membership pursuant to subdivision six of this\nsection, if, by so doing, the percentage of such non-resident members in\nthe fire company would exceed forty-five per centum of the actual\nmembership of the fire company, provided however, that the provisions of\nthis subdivision shall not apply to the memberships of the Shelter\nIsland Heights fire district, the Cherry Grove fire district, the Fire\nIsland Pines fire district, the Davis Park fire department, and the Cold\nSpring Harbor fire district in Suffolk county, the New Hampton fire\ndistrict, the Mechanicstown fire district, the Pocatello fire district,\nthe Washington Heights fire district and the Good Will fire district in\nOrange county, the Jericho fire district, the Westbury fire district and\nthe Roslyn Rescue Hook and Ladder Company, No. 1 in Nassau county, the\nOrangeburg fire district in Rockland county, the South Lockport Fire\nCompany and the Terry's Corners volunteer fire company in Niagara\nCounty, the Taunton fire district and the Onondaga Hill fire department\nin Onondaga county, the Town of Batavia fire department in Genesee\nCounty, the Schuyler Heights fire district, the Boght Community fire\ndistrict and the Slingerlands fire district I in Albany county, the town\nof Providence fire district in Saratoga county, the River Road fire\ndistrict, No. 3 and the Armor Volunteer Fire Company in Erie county, the\nSir William Johnson Fire Company in Fulton county, the Fort Johnson Fire\ndistrict in Montgomery county or the memberships of the Millwood fire\ndistrict, the Purchase Fire District, the North Castle South Fire\nDistrict, No. 1 in Westchester county, the Thornwood fire company, No. 1\nin Westchester county and the Rockland Lake fire district in Rockland\ncounty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon application by a fire district or fire company to the state\nfire administrator, the requirements of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision shall be waived, provided that no adjacent fire district\nobjects within sixty days of notice, published in the state register.\nAny such objection shall be made in writing to the state fire\nadministrator setting forth the reasons such waiver should not be\ngranted. In cases where an objection is properly filed, the state fire\nadministrator shall have the authority to grant a waiver upon\nconsideration of</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the difficulty of the fire company or district in\nretaining and recruiting adequate personnel;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any alternative means\navailable to the fire company or district to address such difficulties;\nand</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the impact of such waiver on adjacent fire districts.\n  8. The board of fire commissioners by resolution may restrict the\nmembership of volunteer members in any or all of the fire companies of\nthe fire department to residents of the fire district. Any volunteer\nmember who then resides in territory outside the fire district shall\ncease to be a member of any fire company to which the restriction is\napplicable unless the resolution provides that his membership shall\ncontinue during the existence of any contract for fire protection to\nsuch territory by his company or during the period in which he may\ncontinue to meet the requirements of subdivision three, five or six.\n  9. Residents of outside territory which is protected pursuant to a\ncontract for fire protection who have been elected to volunteer\nmembership, and non-residents whose volunteer memberships have been\ncontinued or authorized pursuant to subdivision five or six of this\nsection may be elected or appointed to any o...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>who was recognized prior to the first day of July, nineteen\nhundred fifty-four, as a volunteer member of any fire company of the\nfire district by the board of fire commissioners of the fire district or\nby the officers and members of his fire company, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>who rendered active service with such fire company prior to such\ndate, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>who was, at the time of his or her election to membership, a\nresident of the fire district or of territory outside the fire district\nwhich was afforded fire protection by the fire department of the fire\ndistrict, or any fire company thereof, pursuant to a contract for fire\nprotection,\nshall for all purposes in law be considered to have been duly elected\nand appointed to membership in such fire company as of the date of such\nappointment, if any, and, if none, then as of the date of such election;\nnotwithstanding that there may have been some legal defect in such\nelection, or the proceedings precedent thereto, or a failure of the\nboard of fire commissioners to appoint such member, as provided by the\nlaw in force at the time of such election, and the status of such person\nas a volunteer firefighter as of the date of such appointment or\nelection is hereby legalized, validated, and confirmed.  This\nsubdivision shall not apply to a person, if any, whose volunteer\nmembership in...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>who was recognized on and after the first day of July, nineteen\nhundred fifty-four and prior to the first day of January, two thousand\neleven, as a volunteer member of any fire company of the fire district\nby the board of fire commissioners of the fire district or by the\nofficers and members of his fire company, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>who rendered active service with such fire company between such\ndates, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>who was, at the time of his election to membership, a resident of\nthe fire district or of territory outside the fire district which was\nafforded fire protection by the fire department of the fire district, or\nany fire company thereof, pursuant to a contract for fire protection,\nor, who was a nonresident who was elected to membership or who was\ncontinued as a member, pursuant to the provisions of subdivision five or\nsix of this section, shall for all purposes in law be considered to have\nbeen duly elected and approved, or continued, as a member in such fire\ncompany as of the date of such approval, if any, and, if none, then as\nof the date of such election or, in the case of a continuance, as of the\ndate of the approval, if any, by the board of fire commissioners, and,\nif none, as of the date of authorization of continuance by the fire\ncompany; notwithstanding that there may have been some legal defect in\nsuch election, or the proceedings precedent thereto, or a failure of t...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be an unlawful discriminatory practice for any\nvolunteer fire department or fire company, through any member or members\nthereof, officers, board of fire commissioners or other body or office\nhaving power of appointment of volunteer firefighters in any fire\ndepartment or fire company pursuant to this section, because of the\nrace, creed, color, national origin, sex or marital status of any\nindividual, to exclude or to expel from its volunteer membership such\nindividual, or to discriminate against any of its members because of the\nrace, creed, color, national origin, sex or marital status of such\nvolunteer members.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person claiming to be aggrieved by an unlawful discriminatory\npractice pursuant to this section may by himself or his attorney at law\nmake, sign and file with the state division of human rights, a verified\ncomplaint which shall set forth the particulars of the alleged unlawful\ndiscriminatory practice and contain such other information as the\ndivision of human rights may require. The division shall thereupon cause\nto be made an investigation and disposition of the charges pursuant to\nthe provisions of article fifteen of the executive law.\n  16. A person who has been convicted of arson in any degree shall not\nbe eligible to be elected or appointed as a volunteer member of a fire\ncompany. The membership of any volunteer member of a fire company shall\nimmediately terminate if he is convicted of arson in any degree while a\nmember of a fire company.\n  17. Upon application by any person for membership in a fire company\noperating pursuant to this section, the fire chief shall cause the\napplicant's background to be checked pursuant to section eight hundred\nthirty-seven-o of the executive law for a criminal history involving a\nconviction for arson and conviction of a crime which requires the person\nto register as a sex offender under article six-C of the correction law.\nWhere such criminal history information includes conviction of a crime\nwhich requires the person to register as a sex offender under article\nsix-C of the correction law, a fire company shall determine whether or\nnot such person shall be eligible to be elected or appointed as a\nvolunteer member of such fire company. Such determination shall be made\nin accordance with the criteria established in sections seven hundred\nfifty-two and seven hundred fifty-three of the correction law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>