<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="176-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_176_A">
        <num>176-A</num>
        <heading>Duties of chief and assistant chiefs of fire department of fire district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 176-a. Duties of chief and assistant chiefs of fire department of\nfire district. 1. The chief shall, under the direction of the board of\nfire commissioners, have exclusive control of the members of the fire\ndepartment of the fire district at all fires, inspections, reviews and\nother occasions when the fire department is on duty or parade; he shall\nalso have supervision of the engines, fire trucks, pumpers, hose wagons\nand other apparatus and of the equipment and other property used for the\nprevention or extinguishment of fire and of all officers and employees\nof the fire department. He shall see that the rules and regulations of\nthe board of fire commissioners are observed and that the orders of the\nboard of fire commissioners are duly executed. He shall, whenever\nrequired by the board of fire commissioners, report to said board the\ncondition of the property of said fire district and such other\ninformation as may be required of him. He shall hold the members,\nofficers and employees of the fire department strictly to account for\nneglect of duty and may suspend them for improper conduct, subject to\nthe action of the board of fire commissioners at its next meeting. In\ncase of the disability or absence of the chief, the first assistant\nchief, and in the case of the disability or absence of both the chief\nand first assistant chief, the other assistants, in numerical order,\nshall perform the duties and exercise the powers of the chief. When the\nfire department or any company or squad thereof is on duty no member of\nthe board of fire commissioners shall interfere with the duties of the\nchief or assistant chief.\n  2. If an agreement in relation to the issuance of fire permits is\nentered into between the town board and the board of fire commissioners\npursuant to section one hundred thirty-nine and subdivision twenty-four\nof section one hundred seventy-six of this chapter, the duties performed\nfor the fire district by the chief, or an assistant chief, of the fire\ndistrict fire department in relation to the issuance of the fire permit,\nor any preliminary investigation in connection therewith shall, in the\ncase of any such officer who is a volunteer firefighter, be deemed to\nhave been performed by him or her in his or her capacity as such and to\nbe a duty within the meaning of paragraph c of subdivision one of\nsection five of the volunteer firefighters' benefit law and shall, in\nthe case of any such officer who is a paid firefighter, be deemed to\nhave been performed by him or her in his or her capacity as such and to\nbe a duty within the meaning of section two hundred seven-a of the\ngeneral municipal law and other laws applicable in the event of injuries\nto or death of paid firefighters in line of duty. A chief or an\nassistant chief who is a volunteer firefighter shall not receive any\nremuneration for his or her services in relation to the issuance of such\npermits and any investigation in relation thereto, and any such officer\nwho is a paid firefighter shall not receive any additional remuneration\nabove his or her regular salary for any such service. Any such officer\nshall, however, be entitled to his or her actual and necessary travel\nexpenses or mileage in connection with such services as provided in\nsection one hundred seventy-eight-c of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>