<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-07-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="176"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_176">
        <num>176</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of fire district commissioners</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section one hundred seventy-nine\nof this chapter.\n  The foregoing limitations on expenditures shall not be applicable to\nthe proceeds of a contract for fire department services entered into\npursuant to the provisions of subdivision sixteen of this section and\nsuch proceeds may be expended for purposes authorized by or pursuant to\nlaw.\n  The foregoing limitations on expenditures shall not be applicable to\nappropriations to or expenditures from a repair reserve fund,\ncontingency and tax stabilization reserve fund, capital reserve fund,\ndebt stabilization fund, workers' compensation reserve fund, mandatory\nreserve fund, unemployment insurance reserve fund or liability and\ncasualty reserve fund established pursuant to sections six-d, six-e,\nsix-g, six-h, six-j, six-l, six-m and six-n of the general municipal\nlaw, or to the use of the income and capital gains realized on the\ninvestments of the assets of such funds.\n  The foregoing limitations on expenditures shall not be applicable to\nthe use of premiums from the sale of fire district obligations, the\nunexpended portion of the proceeds of fire district obligations, the\nincome and capital gains realized on the temporary investment of the\nproceeds, inclusive of premiums, of fire district obligations, as\nprovided in section 165.00 of the local finance law.\n  The foregoing limitations on expenditures shall not be applicable to\nthe use of the proceeds of a gift or gifts given to a fire district, and\nsuch proceeds may be expended for purposes authorized by or pursuant to\nlaw.\n  The provisions of this subdivision shall not be deemed to prevent the\nissuance of bonds, bond anticipation notes, capital notes or budget\nnotes to finance any object or purpose for which the fire district may\nexpend money.\n  The foregoing limitation on expenditures shall not be applicable to\nthe use of insurance proceeds received for the loss, theft, damage or\ndestruction of real or personal property...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section four hundred four of\nthe not-for-profit corporation law.\n  21. Shall have and exercise all the powers conferred upon the fire\ndistrict and such additional powers as shall be necessarily implied\ntherefrom.\n  22.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>May contract for the furnishing of fire protection within the\nfire district with any city, village, fire district, or incorporated\nfire company having its headquarters outside such fire district and\nmaintaining adequate and suitable apparatus and appliances for the\nfurnishing of fire protection in such district; provided there is no\nfire company maintaining its headquarters in said district or provided\nthe fire department of said district is, in the judgment of such fire\ncommissioners, unable to render adequate and prompt fire protection to\nsuch district or any area thereof. The contract also may provide for the\nfurnishing of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>emergency service in case of accidents, calamities or\nother emergencies in connection with which the services of firefighters\nwould be required and (ii) general ambulance service subject, however,\nto the provisions of section two hundred nine-b of the general municipal\nlaw. In the event that the fire department or fire company furnishing\nfire protection within the district pursuant to contract does not\nmaintain and operate an ambulance and provision has not otherwise been\nmade for ambulance service for the area of the district pursuant to\nsection one hundred twenty two-b of the general municipal law then a\nseparate contract may be made for the furnishing within the district of\nemergency ambulance service or general ambulance service, or both, with\nany city, village or fire district the fire department of which, or with\nan incorporated fire company having its headquarters outside the\ndistrict which, maintains and operates an ambulance subject, however, in\nthe case of general ambulance service, to the provisions of section two\nhundred nine-b of the general municipal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph,\nprior to commencing the negotiation process for such contract with an\nincorporated fire company, the incorporated fire company shall file with\nthe board of fire commissioners a statement itemizing the estimated\ncosts of the incorporated fire company attributable to the provision of\nservices under the prospective contract. The estimated costs\nattributable to the provision of services under the prospective contract\nitemized in the statement shall include, at a minimum, those, if any,\nfor: supplies; materials; operation, maintenance and repair of equipment\nand apparatus; insurance; training; protective clothing, gear and other\npersonnel costs; building rental, maintenance and operation; and a\nspecified proportionate share of capital costs. If the fire company is\nrequired to prepare any of the following documents, copies shall be\nincluded with the statement:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the fire company's most recent annual report of directors pursuant\nto section five hundred nineteen of the not-for-profit corporation law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the fire company's most recent verified certificate pursuant to\nsubdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen hundred two of the not-for-profit\ncorporation law;\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176__subsec_f__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the fire company's most recent internal revenue service form 990;\nand\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_176__subsec_f__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the fire company's most recent annual report pursuant to section\nthirty-a of the general municipal law.\n  (ii) The provisions of subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall not\napply to the renewal of a contract when the contract is deemed renewed\nin accordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. Upon good cause\nshown, the board of fire commissioners may, by resolution, waive in\nwhole or in part the requirement that the fire company file the\nstatement, and copies of documents, required by subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nparagraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The contract shall not be entered into until a public hearing has\nbeen held by the board of fire commissioners. Notice of the hearing\nshall be published at least once in at least one newspaper having\ngeneral circulation in the district. The notice shall specify the time\nwhen and place where the hearing will be held, and describe in general\nterms the proposed contract. The first publication thereof shall be at\nleast ten days prior to the day specified for the hearing.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as hereinafter provided, the term of the contract shall be\nfor a definite period of time, but in no event shall the term exceed\nfive years. The contract year or years in all such contracts entered\ninto after the year nineteen hundred sixty shall terminate on December\nthirty-first.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Instead of being for a definite term as hereinabove provided, the\ncontract may be for an original term of one calendar year or less and\nprovide that it shall be deemed renewed on the same basis each year\nthereafter for a further term of one full calendar year without any\nfurther public hearing unless one of the contracting parties shall\nnotify the other in writing on or before the first day of August that it\nelects to terminate the contract on December thirty-first in that year.\nThe term of any such contract, including renewals, shall not exceed five\nyears, but the contract may provide that there shall be less than four\nsuch renewals. If the city, village or fire district fire department or\nfire company which is to furnish the service under such a contract is\nnot a fully paid department or company, the city, village or fire\ndistrict governing board upon the request of the department or company,\nshall terminate the contract as provided in this paragraph. Any contract\nentered into pursuant to this paragraph may provide that in the month of\nJuly of each year in which such a renewal could occur the fire district\nsecretary shall notify the secretary of the fire department or fire\ncompany which is to furnish the service under the contract that the\ncontract shall be deemed renewed on the same basis for a further full\nterm of one calendar year unless one of the contracting parties shall\nnotify the other in writing on or before the first day of August that it\nelects to terminate the contract on December thirty-first in such year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The contract shall specify a definite sum to be paid each year for\nall of the services to be rendered thereunder and may provide that such\namount shall be paid in one sum or in installments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By mutual consent of the contracting parties, and after a public\nhearing held pursuant to notice in the manner aforesaid, any such\ncontract heretofore or hereafter executed may be</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>amended, (ii)\nterminated, or (iii) terminated and a new contract may be entered into\nin lieu thereof, if the board of fire commissioners, after such hearing,\nshall determine by resolution, that it is in the public interest so to\ndo. Such notice shall state in general terms the reason why any existing\ncontract is to be amended or terminated, and if a new contract is to be\nentered into the notice shall also describe the new contract in general\nterms.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "fire protection", as used in this subdivision, includes\ninspections of buildings and properties in the fire district for the\npurposes specified in and as authorized by section eight hundred seven-a\nof the education law, subdivision four of section three hundred three of\nthe multiple residence law, and section one hundred eighty-nine of the\ntown law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_176__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this subdivision shall not be deemed to have\namended subdivision two of section two hundred nine-b or section two\nhundred nine-d of the general municipal law, or any other general,\nspecial or local law requiring the consent of a fire department, fire\ncompany or an emergency rescue and first aid squad to the entering into\nof a contract for services to be performed by such department, company\nor squad.\n  23. May sell or otherwise dispose of real and personal property of the\ndistrict no longer necessary for any of its uses or purposes if, when\nand in the manner and to the extent authorized so to do in a proposition\nwhich is duly submitted and adopted or approved at a special or annual\nfire district election in the manner provided by section one hundred\nseventy-nine of this article for voting upon appropriations, except that\nif a proposition shall be submitted pursuant to the provisions of said\nsection for the purchase of apparatus or if a proposition shall be\nsubmitted pursuant to the local finance law for the approval of a bond\nresolution or a capital note resolution for obligations to be issued for\nthe purchase of apparatus, such proposition may specify that apparatus\nor equipment owned by the district or the proceeds of the sale thereof\nis to be used in part payment for new apparatus and the adoption of such\nproposition shall authorize the sale or such other disposition of such\napparatus or equipment, or if apparatus or equipment is to be purchased\nwithout the submission of a proposition as aforesaid apparatus or\nequipment owned by the district may be used as part payment for new\napparatus or equipment without the adoption of a proposition therefor,\nand except also that the board of fire commissioners may at any time\nsell or otherwise dispose of real and personal property of the district\nno longer necessary for any of its uses or purposes if valued at less\nthan one hundred thousand dollars but not below twenty thousand d...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>