<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="178-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_178_A">
        <num>178-A</num>
        <heading>Expenses incurred in attending town and county officers training school</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 178-a. Expenses incurred in attending town and county officers\ntraining school. The actual and necessary expenses incurred by a fire\ndistrict officer or person duly elected as a fire district officer, in\nattending a course of training for his respective office as provided by\nthe town and county officers training school of the state of New York\nfor the purpose of improving the administration of municipal affairs in\nthe town and counties of the state, shall be a charge against the fire\ndistrict of which he is an officer or officer-elect. No person, however,\nshall be allowed such expenses for attending a regional school unless\nhis district shall be included within the area of such region as\nestablished by the board of trustees of the town and county officers\ntraining school of the state of New York. The board of fire\ncommissioners, in lieu of auditing and allowing the claim of a fire\ndistrict officer or officer-elect for actual and necessary expenses for\ntravel in attending any such course of training, may determine by\nresolution to allow and pay such officer or officer-elect a reasonable\nmileage allowance for the use of his own automobile for each mile\nactually and necessarily traveled by him in attending such course of\ntraining.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>