<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="178-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-178-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_178_B">
        <num>178-B</num>
        <heading>Expenses of the association of fire districts of the state of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 178-b. Expenses of the association of fire districts of the state of\nNew York. The board of fire commissioners of any fire district may\ndetermine to expend and raise by taxation annually such sums as may be\nrequired toward defraying the actual and necessary expenses of\nmaintaining and continuing the association of fire districts of the\nstate of New York, and any of its activities in this state for the\npurpose of devising practical ways and means of obtaining greater\neconomy and efficiency in the administration of fire district affairs.\n  The board of fire commissioners of any fire district may determine to\nexpend and raise by taxation annually such sums as may be required to\ndefray the proportionate share of such fire district to meet the actual\nand necessary expenses of maintaining and continuing (1) the county\nassociation of fire districts or the county association of fire district\nofficers of the fire districts in a county in which all or part of such\nfire district is located and (2) a regional association of fire\ndistricts or a regional association of fire district officers of the\nfire districts located in an area of adjoining counties, and to maintain\nand continue any of the activities of any such association, for the\npurposes of obtaining greater economy and efficiency in the\nadministration of fire district affairs.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>