<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-183"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-183"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="183"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-183/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-183/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-183/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-183/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_183">
        <num>183</num>
        <heading>Fire alarm districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 183. Fire alarm districts. Whenever the town board shall have\nestablished a fire alarm district pursuant to the provisions of this\narticle, the town board shall prepare, or cause to be prepared, plans,\nspecifications, estimates and a proposed contract for the installation,\nextension and maintenance of a fire alarm system in such district. Upon\nthe completion of the plans, specifications, estimates and proposed\ncontract therefor, the town clerk shall give notice of a public hearing\nthereon in the same manner as provided in this article for notice of\nhearing upon the creation of such district. At such hearing, the town\nboard shall hear such persons as may be interested in the subject matter\nthereof and may make such modification and changes in the plans,\nspecifications, estimates and proposed contract as the town board shall\ndeem expedient, and thereupon the town board may adopt or reject same.\nSo far as consistent with the provisions of this section, the town board\nshall award contracts for the performance of the work and the supplying\nof materials or may cause the same to be done by day labor under the\ndirection of the town engineer or any other town officer, in the same\nmanner as provided by section one hundred ninety-seven of this chapter\nfor the making of special improvements, and may enter into contracts\nwith persons or corporations for the use of their property in connection\nwith such fire alarm system.\n  After a public hearing as hereinafter specified, the town board, in\naddition, shall provide for the furnishing of fire protection within\nsuch fire alarm district and for that purpose may contract for a period\nnot exceeding five years with any city, incorporated village, fire\ndistrict or incorporated fire company maintaining adequate and suitable\napparatus and appliances for the furnishing of fire protection in such\ndistrict. Notice of such hearing shall be published in at least one\nnewspaper having general circulation in the district. Such notice shall\nspecify the time when and place where said hearing will be held, and\ndescribe in general terms the proposed contract. The first publication\nthereof shall be at least ten days prior to the day specified for such\nhearing. The expense incurred by reason of the establishment of such\nfire alarm district, the maintenance of said fire alarm system and the\ncontract for fire protection, shall be assessed and levied upon the\ntaxable property in said district and collected in the same manner, at\nthe same time and by the same officers as town taxes are assessed,\nlevied and collected and, when collected, the amount thereof shall be\npaid to the supervisor of the town. The supervisor shall pay to the\ncity, incorporated village, fire district or incorporated fire company\nfurnishing such fire protection, the expense thereof pursuant to said\ncontract. The expense of the installation or extension of such fire\nalarm system may be raised, in whole or in part, in the same manner as\nthe expense of maintenance or may be financed, in whole or in part,\npursuant to the local finance law.\n  If a fire alarm district shall be situated partly in each of two or\nmore towns any action which would be taken by the town board in the case\nof a district situated in only one town shall be taken by the town\nboards of the several towns acting jointly by a majority vote of the\nmembers of each of such town boards, and the notices of public hearing\nrequired by this section shall be given by the town clerks of the\nseveral towns acting jointly.\n  By mutual consent of the contracting parties, and after a public\nhearing held pursuant to notice in the manner provided in this section\nin relation to fire protection contracts, any such contract heretofore\nor hereafter executed may be (1) amended, (2) terminated, or (3)\nterminated and a new contract may be entered into in lieu thereof, if\nthe town board, after such hearing, shall determine, by resolution, that\nit is in the public interest so to do. Such notice shall state in\ngeneral terms the reason why any existing contract is to be amended or\nterminated, and if a new contract is to be entered into the notice shall\nalso describe the new contract in general terms.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>