<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="189-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_189_E">
        <num>189-E</num>
        <heading>Management of affairs of joint fire districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 189-e. Management of affairs of joint fire districts. Subject to the\nrestrictions hereinafter established, the property and affairs of joint\nfire districts shall be under the management and control and in charge\nof a board of not less than three and not more than seven commissioners,\nappointed by the town board of the town or the town boards of the towns\nand the board of trustees of the village or the boards of trustees of\nthe villages in joint session as hereinafter provided, or elected as\nprovided in article eleven of this chapter, as may be determined by\nresolution adopted at the meeting for the establishment of the district\nin the same manner as the resolution for the establishment of the\ndistrict is adopted; or as may be determined by a joint consolidation\nagreement or elector initiated consolidation plan in accordance with\narticle seventeen-A of the general municipal law. In case it is\ndetermined that the commissioners shall be selected in the manner\nprovided by article eleven of this chapter, the appointments as provided\nfor in subdivision one of section one hundred seventy-four of this\nchapter shall be made by the town board, or, if the district includes\nterritory in more than one town, by the town board of all of the towns\nat a joint session held at one location within the district and\nthereafter elections shall be held as provided in article eleven of this\nchapter except that the terms of the commissioners shall be as\nhereinafter provided. They shall be residents of such district and in\ncase selection is made as provided in article eleven of this chapter\nthere shall be no other residential requirement, but otherwise if there\nare an even number of commissioners not more than half at any time shall\nbe residents of such village or villages and if there are an odd number,\nthe number that are residents of such village or villages shall not\nexceed the number that are residents of such town or towns by more than\none. First appointments hereunder shall be made in the following manner:\nIf there be three commissioners, the term of one shall expire one year,\nof another two years and of the other three years from the then next\nensuing thirty-first day of December, and thereafter one shall be\nappointed annually for a term of three years from the date of the\nexpiration of the term of his predecessor. If there be four\ncommissioners, the term of one shall expire one year, of another two\nyears, of another three years, and of the other four years from the then\nnext ensuing thirty-first day of December, and thereafter one shall be\nappointed annually for a term of four years from the date of the\nexpiration of the term of his predecessor. If there be five\ncommissioners, the term of one shall expire one year, of another two\nyears, of another three years, of another four years, and of the other\nfive years from the then next ensuing thirty-first day of December, and\nthereafter one shall be appointed annually for a term of five years from\nthe date of the expiration of a term of his predecessor. If there be six\ncommissioners, the term of one shall expire one year, of another two\nyears, of another three years, of another four years, and of the\nremaining two, five years from the then next ensuing thirty-first day of\nDecember, and thereafter appointments shall be made for a term of five\nyears from the date of the expiration of the term of each commissioner.\nIf there be seven commissioners, the term of one shall expire one year,\nof another two years, of another three years, and of two of the others\nfour years, and of the remaining two, five years from the then next\nensuing thirty-first day of December, and thereafter appointments shall\nbe made for a term of five years from the date of the expiration of the\nterm of each commissioner. Such board of commissioners may employ\nnecessary labor and assistants, at a compensation approved by such\nboards in joint session. Such commissioners shall receive no\ncompensation for their services, but they and their employees shall be\nallowed and paid their necessary expenses, payable as expenses of the\ndistrict.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>