<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="189-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-189-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_189_F">
        <num>189-F</num>
        <heading>Powers of board of commissioners</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 189-f. Powers of board of commissioners. The board of commissioners\nshall have and exercise, with respect to such district, the applicable\npowers and duties of a board of fire district commissioners as\nprescribed by the town law, with respect to similar functions of a fire\ndistrict in a town and all of the provisions of article eleven of this\nchapter shall be applicable to a joint fire district created pursuant to\nthis article. Such powers and duties of the board of district\ncommissioners are subject to the following restriction:\n  No real property or easement therein shall be acquired by the board of\ncommissioners without the approval of the village board or boards and\nthe town board or boards of each village or town in which any portion of\nthe district is situated. But this restriction shall not apply if, at\nthe meeting for the establishment of any such district hereafter\nestablished, a resolution to that effect is adopted in the same manner\nas the resolution for the establishment of the district is adopted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>