<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-192"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-192"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="192"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-192/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-192/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-192/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-192/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_192">
        <num>192</num>
        <heading>Maps and plans for sewer, wastewater disposal, drainage and water districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 192. Maps and plans for sewer, wastewater disposal, drainage and\nwater districts. Every petition for the establishment or extension of a\nsewer, wastewater disposal, drainage or water district shall be\naccompanied by a map and plan prepared by a competent engineer, duly\nlicensed by the state of New York, showing the boundaries of the\nproposed district and a general plan of the proposed sewer, wastewater\ndisposal, drainage or water system, as the case may be. If a sewer or\ndrainage district is proposed, such map shall show all outlets and the\nterminus and course of each proposed main sewer or drain together with\nthe location and a general description of all sewage disposal plants,\npumping stations and other public works, if any, and shall be consistent\nwith, so far as possible, any comprehensive plan for sewers developed\nand maintained pursuant to section ninety-nine-f of the general\nmunicipal law. If a water district is proposed, said map and plan shall\nshow the source of water supply and a description of the lands, streams,\nwater or water rights to be acquired therefor, the mode of constructing\nthe proposed water works and the location thereof, including reservoirs,\nwater purification or treatment works, water mains, distributing pipes\nand hydrants, and shall be consistent with, so far as possible, any\ncomprehensive plan for public water supply systems developed and\nmaintained pursuant to section ninety-nine-f of the general municipal\nlaw. If, however, the petition shall specify that the supply of water to\nbe used in said water district shall be purchased from a municipal or\nother corporation, or any person, then said map and plan shall set forth\nand show only the water mains, distributing pipes, hydrants, reservoirs,\nif any, and location of each.  Before any sewer system is constructed in\nany such district, the town board shall cause a copy of the map and plan\nof the proposed sewer system and sewage disposal plant or proposed\nextension thereto to be submitted to the state department of health,\nand, if approved, it shall be filed in the office of the state\ndepartment of health and the town clerk. The state department of health\nmay require profiles to be submitted for any sewers or drains shown on\nsuch map and plan. Such map and plan may be amended with the approval of\nthe state department of health, and if approved, it shall be filed in\nthe office of the state department of health and the town clerk.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>