<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-196"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-196"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="196"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-196/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-196/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-196/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-196/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_196">
        <num>196</num>
        <heading>Modification of plans for sewer, wastewater disposal, drainage, water or water quality treatment districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 196. Modification of plans for sewer, wastewater disposal, drainage,\nwater or water quality treatment districts. 1. When the town board shall\nhave established a sewer, wastewater disposal, drainage, water or water\nquality treatment district and adopted a plan of sewerage, wastewater\ndisposal, drainage, water or water quality treatment system for such\ndistrict, such plan shall not be modified by the board, nor by any\nofficer of the town, except after public notice given by publication in\nthe official paper of intention to modify the same, which notice shall\nspecify the particulars in which it is proposed to modify it, and a time\nand place when the board will consider any objections which may be made\nthereto, which time shall not be less than ten nor more than twenty days\nafter the first publication of said notice. When any change shall be\nmade in the plan proposed and once adopted, a revised or additional map\nand profile shall be made showing the change, and all such maps and\nprofiles shall be carefully preserved in the office of the town clerk\nand open to inspection by all persons interested.\n  2. In the case of water quality treatment districts, amendments or\nmodifications of plans must have the written approval of the department\nof health prior to adoption. At the request of an owner of a parcel of\nproperty within the town, if the private well water on such property is\ncontaminated, a water quality treatment district plan may be amended,\nfrom time to time, to include said parcel of property. If an owner of a\nparcel of property within the town requests exclusion from the district,\nsuch request shall be granted without the state department of health\napproval. The removal of a parcel of property from a district shall in\nno way affect the owner's liability for charges which have accrued\nagainst the owner's property, prior to said exclusion, for the\nprocurement, installation, modification, replacement and removal of a\nwater quality treatment unit or device or for expenses of operation and\nmaintenance including monitoring, testing, regenerating and treating.\nShould a public or private water system, supplier or authority commence\nsupplying water to any parcel of property within a water quality\ntreatment district, such parcel of property shall no longer be\nconsidered part of the water quality treatment district, and all\nservices to such parcels shall be terminated. Termination of services\nshall include, the removal of all water quality treatment units or\ndevices and a charge for the cost of doing so to the benefited property,\nexcept when such unit or device was acquired and owned by the property\nowner or when the district determines that such unit or device is\nobsolete and no longer useful for any district purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>