<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-198-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-198-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="198-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-198-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-198-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-198-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-198-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_198_A">
        <num>198-A</num>
        <heading>Special districts for disposal of duck waste in Suffolk county</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>employ a sufficient\nnumber of persons and provide the necessary equipment to operate and\nmaintain said collection system or said treatment and disposal plant, or\nboth, at the expense of said district, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_198_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish from time to\ntime, charges, fees or rates to be paid by users for such operation and\nmaintenance and may provide for the payment of said charges in advance.\nSuch charges, fees or rates may be based upon the volume of duck waste\ntreated, or upon any other equitable basis as the town board may\ndetermine. Such charges shall be a lien upon the real property for which\nor in connection with which the services are rendered. The town board\nmay provide by ordinance, rule or regulation for the time within which\nrates, charges or fees for such operation and maintenance shall be paid,\nand may provide a penalty not exceeding ten per centum of the amount\ndue, when such rates, charges or fees are in arrears for thirty days, or\nlonger. The town clerk shall annually file with the town board\nstatements showing unpaid rates, charges or fees in such districts.\nSuch statements shall contain a brief description of the property for\nwhich or in connection with which such operation and maintenance was\nprovided, the names of the persons or corporations liable to pay the\nsame and the amount chargeable to each. The supervisor shall transmit\nsuch statements to the board of supervisors, which shall levy such sums\nagainst the property liable and shall state the amount of the tax in a\nseparate column in the annual tax rolls of such town under the name of\n"duck waste charges".  Such tax shall be paid to the supervisor of such\ntown. All the provisions of the existing laws of the state of New York\ncovering the enforcement and collection of unpaid town taxes or\nassessments for special improvements in the several towns of the county\nof Suffolk, not inconsistent herewith, shall apply to the collection of\nsuch unpaid charges for the treatment and disposition of duck waste. All\nsuch rates, charges and fees shall be used for the payment of the cost\nof the management, maintenance and operation of the duck waste\ncollection, treatment and disposition service, or for the e...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>