<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="201"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_201">
        <num>201</num>
        <heading>Sewer and water connections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 201. Sewer and water connections. Whenever the town board shall have\nestablished one or more sewer or water districts, or both, the town\nboard shall adopt a resolution or ordinance prescribing how sewer or\nwater connections shall be made therein. After the board shall have\nadopted such resolution or ordinance prescribing how sewer and water\nconnections shall be made, the board may adopt orders, from time to\ntime, directing the owners of the respective lots and parcels of land in\nfront of which it is desired that a sewer or water connection be made,\nto make the same to conform to such resolution or ordinance and\nspecifying the time within which the same must be done. Before any\nhighway in which sewer or water mains have been laid, shall be paved or\notherwise improved, the town board may, in its discretion, direct the\nowners of adjoining lots or parcels of land to make connections with\nsuch sewers or water mains, at the curb line or at the sewer or water\nmain if extensions to the curb line have not been provided, under the\nsupervision of the town board, and in the manner required by the\nresolution or ordinance, at such a distance apart as the board may\nprescribe. The town clerk shall publish a notice thereof in the official\npaper at least twice, the first publication of which shall be at least\nfifteen days before the time specified for the completion of the work.\nIf, within the time prescribed in the order and notice, the connections\nrequired to be made shall not have been so made, then the board may\ncause the same to be done and audit and pay the expense of doing the\nsame and assess the expense thereof against the property benefited.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>