<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-12-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="202-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_202_C">
        <num>202-C</num>
        <heading>Dissolution and diminishing area of certain districts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions one and two of\nthis section, as well as any other provision of general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation to the contrary, whenever the town board\nof the town of Westerlo, county of Albany, shall determine it to be in\nthe public interest, such town board may, upon its own motion and\nwithout a petition, but after a public hearing held in the manner and\nupon the notice specified in subdivision one of this section, diminish\nthe Westerlo Water District No. 1 by deleting therefrom the lands\ndescribed in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, provided that said\nproperties have not received any benefit from the water district since\nits inception.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The lands authorized to be deleted from the Westerlo Water\nDistrict No. 1 are described as follows:\n                               AREA NO. 1\n  Beginning at a point in the northerly boundary line of New York State\nRoute 143, said point being the southwesterly corner of tax map parcel\n139.09-2-22; thence in a southerly direction across New York State Route\n143, 55 feet, more or less, to a point in the southerly boundary line of\nNew York State Route 143, said point also being the northeasterly corner\nof tax map parcel 139.09-3-22; thence in a southerly direction along the\neasterly boundary line of said parcel 139.09-3-22, 148 feet, more or\nless, to a point, said point being the southeasterly corner of said\nparcel 139.09-3-22; thence in a westerly direction along the southerly\nboundary line of said parcel 139.09-3-22, 86.05 feet, more or less, to a\npoint, said point being the southwesterly corner of said parcel\n139.09-3-23, said point also being in the easterly boundary line of tax\nmap parcel 139.09-3-21; thence in a southerly direction along the\neasterly boundary line of said parcel 139.09-3-21, 189.72 feet, more or\nless, to a point, said point being the southeast corner of said parcel\n139.09-3-21; thence in a westerly direction along the southerly boundary\nline of said parcel 139.09-3-21, 99.08 feet, more or less, to a point,\nsaid point being the southwest corner of said parcel 139.09-3-21, said\npoint also being in the easterly boundary line of tax map parcel\n139.09-3-20; thence in a southerly direction along the easterly boundary\nof tax map parcel 139.09-3-20, 120 feet, more or less, to a point, said\npoint being the southeast corner of said parcel 139.09-3-20; thence in a\nwesterly direction along the southerly boundary line of said parcel\n139.09-3-20, 100 feet, more or less, to a point, said point being the\nsouthwest corner of said parcel 139.09-3-20; said point also being in\nthe easterly boundary line of tax map parcel 139.00-1-30; thenc...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of general, special or\nlocal law, rule, or regulation to the contrary, whenever the town board\nof the town of Chester, Warren county shall determine it to be in the\npublic interest, said town board may, upon its own motion and without a\npetition, but after a public hearing held in the manner and upon the\nnotice specified in subdivision one of this section, diminish the\nPottersville water district by deleting therefrom the lands described in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision located in the hamlet of Pottersville\nand presently included in said district. In addition, any order adopted\nby the town board pursuant to this subdivision shall be subject to a\npermissive referendum pursuant to article seven of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The lands authorized to be deleted from the Pottersville water\ndistrict is described as follows:\n  All that parcel of land located in and near the Hamlet of Pottersville\nin the Town of Chester, Warren County, New York being part of lands\nshown on "Map Proposed Water District Pottersville" dated April 15, 1946\nby E. D. Collamer, C. E. and surveyed by G. J. Weaver in October 1945,\nsaid map being duly filed in the Office of the Clerk for the Town of\nChester, said parcel being more particularly bounded and described as\nfollows:\n  Beginning at the point of intersection of the centerline of the New\nYork State Highway leading northerly from Loon Lake to Pottersville and\nmore commonly known as Route #9 with the southerly line of the former\nLighting District #2 in the Town of Chester, New York, which said point\nof beginning lies in the southerly line of the said Water District and\nrunning\n  Thence along the southerly line of said District and accordance to the\ntrue meridian North 75Á East, 500 feet to the southeasterly corner of\nsaid District;\n  Thence along said easterly line of same North 04Á 50' West,\napproximately 600 feet to a point in the southerly boundary of lands\nreputedly of Russell and Duell known as Lot No. 1 on a plat entitled\n"Dalaba Subdivision" originally dated April 22, 1991 by James P. Hughes,\nP.L.S. and filed in the Warren County Clerk's Office on August 29, 1991,\n  Thence according to the magnetic meridian South 65Á 30' 50" West,\nalong said southerly boundary approximately 270 feet to a tall iron pipe\nin the westerly boundary of said lot No. 1;\n  Thence North 28Á 47' 40" West, along said westerly boundary, 414.54\nfeet to an iron pipe found in the easterly boundary of said Route 9;\n  Thence Northeasterly, along said easterly boundary, the following four\ncourses:\n  1.) North 28Á 10' 30" East, 404.95 feet to a point;\n  2.) North 37Á 56' 20" East, 516.24 feet to an iron rod set;\n  3.) North 23Á 48' 50" East, 91.91 feet to an ir...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of general, special or\nlocal law, rule, or regulation to the contrary, whenever the town board\nof the town of Byron, Genesee county shall determine it to be in the\npublic interest, said town board may, upon its own motion and without a\npetition, but after a public hearing held in the manner and upon the\nnotice specified in subdivision one of this section, diminish the Byron\nsewer district by deleting therefrom the lands described in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision located in the town of Byron and presently\nincluded in said district. In addition, any order adopted by the town\nboard pursuant to this subdivision shall be subject to a permissive\nreferendum pursuant to article seven of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The lands authorized to be deleted from the Byron sewer district\nis described as follows:\n  ALL THAT TRACT OR PARCEL OF LAND, situate in the Town of Byron, County\nof Genesee and State of New York, known and distinguished as the south\nwest corner of lot number six in township number one of the 100,000 Acre\nor Connecticut Tract, so called, bounded as follows, viz: Beginning at a\npoint in the west line of said Lot number six distant three chains\neighty-nine links north of the southwest corner thereof, thence north on\nsaid west line one chain and fifty links, thence east three chains\nthirty-seven and one-half links, thence south parallel with the west\nline one chain and fifty links, thence west parallel with the north line\nthree chains thirty-seven and one half links to the place of beginning,\ncontaining land more or less.\n  ALSO ALL THAT TRACT OR PARCEL OF LAND, situate in the Town of Byron,\nCounty of Genesee, and State of New York, distinguished as part of lot\nnumber 6, township number 1, of the 100,000 Acre or Connecticut Tract,\nso called, bounded and described as follows: Commencing at the\nsouth-east corner of land conveyed by Levi W. Fisk and Nellie, his wife,\nto Ernest H. Schaufelberger by deed dated August 19th, 1902 in Liber 197\nof Deeds, at page 90; thence northerly bounding thereon one chain fifty\nlinks to the north-east corner of said lands; thence easterly in a\ndirect line with the north bounds thereof, prolonged fifty-feet; thence\nsoutherly parallel with the first mentioned boundary one chain fifty\nlinks; thence westerly in a direct line fifty feet to the south-east\ncorner of the lands first mentioned and to the place of beginning,\ncontaining land more or less.\n  8.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of general, special or\nlocal law, rule, or regulation to the contrary, whenever the town board\nof the of town of Rockland, Sullivan county shall determine it to be in\nthe public interest, said town board may, upon its own motion and\nwithout a petition, but after a public hearing held in the manner and\nupon the notice specified in subdivision one of this section, diminish\nthe Roscoe sewer district by deleting therefrom the lands described in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision located in the town of Rockland and\npresently included in said district. In addition, any order adopted by\nthe town board pursuant to this subdivision shall be subject to a\npermissive referendum pursuant to article seven of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The lands authorized to be deleted from the Roscoe sewer district\nare described as follows:\n  ALL that certain plot, piece or parcel of land, with the buildings and\nimprovements thereon erected, situate, lying and being in the Town of\nRockland, County of Sullivan and State of New York and described as\nfollows: Beginning at a point in the center of the highway leading from\nRoscoe to Rockland and in the line dividing lots 21 and 22 and running\nthence south 62 degrees 45' east 330' passing through crotch of an apple\ntree standing on the east side of said highway to an iron at end of old\nfence line; thence along fence line South 22 degrees west 65 feet to an\niron; thence north 62 3/4 degrees west 329 feet to a point in the center\nof highway; thence north 17 1/2 degrees east 65' to place of beginning,\ncontaining nearly one-half acre of ground more or less.\n  9. Notwithstanding any other provision of general, special or local\nlaw, rule, or regulation to the contrary, whenever the town board of the\ntown of Hyde Park, Dutchess county, shall determine it to be in the\npublic interest, said town board may, upon its own motion and without a\npetition, but after a public hearing held in the manner and upon the\nnotice specified in subdivision one of this section, diminish the\nGreenfields Water District by deleting therefrom the one hundred\nnineteen townhouse lots which have not since the formation of the\ndistrict been provided with any water infrastructure or service and\npresently are included in said district. In addition, any order adopted\nby the town board pursuant to this subdivision shall be subject to a\npermissive referendum of the property owners in the Greenfields Water\nDistrict pursuant to article seven of this chapter.\n  The lands authorized to be deleted from the Greenfields Water District\nis described as follows:\n  ALL that certain parcel of land situate in the Town of Hyde Park,\nCounty of Dutchess and State of New York and is more particul...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses:\n  1. South 72Á25'56" East 180.00 feet,\n  2. South 71Á50'56" East 384.20 feet and\n  3. South 72Á49'56" East 262.85 feet\nto the northeasterly corner of Map No. 4604; thence southerly along the\neasterly line of Map No. 4604 the following five</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses:\n  1. South 07Á30'57" West 170.03 feet,\n  2. South 09Á05'57" West 218.24 feet,\n  3. South 06Á59'57" West 148.58 feet,\n  4. South 07Á42'57" West 151.40 feet and\n  5. South 07Á52'57" West 266.32 feet\nto the southeasterly corner of Map No. 4604; thence westerly along the\nsoutherly line of Map No. 4604 the following four</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>courses:\n  1. North 72Á59'04" West 221.10 feet,\n  2. North 59Á47'03" West 9.80 feet,\n  3. North 74Á01'04" West 194.72 feet and\n  4. North 72Á25'04" West 105.87 feet\nto the point or place of BEGINNING and containing 12.897 acres of land,\nmore or less.\n  10.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of general, special or\nlocal law, rule, or regulation to the contrary, whenever the town board\nof the town of Fort Ann, in the county of Washington, shall determine it\nto be in the public interest, said town board may, upon its own motion\nand without a petition, but after a public hearing held in the manner\nand upon the notice specified in subdivision one of this section,\ndiminish the Lake Hadlock park district by deleting therefrom the\nparcels of lands described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision located\nin the town of Fort Ann and presently included in said district,\nprovided that such lands have not received any benefit from such park\ndistrict since its inception. In addition, any order adopted by the town\nboard pursuant to this subdivision shall be subject to a permissive\nreferendum pursuant to article seven of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The parcels of lands authorized to be deleted from the Lake\nHadlock park district are described as follows:\n                                PARCEL A\n  All that piece or parcel of land situate, lying and being in the Town\nof Fort Ann, County of Washington and State of New York, being bounded\nand described as follows:\n  Beginning at a point in the center of Hadlock Pond Road at the\nintersection of said Hadlock Pond Road with Twiss Road, said point being\nthe northeasterly corner of Lot 1 and the southeasterly corner of the\nparcel herein described and being 25 feet from a capped iron pin set;\nrunning thence along said Lot 1 the following two courses:\n  S 43 degrees 40' 46" W 188.26 feet passing through said iron pin set\nto a capped iron pin set;\n  S 58 degrees 54' 56" W 552.56 feet to a capped iron pin set on the\neasterly bounds of lands of Mahoney; running thence along said lands of\nMahoney\n  N 12 degrees 56' 54" E 363.49 feet to a capped iron pin at the\nsouthwesterly corner of Lot 3; running thence along said Lot 3\n  N 56 degrees 19' 59" E 618.90 feet passing through a capped iron pin\nset to a point in the centerline of the aforementioned Twiss Road;\nrunning thence along said centerline of Twiss Road the following three\ncourses:\n  S 00 degrees 11' 59" W 158.11 feet;\n  S 05 degrees 56' 23" E 80.08 feet;\n  S 01 degrees 34' 02" W 38.15 feet to the point and place of beginning.\nContaining 4.020 acres of land.\n                                PARCEL B\n  All that piece of parcel of land situate, lying and being in the Town\nof Fort Ann, County of Washington and State of New York, being bounded\nand described as follows:\n  Beginning at a point in the center of Twiss Road approximately 290\nfeet north of the intersection of said Twiss Road with Hadlock Pond\nRoad, said point being the northeasterly corner of Lot 2 and the\nsoutheasterly corner of the parcel herein described and being 25 feet\nfrom a capped iron pin set; running thence along said Lot...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation to the contrary, whenever the town board\nof the town of Queensbury, in the county of Warren, shall determine it\nto be in the public interest, said town board may, upon its own motion\nand without a petition, but after a public hearing held in the manner\nand upon the notice specified in subdivision one of this section,\ndiminish the Glen Lake aquatic plant growth control district by deleting\ntherefrom the parcels of land described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision located in the town of Queensbury and presently included in\nsaid district, provided that such lands have not received any benefit\nfrom such aquatic plant growth control district since its inception. In\naddition, any order adopted by the town board pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be subject to a permissive referendum pursuant to\narticle seven of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The parcels of land authorized to be deleted from the Glen Lake\naquatic plant growth control district are described as follows:\n                                PARCEL A\n  31 Glen Lake Road, Town of Queensbury, County of Warren, State of New\nYork\n  More particularly described in a deed from Mary L. Sicard and Linda L.\nSicard to Mary L. Sicard dated February 26, 2015 and recorded in the\nWarren County Clerk's Office on February 27, 2015 in Book 5119 of deeds\nat Page 77.\n  Lot 12. Tax Parcel 289.6-1-17.2. All that certain piece or parcel of\nland situate lying and being in the Town of Queensbury, County of Warren\nand State of new York, referenced as Lot 12 in a subdivision of land\nshown on a map entitled; "Residential Subdivision Sicard Properties" as\nprepared by W. J. Rourke and Dated March 2014 and filed in the Warren\nCounty Clerk's Office on June 13, 2014 at Plat Cabinet C, Slide 358 and\nbeing more particularly bound and described as follows:\n  Beginning at a point on the northerly bounds of lot 10 at the\nsoutheasterly corner of lot 11, thence running the following two courses\nand distances along the easterly then northerly bounds of lot 11; North\n5 degrees 54 minutes 15 seconds East 104.80 feet, thence running North\n86 degrees 2 minutes 45 seconds West 108.00 feet to a point in the\neasterly bounds of Glen Lake Road, thence running, along the easterly\nbounds of Glen Lake Road; North 6 degrees 28 minutes 36 seconds East\n94.08 feet to the southwesterly corner of lot 13, thence running, along\nthe southerly bounds of lot 13 South 86 degrees 58 minutes 15 seconds\nEast 189.48 feet to a point being the southeast corner of lot 13 and a\nsouthwesterly corner of lot 3, thence running the following three\ncourses along the southerly bounds of lot 3; South 86 degrees 58 minutes\n15 seconds East 124.58 feet, then South 51 degrees 57 minutes 12 seconds\nEast 63.98 feet, then South 14 degrees 25 minutes 47 seconds West 26.62\nfeet to a point being the northw...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>