<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="202-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_202_D">
        <num>202-D</num>
        <heading>Increase of maximum amount to be expended</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 202-d. Increase of maximum amount to be expended. 1. At any time\nafter the establishment of an improvement district the maximum amount\nproposed to be expended for the improvement in such district, as stated\nin the petition for the establishment of such district, may be increased\nby an order of the town board provided a petition requesting such\nincrease signed as required by section one hundred ninety-one of this\narticle is presented to the town board and provided the town board\nshall, after a public hearing ordered and held in the manner prescribed\nby sections one hundred ninety-three and one hundred ninety-four of this\narticle, determine that it is in the public interest to authorize the\nincrease of such maximum amount, and provided the comptroller of the\nstate of New York shall have made as may be required pursuant to\nsubdivision six of section one hundred ninety-four of this article,\nafter such public hearing, an order approving the increase of such\nmaximum amount as stated in the petition. The order of the comptroller\nshall be prepared in duplicate and one copy thereof filed in the office\nof the department of audit and control and the other copy in the office\nof the town clerk of the town.\n  2. If the petition for establishment of the district proposes only the\nperformance or supplying of certain services, and states the maximum\namount to be expended annually for such services, the maximum amount to\nbe expended annually may be increased by an order of the town board\nprovided the town board shall, after a public hearing, determine that it\nis in the public interest to authorize the increase of such maximum\namount. The town board shall give notice of such hearing by publication\nof a notice in at least one newspaper having general circulation in the\ndistrict specifying the time when and the place where such hearing will\nbe held and stating the increase proposed in the maximum amount to be\nexpended annually. Such notice shall be published once at least ten days\nprior to the date specified for such hearing. The approval of the state\ncomptroller to such increase in the maximum amount to be expended\nannually shall not be required.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>