<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="202-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-202-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_202_E">
        <num>202-E</num>
        <heading>Acquisition and improvement of additional property in park districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 202-e. Acquisition and improvement of additional property in park\ndistricts.  1. Petition. After the establishment of a park district and\nthe acquisition for park purposes of the property described in the\npetition for the establishment of the district, the town board upon a\npetition therefor may acquire additional property for the purposes of\nsuch park district, in the manner herein provided. Such petition shall\nbe signed, and acknowledged or proved, or authenticated, in the manner\nspecified in section one hundred ninety-one for petitions for the\nestablishment of a park district and shall be subject to the\nrequirements of such section as to sufficiency of signers. The petition\nshall also describe the additional property proposed to be acquired for\npark purposes and shall state the maximum amount proposed to be expended\nfor the acquisition and improvement thereof.\n  2. Hearing. Whenever such a petition containing the required\nsignatures shall have been presented to the town board, the board shall\nadopt an order providing for a meeting to consider such petition and to\nhear all interested persons and shall cause notice of such hearing to be\ngiven in the manner provided in section one hundred and ninety-three.\nAfter such hearing and upon the evidence given thereat, the town board\nshall make the determinations specified in subdivision one of section\none hundred and ninety-four.\n  3. Permission of comptroller. If such board shall determine in the\naffirmative all the questions set forth in such subdivision and shall\napprove said petition, an application shall be filed in the office of\nthe state department of audit and control for permission to acquire and\nimprove the additional property described in said petition.  Such\napplication shall be executed and filed in the form and manner specified\nin section one hundred and ninety-four for the execution and filing of\nan application for permission to create or extend an improvement\ndistrict and the state comptroller shall make and file an order, in the\nmanner and subject to the restrictions specified in subdivisions three\nand four of said section, granting or denying such permission. The town\nclerk shall present the order of the comptroller to the town board at\nthe next meeting thereof.\n  4. Powers of town board. If the state comptroller shall deny\npermission for the acquisition and improvement of such property, the\ntown board shall forthwith adopt an order denying the petition. If the\nstate comptroller shall grant permission therefor, the town board may\nacquire by purchase or condemnation the property described in the\npetition; provided, however, that no property situated within an\nincorporated village or city shall be acquired unless the permission and\nconsent of the legislative body thereof, is first obtained.\n  After such additional property has been acquired, the town board shall\nhave such powers and shall be subject to such duties in relation thereto\nas shall be prescribed in subdivision four of section one hundred and\nninety-eight in relation to property acquired for park purposes pursuant\nto the petition for the establishment of such district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>