<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207">
        <num>207</num>
        <heading>Re-establishment of certain water supply districts as water districts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_207__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether it is in\npublic interest to re-establish such water supply district as a water\ndistrict, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether all the property and property owners within\nthe district will be benefited by such re-establishment.\n  5. Re-establishment. If the town board shall determine in the\naffirmative both questions set forth in the preceding subdivision, the\ntown board may adopt an order re-establishing any such district as a\nwater district and thereafter such district shall be governed, operated\nand managed and improvements may be made therein in accordance with the\nprovisions of this chapter relating to water districts as now in force\nor hereafter amended, and the town board shall have such powers for the\ngoverning, operation and the management of such water districts and for\nthe making of improvements therein and shall be subject to such duties\nin relation thereto, as shall be prescribed in said chapter.\n  6. Recording. A certified copy of the determination or order of the\ntown board shall be duly recorded in the manner provided in section one\nhundred ninety-five in the office of the clerk of the county in which\nsuch town is located and when so recorded shall be presumptive evidence\nof the regularity of the proceedings of the town board. Any interested\nperson aggrieved by any final determination or order made pursuant to\nthe provisions of this act, may review the same in the manner provided\nin subdivision two of said section one hundred ninety-five. The said\ndetermination or order shall be final and conclusive unless application\nhas been made for review by certiorari within thirty days from the time\nof recording thereof.\n  7. Effect of section. The re-establishment of any water supply\ndistrict as a water district pursuant to this section shall not impair\nor affect the validity of any obligations issued by the town to provide\nfor the supplying of water in such water supply district nor any tax or\nassessment heretofore levied for such purposes on the property within\nsuch district, nor any action or proceeding pending in any court at the\ntime this sect...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>