<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_H">
        <num>209-H</num>
        <heading>Increase of maximum amount to be expended</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-h. Increase of maximum amount to be expended. 1. At any time\nafter the establishment of an improvement district or of an extension\nthereof pursuant to the provisions of this article or any other\napplicable provision of law, the maximum amount proposed to be expended\nfor the improvement in such district, as stated in the notice of public\nhearing on the establishment or extension of such district, may be\nincreased by an order of the town board provided that the town board\nshall, after a public hearing is held in the manner prescribed by\nsection two hundred nine-d of this article, determine that it is in the\npublic interest to authorize the increase of such maximum amount, and\nprovided the comptroller of the state of New York shall have made as may\nbe required pursuant to subdivision one of section two hundred nine-f of\nthis article, after such public hearing, an order approving the increase\nof such maximum amount as stated in the said notice of hearing. The\norder of the comptroller shall be prepared in duplicate and one copy\nthereof filed in the office of the department of audit and control and\nthe other copy in the office of the town clerk of the town. The order of\nthe town board increasing the maximum amount to be expended shall be\nsubject to a permissive referendum in the manner provided in subdivision\nthree of section two hundred nine-e of this article. The comptroller may\nnot make an order approving the increase in such maximum amount until\nafter the expiration of the time for filing a petition requesting that\nthe matter be submitted to referendum or, if such a petition is filed,\nunless the vote on the proposition submitted at referendum was\naffirmative.\n  2. If the notice of public hearing for the establishment or extension\nof the district proposes only the performance or supplying of certain\nservices, and states the maximum amount to be expended annually for such\nservices, the maximum amount to be expended annually may be increased by\nan order of the town board provided the town board shall, after a public\nhearing, determine that it is in the public interest to authorize the\nincrease of such maximum amount. The town board shall give notice of\nsuch hearing by publication of a notice in at least one newspaper having\ngeneral circulation in the district specifying the time when and the\nplace where such hearing will be held and stating the increase proposed\nin the maximum amount to be expended annually. Such notice shall be\npublished once at least ten days prior to the date specified for such\nhearing. The approval of the state comptroller to such increase in the\nmaximum amount to be expended annually shall not be required.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>