<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-209-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_C">
        <num>209-C</num>
        <heading>Maps, plans and reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-c. Maps, plans and reports. The establishment or extension of an\nimprovement district shall be based upon a map, plan and report prepared\nin such manner and in such detail as determined by the town board and\nsuch map, plan and report shall be filed in the office of the town\nclerk. In the case of a sewer, drainage or water district such maps,\nplans and reports shall be prepared by a competent engineer, duly\nlicensed by the state of New York, showing the boundaries of the\nproposed district and a general plan of the proposed sewer, drainage or\nwater system, as the case may be, and a report of the proposed method of\noperation. If a sewer or drainage district is proposed, such map shall\nshow all outlets and the terminus and course of each proposed main sewer\nor drain together with the location and a general description of all\nsewage disposal plants, pumping stations and other public works, if any,\nand shall be consistent with, so far as possible, any comprehensive plan\nfor sewers developed and maintained pursuant to section ninety-nine-f of\nthe general municipal law. If a water district is proposed, said map and\nplan shall show the source of water supply and a description of the\nlands, streams, water or water rights to be acquired therefor, the mode\nof constructing the proposed water works and the location thereof,\nincluding reservoirs, water purification or treatment works, water\nmains, distributing pipes and hydrants, and shall be consistent with, so\nfar as possible, any comprehensive plan for public water supply systems\ndeveloped and maintained pursuant to section ninety-nine-f of the\ngeneral municipal law. If, however, the supply of water to be used in\nsaid water district is to be purchased from a municipal or other\ncorporation, or any person, then said map and plan shall set forth and\nshow only the water mains, distributing pipes, hydrants, reservoirs, if\nany, and location of each. Before any sewer system is constructed in any\nsuch district, the town board shall cause a copy of the map and plan of\nthe proposed sewer system and sewage disposal plant or proposed\nextension thereto to be submitted to the state department of health,\nand, if approved, it shall be filed in the office of the state\ndepartment of health and the town clerk. The state department of health\nmay require profiles to be submitted for any sewers or drains shown on\nsuch map and plan. Such map and plan may be amended with the approval of\nthe state department of health and if approved, shall be filed in the\noffice of the state department of health and the town clerk.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>