<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-211-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-211-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="211-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-211-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-211-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-211-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-211-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_211_A">
        <num>211-A</num>
        <heading>Special provisions applicable to the Fishers Island garbage and refuse district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 211-a. Special provisions applicable to the Fishers Island garbage\nand refuse district. 1. Effective January first, nineteen hundred\nninety-nine, the number of district commissioners of the Fishers Island\ngarbage and refuse district shall be increased by two to a total of five\ncommissioners, consisting of the offices of three district commissioners\nwhich already exist pursuant to section four of chapter three hundred\nsixty-eight of the laws of nineteen hundred fifty-three and section two\nhundred eleven of this article and two additional offices of district\ncommissioners. The original terms of office of the three district\ncommissioners whose offices already exist shall continue until the dates\nthey would otherwise next expire in the absence of this section.\n  2. At the annual district election in the year nineteen hundred\nninety-eight, conducted in the manner prescribed by section two hundred\ntwelve of this article, the three vacancies in the offices of district\ncommissioners which arise by reason of the creation of two additional\noffices of district commissioners on January first, nineteen hundred\nninety-nine pursuant to subdivision one of this section and by reason of\nthe expiration of the term of office of the one district commissioner\nwhose term expires on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nninety-eight pursuant to section four of chapter three hundred\nsixty-eight of the laws of nineteen hundred fifty-three (and as provided\nin such section, pursuant to section two hundred eleven of this\narticle), shall be filled. At such election, the qualified voters of the\ndistrict shall elect one commissioner for a term of three years, one\ncommissioner for a term of four years and one commissioner for a term of\nfive years.\n  3. At each annual district election conducted subsequent to the year\nnineteen hundred ninety-eight, the single vacancy arising each year by\nreason of the expiration of the term of office of one of the five\ndistrict commissioners on December thirty-first of that year, shall be\nfilled by the election to such office for a term of five years of a\nresident of the district who is qualified to vote for a town officer.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>