<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-212"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-212"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-01-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="212"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_212">
        <num>212</num>
        <heading>Annual election and notice thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 212. Annual election and notice thereof. The district commissioners\nof such improvement district shall publish at the expense of the\ndistrict the notice of each election of improvement district\ncommissioners held pursuant to this article. Such notice shall be\npublished at least once in one or more newspapers having general\ncirculation in the district and the first publication thereof shall be\nat least twenty days before the day of such election. The notice of\nannual election shall specify the time when and the place or places\nwhere such election shall be held and the hours during which the polls\nwill be open for the receipt of ballots. Notice of such election shall\nalso be posted on the websites of the district and the town in which the\ndistrict is located, if such websites are maintained, on the signboard\nof the town, and conspicuously posted in three or more designated public\nlocations within the district, on or about the day on which such notice\nis published. Such election shall be held at a suitable place or places\nwithin the district designated by the district commissioners and the\npolls shall remain open from six o'clock in the evening until nine\no'clock in the evening and such additional consecutive hours prior\nthereto as the district commissioners may determine and specify in the\nnotice of such election. The board of commissioners of such district\nshall designate for each district election not less than two nor more\nthan four resident taxpayers to act as election inspectors and ballot\nclerks for each designated polling place. The board of commissioners\nshall fix the compensation of such election inspectors and ballot clerks\nin an amount not to exceed ten dollars per hour each for every hour or\npart thereof of such service and such compensation shall be a charge\nagainst the district. The board of commissioners shall cause to be\nprepared the ballots for all elections, and may authorize the use of\nvoting machines at any annual or special election of the district in\naccordance with article nine of the election law. After the polls shall\nhave been closed at any election, the election inspectors and ballot\nclerks at each polling place shall immediately canvass the ballots cast\nand shall publicly announce the result of the vote at that polling\nplace. Within twenty-four hours the chairman of the board of\ncommissioners, election inspectors and ballot clerks shall execute and\nfile a certificate of the result of the canvass with the board of\ncommissioners of the improvement district and with the clerk of the town\nin which said district is located.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>