<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-216"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-216"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="216"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_216">
        <num>216</num>
        <heading>Powers of town board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 216. Powers of town board. Every petition for any purpose required\nby article twelve of this chapter to be initiated by petition shall be\npresented to the town board but no such petition for any such purpose\nwithin a district to which this article shall apply, shall be acted upon\nby the town board unless such petition and the purposes thereof shall\nhave been approved in writing by a majority of the commissioners of such\ndistrict. The town board shall call a hearing upon all petitions so\napproved by the commissioners and give notice thereof and such hearing\nshall be held in the manner provided in article twelve of this chapter.\nThe town board shall call a hearing upon other purposes authorized by\narticle twelve of this chapter to be undertaken without petition, only\nafter such purposes shall have been approved in writing by a majority of\nthe commissioners of such district, and the town board shall give notice\nthereof and such hearing shall be held in the manner provided in article\ntwelve of this chapter. If the town board shall determine to grant the\npetition or to authorize any such purpose, it may delegate to the board\nof commissioners the conduct of all further proceedings thereon pursuant\nto article twelve. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to\ndelegate or transfer any power of the town board not contained in\narticle twelve or in sections two hundred thirty-seven, two hundred\nthirty-eight and two hundred thirty-nine of article fifteen of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>