<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-221"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-221"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="221"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_221">
        <num>221</num>
        <heading>Solid waste management facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 221. Solid waste management facilities. 1. Upon the adoption of a\nresolution therefor, subject to a permissive referendum, in a town of\nthe first class, or, upon the adoption of a proposition therefor at a\ntown election, in a town of the second class, the town board may provide\nfor the collection, separation, treatment, processing and disposal of\nsolid waste, as defined in section 27-0701 of the environmental\nconservation law, and for that purpose may construct, operate and\nmaintain solid waste management facilities, as defined in section\n27-0701 of the environmental conservation law, acquire the necessary\nlands therefor, and purchase, operate and maintain all necessary\nappliances appurtenant thereto, including such vehicles as may be\nrequired for such collection, separation, treatment, processing and\ndisposition. Such town board may also employ such employees as may be\nnecessary for the maintenance and operation of such facility or\nfacilities or appurtenant equipment and fix their compensation.\n  2. In a town which acquires such a facility or facilities, the  town\nboard may contract with any municipality or special district for the\ncollection, separation, treatment, processing or disposal, by the town\nof the solid waste from any other municipality or special district. The\ntown board may also contract with any corporation, partnership or\nindividual for the disposal by the town of solid waste accumulated or\ncollected by such corporation, partnership or individual. The contract\nprice therefor shall be such sum as shall be fixed by the town board and\nthe term of such a contract shall be for a period not longer than five\nyears for a contract involving collection and disposal by means other\nthan resource recovery, and not longer than twenty-five years for a\ncontract involving collection and disposal through resource recovery, in\neither case subject to renewal from time to time upon such terms as the\ntown board may determine.\n  3. Any expenditure approved pursuant to this section shall be paid for\nby taxes levied for the fiscal year in which such expenditure is to be\nmade. However, nothing contained in this section shall be construed to\nprevent the financing in whole or in part, pursuant to the local finance\nlaw, of any expenditure enumerated in this section which is not\nauthorized pursuant to this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>