<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-23"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-23"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-09-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23">
        <num>23</num>
        <heading>Eligibility of town officers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in towns having no resident\nattorney, the town attorney and such counsel as may be employed need not\nbe electors; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in towns having no resident engineer and in the towns of Mount\nPleasant, Westchester county, North Castle, Westchester county,\nLewisboro, Westchester county, Somers, Westchester county, Carmel,\nPutnam county, and Ithaca, Tompkins county, the town engineer and such\nconsultant engineers as may be employed need not be electors; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the towns of North Castle, Westchester county, North Salem,\nLewisboro and Pound Ridge, Westchester county, the town building\ninspector and such deputy building inspectors as may be employed need\nnot be electors; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the town of Lewisboro, Westchester county, the town wetlands\ninspector need not be an elector; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the towns of Carmel and Patterson, Putnam county, the town\nwetlands inspector need not be an elector; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the town of Hamlin, Monroe county, the court clerk need not be\nan elector; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in towns participating in a shared town justice agreement pursuant\nto section one hundred six-b of the uniform justice court act, a town\njustice may be an elector of any town participating in such an\nagreement.\n  No county treasurer, district superintendent of schools, or trustee of\na school district shall be eligible to the office of supervisor.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nin the town of New Castle, Westchester county, and in the town of\nBolivar, Allegany county, the person performing the functions of town\nsuperintendent of highways need not be an elector of such town.\nProvided, further, that in the town of Pound Ridge, Westchester county,\nthe person performing the functions of town superintendent of highways\nand such deputies as may be employed need not be electors of such town.\n  3. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nin the town of Mount Pleasant, Westchester county, the persons\nperforming the functions of comptroller and building inspector need not\nbe electors of such town.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nin the town of Sweden, Monroe county, the person performing the\nfunctions of court clerk need not be an elector of such town.\n  5. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nin the town of Ogden, Monroe county, the person performing the functions\nof court clerk need not be an elector of such town.\n  6. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nin the town of North East, Dutchess county, the person performing the\nfunctions of the town engineer need not be an elector of such town.\n  7. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nin the town of Independence, Allegany county, the person performing the\nfunctions of town justice need not be an elector of such town. Provided,\nhowever, the person performing the functions of town justice in any\nother town ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>