<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-236"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-236"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="236"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-236/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-236/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-236/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-236/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_236">
        <num>236</num>
        <heading>Completion of improvements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 236. Completion of improvements. Upon the completion of any of the\nimprovements authorized by article twelve, article twelve-A, or section\neighty-one, two hundred twenty or two hundred twenty-one of this\nchapter, the town board, engineer, or other official or employee in\ncharge thereof, shall file in the office of the town clerk a statement\nin detail showing the actual and complete cost thereof. Such statement\nshall thereupon be entered in full in the minutes of the town board and\nif the cost of the improvement shall be borne by local assessment upon\nthe several lots or parcels of land especially benefited, pursuant to\narticle twelve, the town clerk shall file a certified copy thereof with\nthe assessors, accompanied by a certified copy of the resolution of the\ntown board specifying the property especially benefited by the\nimprovement and directing the assessors to apportion so much of the cost\nthereof upon the several lots and parcels of land so deemed benefited as\nshall be in just proportion to the amount of benefit which the\nimprovement shall have conferred upon the same.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>