<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="24"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_24">
        <num>24</num>
        <heading>Terms of office</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 24. Terms of office. All elective officers other than town council\nmembers, town justices, receivers of taxes and assessors shall hold\ntheir respective offices for two years. The terms of office of the town\ncouncil members first elected after this chapter shall take effect and\nof the town council members first elected in a town which shall have\nchanged its classification from that of a town of the second class to\nthat of a town of the first class, shall be two years each for two town\ncouncil members and four years each for two town council members, and\nthereafter at each biennial town election there shall be elected two\ntown council members for terms of four years each.\n  The terms of office of the town justices and elective receivers of\ntaxes and assessments shall be four years. The term of office of the\nassessor shall be six years, unless the town retains a board of\nassessors, in which case the term for each shall be four years with no\nmore than two assessors to be elected at any biennial election after\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred eighty-one except when the\nunexpired balance of term is being filled in which case three assessors\nmay be elected; when appointed, the term of office shall be as provided\nby section three hundred ten of the real property tax law. The term of\neach elective officer shall begin on the first day of January next\nsucceeding the election at which he was elected. The town clerk, the\ntown superintendent of highways, the receiver of taxes and assessments,\nthe town engineer and the town attorney, whenever appointed, shall hold\ntheir respective offices until the first day of January next succeeding\nthe first biennial town election held after the time of their\nappointment. All other appointed officers and employees shall hold their\nrespective offices and positions at the pleasure of the town board,\nexcept as otherwise provided by law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>