<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-267-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-267-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="267-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-267-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-267-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-267-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-267-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_267_A">
        <num>267-A</num>
        <heading>Board of appeals procedure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_267_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each\norder, requirement, decision, interpretation or determination of the\nadministrative official charged with the enforcement of the zoning local\nlaw or ordinance shall be filed in the office of such administrative\nofficial, within five business days from the day it is rendered, and\nshall be a public record. Alternately, the town board may, by\nresolution, require that such filings instead be made in the town\nclerk's office.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_267_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An appeal shall be taken within sixty days after the filing of any\norder, requirement, decision, interpretation or determination of the\nadministrative official, by filing with such administrative official and\nwith the board of appeals a notice of appeal, specifying the grounds\nthereof and the relief sought. The administrative official from whom the\nappeal is taken shall forthwith transmit to the board of appeals all the\npapers constituting the record upon which the action appealed from was\ntaken.\n  6. Stay upon appeal. An appeal shall stay all proceedings in\nfurtherance of the action appealed from, unless the administrative\nofficial charged with the enforcement of such ordinance or local law,\nfrom whom the appeal is taken, certifies to the board of appeals, after\nthe notice of appeal shall have been filed with the administrative\nofficial, that by reason of facts stated in the certificate a stay,\nwould, in his or her opinion, cause imminent peril to life or property,\nin which case proceedings shall not be stayed otherwise than by a\nrestraining order which may be granted by the board of appeals or by a\ncourt of record on application, on notice to the administrative official\nfrom whom the appeal is taken and on due cause shown.\n  7. Hearing on appeal. The board of appeals shall fix a reasonable time\nfor the hearing of the appeal or other matter referred to it and give\npublic notice of such hearing by publication in a paper of general\ncirculation in the town at least five days prior to the date thereof.\nThe cost of sending or publishing any notices relating to such appeal,\nor a reasonable fee relating thereto, shall be borne by the appealing\nparty and shall be paid to the board prior to the hearing of such\nappeal. Upon the hearing, any party may appear in person, or by agent or\nattorney.\n  8. Time of decision. The board of appeals shall decide upon the appeal\nwithin sixty-two days after the conduct of said hearing. The time within\nwhich the...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_267_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Decision of the board. Except as\notherwise provided in subdivision twelve of this section, every motion\nor resolution of a board of appeals shall require for its adoption the\naffirmative vote of a majority of all the members of the board of\nappeals as fully constituted regardless of vacancies or absences. Where\nan action is the subject of a referral to the county planning agency or\nregional planning council the voting provisions of section two hundred\nthirty-nine-m of the general municipal law shall apply.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_267_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Default denial of appeal. In exercising its appellate jurisdiction\nonly, if an affirmative vote of a majority of all members of the board\nis not attained on a motion or resolution to grant a variance or reverse\nany order, requirement, decision or determination of the enforcement\nofficial within the time allowed by subdivision eight of this section,\nthe appeal is denied. The board may amend the failed motion or\nresolution and vote on the amended motion or resolution within the time\nallowed without being subject to the rehearing process as set forth in\nsubdivision twelve of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>