<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-273"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-273"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="273"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-273/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-273/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-273/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-273/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_273">
        <num>273</num>
        <heading>Official map, changes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 273. Official map, changes. Such town board is authorized and\nempowered, whenever and as often as it may deem it for the public\ninterest, to change or add to the official map of the town so as to lay\nout new streets, highways, drainage systems or parks, or to widen or\nclose existing streets, highways, drainage systems or parks within that\npart of the town outside the limits of any incorporated city or village.\nAt least ten days' notice of a public hearing on any proposed action\nwith reference to any such change in the official map shall be published\nin a newspaper of general circulation in such town. Before making any\nsuch addition or change, the town board shall refer the matter to the\nplanning board for report thereon, but if the planning board shall not\nmake its report within thirty days of such reference, it shall forfeit\nthe right further to suspend action. Such additions and changes, when\nadopted, shall become a part of the official map of the town, and shall\nbe deemed to be final and conclusive with respect to the location of the\nstreets, highways, drainage systems and parks shown thereon. The layout,\nwidening or closing, or the approval of the layout, widening or closing,\nof streets, highways, drainage systems or parks, by the town board, or\nthe town superintendent of highways, under provisions of law other than\nthose contained in this article, shall be deemed to be an addition or\nchange of the official map, and shall be subject to all the provisions\nof this article with regard to such additions or changes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>