<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-274-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-274-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="274-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-274-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-274-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-274-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-274-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_274_A">
        <num>274-A</num>
        <heading>Site plan review</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_274_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The town board may, as part of a zoning\nordinance or local law adopted pursuant to this article or other\nenabling law, authorize the planning board or such other administrative\nbody that it shall so designate, to review and approve, approve with\nmodifications or disapprove site plans prepared to specifications set\nforth in the ordinance or local law and/or in regulations of such\nauthorized board. Site plans shall show the arrangement, layout and\ndesign of the proposed use of the land on said plan. The ordinance or\nlocal law shall specify the land uses that require site plan approval\nand the elements to be included on plans submitted for approval. The\nrequired site plan elements which are included in the zoning ordinance\nor local law may include, where appropriate, those related to parking,\nmeans of access, screening, signs, landscaping, architectural features,\nlocation and dimensions of buildings, adjacent land uses and physical\nfeatures meant to protect adjacent land uses as well as any additional\nelements specified by the town board in such zoning ordinance or local\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_274_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When an authorization to approve site plans is granted by the town\nboard pursuant to this section, the terms thereof may condition the\nissuance of a building permit upon such approval.\n  3. Application for area variance. Notwithstanding any provision of law\nto the contrary, where a proposed site plan contains one or more\nfeatures which do not comply with the zoning regulations, application\nmay be made to the zoning board of appeals for an area variance pursuant\nto section two hundred sixty-seven-b of this article, without the\nnecessity of a decision or determination of an administrative official\ncharged with the enforcement of the zoning regulations.\n  4. Conditions attached to the approval of site plans. The authorized\nboard shall have the authority to impose such reasonable conditions and\nrestrictions as are directly related to and incidental to a proposed\nsite plan. Upon its approval of said site plan, any such conditions must\nbe met in connection with the issuance of permits by applicable\nenforcement agents or officers of the town.\n  5. Waiver of requirements. The town board may further empower the\nauthorized board to, when reasonable, waive any requirements for the\napproval, approval with modifications or disapproval of site plans\nsubmitted for approval. Any such waiver, which shall be subject to\nappropriate conditions set forth in the ordinance or local law adopted\npursuant to this section, may be exercised in the event any such\nrequirements are found not to be requisite in the interest of the public\nhealth, safety or general welfare or inappropriate to a particular site\nplan.\n  6. Reservation of parkland on site plans containing residential units.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_274_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Before such authorized board may approve a site plan containing\nresidential units, such site plan shall also show, when required by such\nboard, a park or parks suitably located for playground or other\nrecreational purposes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_274_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Land for park, playground or other recreational purposes may not\nbe required until the authorized board has made a finding that a proper\ncase exists for requiring that a park or parks be suitably located for\nplaygrounds or other recreational purposes within the town. Such\nfindings shall include an evaluation of the present and anticipated\nfuture needs for park and recreational facilities in the town based on\nprojected population growth to which the particular site plan will\ncontribute.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_274_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event the authorized board makes a finding pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_274_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision that the proposed site plan presents a\nproper case for requiring a park or parks suitably located for\nplaygrounds or other recreational purposes, but that a suitable park or\nparks of adequate size to meet the requirement cannot be properly\nlocated on such site plan, the authorized board may require a sum of\nmoney in lieu thereof to be established by the town board. In making\nsuch determination of suitability, the board shall assess the size and\nsuitability of lands shown on the site plan which could be possible\nlocations for park or recreational facilities, as well as practical\nfactors including whether there is a need for additional facilities in\nthe immediate neighborhood. Any monies required by the authorized board\nin lieu of land for park, playground or other recreational purposes,\npursuant to the provisions of this section, shall be deposited into a\ntrust fund to be used by the town exclusively for park, playground or\nother recreational purposes, including the acquisition of property.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_274_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this subdivision, if\nthe land included in a site plan under review is a portion of a\nsubdivision plat which has been reviewed and approved pursuant to\nsection two hundred seventy-six of this article, the authorized board\nshall credit the applicant for any land set aside or money donated in\nlieu thereof under such subdivision plat approval. In the event of\nresubdivision of such plat, nothing shall preclude the additional\nreservation of parkland or money donated in lieu thereof.\n  7. Performance bond or other security. As an alternative to the\ninstallation of required infrastructure and improvements, prior to\napproval by the authorized board, a performance bond or other security\nsufficient to cover the full cost of the same, as estimated by the\nauthorized board or a town department designated by the authorized board\nto make such estimate, where such departmental estimate is deemed\nacceptable by the authorized board, shall be furnished to the town by\nthe owner. Such security shall be provided to the town pursuant to the\nprovisions of subdivision nine of section two hundred seventy-seven of\nthis article.\n  8. Public hearing and decision on site plans. In the event a public\nhearing is required by ordinance or local law adopted by the town board,\nthe authorized board shall conduct a public hearing within sixty-two\ndays from the day an application is received on any matter referred to\nit under this section. The authorized board shall mail notice of said\nhearing to the applicant at least ten days before said hearing and shall\ngive public notice of said hearing in a newspaper of general circulation\nin the town at least five days prior to the date thereof and shall make\na decision on the application within sixty-two days after such hearing,\nor after the day the application is received if no hearing has been\nheld. The time within which the authorized board must render its\ndecision may be extended by mutua...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>