<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-283-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-283-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="283-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-283-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-283-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-283-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-283-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_283_A">
        <num>283-A</num>
        <heading>Coordination with agricultural districts program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 283-a. Coordination with agricultural districts program. 1. Policy\nof local governments. Local governments shall exercise their powers to\nenact local laws, ordinances, rules or regulations that apply to farm\noperations in an agricultural district in a manner which does not\nunreasonably restrict or regulate farm operations in contravention of\nthe purposes of article twenty-five-AA of the agriculture and markets\nlaw, unless it can be shown that the public health or safety is\nthreatened.\n  2. Agricultural data statement; submission, evaluation. Any\napplication for a special use permit, site plan approval, use variance,\nor subdivision approval requiring municipal review and approval by the\ntown board, planning board, or zoning board of appeals pursuant to this\narticle, that would occur on property within an agricultural district\ncontaining a farm operation or on property with boundaries within five\nhundred feet of a farm operation located in an agricultural district,\nshall include an agricultural data statement. The town board, planning\nboard, or zoning board of appeals shall evaluate and consider the\nagricultural data statement in its review of the possible impacts of the\nproposed project upon the functioning of farm operations within such\nagricultural district. The information required by an agricultural data\nstatement may be included as part of any other application form required\nby local law, ordinance or regulation.\n  3. Agricultural data statement; notice provision. Upon the receipt of\nsuch application by the planning board, zoning board of appeals, or town\nboard, the clerk of such board shall mail written notice of such\napplication to the owners of land as identified by the applicant in the\nagricultural data statement. Such notice shall include a description of\nthe proposed project and its location, and may be sent in conjunction\nwith any other notice required by state or local law, ordinance, rule or\nregulation for the said project. The cost of mailing said notice shall\nbe borne by the applicant.\n  4. Agricultural data statement; content. An agricultural data\nstatement shall include the following information: the name and address\nof the applicant; a description of the proposed project and its\nlocation; the name and address of any owner of land within the\nagricultural district, which land contains farm operations and is\nlocated within five hundred feet of the boundary of the property upon\nwhich the project is proposed; and a tax map or other map showing the\nsite of the proposed project relative to the location of farm operations\nidentified in the agricultural data statement.\n  5. Notice to county planning board or agency or regional planning\ncouncil. The clerk of the town board, planning board, or zoning board of\nappeals shall refer all applications requiring an agricultural data\nstatement to the county planning board or agency or regional planning\ncouncil as required by sections two hundred thirty-nine-m and two\nhundred thirty-nine-n of the general municipal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>