<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="30"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_30">
        <num>30</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of town clerk</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The town clerk may appoint, and at his or her pleasure remove,\na first deputy town clerk, who shall serve without compensation from the\ntown unless otherwise provided by the town board. Such compensation may\nbe in addition to any other compensation he or she may receive as a town\nofficer, town official or town employee. The town clerk shall establish\nthe duties and responsibilities of the first deputy town clerk and such\nfirst deputy town clerk shall possess the powers and perform the duties\nof the town clerk during the absence or inability to act of the town\nclerk, or during a vacancy in the office of town clerk. Before he or she\nshall perform any function as such, the first deputy town clerk shall\ntake and file the constitutional oath of office and execute and file an\nofficial undertaking in the manner prescribed in section twenty-five of\nthis article.\n  In addition, the town clerk may appoint, and at his or her pleasure\nremove, up to two additional deputy town clerks whose duties and\nresponsibilities shall be established by the town board. The town board,\nin its discretion, may delegate to the town clerk the authority to\nestablish the duties of the additional deputy town clerks. Any such\nadditional deputy town clerks shall serve without compensation from the\ntown, unless otherwise provided by the town board. Such compensation may\nbe in addition to any other compensation he or she may receive as a town\nofficer, town official or town employee. Before he or she shall perform\nany function as such, the additional deputy town clerk shall take and\nfile the constitutional oath of office and if required by the town\nboard, execute and file an official undertaking in the manner prescribed\nin section twenty-five of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that the town clerk is absent or unable to act and\nthere is no duly appointed and qualified first deputy town clerk present\nand able to act, the town board may appoint as deputy town clerk any\nperson other than a member of the town board; provided, however, that\nsuch person be qualified as provided in section three of the public\nofficers law and section twenty-three of this article. If the town board\nshall provide compensation for such deputy town clerk, such compensation\nmay be in addition to any other compensation he or she may receive as a\ntown officer, town official or town employee. Such deputy town clerk\nshall hold office at the pleasure of the town board and in no event for\nlonger than the duration of such absence or incapacity of the town\nclerk.\n  10-a. Where a town has not established the office of receiver of taxes\nand assessments, the town clerk shall collect water rates and sewer\nrents unless the town board has designated another officer or employee\nto make such collections.\n  11. The town clerk shall have such additional powers and perform such\nadditional duties as are or hereafter may be conferred or imposed upon\nhim by law, and such further duties as the town board may determine, not\ninconsistent with law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>