<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="31"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-31/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-31/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-31/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-31/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31">
        <num>31</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of town justices; requirements; restriction</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_31__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Keep or cause to be kept the records and dockets required by the\nuniform justice court act. No town justice shall receive or disburse any\nmoneys unless he shall furnish or receive a proper receipt therefor, or\nmake a memorandum or record of such transaction, in such form and detail\nas the state comptroller shall prescribe.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_31__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At least annually and as often as may be required, submit his\ndockets to the members of the town board for examination and audit.\n  2. No town justice selected for a term of office commencing on or\nafter September first, nineteen hundred sixty-seven, except one who has\nbeen admitted to practice law in this state, shall assume the functions\nof his office unless he has filed in the office of the town clerk a\ncertificate of completion of a course of training prescribed by the\nadministrative board of the judicial conference. The administrative\nboard may issue a temporary certificate enabling a justice to assume the\nfunctions of his office pending completion of the earliest such course\navailable thereafter. Such certificates shall be in a form, and subject\nto terms and conditions, prescribed by the administrative board.\n  3. Notwithstanding any other law, actual and necessary expenses\nincurred by a justice or justice elect in attending a course of training\nrequired of him before he can assume the functions of his office shall\nbe a charge against the town.\n  4. No town justice selected for a term of office commencing on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five, shall engage in or\naccept any employment as a "police officer" or a "peace officer" as\nthose terms are defined in the criminal procedure law.\n  5. A person who has been convicted of a felony pursuant to the laws of\nthis state or who has been convicted in federal court or in another\nstate for a crime or offense that would constitute a felony under the\nlaws of this state shall be permanently ineligible to be a candidate for\ntown justice or to be appointed or continue to hold such office.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>