<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-32"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-32"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="32"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_32">
        <num>32</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of town superintendent of highways and deputy superintendent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 32. Powers and duties of town superintendent of highways and deputy\nsuperintendent. 1. The town superintendent of highways shall have such\npowers and shall perform such duties as are or hereafter may be\nconferred or imposed upon him by law, and such further duties as the\ntown board may determine not inconsistent with law.\n  2. The town board of any town may at any time establish the office of\ndeputy town superintendent of highways. The deputy town superintendent\nof highways shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the town\nsuperintendent of highways. If the town superintendent of highways shall\nfail to appoint such deputy within five days after the establishment of\nthe office of deputy or within five days after a vacancy occurs in the\noffice of deputy, the town board shall have power to appoint such deputy\ntown superintendent of highways. During the absence or inability of the\ntown superintendent of highways to act, such deputy shall act and be\nvested with all the powers and duties of the town superintendent as\nprovided by law. Before such deputy shall perform any power or duty of\nthe office of superintendent such deputy town superintendent of highways\nshall take and file the constitutional oath of office and execute and\nfile an official undertaking to be approved by the town board. The town\nboard shall fix the compensation to be received by such deputy.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>