<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-323"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-323"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="323"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-323/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-323/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-323/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-323/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_323">
        <num>323</num>
        <heading>Damages from other personal property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 323. Damages from other personal property. When any person shall be\nauthorized to distrain inanimate goods or chattels doing damage, or\nwhenever any logs, timbers, boards or plank, in rafts or otherwise, or\nother personal property shall have drifted upon his lands, he shall be\nentitled to the same remedies and shall proceed therein in the same\nmanner and with the same powers as herein provided with respect to\nbeasts found doing damage, so far as such provisions are applicable. He\nmust deliver his notice of lien to the town clerk, describing the\nproperty, within thirty days after it lodges upon his lands, and he\nshall keep the same in some convenient place without removal to a pound\nuntil the property is sold or reclaimed. The same officer shall conduct\nproceedings therein as in proceedings where beasts are found doing\ndamage, and all proceeds of sale shall be, in like manner, paid over and\napplied, subject to the same penalties and liabilities, and with the\nsame force and effect. The fee of the town clerk for filing and\nrecording such notices of lien shall be one dollar and the charges of\nthe land owner claiming such lien and delivering such notice to the town\nclerk, pursuant to this section, shall be at the rate of five cents for\neach such stray, but shall in no event exceed the sum of fifty dollars\nupon any one lien.  Any lien for logs, timber, boards or planks, in\nrafts or otherwise, filed herein may be discharged in the manner\nprovided in sections nineteen and twenty of the lien law, with reference\nto the discharge of mechanics' liens, so far as such provisions are\napplicable.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>