<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-341"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-341"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="341"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_341">
        <num>341</num>
        <heading>Temporary provisions and saving clause</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_341__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this chapter as to\nleasing of water storage and distribution facilities shall apply to\njoint water districts continued pursuant to this subdivision twelve.\n  13. Not later than June fifteenth, nineteen hundred thirty-three, the\ntown board of any town containing a population of ten thousand or more\nas shown by the latest federal census, excepting towns in Broome and\nSuffolk counties, and of any other town which shall determine by any of\nthe methods prescribed by subdivision one of this section to be a town\nof the first class, may adopt a resolution to establish the ward system\nfor the election of council members for such town, which resolution\nshall be subjected to referendum as herein provided. Within four days\nafter the adoption of such resolution, the town clerk shall cause copies\nthereof to be posted in ten public places in the town, with a statement\nof the date of its adoption Within fourteen days after the adoption of\nsuch resolution, a petition may be filed requiring such resolution be\nsubmitted to the electors of the town, for their approval. The form of\nquestion to be submitted thereon shall be "Shall the resolution of the\ntown board of the town of ............., establishing the ward system\nfor the election of town council members, be approved?" If no such\nresolution shall have been adopted within the time above provided, a\npetition may be filed not later than June twenty-ninth, nineteen hundred\nthirty-three, requiring the submission to such electors of the\nproposition "Shall the ward system be established for the election of\ntown council members?" A petition for any of the above purposes shall be\nfiled with the town clerk, and shall be signed and duly acknowledged by\nat least one hundred electors of the town. The question or proposition\nfor which a petition shall have been filed shall be submitted by the\ntown board at a special town meeting to be held at a time, not later\nthan August first, nineteen hundred thirty-three, and ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>