<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-342"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-342"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="342"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-342/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-342/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-342/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-342/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_342">
        <num>342</num>
        <heading>When to take effect</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 342. When to take effect. The provisions of sections one hundred\neighty-six and three hundred forty-one of this chapter shall take effect\nJune first, nineteen hundred thirty-three. The provisions of sections\none hundred ten to one hundred twenty-one, inclusive, of this chapter so\nfar as the same pertain to the preparation of preliminary and annual\nestimates and public hearings thereon, the adoption of the annual\nestimate, annual appropriations, the levy of taxes for the year nineteen\nhundred thirty-four and the issuance and sale of bonds or certificates\nof indebtedness, pursuant to section one hundred twenty-one, shall take\neffect August fifteenth, nineteen hundred thirty-three in every town\ncontaining a population of ten thousand or more as shown by the\ndecennial federal census of nineteen hundred thirty, excepting towns in\nthe counties of Broome and Suffolk, in every town which shall have\ndetermined by any method prescribed in subdivision one of section three\nhundred forty-one of this chapter that such town is to be in the first\nclass, excepting, however, towns in the county of Ontario and the towns\nto which the provisions of article six-a of the former town law repealed\nby this act, shall apply prior to August fifteenth, nineteen hundred\nthirty-three. The provisions of sections one hundred ninety to two\nhundred two, inclusive, and two hundred twenty to two hundred forty-six,\ninclusive, of this chapter shall take effect immediately. In all other\nrespects this chapter shall take effect January first, nineteen hundred\nthirty-four.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>