<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-42"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-42"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="42"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-42/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-42/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-42/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-42/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_42">
        <num>42</num>
        <heading>Deputy supervisor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 42. Deputy supervisor. The town board of any town may at any time\nestablish the office of deputy supervisor. The deputy supervisor shall\nbe appointed by the supervisor to serve at the pleasure of the\nsupervisor, and in case the office of supervisor becomes vacant any\ndeputy supervisor in office at the time such vacancy occurs shall\ncontinue to serve until the successor of such deputy supervisor is\nappointed. If the supervisor shall fail to appoint a deputy supervisor\nwithin five days after the establishment of the office or within five\ndays after a vacancy occurs in the office, the town board shall have\npower to appoint such deputy supervisor. During the absence or inability\nto act of the supervisor, or while the office of supervisor is vacant,\nthe deputy supervisor shall preside, when present, at the meetings of\nthe town board and shall be vested with all of the powers and may\nperform all of the duties of the supervisor under this chapter or any\nother law, except that he shall have no vote in his capacity as deputy\nsupervisor on matters coming before the town board and he shall not\nserve as a member of the county board of supervisors. Any person,\nincluding a town officer, official or employee, may be appointed deputy\nsupervisor, provided that the person appointed shall possess the same\nqualifications as an elective town officer. Before he shall perform any\nfunction as such, the deputy supervisor shall take and file the\nconstitutional oath of office and execute and file an official\nundertaking in the manner prescribed in section twenty-five of this\nchapter. The town board shall fix the compensation which the deputy\nsupervisor shall receive, which compensation may be in addition to any\nother compensation he may receive as a town officer, town official or\ntown employee.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>