<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-51"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-51"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="51"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_51">
        <num>51</num>
        <heading>General powers of town board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 51. General powers of town board. The town board of a suburban town\nshall be the legislative, appropriating, governing and policy\ndetermining body of the town and shall have and exercise all such powers\nand duties as are conferred or imposed upon it or are necessarily\nincidental thereto which are consistent with the provisions of this\narticle; provided, however, that whenever the expense of a function or\nactivity is required by law or agreement to be a charge upon the taxable\nproperty of that part of the town outside of any village and the\nresponsibility for the performance of such function or activity is\nreassigned, transferred or changed in any way pursuant to the provisions\nof this article, the expenses and liabilities attributable to such\nfunction or activity shall continue to be a charge upon such taxable\nreal property outside of any village. In addition to functions, powers\nand duties otherwise granted to it, the town board of a suburban town\nalso shall have the following functions, powers and duties:\n  1. Appointment of the heads and deputies of departments of town\ngovernment in cases in which such officers are appointive and the\nhearing and determination of charges brought by the supervisor for the\nremoval from office of any of such appointive officers.\n  2. On recommendation of the supervisor, approval of budget\nmodifications and transfers between budgetary appropriations in the\nannual budget or in the capital budget, if any.\n  3. Requiring reports from the supervisor concerning the conduct of the\nofficial business of the town and the performance by town officers and\nemployees of their functions, powers and duties.\n  4. Making of studies and investigations as it deems to be in the best\ninterests of the town and, in connection therewith, to obtain and\nprovide for compensation for professional and technical advice, subpoena\nwitnesses, administer oaths and require the production of books, papers\nand other evidence deemed necessary or material for any such study or\ninvestigation.\n  5. Creation of non-compensated advisory boards, each member of which\nshall be appointed by the town board or the supervisor, or both, as\nshall be specified by the town board in its action providing for the\nparticular advisory board.\n  6. Determination and provision for any matter of town government not\notherwise provided for, including but not restricted to, any matter\nnecessarily involved in the transition to government of the town as a\nsuburban town under the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>