<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="52-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52_A">
        <num>52-A</num>
        <heading>Official newspaper in town of Greenburgh, Westchester county</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 52-a. Official newspaper in town of Greenburgh, Westchester county.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the town\nboard of the town of Greenburgh, Westchester county is hereby authorized\nand empowered to designate as the official newspaper of such town any\nnewspaper regularly published in such town if such newspaper has been\nentered as second class mail matter, or such town board shall have the\noption to designate as its official newspaper any newspaper published in\nthe county if such newspaper has general circulation in such town. If no\nofficial newspaper has been designated, the town board may authorize the\npublication of a notice, resolution or ordinance in any newspaper which\ncould be designated as the official newspaper of the town. Such\nauthorization shall be deemed a designation of such newspaper as the\nofficial newspaper of the town for the purpose of such publication.\nAdditional newspapers published in the English language may be\ndesignated for the publication of such notices, resolutions and\nordinances at the option of the town board. Any designation by the town\nboard pursuant to the foregoing provisions shall be deemed sufficient\nauthority for designation of any such newspaper by any board, agency,\ncommission or authority of such town for any publication of notice or\nresolution required by law unless the town board in its discretion shall\nclearly indicate otherwise.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>