<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="52"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-52/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52">
        <num>52</num>
        <heading>Supervisor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 52. Supervisor. The supervisor shall be the chief executive officer\nof a suburban town and head of the administrative branch of town\ngovernment. He shall be responsible for the proper administration of\ntown affairs, law enforcement and the maintenance of peace and order in\nthe town. Except as otherwise provided in this article or other\napplicable law, in addition to the functions, powers and duties of a\nsupervisor as provided by this chapter and other laws of the state, the\nsupervisor shall have the following functions, powers and duties:\n  1. Appoint, and at pleasure remove, a director of finance who shall\nassist the supervisor in the preparation of the preliminary budget and\nthe capital budget, if any, and in the administration of other fiscal\noperations of the town for which the supervisor is responsible.\n  2. On the basis of estimates submitted to him by departments, agencies\nand officers of the town, prepare annually the preliminary budget of the\ntown and submit it to the town board and be responsible for\nadministration of the annual budget after adoption by the town board,\nand be responsible for recommending modifications and transfers between\nappropriations in such budget during the fiscal year.\n  3. Where the town board has, by local law, established a capital\nbudget procedure, on the basis of estimates submitted to him by\ndepartments, agencies and officers of the town, prepare with the\nassistance of the planning board, if any, a proposed capital budget and,\nafter adoption of a capital budget by the town board, recommend for\naction by the board, from time to time when necessary, modifications and\ntransfers between appropriations in such capital budget.\n  4. Bring removal charges against the appointive head or deputy head of\nany department of town government for hearing and determination by the\ntown board.\n  5. Approve the transfer of personnel in and among agencies and\ndepartments of the town.\n  6. Provide for and direct the internal organization and reorganization\nwithin individual town departments or agencies where consistent with\napplicable law, provided, however, that in any event, permissible\ntransfers of functions between departments or agencies shall be subject\nto approval of the town board.\n  7. Keep the town board informed generally concerning town affairs and\nof the financial condition and future needs of the town and make such\nrecommendations as may seem to him desirable.\n  8. Have and perform the functions, powers and duties necessary for the\nexecution of those functions, powers and duties specifically granted in\nthis article or other applicable law consistent herewith.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>