<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-55-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-55-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="55-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-55-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-55-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-55-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-55-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_55_B">
        <num>55-B</num>
        <heading>Reserve fund for judgments and claims</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Judgments or compromised or settled claims against the town; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Awards or sums payable by the town pursuant to a determination by\na court, or an officer, body or agency acting in an administrative or\nquasi-judicial capacity.\n  2. The amount of any such fund shall not exceed the greater of\nthirty-three thousand dollars or five per centum of the total budget for\nsuch fiscal year at any one time, exclusive of any interest or capital\ngains realized from the investment of the money in such fund. Whenever\nan expenditure shall be made from such fund, additional money may be\nappropriated or transferred thereto in an amount which, together with\nall money remaining in such fund including any interest or capital gains\nrealized from the investment of the money in such fund, shall not exceed\nthe greater of thirty-three thousand dollars or five per centum of the\ntotal budget for such fiscal year.\n  3. There may be paid into such fund:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such an amount as may be provided therefor by budgetary\nappropriation or transfer or raised by tax therefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such revenues as are not required by law to be paid into any other\nfund or account, including the proceeds from the sale of any capital\nimprovement or equipment owned by such town.\n  4. An expenditure may be made from the fund only by authorization of\nthe town board and only for a specific object or purpose, the cost of\nwhich may be financed therefrom. Any expenditure made from such fund to\npay all or part of the cost of a judgment, claim, award or determination\narising out of the management, improvement, operation or maintenance of\nany special improvement district located in the town shall be charged\nback against such district and raised in the same manner as other\ndistrict charges. Any amount so charged to a district shall be included\nin determining the amount of such fund, exclusive of any interest or\ncapital gains realized from the investment of the money in such fund.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>