<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-62"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-62"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="62"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-62/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-62/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-62/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-62/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_62">
        <num>62</num>
        <heading>Meetings of town board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 62. Meetings of town board. 1. The town board of every town shall\nmeet on or before the twentieth day of January in each year for the\npurpose of making the annual accounting by town officers and employees\nas required by section one hundred twenty-three of this chapter. The\nrequirement for the annual accounting shall not apply to a town having a\ntown comptroller, nor to a town which, prior to the twentieth day of\nJanuary, shall have engaged the services of a certified public\naccountant or public accountant to make an annual audit to be completed\nwithin sixty days after the close of the town's fiscal year.\n  2. The town board of every town of the first class shall hold at least\none meeting in each month. The supervisor of any town may, and upon\nwritten request of two members of the board shall within ten days, call\na special meeting of the town board by giving at least two days notice\nin writing to members of the board of the time when and the place where\nthe meeting is to be held. All meetings of the town board shall be held\nwithin the town at such place as the town board shall determine by\nresolution, except that where provision is made by law for joint\nmeetings of two or more town boards such joint meetings may be held in\nany of the towns to be represented thereat.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>