<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-64"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-64"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="64"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_64">
        <num>64</num>
        <heading>General powers of town boards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 64. General powers of town boards. Subject to law and the provisions\nof this chapter, the town board of every town:\n  1. Control of town finances. Shall have the general management and\ncontrol of the finances of the town and shall designate in the manner\nprovided by section ten of the general municipal law the depositaries in\nwhich the supervisor, town clerk, tax collector, tax receiver, and\ntrustees of the freeholders and commonalty of a town shall deposit and\nsecure all moneys coming into their hands by virtue of their offices.\n  1-a. Petty cash fund. Notwithstanding the provisions of section one\nhundred eighteen of this chapter, may by resolution establish a petty\ncash fund for any town officer or head of a department or office in any\ntown, for the payment, in advance of audit, of properly itemized and\nverified or certified bills for materials, supplies or services\nfurnished to the town for the conduct of its affairs and upon terms\ncalling for payment to the vendor upon the delivery of any such\nmaterials or supplies or the rendering of any such services, provided\nthat moneys in any such fund also may be used for the purpose of making\nchange when such is required in the performance of official duties. The\namount of the petty cash fund established for a receiver of taxes and\nassessments in a town of the first class shall not exceed one thousand\ndollars and for any other officer or office or department head shall not\nexceed five hundred dollars. Prior to making his return of unpaid taxes\nto the county treasurer, a collector of taxes in a town of the second\nclass shall reimburse the supervisor for the amount of the petty cash\nfund previously advanced to him. At the time of any payment from such\nfund, the officer for which the fund was established shall require\ndelivery to him of a bill in form sufficient for audit by the town board\nas required by law. At each meeting of the town board a list of all\nexpenditures made from each such fund since the last meeting of the\nboard, together with the bills supporting such expenditures, shall be\npresented to the town board for audit and the town board shall direct\nthe supervisor to reimburse each petty cash fund from the appropriate\nbudgetary item or items, in an amount equal to the totals of such bills\nwhich it shall so audit and allow, except that, in any such town in\nwhich there is a town comptroller, such list of expenditures, together\nwith such bills shall be presented to said town comptroller for audit no\nlater than the last day of each month and the supervisor shall so\nreimburse each petty cash fund in an amount equal to the total of such\nbills which the town comptroller shall so audit and allow. Any of such\nbills or any portion of any of such bills which the town board or the\ntown comptroller, as the case may be, shall refuse to audit and allow\nshall be the personal liability of the officer for which the fund was\nestablished and he shall promptly reimburse his petty cash fund in the\namount of such disallowances. If such reimbursement has not been made by\nthe time of the first payment of salary to such officer after the action\nof the town board or the town comptroller, as the case may be, in\ndisallowing an amount so expended, such amount shall be withheld from\nhis salary payment and, if necessary, subsequent salary payments and\npaid into the appropriate petty cash fund until an amount equal to the\namount so disallowed has been repaid to such petty cash fund. Any bond\nor undertaking filed by any town officer or department or office head\nshall be available to the town for recovery of any losses incurred by\nreason of the operation of the petty cash fund established for him.\n  2. Acquisition and conveyance of real property. May acquire by lease,\npurchase, in the manner provided by law, or by acquisition in the manner\nprovided by the eminent domain procedure law, any lands or rights\ntherein, either within or outside the town boundaries, required for any\npublic purpose, and may, upon the adoption of a resolution, convey or\nlease real property in the name of the town, which resolution shall be\nsubject to a permissive referendum. If the property or rights be\nacquired by acquisition, the town board may subject to the provisions of\nthe eminent domain procedure law at once enter into possession of the\nreal property or rights described when the judgment shall have been made\nand entered, and the town shall thereupon stand charged and responsible\nfor the prompt payment of the amount which may ultimately be awarded.\nLands or rights required for a district purpose shall be acquired by the\ntown board in the name of the district, and the cost thereof shall be a\ncharge upon and assessed against such district. Such district lands and\nrights may be sold or leased in the manner provided in subdivision\ntwelve of section one hundred ninety-eight of this chapter.\n  2-a. Acquisition and sale of personal property. May take, purchase,\nlease, sell and dispose of personal property as the purposes of the town\nmay require, except as otherwise provided by law.\n  3. Management, custody and control of town property. Shall have the\nmanagement, custody and control of all town lands, buildings and\nproperty of the town and keep them in good repair and may cause the same\nto be insured against loss or damage by fire or other hazard.\n  4. Indemnity insurance. May contract at the expense of the town for\ninsurance indemnifying the town against any loss arising from injuries\nto persons or property.\n  5. Vacancies. Whenever a vacancy shall occur or exist in any town\noffice, the town board or a majority of the members thereof, may appoint\na qualified person to fill the vacancy. If the appointment be made to\nfill a vacancy in an appointive office, the person so appointed shall\nhold office for the remainder of the unexpired term. If the appointment\nbe made to fill a vacancy in an elective office, the person so appointed\nshall hold office until the commencement of the calendar year next\nsucceeding the first annual election at which the vacancy may be filled.\nA person, otherwise qualified, who is a member of the town board at the\ntime the vacancy occurs may be appointed to fill the vacancy provided\nthat he shall have resigned prior to such appointment.\n  5-a. Removal of fire and health hazards and weeds. The town board may\nrequire the owners of land to cut, trim or remove from the land owned by\nthem brush, grass, rubbish, or weeds, or to spray poisonous shrubs or\nweeds on such land, and upon default may cause such grass, brush,\nrubbish or weeds to be cut, trimmed or removed and such poisonous shrubs\nor weeds to be sprayed by the town and the total expense of such\ncutting, trimming, removal or spraying may be assessed by the town board\non the real property on which such brush, grass, rubbish, weeds or\npoisonous shrubs or weeds were found, and the expense so assessed shall\nconstitute a lien and charge on the real property on which it is levied\nuntil paid or otherwise satisfied or discharged and shall be collected\nin the same manner and at the same time as other town charges. If the\nowner of said lands is a non-resident, a notice to so cut, trim or\nremove such brush, grass, rubbish or weeds or to spray such poisonous\nshrubs or weeds mailed to such owner addressed to his last known address\nshall be sufficient service thereof. The provisions of this subdivision\nshall not apply within the property lines of any lands or highway\neasements owned by another municipal corporation or political\nsubdivision of the state.\n  6. Award and execution of town contracts. May award contracts for any\nof the purposes authorized by law and the same shall be executed by the\nsupervisor in the name of the town after approval by the town board.\n  7. Franchises. Except as otherwise provided by law, may grant rights,\nfranchises, permissions or consents for the use of the streets,\nhighways, and public places or any part thereof or the space above or\nunder them or any of them, for any specific purpose authorized by law\nupon such terms and conditions as it may deem proper and as may be\npermitted by law. No such franchise, permission or consent shall be\ngranted without a public hearing, notice of which shall be given by the\npublication of a notice thereof in the official paper at least ten days\nbefore the meeting.\n  8. Gifts to town. May take by gift, grant, bequest or devise and hold\nreal and personal property absolutely or in trust for parks or gardens,\nor for the erection of statues, monuments, buildings or structures, or\nfor any public use, upon such terms or conditions as may be prescribed\nby the grantor or donor and accepted by said town, and provide for the\nproper administration of the same.\n  9. Naming and numbering streets, and providing street signs. May\ndesignate by name and number the streets, avenues, lots, public\nbuildings and places, and may cause a map of the town to be prepared and\nfiled in the office of the town clerk, and purchase, install and\nmaintain street signs showing the names of streets and avenues therein.\nSuch names may also be changed and altered as the town board may\ndetermine. Whenever the town board shall change the name or number of\nany street, avenue, public building or place, the town clerk shall\nwithin ten days thereafter notify the board of assessors and the\nplanning board, if any, of said town, the county clerk and county\nengineer of the county in which said town is located, and the\npost-office department of the United States thereof.\n  10. Street profiles. The town board may provide for the establishment\nof the profiles and grades of any accepted street, avenue or highway in\nthe town and upon the completion thereof shall cause the same to be\nfiled in the office of the town clerk and of the superintendent of\nhighways of the town.\n  10-a. Permits for filling or diver</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>