<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-74"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-74"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="74"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-74/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-74/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-74/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-74/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_74">
        <num>74</num>
        <heading>Effective date of alteration or division</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 74. Effective date of alteration or division. 1. When only the\nboundary lines are altered between two towns, the same shall be\neffective on the first of July next succeeding the adoption of the\nproposition. The town board of the respective towns shall prior thereto\nmake all necessary alterations in the election districts in such town.\nThe term of any town officer shall not be abridged by reason of any\nalteration in town lines.\n  2. When a town is divided into two or more towns, the same shall be\neffective for the purposes of exercise of governmental functions on the\nfirst day of January next succeeding the first biennial town election at\nwhich town officers for the new towns may be elected. All officers of\nthe town in office on such first day of January shall continue in\noffice, unless a vacancy occurs, until the expiration of the term for\nwhich elected or appointed. The town board shall prior to such effective\ndate, make all necessary alterations or creation of new election\ndistricts as provided in the election law.\n  * NB This section partially repealed by chapter 73/64. Certain\nprovisions were retained by opinion of the Atty. Gen. (Inf.)  October 1,\n1981;(Inf.) 195/1975; and (Inf.) 143/1977.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>