<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-79-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-79-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="79-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-79-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-79-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-79-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-79-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_79_A">
        <num>79-A</num>
        <heading>Dissolution of certain towns</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 79-a  Dissolution of certain towns. 1. Any town having no bonded\nindebtedness may be dissolved and may be annexed to and become a part of\nan adjoining town in the same county, upon compliance with the following\nconditions:\n  a. The submission at a special or biennial town election in the town\nproposed to be dissolved of a proposition, in the manner provided by\narticle six, for the dissolution of such town and the annexation of the\nterritory therein to a specified adjoining town in the same county, and\nthe approval of such proposition by a majority of the electors voting\nthereon at such election.\n  b. The submission at a special or biennial town election in such\nadjoining town, at the same time as the proposition provided for in the\nlast preceding paragraph is submitted, of a proposition, in the manner\nprovided by article six, for the annexation of the territory of the town\nproposed to be dissolved, and the approval of such proposition by a\nmajority of the duly qualified electors voting at such election.\n  2. If such proposition be so approved and adopted, the dissolution and\nannexation therein provided for shall become effective at the expiration\nof the thirty-first day of December of the odd numbered year next\nsucceeding the year in which such propositions are so approved and\nadopted except in the county of Broome where such dissolution and\nannexation shall become effective at the expiration of the next\nsucceeding even numbered year. Provided, however that such dissolution\nor annexation shall not affect a fire district or other special\nimprovement district in the territory to be annexed. No election of town\nofficers shall be held in the town so to be dissolved during the year\nimmediately preceding the time such dissolution becomes effective but\nvoters of such town shall have the right to vote at the election in such\nyear for officers of the town to which such town is to be annexed and\nthe board of elections shall make provision for the holding of such\nelection in such town. The terms of office of all town officers of such\ntown shall expire when such dissolution becomes effective, except\njustices of the peace who shall continue in office until the expiration\nof the term for which they were elected or appointed and who shall\nexercise all the powers and duties of and be entitled to compensation as\na justice of the peace of the town to which such dissolved town is\nannexed, provided that they shall not be members of the town board of\nsuch town. No successors to such justices of the peace of the town so\ndissolved shall be elected or appointed.\n  3. All the property and assets, real and personal, of a town so\ndissolved, shall become the property and assets of the town to which it\nis annexed, and all debts and charges of a town so dissolved shall be\nthe liability of and be paid by the town to which it is annexed. All\nfunds and sums of money held by such a town so dissolved or any officer\nthereof to the credit of such town shall be paid to the supervisor of\nthe town to which such dissolved town is annexed. All the books, records\nand documents of or on file with the town officers of a town so\ndissolved, shall be turned over at the expiration of their terms of\noffice to appropriate officers of the town to which such territory is\nannexed.\n  4. In case of dissolution and annexation as herein permitted, in the\nyear at the end of which the dissolution and annexation become\neffective, the retiring supervisor of the town to be so dissolved shall\npresent the assessment roll of such town, as completed by the assessors\nthereof, to the board of supervisors of the county and such board of\nsupervisors shall cause each of the assessments thereon to be\ntransferred and added to the assessment roll of the town to which such\ndissolved town is to be annexed, consolidated and treated as one tax\nroll and each of the pieces of property and all of the assessments so\ntransferred shall thenceforth, for tax purposes, be part of the taxable\nproperty and assessments of the town to which such dissolved town is to\nbe annexed.\n  5. In case of dissolution and annexation as herein permitted, the town\nboard of the town to which the territory of the dissolved town is\nannexed shall make a proper revision of the election districts in such\ntown.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>