<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-84"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-84"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="84"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-84/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-84/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-84/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-84/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_84">
        <num>84</num>
        <heading>Qualifications of electors at town elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 84. Qualifications of electors at town elections. 1. No person shall\nbe entitled to vote upon any proposition for raising, appropriating or\nexpending money or incurring any town liability, or for the sale or\nother disposition of town land or property, unless he or she is an\nelector of the town; nor shall he or she be entitled to vote upon any\nproposition for raising, appropriating or expending money or incurring\nany liability which shall be a charge wholly against a district or a\nportion of said town unless he or she is an elector.\n  2. The town board of a town may, by resolution adopted at a regular\nmeeting, determine that thereafter personal registration of voters shall\nbe required for special town elections. Such resolution and the notice\nhereinafter provided for shall specify the day or days, the place or\nplaces, and the hours during which a board or boards of registration\nshall meet for the purpose of preparing a register of voters of the town\nqualified to vote in such special elections, who shall present\nthemselves personally for registration for such special election. The\ntown clerk shall give notice at the expense of the town, by the\npublication of a notice in a newspaper published in said town, if there\nbe any, or, if there be none, in a newspaper published in the county\nhaving general circulation in the town, specifying the day or days, the\nplace or places, and hours during which the board or boards of\nregistration will meet for the purpose of preparing a register of\nqualified voters of the town as provided in this section. The first\npublication of such notice shall be at least ten days prior to the first\nday fixed by the town board on which boards of registration shall meet.\nIn addition, the town clerk shall post or cause to be posted in five\nconspicuous places in said town copies of such notice at least ten days\nprior to the first day fixed by the town board on which the boards of\nregistration shall meet.\n  3. In such event, the town board shall select from the list of\nelection inspectors previously designated for general election purposes,\nnot less than two nor more than four persons to constitute a board of\nregistration for each voting place designated by the town board,\nprovided, however, a town board may, by resolution adopted at a regular\nmeeting, determine that one or more boards of registration shall be\nreasonably capable of carrying out the personal registration\nrequirements, as provided in this section, for all voting places\ndesignated for such special town election. Each member of a board of\nregistration shall be entitled to compensation at a rate to be fixed by\nthe town board for time spent upon the duties of his office.\n  4. Such boards of registration shall meet on such days as the town\nboard shall, by said resolution designate, the last day of which shall\nnot be more than fifteen nor less than ten days preceding such special\ntown election at the place in each election district where the election\nis to be held, and at such hours as the town board shall designate,\nwhich shall include at least four consecutive hours between twelve\no'clock noon and nine o'clock in the evening of each day required for\nthe preparation of the register for such election, which shall include,\nat a minimum, a space for the name of the voter and his address within\nthe town, a space for the voter's signature to be signed on the day of\nthe election and a space in which there shall be entered the\nqualifications for voters as provided by this section. All the\nprovisions of the election law in relation to the registration of voters\nshall, so far as applicable, apply to the registration provided for by\nthis section and such special elections in such towns shall be conducted\nin the manner provided by this chapter and the election law, except that\nno person shall be entitled to vote thereat whose name does not appear\nupon the register of the voting place in which he claims to be entitled\nto vote.\n  5. In order to assist boards of registration in the preparation of\ntheir registers, the town clerk, prior to the first meeting of such\nboards of registration, shall obtain from the board of elections of the\ncounty in which such town is located, the list of names and addresses of\nall voters registered with such board of elections on or before the\ntwenty-third day before such special election. The town clerk shall\ndeliver the names and addresses of qualified voters to the appropriate\nboard or boards of registration on or before the first meeting of such\nboard or boards. At the first and subsequent meetings of the board of\nregistration for each voting place designated by the town board for such\nspecial town election, such board of registration shall place on the\nregister described in subdivision four hereof the names of all qualified\nvoters and all other qualified voters who personally appear, those\nvoters who have made application for early mail ballots, and those\nmilitary voters and such other voters who are absent by reason of\nconfining illness or physical disability or whose duties, occupation or\nbusiness required them to be outside of the state of New York, having\nthe qualifications of voters prescribed in this section and who have\nmade application for absentee ballots as certified to them by the town\nclerk.\n  6. The register prepared as provided in this section shall immediately\nupon its completion and not more than eighteen hours thereafter; be\nfiled in the office of the town clerk, and thereafter shall at all\nreasonable times be open to inspection by any qualified voter of the\ntown on each day up to and including the day next preceding the day set\nfor such town election, except Saturdays, Sundays and holidays.\n  Additions, corrections, challenges and judicial review of registration\nprocedure shall so far as practicable conform to sections 5-218, 5-220\nand 16-108 of the election law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>