<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TWN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-86"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-86"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="86"/>
          <FRBRname value="TWN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-86/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-86/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-86/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/twn/section-86/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_86">
        <num>86</num>
        <heading>Town elections in the county of Broome</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 86. Town elections in the county of Broome. Biennial town elections\nin the several towns of the county of Broome, for the election of town\nofficers and for the consideration of such questions as may be proposed\nby the town board or the duly qualified electors, pursuant to the\nprovisions of this chapter, shall be held on the Tuesday next succeeding\nthe first Monday in November of every even-numbered year.  All other\ntown elections in towns of such county are special elections.  All\nelective town officers of the several towns in the county in office at\nthe time this section takes effect, shall continue in office for the\nterms for which elected and until their successors have been elected and\nhave qualified. The town officers to be elected at any such election\nshall be those and only those elective town officers of a town of the\nsecond class, unless such town shall have determined to become a town of\nthe first class, pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, and shall\nbe elected for terms prescribed by this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>