<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11">
        <num>11</num>
        <heading>Adjutant general</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11. Adjutant general.  The adjutant general shall serve as such at\nthe pleasure of the governor and, under his direction, shall exercise\ncontrol over the division of military and naval affairs of the executive\ndepartment of the state.  The adjutant general may perform any act\nauthorized by this chapter or the regulations issued pursuant to this\nchapter through or with the aid of such officers, officials or bureaus\nof the division of military and naval affairs as he may designate.  It\nshall be the duty of the adjutant general to direct the planning and\nemployment of the forces of the organized militia in carrying out their\nstate military mission; to establish unified command of state forces\nwhenever they shall be jointly engaged; to act as the state director of\ncivil defense for the state; to submit an annual written report to the\ngovernor in such form as the governor may prescribe; and to perform such\nother duties as the governor may direct. The adjutant general may\nappoint such assistant adjutants general as may be necessary. Whenever\nthe governor and those who would act in succession to the governor under\nthe constitution and laws of the state shall be unable to perform the\nduties of commander-in-chief, the adjutant general shall command the\nmilitia.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>