<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.57"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.57"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="130.57"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.57/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.57/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.57/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.57/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_130_57">
        <num>130.57</num>
        <heading>Effective date of sentences</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_57__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a sentence of a\ncourt-martial as lawfully adjudged and approved includes a forfeiture of\npay or allowances in addition to confinement not suspended or deferred,\nthe forfeiture may apply to pay or allowances becoming due on or after\nthe date such sentence is approved by the convening authority and to any\npay or allowances accrued before such date.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_57__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any period of confinement included in a sentence of a\ncourt-martial shall begin to run from the date the sentence is adjudged\nby the court-martial, but periods during which the sentence to\nconfinement is suspended or deferred shall be excluded in computing the\nservice of the term of confinement. Regulations adopted pursuant to this\nchapter may provide that sentences of confinement shall not be executed\nuntil approved by such officers as may be designated in such\nregulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_57__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All other sentences of court-martial shall become effective on the\ndate ordered executed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_57__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On application by an accused who is under sentence to confinement\nthat has not been ordered executed, the convening authority or, if the\naccused is no longer under his jurisdiction, the officer exercising\nsimilar court-martial convening authority over the command to which the\naccused is currently assigned, may in his sole discretion defer service\nof a sentence to confinement.  The deferment shall terminate when the\nsentence is ordered executed. The deferment may be rescinded at any time\nby the officer who granted it or, if the accused is no longer under his\njurisdiction, by the officer exercising similar court-martial\njurisdiction over the command to which the accused is currently\nassigned.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>