<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.65"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.65"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="130.65"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.65/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.65/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.65/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.65/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_130_65">
        <num>130.65</num>
        <heading>Review by board of military review and approval by the adjutant general</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_65__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state judge advocate shall establish a board\nof military review which shall be composed of not less than three\nofficers of the organized militia or on the state reserve list or state\nretired list, each of whom shall be a member of the bar of the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_65__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state judge advocate shall refer to a board of military review\nthe record in each case of trial by court-martial:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130_65__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in which the sentence, as approved, extends to, dismissal of a\ncommissioned officer, dishonorable or bad-conduct discharge, or any\nconfinement; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_130_65__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the right to appellate review has not been waived or an appeal has\nnot been withdrawn under section 130.61 of this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_65__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a case referred to it, the board of military review may act\nonly with respect to the findings and sentence as approved by the\nconvening authority. It may affirm only such findings of guilty and the\nsentence or such part or amount of the sentence, as it finds correct in\nlaw and fact and determines, on the basis of the entire record, should\nbe approved.  In considering the record, it may weigh the evidence,\njudge the credibility of witnesses, and determine controverted questions\nof fact, recognizing that the trial court saw and heard the witnesses.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_65__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the board of military review sets aside the findings and\nsentence, it may, except where the setting aside is based on lack of\nsufficient evidence in the record to support the findings, order a\nrehearing. If it sets aside the findings and sentence and does not order\na rehearing, it shall order that the charges be dismissed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_65__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The action taken by the board of review shall be subject to the\napproval of the adjutant general. If the adjutant general disapproves\nthe action taken by the board of review, he may take any action on the\nsentence or findings that could be taken by the convening authority\nunder section 130.60 of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_65__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state judge advocate shall, unless there is to be further\naction by the governor, instruct the convening authority to take action\nin accordance with the decision of the board of military review as\napproved by the adjutant general. If the board of military review has\nordered a rehearing but the convening authority finds a rehearing\nimpracticable, he may dismiss the charges.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_65__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No member of a board of military review shall be eligible to\nreview the record of any trial if such member served as investigating\nofficer in the case or served as a member of the court-martial before\nwhich such trial was conducted, or served as military judge, trial or\ndefense counsel, or reviewing officer of such trial.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>