<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.32"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.32"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="130.32"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-130.32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_130_32">
        <num>130.32</num>
        <heading>Investigation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_32__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No charge or specification shall be\nreferred to a general court-martial for trial until a thorough and\nimpartial investigation of all the matters set forth therein has been\nmade. This investigation shall include inquiries as to the truth of the\nmatter set forth in the charges, form of charges, and the disposition\nwhich should be made of the case in the interest of justice and\ndiscipline.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_32__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The accused shall be advised of the charges against him and of his\nright to be represented at such investigation by counsel. Upon his own\nrequest he shall be represented by civilian counsel if provided by him\nat his own expense, or military counsel of his own selection if such\ncounsel be reasonably available, or by counsel appointed by the adjutant\ngeneral. At such investigation full opportunity shall be given to the\naccused to cross-examine witnesses against him if they are available and\nto present anything he may desire in his own behalf, either in defense\nor mitigation, and the investigating officer shall examine available\nwitnesses requested by the accused. If the charges are forwarded after\nsuch investigation, they shall be accompanied by a statement of the\nsubstance of the testimony taken on both sides and a copy thereof shall\nbe given to the accused.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_32__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If an investigation of the subject matter of an offense has been\nconducted prior to the time the accused is charged with the offense, and\nif the accused was present at such investigation and afforded the\nopportunities for representation, cross-examination, and presentation\nprescribed in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_32__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, no further investigation\nof that charge is necessary under this section unless it is demanded by\nthe accused after he is informed of the charge. A demand for further\ninvestigation entitled the accused to recall witnesses for further\ncross-examination and to offer any new evidence in his own behalf.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130_32__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The requirements of this section shall be binding on all persons\nadministering this code, but failure to follow them in any case shall\nnot divest a military court of jurisdiction.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>