<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131.8"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.8/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.8/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_8">
        <num>131.8</num>
        <heading>Payment of fines and disposition thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131.8. Payment of fines and disposition thereof.  Fines may be paid\nto a military court or to an officer executing its process.  The amount\nof any such fine may be noted upon any state roll or account for pay of\nthe delinquent and deducted from any pay or allowance due or thereafter\nto become due him, until said fine is liquidated.  Any sum so deducted\nfrom any state pay or allowance shall be turned into the military court\nwhich imposed the fine and shall be paid over by the officer receiving\nthe same in like manner as provided for other fines and moneys collected\nunder a sentence of a summary court-martial.  Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of any other law, a fine or penalty imposed by a military\ncourt upon an officer or enlisted man shall be paid by the officer\ncollecting the same within thirty days to the chief of staff of the\nstate and shall form a part of, be credited to and expended from the\nmilitary fund of the unit of which the person paying the same is a\nmember or to which he is detailed or attached.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>