<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-131.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_1">
        <num>131.1</num>
        <heading>Courts of inquiry</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_1__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Courts of inquiry to investigate any\nmatter may be convened by the governor or by any other person designated\nby the governor for that purpose whether or not the persons involved\nhave requested such an inquiry.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_1__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A court of inquiry shall consist of three or more officers.\nFor each court of inquiry the convening authority shall also appoint\ncounsel for the court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_1__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person subject to this code whose conduct is subject to\ninquiry shall be designated as a party. Any person subject to this code\nor employed in the division of military and naval affairs who has a\ndirect interest in the subject of inquiry shall have the right to be\ndesignated as a party upon request to the court. Any person designated\nas a party shall be given due notice and shall have the right to be\npresent, to be represented by counsel, to cross-examine witnesses, and\nto introduce evidence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_1__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Members of a court of inquiry may be challenged by a party, but\nonly for cause stated to the court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_1__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members, counsel, the reporter, and interpreters of courts of\ninquiry shall take an oath or affirmation to faithfully perform their\nduties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_1__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Witnesses may be summoned to appear and testify and be examined\nbefore courts of inquiry as provided for courts-martial.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_1__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Courts of inquiry shall make findings of fact but shall not\nexpress opinions or make recommendations unless required to do so by the\nconvening authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131_1__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each court of inquiry shall keep a record of its proceedings,\nwhich shall be authenticated by the signatures of the president and\ncounsel for the court and forwarded to the convening authority. In case\nthe record cannot be authenticated by the president it shall be signed\nby a member in lieu of the president and in case the record cannot be\nauthenticated by the counsel for the court it shall be signed by a\nmember in lieu of the counsel.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>