<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-179"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-179"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="179"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_179">
        <num>179</num>
        <heading>Costs of construction, repair, maintenance and operation of armories, camps, ranges and other facilities, a charge upon the state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 179. Costs of construction, repair, maintenance and operation of\narmories, camps, ranges and other facilities, a charge upon the state.\n1. The costs of construction, reconstruction, repair, rehabilitation and\nimprovement of armories, camps, ranges, bases, buildings, structures and\nother facilities under the jurisdiction of the division of military and\nnaval affairs, including armories and armory property located in the\ncity of New York the title to which is vested in the corporation of the\ncity of New York, and the costs of maintenance and operation including\npersonal service, furniture and furnishings, equipment and supplies for\nthe same and the costs of repairing, renewing, replacing or maintaining\nthe pavement of streets, gutters, curbing, flagging of sidewalks,\nfences, sewers and water pipes in their connection in, on or with the\nsite of any such armory, camp, range, base, building, structure or other\nfacility shall be a charge upon the state, except to the extent that\npayment of such costs in whole or in part may be otherwise provided for.\n  2. All such costs which are a charge upon the state shall be paid out\nof any moneys of the state available therefor, upon certification, audit\nand approval in the manner provided by law, and subject to all\napplicable provisions of law relating to expenditure of moneys of the\nstate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>