<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-180"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-180"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="180"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-180/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-180/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-180/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-180/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_180">
        <num>180</num>
        <heading>Armories and other facilities in the city of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 180. Armories and other facilities in the city of New York.  1.  All\narmories and other facilities located in the city of New York and\ndevoted to the use of the organized militia, title to which is vested in\nthe corporation of the city of New York, and all armory equipment,\nfurnishings, materials and other property furnished or supplied to\narmories in the city of New York by such city or otherwise pursuant to\nthe provisions of this chapter as existing prior to July first, nineteen\nhundred forty-two shall continue to be available, used and applied to\nand for armory or other military purposes in accordance with the\nprovisions of this chapter, without charge by the city of New York to\nthe state notwithstanding any provision of this chapter or other law.\n  2. The state or the United States or the state and the United States\nacting jointly is or are hereby authorized, as the adjutant general\nshall determine to be necessary and provided that funds have been\nappropriated or provided by the state or by the United States or by both\nfor such purposes, to construct or demolish an armory or building,\nstructure or facility for the use of the organized militia and to\nreconstruct, repair, rehabilitate, improve, equip, furnish, maintain and\noperate such armory, building, structure or facility on land owned by\nthe city of New York and available, used and applied to and for armory\npurposes or other military purposes. Such armory, building, structure or\nfacility shall be available, used and applied to and for armory or other\nmilitary purposes without charge by the city of New York to the state or\nto the United States. The cost of such construction, demolition,\nreconstruction, repair, rehabilitation, improvement, equipping,\nfurnishing, maintenance and operation of such armory, building,\nstructure or facility shall be borne by the state or by the United\nStates or jointly by both and not by the city of New York.\n  3. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nany armory located in the city of New York and devoted to the use of the\norganized militia, title to which is vested in the corporation of the\ncity of New York, may be released to the city of New York by the\nadjutant general, acting for and on behalf and in the name of the people\nof the state of New York, upon such terms and conditions and for such\nconsideration arrived at after an appraisal, as may be agreed upon\nbetween such city and the adjutant general and approved by the director\nof the budget. A release hereby authorized shall be executed by the\nadjutant general under his official seal and, upon being duly\nacknowledged by him and such acknowledgment duly certified, may be\nrecorded in the office of the clerk or register of the county where such\narmory is situated; provided, however, that such release shall not be\nvalid without the approval thereof by the attorney general, as to its\nform and manner of execution, endorsed thereon or annexed thereto. All\nmoneys paid by the city of New York for the release herein authorized\nshall be received by the state comptroller and deposited by him to the\ncredit of the capital projects fund established by section ninety-three\nof the state finance law and shall be available, after appropriation by\nthe legislature, only for construction, reconstruction or improvement of\narmory facilities, including acquisition of real property, if required.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>