<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-182"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-182"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="182"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-182/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-182/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-182/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-182/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_182">
        <num>182</num>
        <heading>Control of armories and other facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 182. Control of armories and other facilities.  1. All armories,\narsenals, camps, ranges, bases and other facilities owned, leased or\nmaintained by the state or by the United States for the use of the\norganized militia and all activities conducted therein shall be under\nthe general charge and control of and shall be regulated by the adjutant\ngeneral. He shall be responsible to the governor for the proper\nexpenditure of all moneys appropriated therefor.\n  2. When two or more units of different forces of the organized militia\nare stationed in one armory, arsenal, camp, range, base or other\nfacility, the adjutant general shall designate the officer to be in\ndirect charge and control thereof, shall apportion the quarters and\nfacilities therein to be occupied by each unit and shall regulate the\nmilitary use and the care thereof. The adjutant general shall also\ndesignate the officer to be in direct charge and control of any armory,\narsenal, camp, range, base or other facility which the adjutant general\nmay retain under his sole jurisdiction.\n  3. Except as provided in subdivision two hereof, the commander of the\nforce concerned shall designate the officer to be in direct charge and\ncontrol of each armory, arsenal, camp, range, base or other facility.\nAll officers so designated pursuant to this subdivision and subdivision\ntwo hereof shall observe and enforce all laws, orders and regulations\napplicable to such armory, arsenal, camp, range, base or other facility,\ntheir furnishings, equipment, contents and all activities conducted\ntherein and to the persons employed therein. They shall perform such\nother duties and functions as may be prescribed by the adjutant general.\n  4. Subject to the regulations of the adjutant general, officers in\ncharge and control so designated may establish and conduct stores,\nrestaurants, messes and places of recreation in the armory, arsenal,\ncamp, range, base or other facility under their charge and control or\nthey may enter into agreements with responsible parties for establishing\nand conducting the same.\n  5. The adjutant general and any officer designated by him, shall have\naccess to all parts of all armories and other facilities at all times.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>