<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-187"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-187"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="187"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-187/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-187/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-187/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-187/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_187">
        <num>187</num>
        <heading>Armory employees; grades, employment, duties and compensation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 187. Armory employees; grades, employment, duties and compensation.\n1. Positions created to provide for the security, maintenance and\noperation of armories, including the surrounding premises and public\nproperty located therein, notwithstanding the provisions of any other\nlaw, shall be classified and allocated to salary grades for comparable\npositions in the classified service of the state as set forth in section\none hundred thirty of the civil service law.\n  2. Subject to the provisions of this chapter and within the\nappropriation therefor, the adjutant general shall employ, assign,\ntransfer and discharge as many employees of each classification or grade\nas may be necessary. Subject to the approval of the director of the\nbudget, the adjutant general may classify or reclassify, allocate or\nreallocate any position established under subdivision one of this\nsection for the purpose of providing appropriate title, salary grade and\nrate of compensation which may be descriptive of duties and\nresponsibilities.  Notwithstanding any other law or any general or\nspecial statute to the contrary, when salary grades or rates of\ncompensation for the comparable classified service positions of the\nstate as contained in section one hundred thirty of the civil service\nlaw are amended, the salary grades or rates of compensation of positions\nauthorized by subdivision one of this section shall be adjusted\ncorrespondingly.\n  3. Armory employees shall perform duties as prescribed by the adjutant\ngeneral and by the officer in charge and control of the armory in which\nthey are employed.\n  4. The adjutant general is hereby authorized to employ any incumbent\narmory employee appointed pursuant to former section one hundred\neighty-seven of this chapter as it existed on March thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-one, in a position created pursuant to this\nsection but no such employee shall thereby suffer any diminution in the\nannual amount of compensation received by him on such date.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>