<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-188"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-188"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="188"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-188/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-188/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-188/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-188/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_188">
        <num>188</num>
        <heading>Annual increments; compensation on promotion, demotion, transfer, reclassification, reinstatement or reallocation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 188. Annual increments; compensation on promotion, demotion,\ntransfer, reclassification, reinstatement or reallocation.  1. Any\nemployee holding a position or employed pursuant to provisions of\nsection one hundred eighty-seven of this chapter shall receive the\nminimum compensation of the classification or grade to which his\nposition is allocated, plus the number of increments which corresponds\nwith the number of his years of service in such position, unless his\nservice during the year immediately preceding shall have been found to\nbe inefficient and unsatisfactory under regulations issued pursuant to\nthis chapter.\n  2. Annual increments shall take effect on the first day of each fiscal\nyear, subject, however, to the provisions of section forty-four of the\nstate finance law. The eligibility of an employee to receive such an\nincrement shall be determined in the same manner as the eligibility of\nan employee in the classified service would be determined under the\nprovisions of subdivision six of section one hundred thirty-one of the\ncivil service law. No employee shall receive an increment which will\nresult in an annual compensation in excess of the maximum established\nfor his position under this article.\n  3. If any such employee is promoted, demoted, transferred or\nreinstated, to or in a position included in section one hundred\neighty-seven of this chapter, his compensation in the new position shall\nbe determined in the same manner as the salary of an employee in the\nclassified service of the state would be determined under the provisions\nof section one hundred thirty-one of the civil service law.\n  4. If the position of any such employee is reallocated, his\ncompensation in the new title shall be adjusted in the same manner as\nthe salary of an employee in the classified service of the state would\nbe adjusted under the provisions of section one hundred thirty-two of\nthe civil service law.\n  5. If the position of any incumbent armory employee appointed pursuant\nto section one hundred eighty-seven of this chapter, is allocated to a\nsalary grade for a position comparable to one in the classified service\nof the state as set forth in section one hundred thirty of the civil\nservice law, such incumbent shall be paid the minimum salary of the new\ngrade and shall be eligible to receive the increments for such grade\nbased on the number of his years of service in the position as it\nexisted on March thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-one.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>