<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-19"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-19"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-19/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-19/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-19/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-19/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19">
        <num>19</num>
        <heading>Employees of the division of military and naval affairs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 19. Employees of the division of military and naval affairs.  1.\nWithin the amounts appropriated therefor, the adjutant general and the\ncommanding general or commanding officer of each force of the organized\nmilitia may employ and discharge such personnel, including officers of\nthe organized militia on permanent duty, as may be required in the\noffices, bureaus, camps and headquarters of their respective commands.\n  2. Within the amounts appropriated therefor the adjutant general may\nemploy and discharge such other personnel as may be authorized by this\nchapter.\n  3. Personnel employed in the division of military and naval affairs,\nother than civilian employees performing the functions of the state\ncivil defense commission, shall be considered as being in the military\nservice and not in the civil service of the state.\n  4. The adjutant general shall promulgate rules and regulations\npertaining to the work schedules, number of hours of work per week and\nper day, duties, annual leave, sick leave, leaves of absence, holidays,\nemployment, promotion, demotion, assignment, transfer, discipline,\ndischarge and any other matters pertinent to the administration of all\nemployees authorized by this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>