<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2">
        <num>2</num>
        <heading>Militia of the state; division and composition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2. Militia of the state; division and composition. 1. The militia of\nthe state shall be divided into the organized militia, the state reserve\nlist, the state retired list and the unorganized militia. The organized\nmilitia shall be composed of the New York army national guard; the New\nYork air national guard; the inactive national guard; the New York naval\nmilitia; the New York guard whenever such a state force shall be duly\norganized and such additional forces as may be created by the governor.\n  2. The unorganized militia shall consist of all able-bodied male\nresidents of the state between the ages of seventeen and forty-five who\nare not serving in any force of the organized militia or who are not on\nthe state reserve list or the state retired list and who are or who have\ndeclared their intention to become citizens of the United States,\nsubject, however, to such exemptions from military duty as are created\nby the laws of the United States.\n  3. The state reserve list and the state retired list shall include the\npersons who are lawfully carried thereon on the effective date of this\nact and such persons who may be transferred thereto or placed thereon by\nthe governor in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.\n  4. The terms "organized militia," "all or any part of the organized\nmilitia," "organized militia or any part thereof" and "organized militia\nor any force thereof," whenever used in this chapter, unless a different\nmeaning is plainly required by the context, shall be deemed to include\nany unit, command, component, element, headquarters, staff or cadre\nthereof as well as any member or members.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>