<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="211"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_211">
        <num>211</num>
        <heading>Salaries, office and traveling expenses of certain personnel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 211. Salaries, office and traveling expenses of certain personnel.\n1. There shall be allowed annually such sum, not exceeding the amount\nappropriated therefor, as may be necessary for the salaries of the\nofficers and enlisted personnel of the organized militia on permanent\nduty in the offices, bureaus, arsenals, camps, headquarters and other\nfacilities of the forces and commands of the organized militia and of\nthe division of military and naval affairs.\n  2. There shall be allowed annually such sum, not exceeding the amount\nappropriated therefor, as may be necessary for the office expenses,\nexpenses for personal services, and other expenses of the offices,\nbureaus, arsenals, camps, headquarters, courts, boards and other\nfacilities of the forces and commands of the organized militia and of\nthe division of military and naval affairs.\n  3. There shall be allowed annually such sum, not exceeding the amount\nappropriated therefor, as may be necessary for necessary traveling\nexpenses, subsistence or per diem allowances of persons in the military\nservice of the state when traveling on duty and under orders.\n  4. The amounts allowed under subdivisions one, two and three of this\nsection shall be expended as the adjutant general may direct, subject to\nthe provisions of sections one hundred eighty-seven, one hundred\neighty-eight and one hundred eighty-nine of this chapter with respect to\narmory employees.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>