<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-22-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-22-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="22-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-22-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-22-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-22-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-22-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_22_A">
        <num>22-A</num>
        <heading>Compacts for military aid</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 22-a. Compacts for military aid.  1. a. With the prior or subsequent\nconsent of the congress of the United States, the governor is authorized\nto enter into, amend, supplement and implement agreements or compacts\nwith the executive authorities of other states and the Dominion of\nCanada and any of the provinces thereof, providing for mutual military\naid, and matters incidental thereto, in case of invasion or other\nhostile action, disaster, insurrection, or imminent danger thereof.\n  b. Such agreements or compacts may include but shall not be limited to\nprovisions for joint military action against a common enemy; for the\nprotection of bridges, tunnels, ferries, pipelines, communication\nfacilities and other vital installations, plants and facilities; for the\nmilitary support of civil defense agencies; for the fresh pursuit, by\nthe organized militia or military forces or any part thereof of a\nsignatory into the jurisdiction of any other signatory, of persons\nacting or appearing to act in the interest of any enemy government or\nseeking or appearing to seek to overthrow the government of the United\nStates or of any signatory; for the powers, duties, rights, privileges\nand immunities of the members of the organized militia or military\nforces of any signatory while so engaged outside their own jurisdiction;\nfor such other matters as are of a military nature, or incidental\nthereto, and which the governor may deem necessary or proper to promote\nthe health, safety and welfare of the people of this state; for the\nallocation of all costs and expenses arising from the planning and\noperation of such agreements or compacts.\n  2. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed or interpreted\nas expressing a limitation, directly or indirectly, of the power of the\ngovernor to enter into, and to amend or supplement, such compacts, with\nlegal force and effect and without the legislative authorization\nexpressed herein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>