<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220">
        <num>220</num>
        <heading>Expenses of military courts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 220. Expenses of military courts.  1. While engaged in the execution\nof the duties imposed upon him or authorized to be performed by him by a\nmilitary court, a marshal, police officer or peace officer shall be paid\ntwo dollars for each day actually employed in the execution of such\nduties and mileage or actual necessary traveling expenses. Mileage shall\nbe computed at the rate of ten cents for each mile necessarily traveled\ngoing and returning to serve any process or mandate of a military court,\nthe distance to be computed from the place where it is served to the\nplace where it is returnable.\n  2. In addition to the compensation provided in subdivision one hereof,\na marshal of a military court, police officer or a peace officer as\ndefined in section 2.10 of the criminal procedure law to whom a warrant\nis delivered for the collection of a fine imposed by the sentence of a\nmilitary court shall be paid by retaining to his own use twenty-five per\ncentum of the fines collected by him under such warrant. Said percentage\nshall be taxed by the officer issuing such warrant and shall be endorsed\nthereon and added to the amount of the fine collectible to satisfy the\nsentence of the military court.\n  3. The compensation and necessary expenses of a summary court-martial\nand of the clerk thereof and the compensation and necessary expenses\npayable to marshals, police officers and peace officers pursuant to\nsubdivision two of this section shall be paid from the military fund of\nthe unit of the organized militia whose commanding officer appointed the\nmilitary court in the same manner as other accounts are paid from such\nfund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>