<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-222"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-222"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="222"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-222/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-222/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-222/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-222/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_222">
        <num>222</num>
        <heading>Headquarters allowances</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 222. Headquarters allowances.  1. On the certificate of the adjutant\ngeneral, the comptroller shall draw his warrant upon the treasurer in\nfavor of the commanding officer of any unit to which an allowance is\nmade for the headquarters thereof in a sum not exceeding two thousand\ndollars. Such allowances in specified amounts shall be available for the\nheadquarters of units as designated by the adjutant general in a\nschedule filed by him and approved by the director of the budget within\nthe amount of annual appropriations therefor.\n  2. The funds thus allowed shall only be expended by the respective\ncommanding officers of the organizations to which the fund is allowed in\naccordance with regulations approved by the adjutant general.\n  3. The adjutant general is hereby authorized and empowered to draw,\nuse, apply or place in escrow to the benefit of any unit of the\norganized militia and of units of the organized militia in the active\nmilitary service of the United States, or otherwise to direct the\ndisposition of any and all moneys and balances remaining on deposit to\nthe credit of the custodian of any headquarters allowance of any unit of\nthe organized militia which has been disbanded, deactivated, or ordered\nor called into the active military service of the United States, or to\npay bills chargeable against such headquarters allowance of disbanded or\ndeactivated units or of units ordered or called into the active military\nservice of the United States from such moneys. The custodian of any\nheadquarters allowance shall pay to the adjutant general, upon his\norder, all moneys remaining in his hands to the credit of any disbanded\nor deactivated unit of the organized militia or of a unit ordered or\ncalled into the active military service of the United States.\n  All unexpended and unobligated balances of headquarters allowances\nremaining to the credit of any unit of the organized militia or of any\ndisbanded or deactivated unit, and of any unit ordered or called into\nthe active military service of the United States shall at the end of\neach fiscal year be turned over to the adjutant general and transmitted\nby him to the state treasurer.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>