<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-238-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-238-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="238-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-238-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-238-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-238-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-238-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_238_C">
        <num>238-C</num>
        <heading>Wearing of uniforms; prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 238-c. Wearing of uniforms; prohibited.  a. It shall be unlawful for\nany person to appear in any public place or in the public view attired\nin any uniform similar to that worn by the military, semi-military,\nnaval, police, storm troop or other official or semi-official forces of\nany foreign state, nation or government, or attired in any distinctive\npart or parts of such a uniform, or to assemble with other persons\nsimilarly attired in any camp, drill ground or other place for the\npurpose of engaging in military drill or training or other military\npractices.\n  b. It shall be unlawful for any person to appear in any public place,\nor in the public view attired in any uniform similar to that worn by the\nmembers of the storm troop of Nazi Germany, or attired in any\ndistinctive part or parts of such a uniform, or to assemble with other\npersons similarly attired in any camp, drill ground or other place.\n  c. It shall be unlawful for any person to appear in any public place\nor in the public view attired in the uniform or wearing the distinctive\ngarment of any association of persons of whatsoever nature or form which\nengages in, adopts, or imitates the drill formations, salutes or other\nmethods or practices or the symbols of any foreign military,\nsemi-military, naval, police, storm troop or similar foreign\norganization, or to assemble with other persons similarly attired in any\ncamp, drill ground or other place for the purpose of engaging in\nmilitary drill or training or other military practices.\n  d. It shall be unlawful for the proprietor, manager or keeper of a\npublic hall, public garden, theatre or any other place of public\nmeeting, resort or amusement to permit therein any assemblage of persons\nattired as prohibited in this section.\n  e. It shall be unlawful for any person to appear in any public place\nor in the public view attired in the uniform or wearing the distinctive\ngarment of any association of persons of whatsoever nature or form which\nengages in, adopts, or imitates the drill formations, salutes or other\nmethods or practices or the symbols of the members of the storm troop of\nNazi Germany or similar foreign organization, or to assemble with other\npersons similarly attired in any camp, drill ground or other place for\nthe purpose of engaging in military drill or training or other military\npractices.\n  f. This section shall not apply to the officers or members of the\nmilitary, semi-military, naval, police or other official or\nsemi-official forces of any foreign state, nation or government lawfully\nwithin the state of New York, the Knights of Columbus, the Boy Scouts of\nAmerica, any student of any school or academy recognized by the board of\nregents of the state of New York, nor to the members of the cast of any\nstage or motion picture production characterizing the officials of a\nforeign state, nation or government; provided, however, that in any\nprosecution hereunder it shall be presumed that a person wearing the\nuniform of a foreign state, nation or government or of any of its\nofficial or semi-official forces or attired in any distinctive part or\nparts of such a uniform, was not at the time of the alleged violation of\nthis section a member of any of the organizations excepted herein.\n  g. A violation of any of the provisions of this section shall be a\nclass A misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>