<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-239"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-239"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="239"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-239/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-239/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-239/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-239/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_239">
        <num>239</num>
        <heading>Trespassers and disturbers to be placed in arrest; sales and gambling prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 239. Trespassers and disturbers to be placed in arrest; sales and\ngambling prohibited.  1. Any person who shall trespass upon any armory,\narsenal, camp, range, base or other facility of the organized militia or\nother place where any unit of the organized militia is performing\nmilitary duty, or who shall in any way or manner interrupt or molest the\ndischarge of his military duties by any member of the organized militia\nor of the armed forces of the United States or who shall trespass or\nprevent the passage of troops of the organized militia or of the armed\nforces of the United States in the performance of their military duties\nmay be placed in arrest by the commanding officer of the unit performing\nsuch military duty at the place where the offense is committed and may\nbe held in arrest during the continuance of the performance of such\nmilitary duty.\n  2. The commanding officer of any unit of the organized militia\nperforming military duty in or at any armory, arsenal, camp, range, base\nor other facility of the organized militia or other place where such\nunit is performing military duty may prohibit persons who hawk, peddle,\nvend or sell goods, wares, merchandise, food products or beverages upon\nthe streets and highways from conducting sales or auctions, and may\nprohibit all gambling within the limits of such armory, arsenal, camp,\nrange, base or other facility of the organized militia or other place\nwhere such unit is performing military duty or within such limits not\nexceeding one mile therefrom as he may prescribe. Such commanding\nofficer may in his discretion abate as common nuisances all such sales,\nauctions and gambling.\n  3. Any person who trespasses upon any missile site under the control\nor jurisdiction of the New York army national guard, or who, in any way\ninterrupts or molests the performance of duty by any person assigned to\nsuch site, may be apprehended and detained in custody at the site, by\nany member of the New York army national guard or any person performing\nduty at such site. Any person so apprehended and detained shall be\ndelivered, without delay, to a police officer, as defined in subdivision\nthirty-four of section 1.20 of the criminal procedure law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>