<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-B*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-B*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="243-B*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-B*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-B*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-B*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-B*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_243_B*2">
        <num>243-B*2</num>
        <heading>Payment of certain pension contributions by the city of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 243-b. Payment of certain pension contributions by the city of New\nYork. As used in this section, the term New York city veteran of the\nPersian Gulf emergency means a member of the New York city employees'\nretirement system, the teachers' retirement system of the city of New\nYork, the New York city police pension fund, the New York city fire\ndepartment pension fund, or the board of education retirement system of\nthe city of New York, who is a member of a reserve component of the\narmed forces of the United States ordered to active duty on or after\nAugust first, nineteen hundred ninety and prior to January first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-three, in response to the nation's military\nmission in the Persian Gulf, who is not receiving full salary from a\nparticipating employer, and who is otherwise eligible to receive\nretirement service credit in any of such systems or funds for active\nduty pursuant to section two hundred forty-two or two hundred\nforty-three of this article, or pursuant to the federal Veterans'\nReemployment Rights Act.\n  Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all benefits payable by a\nretirement system or pension fund to a New York city veteran of the\nPersian Gulf emergency due to the retirement or death of such member\nshall be calculated as though such member had actually paid the amount\nof all contributions, together with applicable interest thereon, which\nsuch member would have been required to make if, during the period of\nactive duty, because of such Persian Gulf emergency, such member had\nbeen present and continuously performed the duties of the position held\nat the time of his or her entry into active duty.\n  Each such member shall be credited with such contributions made on his\nor her behalf. The applicable interest thereon shall be calculated as to\neach such member under the applicable provisions of law governing the\ncrediting of interest to employee contributions for each such member.\n  Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any additional liability\nattributable to this section shall be paid into the retirement system or\npension fund by participating employers at such times and in such\namounts as determined by the actuary in a manner consistent with\nappropriate actuarial methodology.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 243-b's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>