<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-11-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="243-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-243-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_243_D">
        <num>243-D</num>
        <heading>Non-contributory retirement service credit for members of the New York state and local retirement systems, the New York city retirement s...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 243-d. Non-contributory retirement service credit for members of the\nNew York state and local retirement systems, the New York city\nretirement systems or the New York state teachers' retirement system\ncalled to active military duty on or after September eleventh, two\nthousand one. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any member of\nthe New York state and local employees' retirement system, the New York\ncity retirement systems, the New York state and local police and fire\nretirement system, or the New York state teachers' retirement system who\nis called to active military duty on or after September eleventh, two\nthousand one and prior to January first, two thousand six, who is not\nreceiving his or her full salary from a participating employer and is\notherwise eligible to receive retirement service credit in such system\nfor such active military duty pursuant to section two hundred forty-two\nor two hundred forty-three of this article, shall not be required to\nmake member contributions to receive such credit.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>