<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-246"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-246"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="246"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-246/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-246/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-246/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-246/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_246">
        <num>246</num>
        <heading>Leave of absence for public employees who are war veterans to continue study</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 246. Leave of absence for public employees who are war veterans to\ncontinue study.  Notwithstanding the provisions of any law to the\ncontrary, every public officer and employee, who served in the armed\nforces of the United States on or after September sixteenth, nineteen\nhundred forty, and prior to the termination of hostilities in world war\nII, or during the period of hostilities engaged in by the armed forces\nof the United States on and after June twenty-fifth, nineteen hundred\nfifty, or who served in the armed forces of the United States after\nJanuary thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-five, and who is eligible\nunder the provisions enacted by the congress of the United States known\nas "Servicemen's Readjustment Act of nineteen hundred forty-four," or\n"Veterans' Readjustment Assistance Act of nineteen hundred fifty-two,"\nor "Veterans' Readjustment Benefits Act of nineteen hundred sixty-six,"\nto continue the pursuit of studies or to take a refresher or retraining\ncourse shall be granted a leave of absence from his position for the\nperiod of such course of study, not to exceed four years.  Such public\nofficer or employee shall be reinstated to his position provided he\nmakes application for such reinstatement within sixty days after the\ntermination of such course of study.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>