<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-252"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-252"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="252"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-252/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-252/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-252/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-252/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_252">
        <num>252</num>
        <heading>Discrimination against members of organized militia</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 252. Discrimination against members of organized militia.  No\nassociation or corporation, constituted or organized for the purpose of\npromoting the success of the trade, employment, or business of the\nmembers thereof, shall by any constitution, rule, by-law, resolution,\nvote, or regulation, discriminate against any member of the organized\nmilitia of the state of New York, because of such membership in respect\nof the eligibility of such member of the said organized militia to\nmembership in such association or corporation, or in respect of his\nright to retain said last mentioned membership; it being the purpose of\nthis section and the section immediately preceding to protect a member\nof the said organized militia from disadvantage in his means of\nlivelihood and liberty therein but not to give him any preference or\nadvantage on account of his membership of said organized militia.  A\nperson who aids in enforcing any such provisions against a member of the\nsaid organized militia with the intent to discriminate against him\nbecause of such membership, is guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>