<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-311-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-311-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="311-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-311-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-311-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-311-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-311-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_311_A">
        <num>311-A</num>
        <heading>Termination of motor vehicle lease contracts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_311_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such lease was executed by or on behalf of a\nperson who, after the execution of such lease, entered active military\nservice, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_311_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the motor vehicle so leased has been used for such\npurposes, or for a combination of such purposes by such person or his or\nher legal dependents.\n  The provision of this section shall also apply to any lease covering a\nmotor vehicle used for personal purposes where such lease was executed\nby or on the behalf of a person, who, after the execution of such lease,\nentered active military service where such lease was also executed by or\non the behalf of the spouse of such a person.\n  2. All leases described in subdivision one of this section may be\nterminated by notice in writing delivered to the lessor or to the\nlessor's agent by a lessee at any time following the date of the\nbeginning of such active military service. Delivery of such notice shall\nbe accomplished by certified mail duly addressed to the lessor or to the\nlessor's agent. Termination of any such lease providing for monthly\nlease payments shall not be effective until:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_311_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>thirty days after the\nfirst date on which the next lease payment is due and payable subsequent\nto the date when such notice is delivered; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_311_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the motor vehicle\nsubject to the lease is returned to the custody or the control of the\nlessor, whichever is later. In the case of all motor vehicle leases, any\nunpaid lease payments for a period preceding termination shall be\nproratably computed and any lease payments made in advance for a period\nsucceeding termination shall be refunded by the lessor. Upon application\nby the lessor to a court of competent jurisdiction prior to the\ntermination period provided for in the notice, any relief granted in\nthis subdivision shall be subject to such modifications or restrictions\nas in the opinion of such court may be appropriate in the interest of\njustice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>