<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-316"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-316"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="316"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-316/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-316/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-316/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-316/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_316">
        <num>316</num>
        <heading>Policies of insurance; policies not to lapse or be forfeited</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_316__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section one thousand one hundred thirteen of the insurance law.\nIt shall also include any benefit in the nature of life insurance\narising out of membership in any fraternal benefit society as defined in\nsubsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_316__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section four thousand five hundred one of the\ninsurance law. In no case, however, shall the term "policy" include\ninsurance exceeding a total face value of one hundred thousand dollars\nwhether in one or more companies, but shall not include a policy insured\nunder Servicemen's Group Life Insurance. The term "premium" shall\ninclude membership dues or assessments in such society, and the date of\nissuance of policy as herein limited shall refer to the date of\nadmission to membership in such association; the term "insured" shall\ninclude any person who is the holder of a policy as defined in this\nsection; the term "insurer" shall include any corporation, partnership,\nor other form of association which secures or provides insurance under\nany policy as defined herein.\n  3. No individual accident and health insurance policy, defined in\nparagraph three of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_316__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section one thousand one hundred\nthirteen of the insurance law, which policy insures a member of the\norganized militia of the state, and has not lapsed for the non-payment\nof premiums before the commencement of a period of active duty in the\nmilitary service of the state of New York by such member, pursuant to an\norder of the governor issued under the authority of section six or seven\nof this chapter, shall lapse or be forfeited for the non-payment of\npremiums during a period of sixty days from the date that said member\nbegins such active duty provided the insurer is furnished with written\nnotice of said duty within thirty days after the commencement thereof.\nAn insurer shall have the right to deduct the amount of due and unpaid\npremiums from any benefit that may become payable as a result of this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>