<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-317"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-317"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-10-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="317"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-317/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-317/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-317/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-317/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_317">
        <num>317</num>
        <heading>Reemployment in private industry</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_317__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>receives a certificate of completion of military service duly\nexecuted by an officer of the applicable force of the armed forces of\nthe United States or by an officer of the applicable force of the\norganized militia of this state or of any other state as provided for by\nlaw;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_317__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is still qualified to perform the duties of such position; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_317__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>makes application for reemployment within ninety days after he or\nshe is relieved from such service, if such position was in the employ of\na private employer, such employer shall restore such person to such\nposition, or to a position of like seniority, status and pay, unless the\nemployer's circumstances have so changed as to make it impossible or\nunreasonable to do so.\n  2. The benefits, rights and privileges granted to persons in the\nmilitary service by this section shall be extended to and be applicable\nto any person who, in order to participate in assemblies for drill or\nother equivalent training, reserve duty training, instruction or duties,\nor annual full-time training duty, active duty for training or other\nannual training pursuant to any law of the United States or section\nforty-six of this chapter or the regulations issued thereunder, or in\norder to attend service schools conducted by the armed forces of the\nUnited States, temporarily leaves or has left his or her position, other\nthan a temporary position, in the employ of any employer and who, being\nqualified to perform the duties of such position, makes application for\nreemployment within ten days after completion of such temporary period\nof service.\n  2-a. The benefits, rights and privileges granted to persons in the\nmilitary service by this section shall be extended to and be applicable\nto any person who, in order to perform initial full-time training duty\nor initial active duty for training with or in an armed force of the\nUnited States under the provisions of this chapter or the laws of the\nUnited States or both, temporarily leaves or has left his or her\nposition, other than a temporary position, in the employ of any employer\nand who, being qualified to perform the duties of such position, makes\napplication for re-employment within sixty days after completion of such\nperiod of full-time training duty or active duty for training.\n  3. The benefits, rights and privileges gran...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>