<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-46"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-46"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="46"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-46/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-46/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-46/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-46/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_46">
        <num>46</num>
        <heading>Assemblies, annual training and other duty</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 46. Assemblies, annual training and other duty.  1. Members and\nunits of the organized militia shall assemble for drill or other\nequivalent training, instruction or duties and shall participate in\nfield training, annual training, full-time training duty, active duty\nfor training, encampments, maneuvers, schools, conferences, cruises or\nother similar duties as may be prescribed by the laws of the United\nStates or the state or the regulations issued thereunder; provided, that\nno assembly of any unit of the organized militia shall be ordered in\ntime of peace for any day during which a general election shall be held,\nexcept in case of riot, disaster, invasion, insurrection, or imminent\ndanger thereof.\n  2. Within the amount appropriated therefor, the adjutant general may\nprescribe and order the number of days, if any, for assemblies for\ndrills or other equivalent training, instruction or duties to be\nperformed annually by members of the organized militia for which they\nmay receive pay.\n  3. Within the amount appropriated therefor, the adjutant general may\nprescribe and order the number of days, if any, of field training,\nencampments, maneuvers, schools, conferences, cruises or other similar\nduties to be performed by members of the organized militia for which\nthey may receive pay and allowances.\n  4. Members of the organized militia may be ordered by the governor or\nunder his authority to perform special duty, including duty in a\njudicial proceeding or course of justice conducted pursuant to article\nseven of this chapter or as a member of or in any other capacity with\nany military board or as an investigating officer or as a medical\nexaminer or as a judge advocate in the performance of legal services in\nany suit, action or proceeding.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>