<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="MIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-51"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-51"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="51"/>
          <FRBRname value="MIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/mil/section-51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_51">
        <num>51</num>
        <heading>Marksmanship and merit prizes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 51. Marksmanship and merit prizes.  1. To encourage marksmanship,\nthe governor is authorized to offer annually:\n  a. a state decoration to those who shall excel in small arms practice;\n  b. a prize not exceeding three hundred dollars in value, for\ncompetition among the units of the New York national guard and the New\nYork naval militia armed with the rifle;\n  c. a prize not exceeding one hundred dollars in value for competition\namong the units armed with the rifle (1) not forming part of or attached\nto a brigade or division of the New York army national guard; (2) of\neach brigade and division of the New York army national guard; (3) of\nthe New York air national guard and (4) of the New York naval militia.\n  2. The governor may also offer annually three prizes of the value of\none hundred dollars, seventy-five dollars and fifty dollars,\nrespectively, to be awarded to the three companies or corresponding\nunits of the organized militia having the highest general figure of\nmerit (1) in organizations not forming part of or attached to a brigade\nor division of the New York army national guard; (2) in each brigade or\ndivision of the New York army national guard; (3) in the New York air\nnational guard; and (4) in the New York naval militia.\n  3. The governor may also in his discretion provide suitable\ndecorations and prizes for proficiency in practice with other small arms\nand with light and heavy weapons.\n  4. All such prizes and decorations shall be competed for under\nregulations issued pursuant to this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>