<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1101"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1101">
        <num>1101</num>
        <heading>Inspection</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1101. Inspection.  1. The person, officer, board or commission\nhaving the management and control of the potable water supply of any\nmunicipality, state or United States institution, park, reservation or\npost, and in the city of New York, the commissioner of environmental\nprotection, and the board of water supply of the city of New York, or\nthe corporation furnishing such supply, may make such inspection of the\nsources of such water supply as such person, officer, board, corporation\nor commission deems advisable and to ascertain whether the rules or\nregulations of the department, and of the commissioner of environmental\nprotection of the city of New York, and of the board of water supply of\nthe city of New York, are complied with, and shall make such regular or\nspecial inspections as the commissioner, or the commissioner of\nenvironmental protection of the city of New York, or the board of water\nsupply of the city of New York, may prescribe.\n  2. The authorities in charge of the water supply or their duly\nauthorized representatives may without fee or hindrance, enter, examine\nand survey all grounds, structures, buildings and places on the\nwatershed tributary to the sources of such water supply in order to\nascertain whether such rules or regulations are complied with.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>