<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1303"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1303">
        <num>1303</num>
        <heading>Nuisances; local boards of health; general powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1303. Nuisances; local boards of health; general powers and duties.\n1. Every local board of health and local health officer shall receive\nand examine into all complaints made by any inhabitant concerning\nnuisances, or causes of danger or injury to life and health within the\nhealth district, and may enter upon or within any place or premises\nwhere nuisances or conditions dangerous to life and health or which are\nthe cause of nuisances existing elsewhere are known or believed to\nexist, and by its members or other persons designated for that purpose,\ninspect and examine the same.\n  2. The local board of health or local health officer having the powers\nof a local board of health shall furnish the owners, agents and\noccupants of the premises with a written statement of the results and\nconclusions of any examination conducted pursuant to the provisions of\nsections one thousand three hundred three to one thousand three hundred\nfive, inclusive, of this chapter.\n  3. Every local board of health shall order the suppression and removal\nof all nuisances and conditions detrimental to life and health found to\nexist within the health district.\n  4. Whenever the commissioner shall by notice to the presiding officer\nof any local board of health, direct him to convene such local board to\ntake certain definite proceedings concerning which the commissioner\nshall be satisfied that the action recommended by him is necessary for\nthe public good, and is within the jurisdiction of such board of health,\nsuch presiding officer shall convene such local board of health, which\nshall take the action directed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>