<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1320"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1320"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1320"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1320/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1320/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1320/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1320/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1320">
        <num>1320</num>
        <heading>Noxious weeds and growths; declaration of nuisance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1320. Noxious weeds and growths; declaration of nuisance.  1.\nWhenever in any health district there shall be growing on any property\ntherein any ragweed or other species of weed, plant or growth which is\nnoxious or detrimental to the public health, or the seed, pollen or\nother emanation therefrom, when carried through the air or otherwise\ndispersed, is noxious or detrimental to the public health, the local\nboard of health of any such health district may take and file upon its\nrecords what it shall regard as sufficient proof to authorize a\ndeclaration that the existence of any such growth is a nuisance or\ndanger to the public health, and may thereupon enter the same upon its\nrecords as a nuisance and order the same to be removed, destroyed or\notherwise abated on any property wherever found.\n  2. The local board of health may also take and file among its records\nwhat it shall regard as sufficient proof to authorize a declaration that\nat any season or period of the year there exists a particular and\nimminent danger to the public health by reason of the approaching period\nof pollination of any such growth and may enter such determination upon\nits record.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>