<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1341"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1341"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1341"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1341">
        <num>1341</num>
        <heading>Bathing places; safety requirements; ropes and life preservers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1341__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the duty of every person maintaining, as\nowner or lessee, any bathing establishment of any kind along the\nseashore of this state for the accommodation of persons for pay, to\nprovide, for the safety of such bathers, two lines of sound, serviceable\nand strong manila or hemp rope, not less than one inch in diameter,\nanchored at some point above high water, at the same distance apart as\nthe lines of bathing houses, or space fronting on such beach occupied by\nhim or them, is in width. From the two points at which such life-lines\nare so anchored, such life-lines shall be made to extend as far into the\nsurf as bathing is ordinarily safe and free from danger of drowning to\npersons not expert in swimming, and at such points of safety, such lines\nshall be anchored and buoyed. From the two points of such lines so\nextended, anchored and buoyed, a third rope shall be extended, of a\nsimilar size, connecting the two extremities, and buoyed at such points\nas to be principally above the surface of the water, thereby inclosing a\nspace within such lines and the beach within which bathing is believed\nto be safe. In addition thereto, there shall be sufficient ropes of a\nsimilar size as herein described, anchored from a point at high water\nmark and buoyed or anchored at a parallel line or within the outer cross\nrope, so as to have not more than a space of seventy-five feet from one\nrope to another; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1341__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every person maintaining any such bathing establishment shall\ncause to be painted and posted in some prominent place upon the beach\nnear such bathing houses the following words: "Bathing beyond the lines\ndangerous", and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1341__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such lines so placed, anchored and buoyed, and such notice so\nposted, shall be so maintained and continued by every person maintaining\nany such establishment, during the entire season of surf bathing.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1341__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every person maintaining any such bathing establishment shall\nalso keep and provide in connection therewith, for the facilitating of\nthe rescue of persons in danger of drowning, a surfboat or a personal\nwatercraft as defined in subdivision thirty of section two of the\nnavigation law and in compliance with the regulations of the\ncommissioner. A surfboat shall be not less than sixteen feet long, on\neach side of which there shall be hanging ropes arranged so that persons\nin the water can easily catch hold of same, or be supported thereby.\nSuch boats shall be equipped with two or more sets of oars and\nlife-lines and life-belts, and at least one ring buoy or life preserver,\nwith quarter-inch cotton line, not less than five hundred feet in\nlength, with suitable reel attached thereto. In addition thereto, there\nshall be anchored on the shore, a suitable reel with a half-inch cotton\nline not less than five hundred feet in length, with a life-belt\nattached thereto, kept in good order and proper condition, so that it\ncan readily be used by those assisting in saving life.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1341__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At all bathing establishments where there are equipments for two\nhundred bathers or more, said surf or life-boat shall be stationed in\nthe water, opposite the lines, manned and in readiness for use, during\nbathing hours.\n  3. Every person maintaining any such bathing establishment shall\nemploy or otherwise engage or provide the services of a bathing master\nor life-guard at such bathing establishment, who shall be an expert\nswimmer, and who shall be in constant and watchful attendance during\nbathing hours.\n  4. The owner of a bathing establishment shall not be subject to the\nprovisions of this section when it is used, occupied or maintained by a\nlessee for hire, but such lessee shall be deemed the keeper or\nproprietor or person maintaining such bathing establishment.\n  5. Nothing in this section shall be construed in any way to affect any\nbathing establishments, in any municipality, or any bathing\nestablishments or bathing beaches operated by a regional state park\ncommission, at which there is maintained at public expense a life-saving\nguard.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>