<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1370-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1370-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1370-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1370-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1370-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1370-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1370-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1370_C">
        <num>1370-C</num>
        <heading>Screening by health care providers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1370-c. Screening by health care providers. 1. The department is\nauthorized to promulgate regulations establishing the means by which and\nthe intervals at which children and pregnant women shall be screened for\nelevated lead levels. The department is also authorized to require\nscreening for lead poisoning in other high risk groups.\n  2. Every physician or other authorized practitioner who provides\nmedical care to children or pregnant women, shall screen children or\nrefer them for screening for elevated lead levels at the intervals and\nusing the methods specified in such regulations. Every licensed,\nregistered or approved health care facility serving children including\nbut not limited to hospitals, clinics and health maintenance\norganizations, shall ensure, by providing screenings or by referring for\nscreenings, that their patients receive screening for lead at the\nintervals and using the methods specified in such regulations.\n  2-a. Every primary health care provider shall conduct a lead exposure\nrisk assessment questionnaire provided by the department for each child\nwho is at least six months of age and continuing until six years of age\nat each routine well-child visit, or at least annually if a child has\nnot had routine well-child visits.\n  3. The health practitioner who screens any child for lead shall give a\ncertificate of screening to the parent or guardian of the child.\n  4. The department shall establish a separate level of payment, subject\nto the approval of the director of the budget, for payments made by\ngovernmental agencies for screenings performed pursuant to this section\nby hospitals, as defined in section twenty-eight hundred one of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>