<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1377"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1377"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1377"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1377/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1377/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1377/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1377/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1377">
        <num>1377</num>
        <heading>State rental registry and proactive inspections to identify lead hazards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the frequency of such inspections which shall be no less\nfrequent than every three years;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the minimum conditions the\nresidential dwelling must meet for a valid inspection certification;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nqualifications for inspectors;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>minimum standards for a standardized\nform on which the owner of a residential dwelling may self-certify as to\na satisfactory inspection, such form shall require such owner to confirm\nsuch residential dwelling meets all the requirements of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision and may require such owner to submit any documentation\ndeemed necessary by the commissioner, provided, however, such owner\nshall meet the qualifications pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>alternative methods of certification, which may include\nthe submission of a valid and active residential occupancy permit for\nwhich the minimum conditions required under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision were required to be met for such issuance;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>procedures\nfor false certifications, upon a finding by the department that a\nself-certified dwelling contains lead hazards; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1377__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other\ninformation or requirements deemed necessary by the commissioner to\nadminister, coordinate, and enforce this section.\n  8. The inspection requirements under this section shall, at a minimum,\ninclude visual inspections for deteriorated paint and outdoor soil\nconditions, as well as the collection of dust wipe samples obtained in\naccordance with United States Environmental Protection Agency protocols\nfor such procedures.\n  9. Remediation of lead-based paint hazards must be conducted in\ncompliance with all municipal requirements and specific requirements\nspecified in regulation.\n  10. A failure to file or filing a false certificate as required under\nthis section shall be subject to civil penalties under section twelve of\nthis chapter, in addition to any penalties that may apply.\n  11. The commissioner shall, on or before December thirty-first in each\nyear, beginning the calendar year after the effective date of this\nsection, submit a report to the governor, the temporary president of the\nsenate, and the speaker of the assembly on the activity and\nimplementation of this section. Such report shall include but not be\nlimited to: the number of residential properties qualifying for\nregistration, the number of properties required to submit inspection\ncertifications by October first of such year, the number of inspection\ncertifications submitted by October first of such year, the number of\ninspections conducted pursuant to the audit process established in\nsubdivision five of this section, the results of the audit process\nestablished in subdivision five of this section, and such other\ninformation as the commissioner determines. The information provided in\nthe report shall reflect statewide activities in the aggregate and\nactivities for each community of concern.\n  * NB Repealed November 3, 2028\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>