<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1389-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1389-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1389-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1389-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1389-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1389-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1389-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1389_CC">
        <num>1389-CC</num>
        <heading>Storage and containment of regulated medical waste</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1389-cc. Storage and containment of regulated medical waste.  1.\nContainment of regulated medical waste shall be in a manner and location\nwhich affords protection from the environment and limits exposure to the\npublic.\n  2. Regulated medical waste shall be separated from other waste as soon\nas practicable in the generator's facility.\n  3. Unless otherwise approved by the department, regulated medical\nwaste shall be contained at the producing facility only for such periods\nand under such conditions pursuant to rules and regulations adopted in\nfurtherance of this title.\n  4. Containment of regulated medical waste shall be separate from other\nwastes. Containers used for the containment of regulated medical waste\nshall be marked prominently on the containers with the universal warning\nsign or the word "biohazard".\n  5. Regulated medical waste, except for discarded sharps, shall be\ncontained in bags which are impervious to moisture and have a strength\nsufficient to resist ripping, tearing or bursting under normal\nconditions of usage and of handling.  The bags shall be secured so as to\nprevent leakage during storage, handling or transport. All bags used for\ncontainment and disposal of regulated medical wastes shall be red in\ncolor.\n  6. All discarded sharps shall be contained for disposal in leakproof,\nrigid, puncture-resistant containers which are secured to preclude loss\nof the contents. Such containers shall be red in color or shall be\nconspicuously labeled with the word "infectious" or the words "regulated\nmedical waste".\n  7. Before regulated medical waste is transported from the generating\nfacility, regulated medical waste contained in disposable containers\nshall be placed for storage or handling in disposable or reusable pails,\ncartons, drums, dumpsters or portable bins. The containment system shall\nbe leakproof, have tight-fitting covers and be kept clean and in good\nrepair. The containers may be of any color and shall be conspicuously\nlabeled with the word "infectious" or the words "regulated medical\nwaste".\n  8. Reusable containers for regulated medical waste shall be thoroughly\nwashed and decontaminated each time they are emptied unless the surfaces\nof the containers have been completely protected from contamination by\ndisposable liners, bags or other devices removed with the waste.\n  9. Reusable pails, drums, dumpsters or bins used for containment of\nregulated medical waste shall not be used for containment of waste to be\ndisposed of as other wastes or for other purposes except after being\ndecontaminated.\n  10. Trash chutes shall not be used to transfer regulated medical waste\nbetween locations where it is contained.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>