<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1390"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1390"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1390"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1390/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1390/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1390/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1390/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1390">
        <num>1390</num>
        <heading>Establishment of state camp safety advisory council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1390. Establishment of state camp safety advisory council. The\ncommissioner of health shall establish within the state department of\nhealth a state camp safety advisory council to advise and consult on\npolicy matters relating to youth camp safety. The council shall consist\nof nine members to be appointed by the governor with the advice and\nconsent of the senate. Three members of the council shall be\nrepresentatives of youth camps operated in New York for profit, three\nmembers of the council shall be representatives of youth camps operated\nin New York under philanthropic non-profit or charitable auspices, one\nmember of the council shall be a representative of youth camp consumer\ninterests, one shall be a representative of children's interests who\ndoes not operate a children's camp and one shall be a representative of\nsummer day camps and traveling summer day camps operated by municipal\ncorporations and other entities subject to article thirteen-D of this\nchapter. The council shall elect from among its members a chairman. On\nor before January first, nineteen hundred seventy-four, the governor\nshall appoint two youth camp representative members for a term of two\nyears, two youth camp representative members for a term of four years\nand two youth camp representative members for a term of six years.\nBiennially thereafter the youth camp representative members shall be\nappointed to said council in like manner to succeed those whose terms\nexpire, to serve for terms of six years each and until their successors\nare appointed. The member representative of youth camp consumer\ninterests shall also serve for a term of six years and until a successor\nis appointed. On or before January first, nineteen hundred eighty-one,\nthe governor shall appoint the representative of children's interests\nfor a term of four years and the representative of summer day camps and\ntraveling summer day camps operated by municipal corporations and other\nentities subject to article thirteen-D of this chapter for a term of two\nyears. Thereafter, each succeeding representative of children's\ninterests and each succeeding representative of said summer day camps\nand traveling summer day camps shall serve terms of six years each and\nuntil their successors are appointed. Vacancies shall be filled by the\ngovernor for the unexpired portion of the term. Said council shall meet\nat least twice a year, and more often if necessary, on the call of the\nchairman or on the call of the commissioner of health. The members of\nthe council shall receive no compensation but shall be reimbursed for\ntheir reasonable traveling and other expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties. A majority of the appointed voting\nmembership of the council shall constitute a quorum.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>