<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1399-II"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1399-II"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1399-II"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1399-II/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1399-II/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1399-II/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1399-II/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1399_II">
        <num>1399-II</num>
        <heading>Tobacco and vapor product use prevention and control program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Community programs to prevent and reduce tobacco use through local\ninvolvement and partnerships;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>School-based programs to prevent and reduce tobacco use and use of\nvapor products;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Marketing and advertising to discourage tobacco, vapor product and\nliquid nicotine use;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nicotine cessation programs for youth and adults;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Special projects to reduce the disparities in smoking prevalence\namong various populations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Restriction of youth access to tobacco products and vapor\nproducts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Surveillance of smoking and vaping rates; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any other activities determined by the commissioner to be\nnecessary to implement the provisions of this section.\n  Such programs shall be selected by the commissioner through an\napplication process which takes into account whether a program utilizes\nmethods recognized as effective in reducing nicotine use. Eligible\napplicants may include, but not be limited to, a health care provider,\nschools, a college or university, a local public health department, a\npublic health organization, a health care provider organization,\nassociation or society, municipal corporation, or a professional\neducation organization.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be established a tobacco use prevention and control\nadvisory board to advise the commissioner on tobacco use prevention and\ncontrol issues and vapor product use amongst persons less than\ntwenty-one years of age, including methods to prevent and reduce tobacco\nuse in the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board shall consist of seventeen members who shall be\nappointed as follows: nine members by the governor; three members by the\nspeaker of the assembly; three members by the temporary president of the\nsenate and one member each by the minority leader of the senate and\nminority leader of the assembly. Any vacancy or subsequent appointment\nshall be filled in the same manner and by the same appointing authority\nas the original appointment. The chairperson of the board shall be\ndesignated by the governor from among the members of the board.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members shall serve for terms of two years commencing on the\neffective date of this section. Members of the board shall receive no\ncompensation but shall be reimbursed for reasonable travel and other\nexpenses incurred in the performance of their duties hereunder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board shall meet as often as it deems necessary, but no less\nthan four times a year. No nominee to the board shall have any past or\ncurrent affiliation with the tobacco industry, vapor products industry\nor any industry, contractor, agent, or organization that engages in the\nmanufacturing, marketing, distributing, or sale of tobacco products. The\nboard shall be appointed in full within ninety days of the effective\ndate of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1399_II__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department shall prepare and submit to the board a spending\nplan for the tobacco and vapor product use prevention and control\nprogram authorized pursuant to the provisions of subdivision one of this\nsection no later than thirty days after the submission of the budget to\nthe legislature.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>