<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1402"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1402"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1402"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1402">
        <num>1402</num>
        <heading>Delivery of disclosure statement to parent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1402. Delivery of disclosure statement to parent.  1. A copy of the\nshort form disclosure statement shall be mailed or delivered by the\nowner, director or other person soliciting the enrollment of a child\nresiding within the state for any children's camp located without the\nstate to the parent or guardian of such child. Such disclosure statement\nmay accompany any literature or solicitation material mailed or\ndelivered to such parent or guardian, but in no event, shall such\ndisclosure statement be mailed or delivered to such parent or guardian\nlater than the mailing or delivery of enrollment application forms\nand/or enrollment contract forms.\n  2. No advertisement, or other solicitation material, or enrollment\napplication form or enrollment contract or short form, shall contain any\nrepresentation that is inconsistent with any material representation or\nstatement made in the disclosure statement or equivalent statement as\nlast renewed or amended. Any such representation shall be deemed to be a\ndeceptive practice pursuant to section three hundred forty-nine of the\ngeneral business law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>