<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1520"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1520"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1520"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-1520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1520">
        <num>1520</num>
        <heading>County mosquito control commission; appointment; membership</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1520__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>four resident taxpayers of the county, to be appointed by the\nboard of supervisors of the county duly convened by the chairman thereof\nfor the purpose of making the said appointments; and,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1520__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member, to be appointed by the commissioner, who shall be a\nresident of the county for which such commission is appointed, and who\nshall have equal powers, privileges and duties with the other members of\nsuch commission, and who shall, in addition thereto represent the\ncommissioner in all matters as the commissioner may direct; and,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1520__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the chairman of the board of supervisors of the said county, who\nshall be a member ex-officio of said commission and who shall have equal\npowers, privileges and duties with the other members of such commission.\n  3. Each county mosquito control commission shall be known as "The\n(here shall be inserted the name of the county in and for which the\ncommissioners are to be appointed) County Mosquito Control Commission."\n  4. The chairman of the board of supervisors of each county for which a\ncounty mosquito control commission is to be appointed pursuant to the\nprovisions of this section shall convene the said board at the most\nsuitable and convenient place, or otherwise arrange for concerted action\nfor the purpose of acting as a board for the appointment of the four\nresident taxpayers in such county, as herein provided. The members of\nsuch appointing board shall serve without pay, except that the necessary\nexpenses of each member for actual attendance at any meeting of such\nboard shall be allowed and paid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>