<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2004-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2004-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2004-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2004-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2004-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2004-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2004-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2004_A">
        <num>2004-A</num>
        <heading>Coordinating council for services related to Alzheimer's disease and other dementia</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2004_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The council shall meet quarterly or more frequently if its\nbusiness shall require. The community forums in the first year of\nimplementation count as a formal meeting of the council. The members of\nthe council shall receive no compensation but shall be reimbursed for\ntravel and other expenses actually and necessarily incurred in the\nperformance of their duties. The council shall provide reports to the\ngovernor and the legislature on or before June thirtieth, two thousand\nnine and by June thirtieth of every other year thereafter. Such reports\nshall include recommendations for state policy relating to dementia and\na review of services initiated and coordinated among public and private\nagencies to meet the needs of persons with Alzheimer's disease and other\ndementia and their families.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2004_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The council shall additionally review and report upon the use of\nclinically recognized, scientifically based, cognitive impairment\nscreening tools used to identify signs of and individuals at-risk for\ncognitive impairment, including Alzheimer's disease or other dementias,\nin all settings of the health continuum. Such tools shall include but\nnot be limited to tools approved and/or recognized by the Joint\nCommission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations (JCAHO), Agency\nfor Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), the Centers for Medicare and\nMedicaid Services (CMS), and others as determined by the council which\nare used by health care providers, across all settings of the health\ncontinuum. The council shall also review and report on best practices of\nproviders concerning early identification of at-risk individuals and\nreferral practices, the range of interventions and services available\nfor the cognitively impaired, and shall report its assessment of the\nneed and presence of such tools and practices in each sector of the\nhealth continuum. The council shall further include in its reports any\nfindings concerning potential gaps of identification and intervention\nfor the cognitively impaired, the need for public education about\ncognitive impairment, and recommendations to address that education\nneed.\n  5. The department shall serve as the focal point to develop\ncomprehensive coordinated responses of the various state agencies with\nregard to Alzheimer's disease and related dementia and thus help to\nassure timely and appropriate responses to issues and problems. The\ndepartment shall collaborate with the state office for the aging on\nissues related to nonmedical support services for individuals with\nAlzheimer's disease and other dementia and their caregivers. The\ndepartment shall collaborate with other appropriate state agencies to\nestablish a simplified coordinated assessment procedure for obtaining\nneeded services for persons with Alzheim...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>