<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-206-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-206-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="206-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-206-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-206-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-206-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-206-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_206_B">
        <num>206-B</num>
        <heading>Special requirements with respect to Lyme disease diagnosis</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 206-b. Special requirements with respect to Lyme disease diagnosis.\n1. Within thirty days after the effective date of this section, the\ncommissioner shall, in writing, order every physician practicing in\nSuffolk, Westchester and Nassau counties to review the medical records\nof any patient such physician treated during the period commencing\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred seventy-five and ending on the date of\nsuch order wherein such physician made a diagnosis of juvenile\nrheumatoid arthritis and to review the circumstances of such diagnosis\nto reconsider whether such patient has suffered, or is suffering, from\nthe complex, multi-system disorder caused by the bacterium Borrelia\nburgdorferi, which disease is transmitted by the Ixodes dammini tick and\nis commonly referred to as "Lyme disease". In any case where a hospital\nor other health care institution or provider has custody or control of\nthe medical records for a patient so diagnosed, upon request such\nphysician shall be entitled to review such medical records for purposes\nof complying with such order or the commissioner may order any such\nhospital or other health care institution or provider wherever situated\nwithin the state to review such records to reconsider a diagnosis of\nLyme disease.\n  2. The commissioner, upon a showing that there is a reasonable basis\nto believe that the order provided for herein has not been complied\nwith, shall be entitled to apply to a justice of the supreme court for\nan order requiring any such physician to submit for the commissioner's\nconsideration such records, charts or other pertinent data which will\nenable him to determine whether there has been full compliance with such\norder.\n  3. In any case where a review of such records indicates that a patient\nmay have been, or is, suffering from Lyme disease, such physician shall,\nconsistent with customary and acceptable medical standards, take such\naction he deems necessary to inform such patient or in the case of a\nminor, his or her parent or guardian of his findings, conduct additional\ntests, administer other necessary treatments or refer such patient to\nanother physician for further diagnosis and/or treatment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>