<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2108"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2108">
        <num>2108</num>
        <heading>Communicable diseases; epidemic among Indians; state charges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2108. Communicable diseases; epidemic among Indians; state charges.\n1. Whenever an epidemic of a communicable disease shall prevail among\nthe Indians of any nation, tribe or band in this state, the public\nwelfare official of the welfare district in which the reservation of\nsuch nation, tribe or band, is wholly or partly situated, may in\naccordance with rules and regulations adopted by the commissioner, cause\nneeded medical attendance, provisions and maintenance to be furnished to\nany indigent Indian residing in the town, who, or a member of whose\nfamily, is afflicted with such disease, while such disease shall\ncontinue.  The cost thereof after being audited as herein provided shall\nbe a state charge.\n  2. A verified statement of any expenses incurred under this section\nshall be transmitted by the public welfare official to the commissioner.\nThe commissioner shall examine into the matter, and if satisfied that\nsuch expenses were properly and necessarily incurred in accordance with\nhis rules and regulations, he shall approve the same; and the amount\nthereof, after audit by the comptroller, shall be paid from the state\ntreasury on the warrant of the comptroller to such public welfare\nofficial.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>