<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2161"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2161"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2161"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2161/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2161/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2161/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2161/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2161">
        <num>2161</num>
        <heading>Poliomyelitis; persons twenty-one years of age and over; care and maintenance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2161. Poliomyelitis; persons twenty-one years of age and over; care\nand maintenance.  Every county or part-county health commissioner, city\nhealth officer in cities having more than fifty thousand population, and\nstate district health officer shall, within their respective areas and\nafter approval by the commissioner, provide at the remediable stages of\nthe disease known as poliomyelitis, suitable surgical, medical or\ntherapeutic treatment or hospital care, and necessary appliances and\ndevices for all persons twenty-one years of age or over including\nIndians residing on reservations, so infected or exposed who cannot\notherwise be provided for. In a county the determination as to what\npersons cannot otherwise be provided for and relevant matters shall be\nmade by the board of supervisors of such county against which the same\nis to be a charge and an investigation and report thereon to such board\nupon which to make its determination shall be made by the public welfare\ncommissioner or such other county officer, or committee of the board as\nthe board of supervisors may designate by resolution. The charges\napproved for such treatment shall be in full payment thereof and shall\nbe accepted by the person or corporation furnishing such treatment as\nfull payment and no such person or corporation shall ask or receive\ndirectly or indirectly any other or additional compensation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>