<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-221"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-221"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="221"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_221">
        <num>221</num>
        <heading>Public health and health planning council; terms of office; vacancies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 221. Public health and health planning council; terms of office;\nvacancies. 1. The terms of office of members of the public health and\nhealth planning council shall be six years. The members of the council\nshall continue in office until the expiration of their terms and until\ntheir successors are appointed and have qualified. Such appointments\nshall be made by the governor, with the advice and consent of the\nsenate, within one year following the expiration of such terms.\n  2. Vacancies shall be filled by appointment by the governor for the\nunexpired terms within one year of the date upon which such vacancies\noccur.\n  3. In making appointments to the council, the governor shall seek to\nensure that membership on the council reflects the diversity of the\nstate's population including, but not limited to the various geographic\nareas and population densities throughout the state.\n  4. Notwithstanding subdivision one of this section, of the ten members\nappointed or reappointed to the council on or after December first, two\nthousand ten, two shall serve a term of three years, two shall serve a\nterm of four years, three shall serve a term of five years, and three\nshall serve a term of six years. Thereafter, members appointed or\nreappointed upon expiration of a term of office shall be appointed for a\nterm of six years and shall continue in office until their successors\nare appointed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>