<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2223"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2223"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2223"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2223/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2223/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2223/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2223/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2223">
        <num>2223</num>
        <heading>Tuberculosis; carelessness of patients; violation and penalty; duty of health officer</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2223. Tuberculosis; carelessness of patients; violation and penalty;\nduty of health officer.  1. Any person having tuberculosis who shall\ndispose of his sputum, saliva or other bodily secretion or excretion so\nas to cause offense or danger to any person or persons occupying the\nsame room or apartment, house, or part of a house, shall on complaint of\nany person or persons subjected to such offense or danger, be deemed\nguilty of a nuisance and any persons subjected to such a nuisance may\nmake complaint in person or writing to the health officer of the local\nhealth district where the nuisance complained of is committed.\n  2. It shall be the duty of the local health officer receiving such\ncomplaint to investigate and if it appears that the nuisance complained\nof is such as to cause offense or danger to any person occupying the\nsame room, apartment, house or part of a house, he shall serve a notice\nupon the person so complained of, reciting the alleged cause of offense\nor danger and requiring him to dispose of his sputum, saliva or other\nbodily secretion or excretion in such a manner as to remove all\nreasonable cause of offense or danger.\n  3. Any person failing or refusing to comply with orders or regulations\nof the local health officer requiring him to cease to commit such\nnuisance, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction\nthereof shall be fined not more than ten dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>