<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-224-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-224-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="224-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-224-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-224-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-224-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-224-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_224_B">
        <num>224-B</num>
        <heading>Public health and health planning council; powers and duties; health care facilities, home care agencies and hospices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 224-b. Public health and health planning council; powers and duties;\nhealth care facilities, home care agencies and hospices. The public\nhealth and health planning council shall have such powers and duties as\nare set forth in this chapter, including the consideration of\napplications for the establishment and construction of health care\nfacilities, home care agencies and hospices licensed under articles\ntwenty-eight, thirty-six or forty of this chapter. In carrying out its\npowers and duties, the council shall take into account the impact of its\nactions and recommendations on the quality, accessibility, efficiency\nand cost-effectiveness of health care throughout the state. The council\nshall undertake a comprehensive review of regulations and council\nprocedures governing the establishment and construction of such health\ncare facilities, home care agencies and hospices and shall submit to the\ncommissioner any recommendations for the revisions of such regulations.\nSuch review shall be conducted every five years, and the first set of\nrecommendations shall be submitted to the commissioner on or before\nDecember first, two thousand sixteen.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>