<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2305"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2305">
        <num>2305</num>
        <heading>Sexually transmitted diseases; treatment by licensed physician or staff physician of a hospital; prescriptions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2305. Sexually transmitted diseases; treatment by licensed physician\nor staff physician of a hospital; prescriptions. 1. No person, other\nthan a licensed physician, or, in a hospital, a staff physician, shall\ndiagnose, treat or prescribe for a person who is infected with a\nsexually transmitted disease, or who has been exposed to infection with\na sexually transmitted disease, or dispense or sell a drug, medicine or\nremedy for the treatment of such person except on prescription of a duly\nlicensed physician.\n  2. A licensed physician, or in a hospital, a staff physician, may\ndiagnose, treat or prescribe for a person under the age of twenty-one\nyears without the consent or knowledge of the parents or guardian of\nsaid person, where such person is infected with a sexually transmitted\ndisease, or has been exposed to infection with a sexually transmitted\ndisease.\n  3. For the purposes of this section, the term "hospital" shall mean a\nhospital as defined in article twenty-eight of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>