<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2308"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2308"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2308"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2308/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2308/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2308/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2308/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2308">
        <num>2308</num>
        <heading>Sexually transmitted disease; pregnant persons; blood test for syphilis</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2308. Sexually transmitted disease; pregnant persons; blood test for\nsyphilis. 1. Every physician or other authorized practitioner attending\npregnant persons in the state shall in the case of every person so\nattended take or cause to be taken a sample of blood of such person at\nthe time of first examination, and submit such sample to an approved\nlaboratory for a standard serological test for syphilis. In addition to\ntesting at the time of first examination, every such physician or other\nauthorized practitioner shall order a syphilis test during the third\ntrimester of pregnancy consistent with any guidance and regulations\nissued by the commissioner.\n  2. Every other person permitted by law to attend upon pregnant women\nin the state but not permitted by law to take blood tests, shall cause a\nsample of the blood of such pregnant woman to be taken promptly by a\nduly licensed physician and submitted to an approved laboratory for a\nstandard serological test for syphilis.\n  3. The term "approved laboratory" means a laboratory approved for the\npurpose as herein provided by the department, or in the city of New York\nby the department of health of such city.\n  4. A standard serological test for syphilis is one recognized as such\nby the department or in the city of New York by the department of health\nof such city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>