<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-233"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-233"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="233"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-233/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-233/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-233/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-233/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_233">
        <num>233</num>
        <heading>New York state health service corps scholarship and fellowship program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_233__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>New York state health service corps\nscholarships and fellowships for health corps professionals shall be\nawarded, within amounts appropriated, on a competitive basis, as\ndetermined by the commissioner, to students who:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_233__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are or will be\nenrolled in a program of undergraduate or graduate study to become a\nhealth care professional eligible to participate in the health service\ncorps; and\n  (ii) agree to serve in eligible institutions or facilities upon\nsatisfactory completion of their studies and upon satisfaction of\napplicable licensing and certification requirements; and\n  (iii) meet such other requirements as the commissioner, in\nconsultation with the commissioners of education, correctional services,\nmental health, mental retardation and developmental disabilities, the\ncommission for the blind and visually handicapped and the president of\nthe civil service commission, may establish.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_233__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In selecting students to be awarded such scholarships or\nfellowships, preference shall be given to students in the following\norder:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_233__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>New York state residents who attend or plan to attend a\nprogram of undergraduate or graduate study located in New York state;\n(ii) New York state residents who attend or plan to attend a program of\nundergraduate or graduate study located out-of-state; and (iii) persons\nwho are not residents of New York state who attend or plan to attend a\nprogram of undergraduate or graduate study located in New York state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_233__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall, pursuant to agreement with the appropriate\nagency, allocate, to the extent possible, the placement of award\nrecipients to each catchment area or region, as defined by such agency,\nin which an eligible institution or facility is located.\n  2. Within such time as the commissioner shall by regulation provide, a\nrecipient of an award shall have practiced as a health corps\nprofessional in an eligible institution or facility for that number of\nmonths calculated by multiplying by eighteen the number of annual awards\nreceived by the recipient. If a recipient fails to comply fully with\nsuch conditions, the president shall be entitled to receive from such\nrecipient an amount to be determined by the formula:\n                               A = 2B(T-S)\n                                       t\nIn which "A" is the amount the president is entitled to recover; "B" is\nthe sum of all payments made to the recipient and the interest on such\namount which would be payable if at the times such awards were paid they\nwere loans bearing interest at the maximum prevailing rate; "t" is the\ntotal number of months in the recipient's period of obligated services;\nand "s" is the number of months of service actually rendered by the\nrecipient. Any amount which the president is entitled to recover under\nthis subdivision shall be paid within the five-year period beginning on\nthe date that the recipient failed to comply with this condition. Any\nobligation to comply with such provisions shall be cancelled upon the\ndeath of the recipient. The commissioner of health shall promulgate\nregulations to provide for the waiver or suspension of any financial\nobligation when compliance would involve extreme hardship.\n  3. A recipient of an award shall report semi-annually to the\npresident, on forms prescribed by him, as to the performance of the\nrequired services or the recipient's current status, commencing with the\ncalendar year of the first award and continuin...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>