<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-236"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-236"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="236"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-236/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-236/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-236/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-236/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_236">
        <num>236</num>
        <heading>Charles D</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 236.  Charles D. Cook office of rural health created. There is\nhereby created the Charles D. Cook office of rural health within the\nstate department of health. Such office shall:\n  1. Integrate and coordinate selected state health care grant and loan\nprograms established specifically for rural health care providers and\nresidents. As part of this function, the office shall develop a\ncoordinated application process for use by rural providers,\nmunicipalities and others in seeking funds and/or technical assistance\non pertinent rural health care programs and services. The office shall\nalso work to promote the usage of the Rural Assistance Information\nNetwork (RAIN) to assist rural providers and others in obtaining\ninformation on funding and/or technical assistance for rural health care\nprograms and services.\n  2. Apply for grants, and accept gifts from private and public sources\nfor research to improve and enhance rural health care services and\nfacilities. The office shall also promote rural health research in\nuniversities and colleges.\n  3. Together with the rural health council, serve as liaison and\nadvocate for the department on rural health matters. This function shall\ninclude the provision of staff support to the rural health council and\nthe establishment of appropriate program linkages with related federal,\nstate, and local agencies and programs such as the office of rural\naffairs, the agricultural extension service and migrant health services.\n  4. Assist medical schools and state agencies to develop comprehensive\nprograms to improve rural health personnel supply by promoting rural\nclinical training and curriculum improvement, and disseminating rural\nhealth career information to high school and college students.\n  5. Promote community strategic planning or new or improved health care\ndelivery systems and networks in rural areas. Strategic network planning\nand development may include such considerations as personnel, capital\nfacilities, reimbursement, primary care, long term care, acute care,\nrehabilitative, preventive, and related services on the health\ncontinuum.\n  6. Review the impact of programs, regulations, and health care\nreimbursement policies on rural services delivery and access.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>