<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-238-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-238-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="238-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-238-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-238-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-238-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-238-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_238_C">
        <num>238-C</num>
        <heading>Provider reporting requirements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 238-c. Provider reporting requirements. Each health care provider\nproviding clinical laboratory, pharmacy services, radiation therapy\nservices, physical therapy services or x-ray or imaging services shall\nreport to the commissioner in writing every two years information\nconcerning the provider's ownership arrangements, including the health\nor health related items or services provided by the provider and the\nnames and professional license numbers or any appropriate program\nprovider numbers of practitioners with an ownership or investment\ninterest in the provider, or whose immediate relatives have such an\nownership or investment. The information required to be reported to the\ncommissioner pursuant to this section to the extent practicable shall be\nconsistent with the information required pursuant to federal law and\nregulations to be reported to the secretary of health and human services\nfor health care providers providing items or services to beneficiaries\nof title XVIII of the federal social security act (medicare). The\ncommissioner shall consult with the commissioner of social services to\navoid duplication of reporting requirements for health care providers\nthat participate in the medical assistance program pursuant to title\neleven of article five of the social services law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>