<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2444"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2444"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2444"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2444/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2444/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2444/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2444/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2444">
        <num>2444</num>
        <heading>Human research review committees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2444. Human research review committees.  1. Each public or private\ninstitution or agency which conducts, or which proposes to conduct or\nauthorize, human research, shall establish a human research review\ncommittee. Such committee shall be composed of not less than five\npersons, approved by the commissioner, who have such varied backgrounds\nas to assure the competent, complete and professional review of human\nresearch activities conducted or proposed to be conducted or authorized\nby the institution or agency. No member of a committee shall be involved\nin either the initial or continuing review of an activity in which he\nhas a conflicting interest, except to provide information required by\nthe committee. No committee shall consist entirely of persons who are\nofficers, employees, or agents of, or who are otherwise associated with\nthe institution or agency, apart from their membership on the committee,\nand no committee shall consist entirely of members of a single\nprofessional group.\n  2. The human research review committee in each institution or agency\nshall require that institution or agency to promulgate a statement of\nprinciple and policy in regard to the rights and welfare of human\nsubjects in the conduct of human research, and the committee and the\ncommissioner shall approve that statement prior to its taking effect.\nThe committee shall review each proposed human research project to\ndetermine (1) its necessity; (2) that the rights and welfare of the\nhuman subjects involved are adequately protected, (3) that the risks to\nthe human subjects are outweighed by the potential benefits to them or\nby the importance of the knowledge to be gained; (4) that the voluntary\ninformed consent is to be obtained by methods that are adequate and\nappropriate, and (5) that the persons proposed to conduct the particular\nmedical research are appropriately competent and qualified. The\ncommittee shall periodically examine each existing human research\nproject with regard to the proper application of the approved principles\nand policies which the institution or agency has promulgated. The\ncommittee shall report any violation to the commissioner. In addition to\nthe voluntary informed consent of the proposed human subject as required\nby section twenty-four hundred forty-two of this chapter, the consent of\nthe committee and the commissioner shall be required with relation to\nthe conduct of human research involving minors, incompetent persons,\nmentally disabled persons and prisoners.\n  3. Each person engaged in the conduct of human research or proposing\nto conduct human research shall affiliate himself with an institution or\nagency having a human research review committee, and such human research\nas he conducts or proposes to conduct shall be subject to review by such\ncommittee in the manner set forth in this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>