<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-250"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-250"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="250"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-250/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-250/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-250/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-250/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_250">
        <num>250</num>
        <heading>Spinal cord injury research board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 250. Spinal cord injury research board. 1. A spinal cord injury\nresearch board is hereby created within the department for the purpose\nof administering spinal cord injury research projects and administering\nthe spinal cord injury research trust fund created pursuant to section\nninety-nine-f of the state finance law. The purpose of research projects\nadministered by the board shall be neurological research towards a cure\nfor such injuries and their effects. The members of the spinal cord\ninjury research board shall include but not be limited to\nrepresentatives of the following fields: neuroscience, neurology,\nneuro-surgery, neuro-pharmacology, and spinal cord rehabilitative\nmedicine. The board shall be composed of thirteen members, seven of whom\nshall be appointed by the governor, two of whom shall be appointed by\nthe temporary president of the senate, two of whom shall be appointed by\nthe speaker of the assembly, one of whom shall be appointed by the\nminority leader of the senate, and one of whom shall be appointed by the\nminority leader of the assembly.\n  2. Board members shall be reimbursed for ordinary travel expenses,\nincluding meals and lodging, incurred in the performance of duties\npursuant to section two hundred fifty-one of this title.\n  3. The terms of board members shall be four years commencing January\nfirst, nineteen hundred ninety-nine.\n  4. At the end of a term, a member shall continue to serve until a\nsuccessor is appointed. A member who is appointed after a term has begun\nshall serve the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed. A\nmember who serves two consecutive full four year terms shall not be\neligible for reappointment for four years after completion of those\nterms.\n  5. A majority of the full authorized membership of the board shall\nconstitute a quorum.\n  6. One member of the board shall be chosen by the governor to serve as\nchairperson.\n  7. Meetings of the board shall be held at least twice a year but may\nbe held more frequently as deemed necessary, subject to call by the\nchairman or by request of a majority of the board members. Board\nmeetings shall concern, among other things, policy matters relating to\nspinal cord injury research projects and programs, research progress\nreports, and other matters necessary to carry out the intent of this\ntitle.\n  8. Members of the board shall be indemnified pursuant to section\nseventeen of the public officers law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>