<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2500-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2500-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2500_L">
        <num>2500-L</num>
        <heading>Pregnant people, blood test for hepatitis C virus (HCV); follow-up care</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2500-l. Pregnant people, blood test for hepatitis C virus (HCV);\nfollow-up care. 1. Every physician or other authorized practitioner\nattending a pregnant person in the state shall order a hepatitis C virus\n(HCV) screening test and if the test is reactive, an HCV RNA test must\nbe performed on the same specimen, or a second specimen collected at the\nsame time as the initial HCV screening test specimen, to confirm\ndiagnosis of current infection. The health care provider shall either\noffer all persons with a detectable HCV RNA test follow-up HCV health\ncare and treatment or refer the individual to a health care provider who\ncan provide follow-up HCV health care and treatment.\n  2. The physician or other authorized practitioner attending a pregnant\nperson shall record the HCV test results prominently in the pregnant\nperson's medical record at or before the time of hospital admission for\ndelivery.\n  3. The commissioner may promulgate such rules and regulations as are\nnecessary to carry out the requirements of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>