<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-251"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-251"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="251"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-251/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-251/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-251/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-251/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_251">
        <num>251</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 251. Powers and duties. The spinal cord injury research board\ncreated pursuant to section two hundred fifty of this title shall:\n  1. Formulate policies and procedures necessary to carry out the\nprovisions of this title;\n  2. Solicit, receive, and review applications from public and private\nagencies and organizations and qualified research institutions for\ngrants from the spinal cord injury research trust fund, created pursuant\nto section ninety-nine-f of the state finance law, to conduct research\nprograms which focus on the treatment and cure of spinal cord injury.\nThe board shall make recommendations to the commissioner, and the\ncommissioner shall, in his or her discretion, grant approval of\napplications for grants from those applications recommended by the\nboard.\n  3. Ensure that state funds, appropriated for spinal cord injury\nresearch are not diverted to any other use; and\n  4. Provide the governor and the legislature an annual report by\nJanuary thirty-first of each year succeeding the year in which this\ntitle shall take effect setting forth the status of funds appropriated\nfor spinal cord injury research and the progress of the board in terms\nof the results of its spinal cord injury research efforts.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>