<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2530"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2530">
        <num>2530</num>
        <heading>Nurse-family partnership</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2530__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Eligible participant" means a person enrolled in medical\nassistance under title eleven of article five of the social services law\nwho is a pregnant woman who will be a first-time mother; and her\nnewborn, either or both of whom is at risk for poor outcomes.\n"Participant" means an eligible participant who is participating in the\nnurse-family partnership program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2530__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Nurse-family partnership program" or "program" means the\nnurse-family partnership program established under this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2530__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Nurse-family partnership provider" or "provider" means a county\nhealth department, including the health department of the city of New\nYork, or an entity in contract with such a health department to provide\nservices under the program or an entity that contracts directly with the\ncommissioner to provide services under this program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2530__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Case management services" means services that assist a\nparticipant in gaining access to needed medical, social, educational,\nand other services, including: an assessment to determine service needs;\ndevelopment of a care plan based on the assessment; referral to medical,\nsocial, educational and other providers; and monitoring and other\nfollow-up activities to ensure that the care plan is effectively\nimplemented and addresses the assessed needs.\n  3. The nurse-family partnership program is a nurse home-visiting\nprogram in which a nurse-family partnership provider provides case\nmanagement and nursing services (primarily nurse home visits to\nparticipants) to eligible participants up to the child's second\nbirthday. Participation in the program shall be voluntary for eligible\nparticipants.\n  4. A nurse-family partnership provider shall be approved by a\nnationally-recognized organization involved with nurse-family\npartnership programs, designated by the commissioner, and shall meet\nsuch other criteria as established by the commissioner.\n  5. The commissioner may establish the nurse-family partnership program\nin one or more social services districts and may establish program\nenrollment limits based on analysis of need and available\nappropriations.\n  6. Nurse-family partnership program services provided by a provider to\nan eligible participant under this section shall be deemed to be medical\nassistance services under title eleven of article five of the social\nservices law. The commissioner may establish, subject to the approval of\nthe director of the division of the budget, rates of payment to\nnurse-family partnership providers for providing nurse-family\npartnership program services.\n  7. The commissioner shall submit all appropriate amendments to the\nstate plan for medical assistance and shall submit applications for\nwaivers of the federal social security act as shall be necessary to\nobtain federal financial participation in the costs of serv...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>