<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2545"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2545"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2545"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2545/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2545/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2545/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2545/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2545">
        <num>2545</num>
        <heading>Individualized family services plans ("IFSP")</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement, based on objective criteria, of the infant's or\ntoddler's present levels of physical development, including vision and\nhearing; cognitive development; communication development; social or\nemotional development; and adaptive development;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>with parental consent, a statement of the family's strengths,\npriorities and concerns that relate to enhancing the development of the\ninfant or toddler;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the major outcomes expected to be achieved for\nthe child and the family, including timelines, and (ii) the criteria and\nprocedures that will be used to determine whether progress toward\nachieving the outcomes is being made and whether modifications or\nrevisions of the outcomes or services are necessary;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement of specific early intervention services, including\ntransportation and the mode thereof, necessary to meet the unique needs\nof the child and the family, including the frequency, intensity,\nlocation and the method of delivering services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement of the natural environments, including the home and\ncommunity settings where children without disabilities participate, in\nwhich early intervention services shall appropriately be provided and an\nexplanation of their appropriateness, and, where the child is in day\ncare, a plan for qualified professionals to train the day care provider\nto accommodate the needs of the child, where appropriate;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement of other services, including but not limited to\nmedical services, that are not required under this title but that are\nneeded by the child and the family;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement of other public programs under which the child and\nfamily may be eligible for benefits, and a referral, where indicated;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the projected dates for initiation of services and the anticipated\nduration of such services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name of the service coordinator selected by the parent who\nwill be responsible for the implementation of the IFSP and coordination\nwith other agencies and persons;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the steps to be taken supporting the potential transition of the\ntoddler with a disability to services provided under section forty-four\nhundred ten of the education law or to other services, to the extent the\nchild is thought to be eligible for such services, including:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2545__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>discussions with and education of parents regarding potential\noptions and other matters related to the child's transition;\n  (ii) procedures to prepare the child for changes in service delivery,\nincluding steps to help the child adjust to, and function in, a new\nsetting; and\n  (iii) with parental consent, the transmission of information about the\nchild to the committee on preschool special education, to ensure\ncontinuity of services, if appropriate, including evaluation and\nassessment information and copies of IFSPs.\n  3. In developing the IFSP, consideration shall first be given to\nprovision of transportation by a parent of a child to early intervention\nservices. Other modes of transportation shall be provided if the parent\ncan demonstrate the inability to provide appropriate transportation\nservices.\n  4. If the IFSP team members, including the early intervention official\nand the parent agree on the IFSP, the IFSP shall be deemed final and the\nservice coordinator shall be authorized to implement the plan.\n  5. If the IFSP team members, including the early intervention official\nand the parent do not agree on an IFSP, the service coordinator shall\nimplement the sections of the proposed IFSP that are not in dispute, and\nthe parent shall have the due process rights set forth in section\ntwenty-five hundred forty-nine of this title.\n  6. The contents of the IFSP shall be fully explained to the parent,\nand informed consent from the parent shall be obtained prior to the\nprovision of the early intervention services therein. If the parent does\nnot provide such consent with respect to a particular early intervention\nservice, then only those early intervention services with respect to\nwhich consent is obtained shall be provided.\n  7. The IFSP shall be reviewed at six month intervals and shall be\nevaluated annually by the early intervention official, service\ncoordinator, the parent and providers of services to the eligible child.\nUpon request of a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>