<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-263"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-263"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="263"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-263/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-263/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-263/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-263/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_263">
        <num>263</num>
        <heading>Department authorized to study obesity - report</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 263. Department authorized to study obesity - report. 1. The\ndepartment is authorized to sample and collect data on individual cases\nwhere obesity is being actively treated and to analyze such data in\norder to evaluate the impact of treating obesity. Such data collection\nand analysis shall include the following:\n  a. The effectiveness of existing methods for treating or preventing\nobesity;\n  b. The effectiveness of alternate methods for treating or preventing\nobesity;\n  c. The fiscal impact of treating or preventing obesity;\n  d. The compliance and cooperation of patients with various methods of\ntreating or preventing obesity; or\n  e. The reduction in serious medical problems associated with diabetes\nthat results from treating or preventing obesity.\n  2. The department is authorized to fund the research authorized in\nsubdivision one of this section from gifts, grants, and donations from\nindividuals, private organizations, foundations, or any governmental\nunit; except that no gift, grant, or donation may be accepted by the\ndepartment if it is subject to conditions that are inconsistent with\nthis title or any other laws of this state. The department shall have\nthe power to direct the disposition of any such gift, grant, or donation\nfor the purposes of this title.\n  3. After completion of the research authorized in subdivision one of\nthis section, the department shall submit a report and supporting\nmaterials to the governor and the legislature by June first of the\nfollowing year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>