<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="265-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-265-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_265_C">
        <num>265-C</num>
        <heading>Ethics committee</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>scientific, medical, and ethical standards;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>standards for all medical, socioeconomic, and financial aspects of\nclinical trials and therapy delivery to patients, including, but not\nlimited to standards for safe and ethical procedures for: obtaining\nmaterials and cells for research; clinical efforts for the appropriate\ntreatment of human subjects in medical research; and ensuring compliance\nwith patient privacy laws;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>oversight of funded research to ensure compliance with the\nstandards described in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_265_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>relevant ethical and regulatory issues.\n  3. With the exception of the ex officio member, the ethics committee\nshall be divided into three classes. Of the three classes, the first\nclass appointed shall include three of the governor's appointees, one\nappointee nominated by the temporary president of the senate, and one\nappointee nominated by the speaker of the assembly; and shall serve for\na term ending one year from the effective date of this title. The second\nclass shall include two of the governor's appointees, one appointee\nnominated by the minority leader of the senate, and one appointee\nnominated by the minority leader of the assembly; and shall serve for a\nterm ending two years from the effective date of this title. The third\nclass shall include the final governor's appointee, one appointee\nnominated by the temporary president of the senate, and one appointee\nnominated by the speaker of the assembly; and shall serve for a term\nending three years from the effective date of this title. Subsequently,\neach member appointed shall serve a term of three years and no more than\ntwo terms of three years each. A vacancy in the membership of the board\nshall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term in the same manner\nas the original appointment.\n  * NB Repealed December 31, 2025\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>