<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-266-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-266-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="266-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-266-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-266-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-266-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-266-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_266_A">
        <num>266-A</num>
        <heading>The 21st century workgroup for disease elimination and reduction</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 266-a. The 21st century workgroup for disease elimination and\nreduction. The 21st century workgroup for disease elimination and\nreduction is hereby created within the department. The workgroup shall:\n  1. Be comprised of experts within the department's bureau of\nimmunization, experts on the immunization advisory council and other\nexperts the commissioner deems appropriate, charged with the mission of\nreviewing existing vaccines, the status of international research and\ndevelopment for vaccines likely to be candidates for the pharmaceutical\nmarketplace, and to review the status of health threats which could be\naddressed by the development of vaccines;\n  2. Study the severity, frequency of occurrence, likelihood of\nrecurrence, existing animal vaccines and potential human vaccines for\ntuberculosis, eastern equine encephalitis virus, Lyme disease, human\nimmunodeficiency virus, and any other disease or virus the commissioner\ndeems appropriate;\n  3. Consult with national vaccine and immunization policy making\norganizations, including but not limited to, the advisory committee on\nimmunization practices under the centers for disease control and\nprevention, the national institute of health and the national institute\nof allergy and infectious diseases;\n  4. Apply for grants, accept gifts from private and public sources for\npurposes set forth herein; and\n  5. Report every three years, commencing January first, two thousand\neighteen, to the commissioner, the temporary president of the senate,\nthe speaker of the assembly, the chair of the senate standing committee\non health, and the chair of the assembly health committee.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>