<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="268-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_268_E">
        <num>268-E</num>
        <heading>Appeals and appeal hearings; judicial review</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>applicants for or enrollees in insurance affordability programs\nand qualified health plans; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>other persons entitled to an opportunity for an appeal hearing as\ndirected by the commissioner.\n  4. An applicant or enrollee has the right to appeal at least the\nfollowing issues:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An eligibility determination made in accordance with this article\nand applicable law, including:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An initial determination of eligibility, including:\n  (A) eligibility to enroll in a qualified health plan;\n  (B) eligibility for Medicaid;\n  (C) eligibility for Child Health Plus;\n  (D) eligibility for the Basic Health Program;\n  (E) eligibility for the 1332 state innovation program;\n  (F) the amount of advance payments of the premium tax credit and level\nof cost-sharing reductions;\n  (G) the amount of any other subsidy that may be available under law;\nand\n  (H) eligibility for such other health insurance programs as determined\nby the commissioner; and\n  (ii) a re-determination of eligibility of the programs under this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An eligibility determination for an exemption for any mandate to\npurchase health insurance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A failure by NY State of Health to provide timely written notice\nof an eligibility determination made in accordance with applicable law.\n  5. The department may, subject to the discretion of the commissioner,\npromulgate such regulations, consistent with federal or state law, as\nmay be necessary to implement the provisions of this section.\n  6. Regarding every decision of an appeal pursuant to this section, the\ndepartment must inform every party, and his or her representative, if\nany, of the availability of judicial review and the time limitation to\npursue future review.\n  7. Applicants and enrollees of qualified health plans, with or without\nadvance payments of the premium tax credit and cost-sharing reductions,\nalso have the right to appeal to the United States Department of Health\nand Human Services appeal entity:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>appeals decisions issued by NY State of Health upon the exhaustion\nof the NY State of Health appeals process; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a denial of a request to vacate a dismissal made by the NY State\nof Health appeals entity.\n  8. The department must include notice of the right to appeal as\nprovided by subdivision four of this section and instructions regarding\nhow to file an appeal in any eligibility determination issued to the\napplicant or enrollee in accordance with applicable law. Such notice\nshall include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an explanation of the applicant or enrollee's appeal rights;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the procedures by which the applicant or enrollee\nmay request an appeal;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>information on the applicant or enrollee's right to represent\nhimself or herself, or to be represented by legal counsel or another\nrepresentative;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an explanation of the circumstances under which the appellant's\neligibility may be maintained or reinstated pending an appeal decision;\nand\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_268_E__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an explanation that an appeal decision for one household member\nmay result in a change in eligibility for other household members and\nthat such a change will be handled as a redetermination of eligibility\nfor all household members in accordance with the standards specified in\napplicable law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>