<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="268-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_268_G">
        <num>268-G</num>
        <heading>Funding of the Marketplace</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 268-g. Funding of the Marketplace. 1. The Marketplace shall be\nfunded by state and federal sources as authorized by applicable law,\nincluding but not limited to applicable law authorizing the respective\ninsurance affordability programs available through the Marketplace.\n  2. The accounts of the Marketplace shall be subject to supervision of\nthe comptroller and such accounts shall include receipts, expenditures,\ncontracts and other matters which pertain to the fiscal soundness of the\nMarketplace.\n  3. Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, and in accordance with\nsection four of the state finance law, upon request of the director of\nthe budget, in consultation with the commissioner, the superintendent\nand the executive director of the Marketplace, the comptroller is hereby\nauthorized and directed to sub-allocate or transfer special revenue\nfederal funds appropriated to the department for planning and\nimplementing various healthcare and insurance reform initiatives\nauthorized by applicable law. Marketplace moneys sub-allocated or\ntransferred pursuant to this section shall be paid out of the fund upon\naudit and warrant of the state comptroller on vouchers certified or\napproved by the Marketplace.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>