<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="268"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-268/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_268">
        <num>268</num>
        <heading>Statement of policy and purposes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 268. Statement of policy and purposes. The purpose of this title\nis to codify the establishment of the health benefit exchange in New\nYork, known as NY State of Health, The Official Health Plan Marketplace\n(Marketplace), in conformance with Executive Order 42 (Cuomo) issued\nApril 12, 2012. The Marketplace shall continue to perform eligibility\ndeterminations for federal and state insurance affordability programs\nincluding medical assistance in accordance with section three hundred\nsixty-six of the social services law, child health plus in accordance\nwith section twenty-five hundred eleven of this chapter, the basic\nhealth program in accordance with section three hundred sixty-nine-gg of\nthe social services law, the 1332 state innovation program in accordance\nwith section three hundred sixty-nine-ii of the social service law, and\npremium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions, together with\nperforming eligibility determinations for qualified health plans and\nsuch other health insurance programs as determined by the commissioner.\nThe Marketplace shall also facilitate enrollment in insurance\naffordability programs, qualified health plans and other health\ninsurance programs as determined by the commissioner, the purchase and\nsale of qualified health plans and/or other or additional health plans\ncertified by the Marketplace pursuant to this title, and shall continue\nto have the authority to operate a small business health options program\n("SHOP") to assist eligible small employers in selecting qualified\nhealth plans and/or other or additional health plans certified by the\nMarketplace and to determine small employer eligibility for purposes of\nsmall employer tax credits. It is the intent of the legislature, by\ncodifying the Marketplace in state statute, to continue to promote\nquality and affordable health coverage and care, reduce the number of\nuninsured persons, provide a transparent marketplace, educate consumers\nand assist individuals with access to coverage, premium assistance tax\ncredits and cost-sharing reductions. In addition, the legislature\ndeclares the intent that the Marketplace continue to be properly\nintegrated with insurance affordability programs, including Medicaid,\nchild health plus and the basic health program, the 1332 state\ninnovation program, and such other health insurance programs as\ndetermined by the commissioner.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 268's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>