<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2710"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2710"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2710"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2710/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2710/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2710/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2710/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2710">
        <num>2710</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and purposes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2710. Legislative findings and purposes.  It is hereby declared and\nfound that one of the major problems facing medicine and the public\nhealth and welfare is the lack of trained individuals, available\nfacilities, research and equipment for the discovery, evaluation,\ndiagnosis, treatment and cure of kidney disease. It is estimated that\nmore than two thousand people die in New York state each year from\nkidney failure. No parallel situation in medicine exists today where\ntechniques have been developed for the diagnosis and prevention of\ndisease which would save lives, yet at the same time people continue to\nprogress to chronic kidney disease and death only for the lack of\nfacilities for diagnosis and treatment. New York state must take the\ninitiative to combat this indiscriminate and often needless killer.\nBasic research is needed into the nature of diseases of the kidneys and\nthe problems of kidney transplantation; in developing mass testing\nprocedures for the early detection of kidney disease; and for the\ndevelopment of more effective and economical devices for blood\npurification. An intensive survey of state-wide needs and facilities is\nnecessary to formulate a long-range program for the state.\n  It is imperative that a comprehensive program to combat kidney disease\nbe implemented through the combined and correlated efforts of state and\nlocal governments, medicine, universities, non-profit organizations and\nindividuals. The program provided by this article is designed to bring\nto bear all the possible resources of the state and to coordinate the\nefforts of the state in this vital matter of public health.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>