<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2799-R"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2799-R"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-R"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2799-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2799-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2799-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2799-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_R">
        <num>2799-R</num>
        <heading>Program evaluations and recommendations; reports and statewide conference on best practices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-r. Program evaluations and recommendations; reports and\nstatewide conference on best practices. 1. Employers participating in\nthe New York wellness works program pursuant to this article shall\nreport to the commissioner on the findings, experience and benefits\npursuant to such program.\n  2. The commissioner shall evaluate and report his or her findings\nconcerning the New York wellness works program, including but not\nlimited to the health and cost benefits, and shall make recommendations\nfor modifying, expanding or otherwise improving the program as well as\nrecommendations for other health system improvements based on such\nprogram. Such report shall incorporate the information submitted\npursuant to subdivision one of this section and shall be submitted to\nthe governor, temporary president of the senate, speaker of the assembly\nand the school of public health and health professions at the university\nat Buffalo on or before February first, two thousand nine.\n  On or before May first, two thousand nine, and at least biennially\nthereafter, the commissioner in consultation with the advisory panel\nshall convene a statewide conference to further promote the sharing of\nbest practices among employers and others in pursuit of the goals of the\nNew York wellness works program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>