<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2801-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2801-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2801-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2801-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2801-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2801-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2801-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2801_C">
        <num>2801-C</num>
        <heading>Injunctions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2801-c. Injunctions.  The supreme court may enjoin violations or\nthreatened violations of any provisions of this article; and it may\nenjoin violations of the regulations of the department adopted\nthereunder. Upon request of the public health council or the\ncommissioner, the attorney general shall maintain an action in the\nsupreme court in the name of the people of the state to enjoin any such\nviolation.  Notwithstanding any limitation of the civil practice law and\nrules, such court may, on motion and affidavit, and upon proof that such\nviolation is one which reasonably may result in injury to any person,\nwhether or not such person is a party to such action, grant a temporary\ninjunction upon such terms as may be just, pending the determination of\nthe action. No security on the part of the people of this state shall be\nrequired. In any action for injunction brought pursuant to this article,\nany finding of the public health council or the commissioner or hearing\nofficer designated by either shall be prima facie evidence of the fact\nor facts found therein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>