<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2803-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2803-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2803_S">
        <num>2803-S</num>
        <heading>Access to product recall information</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2803-s. Access to product recall information. The commissioner shall\nrequire that every hospital and birth center distribute at the time of\npre-booking or admission directly to each maternity patient and, upon\nrequest, to the general public an informational leaflet. Such leaflet\nshall be designed by the commissioner in conjunction with the secretary\nof state and shall contain information detailing how parents or\nguardians of infants and children can subscribe to the United States\nconsumer product safety commission's e-mail subscription lists to\nreceive consumer product recall and safety news by e-mail from the\nUnited States consumer product safety commission and such other material\nas deemed appropriate by the commissioner. Such leaflet shall be made\navailable to hospitals and birth centers by the department on its\nwebsite and shall be provided in English, as well as the top six\nlanguages other than English spoken in the state according to the latest\navailable data from the United States Bureau of Census.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>