<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-Z"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-Z"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2807-Z"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2807-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2807_Z">
        <num>2807-Z</num>
        <heading>Review of eligible federally qualified health center capital projects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_Z__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Eligible capital project" shall mean:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_Z__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A project that does not involve the establishment of a new\noperator pursuant to section twenty-eight hundred one-a of this article,\nwith a total budget of three million dollars or more funded, in whole or\nin part, with federal monies pursuant to section 330 of the Public\nHealth Service (PHS), 42 USC 254b, as amended; or\n  (ii) A project that does not involve the establishment of a new\noperator pursuant to section twenty-eight hundred one-a of this article,\nwith a total budget of three million dollars or more funded, in whole or\nin part, with federal monies pursuant to the federal Capital\nDevelopment-Building Capacity (CD-BC) Grant Program and Immediate\nFacility Improvements (CD-IFI) Grant Program, as authorized by the\nPatient Protection and Affordable Care Act (Affordable Care Act)((P.L.\n111-148), Section 10503</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_Z__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>).\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Budget" shall mean the budget for the capital project.\n  7. Capital projects, with a total budget of less than three million\ndollars that do not involve the establishment of a new operator pursuant\nto section twenty-eight hundred one-a of this article, funded in whole\nor in part through section 330 of the Public Health Service (PHS), 42\nUSC 254b, as amended, or through the federal Capital\nDevelopment-Building Capacity (CD-BC) Grant Program and Immediate\nFacility Improvements (CD-IFI) Grant Program, as authorized by the\nPatient Protection and Affordable Care Act (Affordable Care Act)((P.L.\n111-148), Section 10503</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_Z__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>), shall not be subject to the requirements\nset forth in this section or any other law or regulation regarding\ncertificate of need process or requirements.\n  8. For capital projects exempt from certificate of need requirements\npursuant to subdivision seven of this section, the department shall</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_Z__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nestablish mechanisms to account for the capital costs of such projects\nin the applicant's rate of payment by governmental agencies established\npursuant to section twenty-eight hundred seven of this article;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_Z__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nestablish licensure requirements for such facility, which shall include\npayment of the fees specified at subdivision seven of section\ntwenty-eight hundred two of this article; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2807_Z__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>deem such facilities\neligible for uncompensated care reimbursement made available pursuant to\nsection seven of chapter four hundred thirty-three of the laws of\nnineteen hundred ninety-seven, as amended by section seventy-five of\nchapter one of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-nine.\n  9. The commissioner shall promulgate regulations, and may promulgate\nemergency regulations, to implement the provisions of this section. To\nthe extent that the commissioner has not promulgated such regulations,\nprojects that would otherwise be exempt from certificate of need\nrequirements may be processed, at the option of the applicant, in\naccordance with statutes and regulations governing the certificate of\nneed process.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>