<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2808-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2808-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2808-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2808-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2808-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2808-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2808-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2808_D">
        <num>2808-D</num>
        <heading>Nursing home quality improvement demonstration program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2808_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an increase in direct care staff, either facility wide or targeted\nat a particular area of care or shift;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2808_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>increased training and education of direct care staff, including\nallowing direct care staff to increase their level of licensure relevant\nto nursing home care;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2808_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>efforts to decrease staff turn-over; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2808_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>other efforts related to the recruitment and retention of direct\ncare staff that will effect the quality of care at such facility.\n  3. The commissioner shall consider, in selecting projects, the\nlikelihood that such project will improve the care for the residents of\nthe facility, the financial need of the nursing home and such other\nmatters as the commissioner deems appropriate.\n  4. Grants and adjustments to Medicaid rates of payment made pursuant\nto this section shall not, in aggregate, exceed sixty-two million five\nhundred thousand dollars for the period beginning April first, two\nthousand two and ending December thirty-first, two thousand two, and, on\nan annualized basis, for each annual period thereafter beginning January\nfirst, two thousand three and ending December thirty-first, two thousand\nfour, and shall not, in aggregate, exceed forty-six million eight\nhundred seventy-five thousand dollars for the period July first, two\nthousand five through December thirty-first, two thousand five and shall\nnot, in aggregate, on an annualized basis, exceed seventy-eight million\none hundred twenty-five thousand dollars for the period January first,\ntwo thousand six through December thirty-first, two thousand six and\nsixty-two million five hundred thousand dollars for the period January\nfirst, two thousand seven through June thirtieth, two thousand seven.\n  5. Adjustments to Medicaid rates of payment made pursuant to this\nsection shall not be subject to subsequent adjustment or reconciliation.\n  6. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section or any other\ncontrary provision of law, the commissioner may, from funds allocated\npursuant to subparagraph (ii) or (iii) or (iv) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2808_D__subsec_u">
          <num>(u)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section twenty-eight hundred seven-v of this article,\nin calendar year two thousand five, make grants in an aggregate amount\nnot to exceed twelve million five hundred thousand dollars, to\nresidential health care facilities in support of projects or programs\ndesigned to improve specific areas of quality of care, as determined by\nthe commissioner using established measures of such quality of care, and\nprovided further the commissioner may, from funds allocated pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2808_D__subsec_u">
          <num>(u)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section twenty-eight hundred seven-v\nof this article, for the period January first, two thousand six through\nJune thirtieth two thousand seven, make grants in an aggregate amount\nnot to exceed thirty-five million dollars on an annualized basis, to\nresidential health care facilities that have an arbitrator's decision\nrendered before April first, two thousand six, requiring payments\nrelated to the recruitment and retention of direct care staff, including\nsalary and benefits. Each eligible facility shall receive a payment\namount proportional to the amount each such facility owes pursuant to\nthe arbitrator's decision compared to such amounts owed by all eligible\nfacilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>