<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2810"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2810"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2810"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2810/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2810/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2810/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2810/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2810">
        <num>2810</num>
        <heading>Residential health care facilities; receivership</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2810__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of section\ntwenty-eight hundred six of this chapter the supreme court shall appoint\na receiver who may be the commissioner or his designee. Such application\nshall contain proof by affidavit that the facility has had its operating\ncertificate revoked. Such order to show cause shall be returnable not\nless than five days after service is completed and shall provide for\npersonal service of a copy thereof and the papers on which it is based\non the owner or owners of the land and/or structure on or in which the\nfacility is located.  If any such owner cannot with due diligence be\nserved personally within the county where the property is located and\nwithin the time fixed in such order, then service may be made on such\nperson by posting a copy thereof in a conspicuous place within the\nfacility in question, and by sending a copy thereof by registered mail,\nreturn receipt requested, to such owner at the last address registered\nby him with the department, or in the absence of such registration, to\nthe address set forth in the last recorded deed with respect to such\nfacility.  Service shall be deemed complete on filing proof of service\nthereof in the office of the county clerk, or the clerk of the city of\nNew York, as the case may be.\n  b. On the return of said order to show cause, determination shall have\nprecedence over every other business of the court unless the court shall\nfind that some other pending proceeding, having similar statutory\nprecedence, shall have priority.  The court may conduct a hearing at\nwhich all interested parties shall have the opportunity to present\nevidence pertaining to the application. If the court shall find that the\nfacts warrant the granting thereof, then the commissioner, or any person\ndesignated by the commissioner, shall be appointed receiver to take\ncharge of the facility, and the court shall determine a fair monthly\nrental for the facility, and for the furniture, fixtures and movable\nequipment...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2810__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall terminate the receivership only under any of\nthe following circumstances:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2810__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>eighteen months after the date on which it was ordered;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2810__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>when the department grants the facility a new operating\ncertificate, whether the structure of the facility or the land on which\nit is located shall be under the same or different ownership; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2810__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at such time as all of the patients in the facility have been\nprovided alternative modes of health care, either in another facility or\notherwise.\n  (ii) At the time of termination, the receiver shall render a full and\ncomplete accounting to the court and shall make disposition of surplus\nmoney at the direction of the court.\n  f.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2810__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who is served a copy of an order of the court\nappointing the receiver shall, upon being notified of the name and\naddress of the receiver, make all payments for goods supplied by the\nfacility, or services rendered by the facility, to the receiver. A\nreceipt shall be given for each such payment, and copies of all such\nreceipts shall be kept on file by the receiver.  The amount so received\nshall be deposited by the receiver in a special account which shall also\nbe used for all disbursements made by the receiver.\n  (ii) Any person refusing or omitting to make such a payment after such\nservice and notice may be sued therefor by the receiver. Such person\nshall not in such suit dispute the authority of the receiver to incur or\norder such expenses, or the right of the receiver to have such payments\nmade to him. The receipt of the receiver for any sum paid to him shall,\nin all suits and proceedings and for every purpose, be as effectual in\nfavor of any person holding the same as actual payment of the amount\nthereof to the owner or other person or persons who would, but for the\nprovisions of this subdivision, have been entitled to receive the sum so\npaid. No patient shall be discharged, nor shall any contract or rights\nbe forfeited or impaired, nor any forfeiture or liability be incurred,\nby reason of any omission to pay any owner, contractor or other person\nany sum so paid to the receiver.\n  g. Any other provision of this chapter notwithstanding, the department\nmay, if it deems appropriate, grant to any facility operating or\nscheduled to operate under a receivership authorized by this subdivision\nan operating certificate the duration of which shall be limited to the\nduration of the receivership.\n  h. No provision contained herein shall be deemed to relieve the owner\nor any other person of any civil or criminal liability incurred, or any\nduty imposed by law, by reason of acts or omissions of the owner or any\nother person prior to the ap...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>