<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2820"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2820"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2820"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2820/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2820/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2820/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2820/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2820">
        <num>2820</num>
        <heading>Home based primary care for the elderly demonstration project</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2820. Home based primary care for the elderly demonstration\nproject.  1. Notwithstanding any law to the contrary there is hereby\ncreated a demonstration program within the department to determine the\neffectiveness of providing home based primary care services to elderly\npatients as part of an integrated program of long term care services. As\npart of the demonstration program a selected provider shall be\nauthorized to provide physician, nurse-practitioner, physician assistant\nand nursing services in the home of patients age sixty-five or older and\nto other patients eligible for benefits pursuant to title XVIII of the\nfederal social security act.\n  2. The department may approve up to three providers as part of the\ndemonstration program.\n  3. In order to be an eligible provider an applicant must be licensed\nto provide residential health care services. In addition such applicant\nmust also provide the following services: on-site rehabilitative\nservices, continuing care retirement community licensed pursuant to\narticle forty-six of this chapter or other residential services for the\nelderly or disabled licensed by the state and adult day services as\nauthorized by the department.\n  4. Any provider selected to participate in the demonstration program\nshall annually report to the department on the number of patients\nserved, the type of services provided, the cost of such services, the\nsources of payment for such services, the number of patients served who\nno longer remain in their homes and such other information as required\nby the department to determine the effectiveness of the provision of\nhome based physician and nurse-practitioner services on the health care\nof patients.\n  * NB Repealed January 1, 2031\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>