<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2822"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2822"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2822"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2822/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2822/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2822/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2822/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2822">
        <num>2822</num>
        <heading>Residential care off-site facility demonstration project</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2822. Residential care off-site facility demonstration project. 1.\nNotwithstanding any law to the contrary, there is hereby created a\ndemonstration program within the department to assess reimbursement\nmethodologies and delivery methods in conjunction with the provision of\nphysical, occupational, and speech therapy and related education\nservices provided by licensed professionals acting within their scope of\npractice and employed by a residential health care facility at an\noff-site facility operated by a residential health care facility. As\npart of the demonstration program, a selected provider shall be\nauthorized to provide such therapy and related services for persons in\nneed of such care.\n  2. The department may approve up to three providers as part of the\ndemonstration program.\n  3. In order to be an eligible provider an applicant must be issued an\noperating certificate for the provision of residential health care\nservices pursuant to this article which shall include a certificate to\nprovide on-site outpatient services and demonstrate that the provision\nof all physical, occupational, and speech therapy and related education\nservices provided at the off-site facility will be in accordance with\nall applicable safety standards set forth in state and local law.\n  4. Any provider selected to participate in the demonstration program\nshall annually report to the department on the number of patients\nserved, the type of services provided, the cost of such services, the\nsources of payment for such services, safety standards in place for the\nprovisions of such services and such other information as required by\nthe department to develop reimbursement methodologies and fee schedules\nfor limited services and to determine the effectiveness of the provision\nof therapy and related services at an off-site facility operated by a\nresidential health care facility. During the demonstration period, an\neligible provider approved for the purposes of this section shall not\nhave their medical assistance rates adjusted for any additional costs\nrelated to such demonstration project.\n  * NB Repealed June 30, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>