<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2830*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2830*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-06-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2830*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2830*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2830*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2830*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2830*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2830*2">
        <num>2830*2</num>
        <heading>Regulation of the billing of facility fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2830. Regulation of the billing of facility fees. 1. For the\npurposes of this section, "fee" means any amount charged or billed by a\nprovider for professional health care services provided in a\nhospital-based facility.\n  2. No hospital or health system or health care provider shall bill or\nseek payment from a patient for a facility fee that is not covered by\nthe patient's health insurance carrier unless the patient was notified\nprior to the date of service that a facility fee would be applicable. If\na health care provider enters into a business relationship with a\nhospital or health system that will result in the provider's patients\nbeing subject to facility fees, the health care provider must notify its\npatients of the change and that facility fees will now be applicable to\nservices received from the health care provider. The notice shall be\nprovided in writing at least seven days in advance of each date of\nservice and shall explain the amount of the fee, the purpose of the fee,\nwhether the patient's insurance plan will pay the fee, and for uninsured\npatients, how to apply for financial assistance. If advance written\nnotice is infeasible because the visit was secured less than seven days\nin advance, then a written notice shall be provided on the date the\nservice is rendered. The notice shall be provided in plain language in\nconspicuous twelve-point bold face type and shall be available in the\ntop six languages spoken in the hospital's service area. In no event\nshall a facility fee be charged for services related to the provision of\npreventive care service as defined by the United States Preventive\nServices Task Force.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 2830's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>