<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2874"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2874"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2874"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2874/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2874/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2874/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2874/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2874">
        <num>2874</num>
        <heading>Loans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2874__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the commissioner\nfinds that such property is not essential for the rendition of required\nhospital services as such term is defined in article twenty-eight of\nthis chapter, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2874__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the agency consents to such exclusion.\n  3. In connection with assistance grants which are made by the state,\nfederal government or a municipality to reimburse the eligible borrower\nfor project costs which have been paid for by such eligible borrower\nfrom the proceeds of a loan or such other funds which are legally made\navailable to the eligible borrower, the eligible borrower shall hold and\napply such assistance grants in accordance with the requirements of the\ncommissioner and the agency.\n  4. Any inconsistent provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding,\nmortgages of an eligible borrower shall be exempt from the mortgage\nrecording taxes imposed by article eleven of the tax law.\n  5. The dormitory authority of the state of New York and the New York\nstate urban development corporation are each hereby authorized to issue\nbonds in one or more series pursuant to article 5-C or article 5-F of\nthe state finance law for the purpose of refunding outstanding secured\nhospital project bonds, as defined in subdivision three-a of section\ntwenty-eight hundred seventy-two of this article, and to finance one or\nmore related debt service reserve funds and to pay costs of issuance\nattributable to such refunding bonds.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>