<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2952"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2952"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-06-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2952"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2952/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2952/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2952/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2952/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2952">
        <num>2952</num>
        <heading>Rural health network development grant program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2952__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The specific objectives and description of the proposed network,\nincluding considerations of the existing health care services currently\nbeing delivered within the rural area, and the unmet health care needs\nof the community;\n  (ii) The degrees to which the plan demonstrates enhanced costs and\nservice delivery efficiencies and access to necessary and high quality\nhealth care services by rural residents;\n  (iii) The degree to which stated objectives and the scope of the\nnetwork plan may reasonably be implemented and achieved using existing\nand projected resources;\n  (iv) The degree to which information sharing, communication, and\ncooperation between health care providers, human service entities and\nconsumers would be fostered;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2952__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The contribution the network would make toward the identification\nand development of innovative delivery systems;\n  (vi) The degree to which management and continuity of care would be\nfostered and improved;\n  (vii) The degree to which participating providers are represented on\ngoverning bodies of the network;\n  (viii) The degree to which consumers within the area served or to be\nserved by the network are made aware of and have an effective\nopportunity to provide input in the creation and on-going development of\na network plan; and\n  (ix) The degree to which providers within the area served by the\nnetwork are made aware of and have an effective opportunity to\nparticipate in or become a member of the network.\n  c. The commissioner shall act on such application within ninety days\nafter its receipt. In the event waivers of any regulations are requested\nby an applicant, the commissioner shall have an additional thirty days\nto act upon such application.\n  4. The commissioner or his or her duly authorized representative may\nprovide or contract to provide technical assistance in the creation and\nimplementation of rural health networks and to promote community\norganization, collaboration and communication in rural network\ndevelopment across the state. The funding for any such contract shall\nnot be made available from funds provided for purposes of this section\nby section twenty-eight hundred seven-l of this chapter.\n  5. If the commissioner determines that a grant is being used for\npurposes other than those which are in conformity with this title, the\ncommissioner may withdraw his or her approval of the project and require\nrepayment of all or part of such grant to the state. The commissioner\nshall cause reports to be prepared and submitted for each project by the\ngrantees at such times and in such manner as are consistent with the\npurposes of this title.\n  6. a. The commissioner or his or her duly authorized representative\nmay also, promote ap...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>