<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-03-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2994-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2994_CC">
        <num>2994-CC</num>
        <heading>Consent to a nonhospital order not to resuscitate</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a second determination of capacity\nshall be made by a health or social services practitioner; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_CC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nauthority of the ethics review committee set forth in article\ntwenty-nine-CC of this chapter shall apply only to nonhospital orders\nissued in a hospital.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the concurrence of a second physician, nurse practitioner\nor physician assistant is sought to fulfill the requirements for the\nissuance of a nonhospital order not to resuscitate for patients in a\ncorrectional facility, such second physician, nurse practitioner or\nphysician assistant shall be selected by the chief medical officer of\nthe department of corrections and community supervision or his or her\ndesignee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2994_CC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the concurrence of a second physician, nurse practitioner or\nphysician assistant is sought to fulfill the requirements for the\nissuance of a nonhospital order not to resuscitate for hospice and home\ncare patients, such second physician, nurse practitioner or physician\nassistant shall be selected by the hospice medical director or hospice\nnurse coordinator designated by the medical director or by the home care\nservices agency director of patient care services, as appropriate to the\npatient.\n  5. Consent by a patient or a surrogate for a patient in a residential\nfacility operated or licensed by the office of mental health, other than\na hospital as defined in section 1.03 of the mental hygiene law, shall\nbe governed by this article. Consent by a patient who is intellectually\nor otherwise developmentally disabled and is eligible for\nlife-sustaining treatment decision pursuant to section seventeen hundred\nfifty-b of the surrogate's court procedure act shall be governed by that\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>