<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-II"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-II"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2994-II"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-II/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-II/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-II/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2994-II/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2994_II">
        <num>2994-II</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2994-ii. Definitions. When used in this article, the following words\nor phrases shall have the following meanings:\n  1. "Hospital" shall mean any "general hospital" as defined in section\ntwenty-eight hundred one of this chapter.\n  2. "After-care" shall mean any assistance provided by a caregiver to a\npatient under this article after the patient's discharge from a hospital\nthat is related to the patient's condition at the time of discharge.\nSuch assistance shall include, but is not limited to, assisting with\nbasic activities of daily living (ADLs), instrumental activities of\ndaily living (IADLs), and other tasks as determined to be appropriate by\nthe discharging physician.\n  3. "Caregiver" shall mean any individual duly identified as a\ncaregiver by a patient under this article who provides after-care\nassistance to a patient living in his or her residence. An identified\ncaregiver shall include, but is not limited to, a relative, partner,\nfriend or neighbor who has a significant relationship with the patient.\n  4. "Discharge" shall mean a patient's exit or release from a hospital\nto the patient's residence following an inpatient admission.\n  5. "Entry" shall mean a patient's admission into a hospital for the\npurposes of receiving inpatient care.\n  6. "Patient" shall mean a patient eighteen years of age or older.\n  7. "Residence" shall mean a dwelling that the patient considers to be\nhis or her home. A "residence" for the purposes of this article shall\nnot include any rehabilitation facility, hospital, nursing home,\nassisted living facility, group home or other residential health care\nfacility as defined in section twenty-eight hundred one of this chapter\nor any inpatient facility regulated by the office of mental health.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>