<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2997-F-1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2997-F-1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-11-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2997-F-1"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2997-F-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2997-F-1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2997-F-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2997-F-1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2997_F_1">
        <num>2997-F-1</num>
        <heading>Provision of information relating to sudden unexpected death in epilepsy</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2997_F_1__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>current and evidence-based information about sudden unexpected\ndeath in epilepsy risk factors and conditions reviewed and approved by\none or more professional not-for-profit organizations with expertise in\nneurology and epilepsy; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2997_F_1__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contact information for nonprofit organizations that provide\ninformation and support services for epilepsy conditions.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2997_F_1__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall provide written information to health\ncare practitioners necessary to implement subdivision one of this\nsection, and shall post such information on the department's website.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2997_F_1__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall ensure that such information is culturally\nand linguistically appropriate for all recipients.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2997_F_1__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any local or national organization that provides education or\nservices related to epilepsy conditions may request that the\ncommissioner include such organization's informational material and\ncontact information on the department's website. Once such a request is\nmade, the commissioner may add the information to the department's\nwebsite at his or her discretion.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2997_F_1__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall, in consultation with local and national\norganizations that provide education or services related to epilepsy\nconditions, provide guidance to health care practitioners to assist\nhealth care practitioners in determining whether a patient is at\nelevated risk for sudden unexpected death in epilepsy, including but not\nlimited to, whether the patient has had convulsive seizures, the\nfrequency and recency of such seizures, and whether the patient's\nsymptoms have subsided in response to medicinal or surgical treatment.\n  3. A health care practitioner found to be in violation of this section\nshall be issued a warning and shall suffer no further civil penalty or\ndiscipline on any first offense, provided such violation was not\ncommitted willfully and knowingly.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>