<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-GG"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-GG"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-04-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2999-GG"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-2999-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2999_GG">
        <num>2999-GG</num>
        <heading>Voluntary foster care agency health facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_GG__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision ten of\nsection three hundred seventy-one of the social services law.\n  2. Such license shall not be issued unless it is determined that the\nequipment, personnel, rules, standards of care and services are fit and\nadequate, and that the health-related services will be provided in the\nmanner required by this article and the rules and regulations\nthereunder.\n  3. The commissioner and the commissioner of the office of children and\nfamily services shall enter into a memorandum of agreement for the\npurposes of administering the requirements of this section.\n  4. Proceedings involving the issuance of licenses for health-related\nservices to authorized agencies:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_GG__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A license for health-related services under this article may be\nrevoked, suspended, limited, annulled or denied by the commissioner, in\nconsultation with the office of children and family services, if an\nauthorized agency is determined to have failed to comply with the\nprovisions of this article or the rules and regulations promulgated\nthereunder. No action taken against a license under this subdivision\nshall affect an authorized agency's license to care for or board\nchildren unless the commissioner of the office of children and family\nservices determines, pursuant to the regulations of such office, that\nthe existing circumstances make it necessary to limit, suspend or revoke\nthe authority of the authorized agency to care for or board children.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_GG__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No such license shall be revoked, suspended, limited, annulled or\ndenied without a hearing. However, a license may be temporarily\nsuspended or limited without a hearing for a period not in excess of\nthirty days upon written notice that the continuation of health-related\nservices places the public health or safety of the recipients in\nimminent danger.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_GG__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall fix a time and place for the hearing. A\ncopy of the charges, together with the notice of the time and place of\nthe hearing, shall be served in person or mailed by registered or\ncertified mail to the authorized agency at least twenty-one days before\nthe date fixed for the hearing. The authorized agency shall file with\nthe department not less than eight days prior to the hearing, a written\nanswer to the charges.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2999_GG__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All orders or determinations hereunder shall be subject to review\nas provided in article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and\nrules.  Application for such review must be made within sixty days after\nservice in person or by registered or certified mail of a copy of the\norder or determination upon the applicant or agency.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>