<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3000-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3000-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3000-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3000-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3000-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3000-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3000-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3000_D">
        <num>3000-D</num>
        <heading>Availability of resuscitation equipment in certain public places</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3000_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an adult exhaled air\nresuscitation mask, for which the federal food and drug administration\nhas granted permission to market, accompanied by a pair of disposable\ngloves, and (ii) a pediatric exhaled air resuscitation mask, for which\nthe federal food and drug administration has granted permission to\nmarket, accompanied by a pair of disposable gloves.\n  g. "Theater" means a motion picture theater, concert hall, auditorium\nor other building used for, or designed for the primary purpose of,\nexhibiting movies, stage dramas, musical recitals, dance or other\nsimilar performances.\n  2. The owner or operator of a public place shall have available in\nsuch public place resuscitation equipment in quantities deemed adequate\nby the department. Such equipment shall be readily accessible for use\nduring medical emergencies. Any information deemed necessary by the\ncommissioner shall accompany the resuscitation equipment. Resuscitation\nequipment shall be discarded after a single use.\n  3. The owner or operator of a public place shall provide notice to\npatrons, by means of signs, printed material or other means of written\ncommunication, indicating the availability of resuscitation equipment\nfor emergency use and providing information on how to obtain\ncardiopulmonary resuscitation training. The type, size, style, location\nand language of such notice shall be determined in accordance with\nrules, promulgated by the commissioner. In promulgating such rules, the\ncommissioner shall take into consideration the concerns of the public\nplaces within the scope of this section. If the department shall make\nsigns available pursuant to this subdivision, it may charge a fee to\ncover printing, postage and handling expenses.\n  4. Any owner or operator of a public place, his or her employee or\nother agent, or any other person who voluntarily and without expectation\nof monetary compensation renders emergency treatment using the\nresuscitation equipment required pursuant to th...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>