<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3002-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3002-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3002-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3002-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3002-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3002-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3002-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3002_A">
        <num>3002-A</num>
        <heading>State emergency medical advisory committee</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3002_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>medical control;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3002_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>treatment,\ntransportation and triage protocols, including protocols for invasive\nprocedures and infection control; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3002_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the use of regulated medical\ndevices and drugs by emergency medical services personnel certified\npursuant to this article. The state emergency medical advisory\ncommittee, with the consent of the commissioner, may issue advisory\nguidelines in any of these areas, which shall not have the force and\neffect of law unless adopted as rules and regulations by the state\nemergency medical services council. The state emergency medical advisory\ncommittee shall advise the state emergency medical services council\nprior to the issuance of any guidelines. The committee shall also review\nprotocols developed by regional emergency medical advisory committees\nfor consistency with statewide standards.\n  2-a. Any decision of the state emergency medical advisory committee\nregarding medical control, protocols for treatment, triage, or\ntransportation, or the use of regulated medical devices may be appealed\nto the commissioner by any required regional emergency medical services\ncouncil, regional emergency medical advisory committee, ambulance\nservice or advanced life support service, or certified first responder,\nemergency medical technician, or advanced emergency medical technician\nadversely affected.\n  3. Each member shall have a term of two years, except that five of\nthose first appointed shall have a term of three years. Members may\nsucceed themselves.\n  4. The committee shall meet as frequently as its business may require.\nThe presence of a majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. The\nmembers of the committee shall receive no compensation for their\nservices as members, but each shall be allowed the necessary and actual\nexpenses incurred in the performance of his or her duties under this\nsection.\n  5. No civil action shall be brought in any court against any member,\nofficer or employee of the committee for any act done, failure to act,\nor statement or opinion made, while discharging his or her duties as a\nmember, officer, or employee of the commit...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>