<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3003-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3003_A">
        <num>3003-A</num>
        <heading>EMS program agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3003-a. EMS program agencies. 1. As provided by agreement with the\ncommissioner or regional councils based on needs identified by the\nregional emergency medical services councils, an EMS program agency may\nbe responsible for facilitating quality improvement of emergency medical\ncare within its region, staffing the regional emergency medical advisory\ncommittees provided for in section three thousand four-a of this\narticle, providing prehospital education programs approved by the\ndepartment, and other activities to support and facilitate regional\nemergency medical services systems.\n  2. The programs developed by the agencies established by subdivision\none of this section shall be implemented beginning in nineteen hundred\nninety-three using funds collected by the New York state emergency\nmedical services training account, established within the miscellaneous\nspecial revenue fund - 339 by section ninety-seven-q of the state\nfinance law.\n  3. The portion of the funds collected by the emergency medical\nservices training New York state account, established and allocated\nwithin the miscellaneous special revenue fund - 339 by section\nninety-seven-q of the state finance law, shall be adequate to support\nthe costs incurred in implementing the programs described in subdivision\none of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>