<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3003-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3003-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3003_B">
        <num>3003-B</num>
        <heading>Availability of ambulance service and advanced life support first response service to store and distribute blood and initiate and adminis...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3003-b. Availability of ambulance service and advanced life support\nfirst response service to store and distribute blood and initiate and\nadminister blood transfusions. 1. An ambulance service or advanced life\nsupport first response service licensed under this article may store and\ndistribute human blood and blood products at all their facilities and\nqualified medical and health personnel, as defined in this article,\noperating within an ambulance service or advanced life support first\nresponse service licensed under this article, may initiate and\nadminister human blood and blood product transfusions while providing\nambulance services or advanced life support care via an advanced life\nsupport mobile unit. As used in this section, " ambulance services"\nmeans emergency medical care and the transportation of sick or injured\npersons by motor vehicle or aircraft to, from or between general\nhospitals or other health care facilities.\n  2. Notwithstanding title five of article five of this chapter, any\nambulance service or advanced life support first response service\nlicensed under this article may store and distribute human blood and\nblood products in accordance with standards for the storage of blood\nproducts of the United States Food and Drug Administration and any\nrules, regulations, guidance or minimum standards established pursuant\nto this section.\n  3. Prior to storing and distributing blood or allowing qualified\nmedical and health personnel to initiate and administer blood\ntransfusions under this section, the ambulance service or advanced life\nsupport first response service shall ensure that it is in compliance\nwith the rules, regulations, guidance or minimum standards established\npursuant to this section and other applicable emergency medical service\nrequirements, and shall provide notification of intent to store and\ndistribute blood or allow qualified medical and health personnel to\ninitiate and administer blood transfusions as part of their ambulance\nservices or advanced life support care at least sixty days prior to\nbeginning such care.\n  4. The state emergency medical services council, with the approval of\nthe commissioner, shall promulgate rules and regulations to effectuate\nthe purposes of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>