<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3011"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3011"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3011"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3011/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3011/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3011/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3011/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3011">
        <num>3011</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the department and the commissioner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3011. Powers and duties of the department and the commissioner. 1.\nThe department may inquire into the operation of ambulance services and\nadvanced life support first response services and conduct periodic\ninspections of facilities, communication services, vehicles, methods,\nprocedures, materials, staff and equipment. It may also evaluate data\nreceived from ambulance services and advanced life support first\nresponse services.\n  2. The department may require ambulance services and advanced life\nsupport first response services to submit periodic reports of calls\nreceived, services performed and such other information as may be\nnecessary to carry out the provisions of this article.\n  3. The commissioner, with the advice and consent of the state council,\nshall designate not more than eighteen geographic areas within the state\nwherein a regional emergency medical services council shall be\nestablished. In making the determination of a geographic area, the\ncommissioner shall take into consideration the presence of ambulance\nservices, hospital facilities, existing emergency medical services\ncommittees, trained health personnel, health planning agencies and\ncommunication and transportation facilities; and shall establish\nseparate regional emergency medical services councils for the counties\nof Nassau and Westchester. The commissioner shall promote and encourage\nthe establishment of a regional emergency medical services council in\neach of said designated areas.\n  3-a. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this article:\n  a. The creation of any regional council or emergency medical services\nprogram agency on or after January first, two thousand shall not\ndiminish any then existing funding appropriated after the effective date\nof this subdivision to regional councils or emergency medical services\nprogram agencies;\n  b. Subject to the provisions of paragraph c of this subdivision,\nfunding for regional councils and emergency medical services program\nagencies existing on or after January first, two thousand shall be\nincreased in proportion to any funding appropriated therefor by the\ndepartment and in such proportion as determined by the department;\n  c. Funding for any regional council or emergency medical services\nprogram agency created on or after January first, two thousand shall be\nin addition to any funds appropriated on the effective date of this\nsubdivision for regional councils or emergency medical services program\nagencies existing on January first, two thousand. Funding for any\nregional council or emergency medical services program agency created\nafter January first, two thousand shall be in an amount at least equal\nto the minimum funding level appropriated to regional councils or\nemergency medical services program agencies existing on such date, or in\nan amount equal to the proportion that such new regional council or\nemergency medical services program agency represented on the basis of\npopulation in its former regional council or emergency medical services\nprogram agency, whichever is larger.\n  4. The commissioner may propose rules and regulations and amendments\nthereto for consideration by the state council. The commissioner shall\nestablish a schedule of certification fees for ambulance services and\nadvanced life support first response services other than voluntary\nambulance services and voluntary advanced life support first response\nservices.\n  5. For the purpose of promoting the public health, safety and welfare\nthe commissioner is hereby authorized and empowered to contract with\nvoluntary ambulance services and municipal ambulance services, or with\nthe fire commissioners of fire districts operating voluntary ambulance\nservices, upon such terms and conditions as he shall deem appropriate\nand within amounts made available therefor, for reimbursement of the\nnecessary and incidental costs incurred by such ambulance services in\norder to effectuate the provisions of this article.\n  6. The commissioner is hereby authorized, for the purposes of\neffectuating the provisions of this article in the development of a\nstatewide emergency medical service system, to contract with any\nambulance service or with the fire commissioners of fire districts\noperating certified voluntary ambulance services for the use of\nnecessary equipment upon such terms and conditions as the commissioner\nshall deem appropriate.\n  7. The commissioner may recommend to the state council minimum\nqualifications for certified first responders (which shall not exceed\nfifty-one hours), emergency medical technicians and advanced emergency\nmedical technicians in all phases of emergency medical technology\nincluding but not limited to, communications, first aid, equipment,\nmaintenance, emergency techniques and procedures, patient management and\nknowledge of procedures and equipment for emergency medical care.\n  8. The commissioner shall provide every certified ambulance service\nand advanced life support first response service with an official\ninsignia which may be attached to every vehicle owned or operated by a\ncertified ambulance service or advanced life support first response\nservice.\n  9. The department shall provide the state council with such assistance\nas the council may request in order to carry out its responsibilities as\nset forth in subdivision two-a of section three thousand two of this\narticle.\n  10. The commissioner is hereby authorized and empowered to extend the\ncertification for emergency medical technicians, advanced emergency\nmedical technicians or certified first responders who have been ordered\nto active military duty, other than for training, on or after the\neleventh day of September, two thousand one and whose certification will\nexpire during their military duty or within the six months immediately\nfollowing separation from military service. The extended certification\nshall be for the period of military duty and for twelve months after\nthey have been released from active military duty.\n  11. The commissioner, with the advice and consent of the state\ncouncil, shall promulgate rules and regulations necessary to ensure\ncompliance with the provisions of subdivision two of section sixty-seven\nhundred thirteen of the education law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>