<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3052"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3052"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3052"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3052/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3052/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3052/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3052/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3052">
        <num>3052</num>
        <heading>Establishment of a training program for emergency medical services personnel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3052. Establishment of a training program for emergency medical\nservices personnel.  1. There is hereby established a training program\nfor emergency medical services personnel including, but not limited to,\nfirst responders, emergency medical technicians, advanced emergency\nmedical technicians and emergency vehicle operators.\n  2. The commissioner shall provide state aid within the amount\nappropriated to entities such as local governments, regional emergency\nmedical services councils, and voluntary agencies and organizations to\nconduct training courses for emergency medical services personnel and to\nconduct practical examinations for certification of such personnel. The\ncommissioner shall establish a schedule for determining the amount of\nstate aid provided pursuant to this section.\n  a. Such schedule may include varying rates for distinct geographic\nareas of the state and for various course sizes, giving special\nconsideration to areas with the most need for additional emergency\nmedical technicians. In determining the need for additional emergency\nmedical technicians, the commissioner shall use measurements such as the\naverage number of emergency medical technicians per ambulance service,\nthe ratio of emergency medical technicians per square mile, the average\nnumber of calls per service and the percentage of calls to which an\nemergency medical technician has responded, provided such data is\navailable to the commissioner.\n  b. Such schedule shall provide sufficient reimbursement to permit\nsponsors to offer basic emergency medical technician courses which\nadhere to curricula approved by the New York state emergency medical\nservices council and the commissioner without the need to charge tuition\nto participants.\n  3. Upon request, the commissioner shall provide management advice and\ntechnical assistance to regional emergency medical services councils,\ncounty emergency medical services coordinators, and course sponsors and\ninstructors to stimulate the improvement of training courses and the\nprovision of courses in a manner which encourages participation. Such\nadvice and technical assistance may relate to, but need not be limited\nto the location, scheduling and structure of courses.\n  4. The department is authorized, either directly or through\ncontractual arrangement, to develop and distribute training materials\nfor use by course instructors and sponsors, to recruit additional\ninstructors and sponsors and to provide training courses for\ninstructors.\n  5. The commissioner shall conduct a public service campaign to recruit\nadditional volunteers to join ambulance services targeted to areas in\nneed for additional emergency medical technicians.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>