<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3065"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3065"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3065"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3065/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3065/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3065/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3065/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3065">
        <num>3065</num>
        <heading>Regional trauma advisory committees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3065. Regional trauma advisory committees. 1. There are hereby\ncontinued or established in the department regional trauma advisory\ncommittees in each geographic area of the state. They shall consist of\ntrauma surgeons, trauma nurses, emergency physicians, emergency nurses,\nand other emergency and trauma care professionals from trauma centers,\nemergency departments, and emergency services designated by the\ndepartment within each region. They shall be representative of the\ncommunities and health care facilities within the region and those\nmedical and nursing specialties and subspecialities regularly involved\nin trauma care. They shall advise the state trauma advisory committee,\nthe department, and the commissioner regarding trauma and disaster care\nwithin each region, and assist the state trauma advisory committee, the\ndepartment, and the commissioner with the coordination of trauma and\ndisaster care within each region, including, but not limited to, the\nimplementation of statewide quality improvement guidelines for trauma\nand disaster care, trauma systems, trauma centers, and trauma stations\nwithin each region, in a manner consistent with the intent and\nprovisions of sections twenty-eight hundred five-j and three thousand\nfour-a of this chapter. The state trauma advisory committee shall\nauthorize the bylaws of each regional trauma advisory committee, subject\nto approval by the commissioner.\n  2. The regional trauma advisory committees shall continue to meet as\nfrequently as their business may require. The members of the regional\ntrauma advisory committees shall receive no compensation for their\nservices as members.\n  3. The department shall determine the ways and means necessary to\nassist the regional trauma advisory committees in performing the duties\nspecified under this section, and may contract with regional trauma\nprogram agencies to provide such assistance.\n  4. In no event shall any member, officer, or employee of the state\ntrauma advisory committee be liable for damages in any civil action for\nany act done, failure to act, or statement of opinion made, while\ndischarging his or her duties as a member, officer, or employee of the\nregional trauma advisory committee if he or she shall have acted in good\nfaith, with reasonable care.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>