<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3121"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3121"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3121"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3121">
        <num>3121</num>
        <heading>Council on human blood and transfusion services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3121. Council on human blood and transfusion services.  1. There is\nhereby created in the department a council on human blood and\ntransfusion services, hereinafter known as the "council," to consist of\nthe commissioner and eight other members appointed by the governor, with\nthe advice and consent of the senate, one of whom shall be a\nrepresentative of the public. The remaining appointive members shall\nhave had experience or training having rendered them knowledgeable in\nthe various aspects of blood banking services, and may include but shall\nnot be limited to, representatives of voluntary and commercial blood\nbanks, representatives of hospitals, and physicians. The governor shall\ndesignate one member to serve as chairman.\n  2. The term of office of each appointive member of the council shall\nbe for three years, provided, however, that of the members first\nappointed, three shall be appointed for terms which shall expire on\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-four, three for terms\nwhich shall expire on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-five and two shall be appointed for terms which shall expire on\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-six.  Vacancies shall be\nfilled by appointment for the unexpired term. The appointive members\nshall continue in office until the expiration of their terms and until\ntheir successors are appointed and have qualified.\n  3. The council shall meet as frequently as its business may require.\nThe members of the council shall receive no compensation for their\nservices as members of the council, but each of them shall be allowed\nthe necessary and actual expenses which he shall incur in the\nperformance of his duties under this section.\n  4. The commissioner, upon request of the council, shall designate an\nofficer or employee of the department to act as secretary of the\ncouncil, and shall assign from time to time such other employees as the\ncouncil may require.\n  5. The council shall have power by the affirmative vote of a majority\nof its members to enact, and from time to time, amend and repeal, rules\nand regulations establishing minimum standards for the proper\ncollection, processing, fractionation, storage, distribution, and supply\nof human blood or blood derivatives, for the purpose of transfusions,\nsubject to approval by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>