<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-326"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-326"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="326"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-326/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-326/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-326/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-326/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_326">
        <num>326</num>
        <heading>Local health officer; temporary or acting; appointment; compensation; powers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_326__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A health officer with the consent of the\nboard of health in a town or village, and with the consent of the board\nor official having power to appoint a health officer in a city, may\nappoint a person who meets the qualifications contained in the sanitary\ncode to act as health officer during his temporary absence or incapacity\non account of illness or other cause for a period not exceeding three\nmonths.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_326__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that the health officer fails to, or is physically\nincapable of appointing a qualified person to act as health officer\nduring his temporary absence or incapacity, then the board of health in\na town or village or the board or official having power to appoint a\nhealth officer in a city, shall appoint a qualified person to act as\nhealth officer during the temporary absence or incapacity of the regular\nhealth officer, for a period not exceeding three months.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_326__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any local board of health fails to appoint an acting health\nofficer pursuant to this section then the commissioner may appoint a\nqualified person to serve as such health officer during the absence or\nincapacity of the health officer, for a period not exceeding three\nmonths.\n  2. The health officer, or the board of health or other official, who\nappoints a qualified person to act as health officer pursuant to this\nsection, shall report immediately in writing to the department the name\nand address of the person so appointed.\n  3. An acting health officer, during the period for which he is\nappointed, shall have all the rights, powers and duties imposed upon the\nhealth officer by this chapter and the sanitary code.\n  4. The board of health in a town or village and the board or officer\nhaving authority to fix the salary of a health officer in a city may\nallow such compensation as it deems reasonable covering such temporary\nservice. The appointment of an acting health officer in a case where the\nregular health officer shall have been appointed jointly by two or more\nlocal boards of health for two or more towns or villages shall be with\nthe consent of the appointing local boards, and the compensation of such\nacting health officer shall be allowed and paid in the same manner as\nthe fixed compensation of the regular health officer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>