<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-329"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-329"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="329"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-329/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-329/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-329/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-329/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_329">
        <num>329</num>
        <heading>Local health officer; immunity from personal liability</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 329. Local health officer; immunity from personal liability.  1. No\nhealth officer, inspector, investigator, public health nurse, or other\nrepresentative of a health officer, and no person or persons other than\nthe county, city, village or town by which such health officer or\nrepresentative thereof is employed shall be sued or held to liability\nfor any act done or omitted by any such health officer or representative\nof a health officer in good faith and with ordinary discretion on behalf\nor under the direction of such county, city, village or town pursuant to\nits regulations or ordinances, or the sanitary code, or this chapter.\n  2. Any person whose property may have been unjustly or illegally\ndestroyed or injured pursuant to any order, regulation or ordinance, or\naction of any board of health or health officer, or representative of a\nhealth officer, for which no personal liability may exist as aforesaid,\nmay maintain a proper action against the county, city, village or town\nfor the recovery of proper compensation or damages. Every such suit must\nbe brought within six months after the cause of action arose and the\nrecovery shall be limited to the damages suffered.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>