<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-33"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-33"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="33"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-33/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-33/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-33/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-33/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33">
        <num>33</num>
        <heading>Cooperation of agency officials and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 33. Cooperation of agency officials and employees. 1. In addition to\nthe authority otherwise provided by this title, the inspector, in\ncarrying out the provisions of this title, is authorized to request such\ninformation, assistance and cooperation from any federal, state or local\ngovernmental department, board, bureau, commission, or other agency or\nunit thereof as may be necessary for carrying out the duties and\nresponsibilities enjoined upon the inspector by this section. State and\nlocal agencies or units thereof are hereby authorized and directed to\nprovide to the inspector, or, at the request of the inspector, to state\nagencies or their contractors, such information, assistance and\ncooperation. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary,\nrequests for information, assistance and cooperation may include, but\nnot be limited to, all state and local government birth, death and vital\nstatistics which may be contained in files, databases or registries, and\nfor all information shall, upon request, include, where possible, making\nelectronic copies or record exchanges available. Executive agencies\nshall coordinate and facilitate the transfer of appropriate functions\nand positions to the office as necessary and in accordance with\napplicable law.\n  2. Upon request of a local social services district or a prosecutor of\ncompetent jurisdiction, the office, department, any other state or local\ngovernment entity and the Medicaid fraud control unit shall provide such\ninformation and assistance as such entity or unit shall deem necessary,\nappropriate and available to aid and facilitate the investigation of\nfraud and abuse within the medical assistance program and the recoupment\nof improperly expended funds.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>