<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3309"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3309"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3309"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3309/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3309/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3309/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3309/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3309">
        <num>3309</num>
        <heading>Opioid overdose prevention</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this section:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Opioid antagonist" means a drug approved by the Food and Drug\nAdministration that, when administered, negates or neutralizes in whole\nor in part the pharmacological effects of an opioid in the body. "Opioid\nantagonist" shall be limited to naloxone and other medications approved\nby the department for such purpose.\n  (ii) "Health care professional" means a person licensed, registered or\nauthorized pursuant to title eight of the education law to prescribe\nprescription drugs.\n  (iii) "Pharmacist" means a person licensed or authorized to practice\npharmacy pursuant to article one hundred thirty-seven of the education\nlaw.\n  (iv) "Opioid antagonist recipient" or "recipient" means a person at\nrisk of experiencing an opioid-related overdose, or a family member,\nfriend or other person in a position to assist a person experiencing or\nat risk of experiencing an opioid-related overdose, or an organization\nregistered as an opioid overdose prevention program pursuant to this\nsection or any person or entity or any person employed by the person or\nentity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this section, "entity" includes, but is not limited to,\na school district, public library, board of cooperative educational\nservices, county vocational education and extension board, charter\nschool, non-public elementary or secondary school, restaurant, bar,\nretail store, shopping mall, barber shop, beauty parlor, theater,\nsporting or event center, inn, hotel or motel.\n  (vi) "Nightlife establishment" means an establishment that is open to\nthe public for entertainment or leisure, serves alcohol or where alcohol\nis consumed on the premises, and conducts a large volume of business at\nnight. Such term includes, but is not limited to, bars, entertainment\nvenues, clubs and restaurants.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A health care professional may prescribe by a patient-specific\nor non-patient-specific prescription, dispense or distribute, directly\nor indirectly, an opioid antagonist to an opioid antagonist recipient.\n  (ii) A pharmacist may dispense an opioid antagonist, through a\npatient-specific or non-patient-specific prescription pursuant to this\nparagraph, to an opioid antagonist recipient.\n  (iii) An opioid antagonist recipient may possess an opioid antagonist\nobtained pursuant to this paragraph, may distribute such opioid\nantagonist to a recipient, and may administer such opioid antagonist to\na person the recipient reasonably believes is experiencing an opioid\noverdose.\n  (iv) The provisions of this paragraph shall not be deemed to require a\nprescription for any opioid antagonist that does not otherwise require a\nprescription; nor shall it be deemed to limit the authority of a health\ncare professional to prescribe, dispense or distribute, or of a\npharmacist to dispense, an opioid antagonist under any other provision\nof law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any pharmacy with twenty or more locations in the state, shall\neither:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3309__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>pursue or maintain a non-patient-specific prescription with\nan authorized health care professional to dispense an opioid antagonist\nto a consumer upon request, as authorized by this section; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3309__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nregister with the department as an opioid overdose prevention program.\n  3-a. Any distribution of opioid antagonists through this program shall\ninclude an informational card or sheet, and fentanyl test strips. The\ninformational card or sheet shall include, at a minimum, information on:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>how to recognize symptoms of an opioid overdose;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>steps to take prior to and after an opioid antagonist is\nadministered, including calling first responders;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number for the toll free office of addiction services and\nsupports' HOPE line;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>how to access the office of addiction services and supports'\nwebsite;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the application of good samaritan protections provided in section\nthree thousand-a of this chapter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other information deemed relevant by the commissioner; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>information about fentanyl test strips and their uses.\n  The educational card shall be provided in languages other than English\nas deemed appropriate by the commissioner. The department shall make\nsuch informational cards available to the opioid overdose prevention\nprograms.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Use of an opioid antagonist pursuant to this section shall be\nconsidered first aid or emergency treatment for the purpose of any\nstatute relating to liability.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A recipient, opioid overdose prevention program, person or entity,\nor any person employed by the person or entity, acting reasonably and in\ngood faith in compliance with this section, shall not be subject to\ncriminal, civil or administrative liability solely by reason of such\naction.\n  5. The commissioner shall publish findings on statewide opioid\noverdose data that reviews overdose death rates and other information to\nascertain changes in the cause and rates of opioid overdoses, including\nfatal opioid overdoses. The report shall be submitted annually, on or\nbefore October first, to the governor, the temporary president of the\nsenate, the speaker of the assembly and the chairs of the senate and\nassembly health committees, and shall be made public on the department's\ninternet website. The report shall include, at a minimum, the following\ninformation on a county basis:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>information on opioid overdoses and opioid overdose deaths,\nincluding age, gender, ethnicity, and geographic location;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>data on emergency room utilization for the treatment of opioid\noverdose;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>data on utilization of pre-hospital services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>data on the dispensing and utilization of opioid antagonists; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other information necessary to ascertain the success of the\nprogram, areas of the state which are experiencing particularly high\nrates of overdoses, ways to determine if services, resources and\nresponses in particular areas of the state are having a positive impact\non reducing overdoses, and ways to further reduce overdoses.\n  * 6. The commissioner shall provide the current information and data\nspecified by each type of drug included in the report required by\nsubdivision five of this section to each county every three months. The\noffice of addiction services and supports website shall include a\nhyperlink to such information and data which may be utilized by a county\nor any combination thereof as it works to address the opioid epidemic.\n  * NB Repealed March 31, 2027\n  7. With the first prescription to a particular patient of an opioid of\neach year for use in a setting other than a general hospital or nursing\nhome under article twenty-eight of this chapter or facility under\narticle thirty-one of the mental hygiene law, or when a practitioner is\nprescribing a controlled substance to a patient under the care of\nhospice as defined by section four thousand two of this chapter, the\nprescriber shall prescribe an opioid antagonist when any of the\nfollowing risk factors are present:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a history of substance use\ndisorder;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>high dose or cumulative prescriptions that result in\nninety morphine milligram equivalents or higher per day;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3309__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>concurrent\nuse of opioids and benzodiazepine or nonbenzodiazepine sedative\nhypnotics.\n  8. The commissioner shall establish guidelines for onsite opioid\noverdose response capacity in nightlife establishments.\n  9. The commissioner shall, in full accordance with the standards,\npowers and authorizations established by this section, coordinate with\nthe commissioner of general services to effectuate the duty established\nby subdivision two-a of section one hundred forty of the public\nbuildings law to equip public institutions and buildings with opioid\nantagonists.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>