<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3311"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3311">
        <num>3311</num>
        <heading>Authority to issue initial licenses, amended licenses, and to renew licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3311. Authority to issue initial licenses, amended licenses, and to\nrenew licenses.  1. Subject to the provisions of this article the\ncommissioner is authorized to issue licenses authorizing the manufacture\nor distribution of controlled substances.\n  2. An application for a license, amendment of a license, or renewal of\na license which, if granted, would authorize the manufacture or\ndistribution of a controlled substance which the applicant is not then\nauthorized to manufacture or distribute shall, with respect to any such\nadditional authorization, be treated as an application for an initial\nlicense.\n  3. An application for a license which, if granted, would authorize a\nlicensee to continue to manufacture or distribute a controlled substance\nshall, with respect to such continued manufacture or distribution only,\nbe treated as an application for renewal of a license.\n  4. A late-filed application for the renewal of a license may, in the\ndiscretion of the commissioner, be treated as an application for an\ninitial license.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>