<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3322"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3322"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3322"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3322">
        <num>3322</num>
        <heading>Reports and records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3322. Reports and records. 1. Persons licensed under this title or\noperating a registered outsourcing facility shall maintain records of\nall controlled substances manufactured, compounded, received, disposed\nof, delivered or distributed by them. The record shall show the date of\nreceipt or delivery, the name and address, and registration number of\nthe person from whom received or to whom delivered or distributed, the\nkind and quantity of substance received and delivered or distributed,\nthe kind and quantity of substance produced or removed from the process\nof manufacture and the date thereof.\n  2. Any person licensed under this title or operating a registered\noutsourcing facility shall prepare and maintain a biennial report\nsetting forth the current inventory of controlled substances, the\nquantities of controlled substances manufactured, compounded, delivered\nor distributed within the state during the period covered by the report\nand such other information as the commissioner shall by regulation\nprescribe. Maintaining for inspection a biennial inventory of controlled\nsubstances prepared and maintained in compliance with federal statutes\nand regulations shall be deemed in compliance with this section.\n  3. Any person licensed under this title or operating a registered\noutsourcing facility shall forthwith notify the department of any\nincident involving the theft, loss or possible diversion of controlled\nsubstances manufactured, compounded, delivered or distributed by the\nlicensee or operator.\n  4. The records and reports required by this section shall be prepared,\npreserved, or filed in such manner and detail as the commissioner shall\nby regulation prescribe.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>