<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3370"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3370"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3370"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3370/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3370/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3370/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3370/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3370">
        <num>3370</num>
        <heading>Preserving and inspection of records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3370. Preserving and inspection of records. 1. Any record, including\nprescriptions, required to be kept or maintained by this article shall\nbe preserved for a period of at least five years following the date of\nthe event or transaction recorded, unless a shorter period of time is\nspecifically provided.\n  2. Such records shall be made available during business hours for\ninspection and copying by any officer or employee of the department who\nis charged with the enforcement of this article and to any officer or\nemployee of this state charged with the duty of regulating or licensing\nof any person who by virtue of such license is authorized to obtain,\ndistribute, dispense or administer controlled substances.\n  3. Every record, including prescriptions, required to be kept under\nthis article shall be maintained at the premises where the licensed\nactivity is conducted.\n  4. The department shall cause to be expunged or otherwise destroyed,\nwithin five years from the date of receipt thereof, any record of the\nname of any patient received by it pursuant to the filing requirements\nof subdivision six of section thirty-three hundred thirty-one,\nsubdivision four of section thirty-three hundred thirty-three, and\nsubdivision four of section thirty-three hundred thirty-four of this\narticle.\n  5. Electronic prescription records shall be maintained and preserved\nin accordance with regulations of the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>