<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3383"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3383"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3383"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3383/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3383/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3383/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3383/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3383">
        <num>3383</num>
        <heading>Imitation controlled substances</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3383__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>its price, nature, use or effect as a controlled substance; or\n  (ii) its packaging in a manner normally used for illicit controlled\nsubstances; or\n  (iii) markings on the substance.\n  2. It shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture, sell or possess\nwith the intent to sell, an imitation controlled substance.\n  3. It shall be unlawful for any person to possess or use any punch,\ndie, plate, stone or any other equipment in order to print, imprint, or\nreproduce the trademark, trade name or other identifying mark, imprint\nor device of another or any likeness of any of the foregoing upon any\nsubstance or container or labeling thereof with intent to manufacture an\nimitation controlled substance.\n  4. No liability shall be imposed by virtue of this section on any\nperson licensed pursuant to article one hundred thirty-one of the\neducation law or licensed under this article who manufactures,\ndistributed, sells, prescribes, dispenses or possesses an imitation\ncontrolled substance for use as a placebo or for use in clinical\nresearch conducted pursuant to the federal food, drug and cosmetic act.\n  5. Nothing in this section shall apply to a noncontrolled substance\nthat was initially introduced into commerce prior to the initial\nintroduction into commerce of the controlled substance which it is\nalleged to imitate.\n  6. In any prosecution under this section it shall be necessary to\nprove that the imitation controlled substance was represented to be a\ncontrolled substance; however, it shall not be a defense to a\nprosecution under this section that the accused believed the imitation\ncontrolled substance to be a controlled substance.\n  7. A violation of subdivision two or three of this section shall be a\nclass A misdemeanor. A violation of subdivision two or three of this\nsection by a person previously convicted of a violation of this section\nwithin the preceding five years shall be a class E felony.\n  8. If any provision or part of this section o...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>