<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3397"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3397">
        <num>3397</num>
        <heading>Fraud and deceit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3397__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>obtain or attempt to obtain a controlled substance, a prescription\nfor a controlled substance or an official New York State prescription\nform,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3397__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by fraud, deceit, misrepresentation or subterfuge; or\n  (ii) by the concealment of a material fact; or\n  (iii) by the use of a false name or the giving of a false address;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3397__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>wilfully make a false statement in any prescription, order,\napplication, report or record required by this article;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3397__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>falsely assume the title of, or represent himself to be a licensed\nmanufacturer, distributor, pharmacy, pharmacist, practitioner,\nresearcher, approved institutional dispenser, owner or employee of a\nregistered outsourcing facility or other authorized person, for the\npurpose of obtaining a controlled substance;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3397__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make or utter any false or forged prescription or false or forged\nwritten order;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3397__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>affix any false or forged label to a package or receptacle\ncontaining controlled substances; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3397__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>imprint on or affix to any controlled substance a false or forged\ncode number or symbol.\n  2. Possession of a false or forged prescription for a controlled\nsubstance by any person other than a pharmacist in the lawful pursuance\nof his profession shall be presumptive evidence of his intent to use the\nsame for the purpose of illegally obtaining a controlled substance.\n  3. Possession of a blank official New York state prescription form by\nany person to whom it was not lawfully issued shall be presumptive\nevidence of such person's intent to use same for the purpose of\nillegally obtaining a controlled substance.\n  4. Any person who, in the course of treatment, is supplied with a\ncontrolled substance or a prescription therefor by one practitioner and\nwho, without disclosing the fact, is supplied during such treatment with\na controlled substance or a prescription therefor by another\npractitioner shall be guilty of a violation of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>