<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3397-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3397_C">
        <num>3397-C</num>
        <heading>Antonio G</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3397-c. Antonio G. Olivieri controlled substances therapeutic\nresearch program established; participation. 1. The Antonio G. Olivieri\ncontrolled substances therapeutic research program is hereby established\nin the department of health. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and\nregulations necessary for the proper administration of the controlled\nsubstances therapeutic research act. In such promulgation, the\ncommissioner shall take into consideration those pertinent rules and\nregulations promulgated by the drug enforcement administration, food and\ndrug administration and the national institute on drug abuse.\n  2. Participation in the Antonio G. Olivieri controlled substances\ntherapeutic research program shall be limited to cancer patients,\nglaucoma patients and patients afflicted with other diseases as such\ndiseases are approved by the commissioner. Such patient shall be\ncertified by a physician to and approved by a patient qualification\nreview board or committee in the manner provided by this article.\nPhysician certification and board or committee approval shall be limited\nto such patients who are involved in a life-threatening or\nsense-threatening situation. Patients seeking participation in such\nprogram may seek the advice and shall be entitled to be advised by\nappropriate medical personnel concerning the medical efficacy of\ntreatment with conventional controlled substances.\n  3. The commissioner, on behalf of the department, shall apply to the\nfood and drug administration for an investigational new drug permit\nwithin ninety days after the effective date of this section.\n  * NB Repealed May 20, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>