<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3397-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3397_E">
        <num>3397-E</num>
        <heading>Patient participation in program; procedure</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3397-e. Patient participation in program; procedure. 1. Any\nhospital may establish a hospital patient qualification review committee\nsubject to the rules and regulations promulgated by the commissioner. A\nhospital may designate a hospital human research review committee as set\nforth in section twenty-four hundred forty-four of this chapter to serve\nas a hospital patient qualification review committee.\n  2. Any physician may recommend a patient for participation in the\nAntonio G. Olivieri controlled substances therapeutic research program\nto the hospital patient qualification review committee for the hospital\nwherein such patient has received medical treatment.\n  3. The hospital patient qualification review committee shall review\neach recommendation and shall submit approved patient applications to\nthe state patient qualification review board.\n  4. The state patient qualification review board shall review all\nphysician applicants for the Antonio G. Olivieri controlled substances\ntherapeutic research program and certify or refuse to certify their\nparticipation in the program.\n  5. The state patient qualification review board may delegate to a\nhospital patient qualification review committee the authority to approve\nor disapprove a patient's participation in such program.\n  6. A patient shall not be eligible to participate in such program\nwithout the approval of the state patient qualification review board or\nthe hospital patient qualification review committee delegated pursuant\nto subdivision five of this section.\n  7. The hospital human research review committee shall review each\nhuman research project proposed hereunder and shall certify to the\nhospital patient qualification review committee that such project meets\nthe requirements of this article and article twenty-four-A of this\nchapter.\n  * NB Repealed May 20, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>