<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3397-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3397-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3397_F">
        <num>3397-F</num>
        <heading>Antonio G</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3397-f. Antonio G. Olivieri controlled substances therapeutic\nresearch program; distribution. 1. The commissioner shall obtain\nmarijuana through whatever means he deems most appropriate, consistent\nwith regulations promulgated by the national institute on drug abuse,\nthe food and drug administration and the drug enforcement administration\nand pursuant to the provisions of this article.\n  2. If, within a reasonable time, the commissioner is unable to obtain\ncontrolled substances pursuant to subdivision one of this section, he\nshall conduct an inventory of available sources of such drugs, including\nbut not limited to the New York state police bureau of criminal\ninvestigation and local law enforcement officials. Said inventory shall\nbe for the purpose of determining the feasibility of obtaining\ncontrolled substances for use in the program. Upon conducting said\ninventory, the commissioner shall contract with the available source for\nthe receipt of controlled substances.\n  3. The commissioner shall cause such marijuana to be transferred to a\nhospital for distribution to the certified patient pursuant to this\narticle.\n  * NB Repealed May 20, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>