<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3398-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3398_G">
        <num>3398-G</num>
        <heading>Selection criteria</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3398-g. Selection criteria. 1. The applicant, if an individual or\nindividuals, shall furnish evidence of the individual's good moral\ncharacter, and if an entity, the applicant shall furnish evidence of the\ngood moral character of the individuals who have or will have\nsubstantial responsibility for the licensed or authorized activity and\nthose in control of the entity, including principals, officers, or\nothers with such control.\n  2. The applicant shall furnish evidence of the applicant's experience\nand competency, and that the applicant has or will have adequate\nfacilities, equipment, process controls, and security to undertake those\nactivities for which licensure is sought.\n  3. The applicant shall furnish evidence of his, her or its ability to\ncomply with all applicable state and local laws, rules and regulations.\n  4. If the commissioner is not satisfied that the applicant should be\nissued a license, the commissioner shall notify the applicant in writing\nof the specific reason or reasons for denial.\n  5. No license pursuant to this article may be issued to an individual\nunder the age of eighteen years.\n  * NB Repealed 6 months after the full cannabis control board created\nby Article 2 of the cannabis law has been appointed\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>