<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3398-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3398_B">
        <num>3398-B</num>
        <heading>Cannabinoid hemp processor license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3398-b. Cannabinoid hemp processor license. 1. Persons processing\ncannabinoid hemp or hemp extract used for human consumption, whether in\nintermediate or final form, shall be required to obtain a cannabinoid\nhemp processor license from the department.\n  2. A cannabinoid hemp processor license authorizes one or more\nspecific activities related to the processing of cannabinoid hemp into\nproducts used for human consumption, whether in intermediate or final\nform, and the distribution or sale thereof by the licensee. Nothing\nherein shall prevent a cannabinoid hemp processor from processing,\nextracting and processing hemp products not to be used for human\nconsumption.\n  3. Persons authorized to grow hemp pursuant to article twenty-nine of\nthe agriculture and markets law are not authorized to engage in\nprocessing of cannabinoid hemp or hemp extract without first being\nlicensed as a cannabinoid hemp processor under this article.\n  4. This article shall not apply to hemp, cannabinoid hemp, hemp\nextracts or products derived therefrom that are not used for human\nconsumption.  This article also shall not apply to hemp, cannabinoid\nhemp, hemp extracts or products derived therefrom that have been deemed\ngenerally recognized as safe pursuant to federal law.\n  5. The commissioner shall have the authority to set reasonable fees\nfor such license, to limit the activities permitted by such license, to\nestablish the period during which such license is authorized, which\nshall be two years or more, and to make rules and regulations necessary\nto implement this section.\n  6. Any person holding an active research partnership agreement with\nthe department of agriculture and markets, authorizing that person to\nprocess cannabinoid hemp, shall be awarded licensure under this section,\nprovided that the research partner is actively performing research\npursuant to such agreement and is able to demonstrate compliance with\nthis article, as determined by the department, after notice and an\nopportunity to be heard.\n  * NB Repealed 6 months after the full cannabis control board created\nby Article 2 of the cannabis law has been appointed\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>