<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3398-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3398_A">
        <num>3398-A</num>
        <heading>Rulemaking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3398-a. Rulemaking authority. The commissioner may make\nregulations pursuant to this article for the processing, distribution,\nmarketing, transportation and sale of cannabinoid hemp and hemp extracts\nused for human consumption, which may include, but not be limited to:\n  1. Specifying forms, establishing application, reasonable\nadministration and renewal fees, or license duration;\n  2. Establishing the qualifications and criteria for licensing, as\nauthorized by law;\n  3. The books and records to be created and maintained by licensees and\nlawful procedures for their inspection;\n  4. Any reporting requirements;\n  5. Methods and standards of processing, labeling, packaging and\nmarketing of cannabinoid hemp, hemp extract and products derived\ntherefrom;\n  6. Procedures for how cannabinoid hemp, hemp extract or ingredients,\nadditives, or products derived therefrom can be deemed as acceptable for\nsale in the state;\n  7. Provisions governing the modes and forms of administration,\nincluding inhalation;\n  8. Procedures for determining whether cannabinoid hemp, hemp extract\nor ingredients, additives, or products derived therefrom produced\noutside the state or within the state meet the standards and\nrequirements of this article and can therefore be sold within the state;\n  9. Procedures for the granting, cancellation, revocation or suspension\nof licenses, consistent with the state administrative procedures act;\n  10. Restrictions governing the advertising and marketing of\ncannabinoid hemp, hemp extract and products derived therefrom; and\n  11. Any other regulations necessary to implement this article.\n  * NB Repealed 6 months after the full cannabis control board created\nby Article 2 of the cannabis law has been appointed\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>