<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3398-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3398-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3398_M">
        <num>3398-M</num>
        <heading>Packaging and labeling of cannabinoid hemp and hemp extract</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3398-m. Packaging and labeling of cannabinoid hemp and hemp\nextract.  1. Cannabinoid hemp processors shall be required to provide\nappropriate label warning to consumers, and restricted from making\nunapproved label claims, as determined by the department, concerning the\npotential impact on or benefit to human health resulting from the use of\ncannabinoid hemp, hemp extract and products derived therefrom for human\nconsumption, which labels shall be affixed to those products when sold,\npursuant to rules and regulations that the department may adopt.\n  2. The department may, by rules and regulations, require processors to\nestablish a code, including, but not limited to QR code, for labels and\nestablish methods and procedures for determining, among other things,\nserving sizes or dosages for cannabinoid hemp, hemp extract and products\nderived therefrom, active cannabinoid concentration per serving size,\nnumber of servings per container, and the growing region, state or\ncountry of origin if not from the United States. Such rules and\nregulations may require an appropriate fact panel that incorporates data\nregarding serving sizes and potency thereof.\n  3. The packaging, sale, or possession of products derived from\ncannabinoid hemp or hemp extract used for human consumption not labeled\nor offered in conformity with regulations under this section shall be\ngrounds for the seizure or quarantine of the product, the imposition of\na civil penalty against a processor or retailer, and the suspension,\nrevocation or cancellation of a license, in accordance with this\narticle.\n  * NB Repealed 6 months after the full cannabis control board created\nby Article 2 of the cannabis law has been appointed\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>