<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3421"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3421"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3421"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3421/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3421/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3421/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3421/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3421">
        <num>3421</num>
        <heading>Funeral directing; requirements for license to practice</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3421__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is a citizen of the United States or a noncitizen lawfully\nadmitted for permanent residence in the United States;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3421__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has satisfactorily completed a course of collegiate level study in\nfuneral service, the curriculum of which has been approved by the\ndepartment, consisting of not less than ninety quarter credits or sixty\nsemester credits in an institution or institutions approved by the\ndepartment or an accrediting agency recognized by the department;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3421__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has upon entering an approved institution as herein provided for\nthe purpose of beginning his funeral service study, registered as a\nstudent with the department upon a form to be provided by the\ndepartment, and has paid to the department a registration fee of fifty\ndollars.\n  3. Delay in registering as a student as herein required may be\nexcused, in the discretion of the commissioner.\n  4. The department shall issue a license to practice funeral directing\nto an applicant for such license on the basis of the following\nprocedures:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3421__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>who shall have successfully passed the examination as herein\nprovided in subdivision one of this section, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3421__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>who pays a fee of one hundred twenty-five dollars, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3421__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>who, after having passed such examination, serves a one year\nperiod as a registered resident in a manner satisfactory to the\ndepartment, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3421__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>who, has passed a second examination after or during the serving\nof a one year period as a registered resident. The said examination\nshall be on the New York state laws, rules and regulations relating to\nfuneral directing and shall be prepared or approved by the department of\nhealth.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>