<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3501"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3501"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3501"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3501">
        <num>3501</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3501. Definitions. When used in this article, the following words\nand phrases shall have the following definitions:\n  1. "Radiologic technology" means the practice of radiography,\nradiation therapy and nuclear medicine technology.\n  2. "Radiologic technologist" means a person who is licensed under this\narticle to practice radiography or radiation therapy or nuclear\nmedicine.\n  3. "Radiography" means the use of x-rays or x-ray producing equipment\non human beings for diagnostic purposes under the supervision of a\nlicensed practitioner. The practice includes, but is not limited to:\nmeasuring and positioning patients; selecting and setting up exposure\nfactors on x-ray equipment, and the making of the x-ray exposure; the\nperformance of quality control tests; under the direct supervision of a\nlicensed physician, the intravascular administration of contrast media\nwhen such administration is an integral part of the x-ray or imaging\nprocedure; and, under the direct supervision of a licensed physician,\ncertified nurse practitioner, or licensed physician assistant, the\nintravenous administration of contrast media when such administration is\nan integral part of the x-ray or imaging procedure.\n  4. "Radiographer" means a person, other than a licensed practitioner,\nwho is licensed under this article to practice radiography.\n  5. "Radiation therapy" means the use of external beam and remote\nafterloading brachytherapy equipment for the application of ionizing\nradiation to human beings for therapeutic purposes under the supervision\nof a radiation oncologist. The practice includes but is not limited to:\nsetting up treatment position; selecting required filter and treatment\ndistance; positioning the beam directional shells and molds; using x-ray\nequipment for tumor localization; delivering the radiation treatment as\nprescribed by the physician; certifying the record of the technical\ndetails of the treatments; assisting the professional medical physicist\nin calibration procedures; assisting in treatment planning procedures;\nand the performance of quality control tests.\n  6. "Radiation therapist" means a person, other than a licensed\nphysician, who is licensed under this article to practice radiation\ntherapy.\n  7. "Nuclear medicine technology" means the use of radiopharmaceuticals\nadministered to human beings for diagnostic or therapeutic purposes\nunder the supervision of a physician authorized by a radioactive\nmaterials license. The practice includes but is not limited to: elution\nof a radiopharmaceutical generator; dosage preparation; assay of\nradiopharmaceutical dosages administered to patients; use of nuclear\nmedicine equipment on patients; performance of quality control tests;\nadministration of radiopharmaceuticals to patients for diagnostic\npurposes; and administration of radioactive materials to patients for\ntherapeutic purposes under the personal supervision of a physician\nauthorized by a radiopharmaceuticals license for such use.\n  8. "Nuclear medicine technologist" means a person who is licensed\nunder this article to practice nuclear medicine technology.\n  9. "Radiologist" means a physician duly licensed to practice medicine\nin the state of New York and who is certified by the American Board of\nRadiology or by the American Osteopathic Board of Radiology in\ndiagnostic radiology or radiation oncology.\n  10. "Radiation oncologist" means a physician duly licensed to practice\nmedicine in the state of New York and who is certified by the American\nBoard of Radiology or by the American Osteopathic Board of Radiology in\nradiation oncology.\n  11. "Licensed practitioner" means a person licensed or otherwise\nauthorized under the education law to practice medicine, dentistry,\npodiatry, or chiropractic.\n  12. "Professional medical physicist" means a person licensed or\notherwise authorized to practice medical physics in accordance with\narticle one hundred sixty-six of the education law.\n  14. "License" means a license granted and issued by the department\nunder this article to practice radiography, radiation therapy technology\nor nuclear medicine technology.\n  15. "X-ray or imaging procedure" means and includes conventional\ndiagnostic x-ray or radiology, computer tomography, angiography,\nmagnetic resonance imaging and ultrasound.\n  16. "Intravenous contrast administration certificate" means a\ncertificate granted and issued by the department under this article to\nadminister and inject contrast media.\n  17. "Supervision" means the oversight of a licensed radiologic\ntechnologist by a licensed practitioner acting within the limits\nspecified in the law under which the practitioner is licensed.\n  18. "Direct supervision" means a physician must be present in the\nsection of the facility where the procedure is being performed and is\nnot concurrently encumbered by responsibilities that would preclude the\nphysician from responding to a request for assistance within a timeframe\nthat poses no risk to the patient. The physician shall be immediately\navailable to furnish assistance and direction throughout the performance\nof the procedure, and is professionally responsible for the performance\nof the procedure. It does not mean that the physician must be present in\nthe room when the procedure is performed.\n  19. "Personal supervision" means the physician must be in attendance\nin the room during the performance of the procedure.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>