<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-357"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-357"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="357"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-357/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-357/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-357/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-357/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_357">
        <num>357</num>
        <heading>Certain counties; health services advisory boards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 357. Certain counties; health services advisory boards. 1. In a\ncounty wherein the legislative body constitutes the board of health of\nsuch county under and pursuant to the provisions of section three\nhundred fifty-six of this title, the county shall provide for the\nappointment by the board of health of a health services advisory board\nconsisting of nine members. One member shall be a physician licensed to\npractice in the state of New York and one member shall be a physician,\nnurse practitioner, or physician assistant licensed to practice in the\nstate of New York. The remaining members of the board shall be known as\npublic members and shall be selected on the basis of their interest and\nknowledge regarding the health needs, resources and facilities of the\ncommunity.\n  2. The health services advisory board shall advise the county health\ndirector with respect to the discharge of his powers, responsibilities\nand duties.\n  3. A person may hold other public office or employment while serving\nas a member of a health services advisory board.\n  4. The members of a health services advisory board shall have fixed\nterms of four years except that three of the initial appointments shall\nbe for two years and three shall be for three years. A term shall be\ndeemed to run from the first day of the year in which the appointment is\nmade. Vacancies shall be filled for unexpired terms in the same manner\nas original appointments. No person may serve as a member for more than\ntwo terms consecutively.\n  5. Board members shall be reimbursed for expenses actually and\nnecessarily incurred in the performance of their duties.\n  6. Two or more such counties may agree to form a conjoined health\nservices advisory board. Each county shall be entitled to appoint\nmembers in accordance with the provisions of subdivision one or may\nappoint such proportion of the total membership so computed as is\nmutually agreed upon by the participating counties.\n  7. Board members shall be residents of the county or a resident of a\ncontiguous county who has a background in a health-related field and\nperforms other substantial work within the county associated with their\nhealth-related background.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>