<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3608"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3608"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3608"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3608">
        <num>3608</num>
        <heading>Certification of home care services agencies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3608__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions three through\nfive of this section, the commissioner shall suspend, limit or revoke a\ncertified home health agency certificate of approval after taking into\nconsideration the public need for the agency and the availability of\nother services which may serve as alternatives or substitutes, and after\nfinding that suspending, limiting, or revoking the certificate of\napproval of such agency would be within the public interest in order to\nconserve health resources by restricting the level of services to those\nwhich are actually needed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3608__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever any finding as described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3608__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision is under consideration with respect to any particular\ncertified home health agency, the commissioner shall cause to be\npublished, in a newspaper of general circulation in the geographic area\nof the agency, at least thirty days prior to making such a finding an\nannouncement that such a finding is under consideration and an address\nto which interested persons can write to make their views known.  The\ncommissioner shall take all public comments into consideration in making\nsuch a finding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3608__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall, upon making any finding described in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3608__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision with respect to any certified home\nhealth agency, cause such agency and the appropriate health systems\nagency to be notified of the finding at least thirty days in advance of\ntaking the proposed action to revoke, suspend or limit such agency's\ncertificate of approval. Upon receipt of any such notification and\nbefore the expiration of the thirty days or such longer period as may be\nspecified in the notice, the certified home health agency or the\nappropriate health sytems agency may request a public hearing to be held\nin the county in which the agency is located. In no event shall the\nrevocation, suspension or limitation take effect prior to the thirtieth\nday after the date of the notice, or prior to the effective date\nspecified in the notice or prior to the date of the hearing decision,\nwhichever is later.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3608__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided by law, all appeals from a finding of\nthe commissioner made pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3608__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision\nshall be directly to the appellate division of the supreme court in the\nthird department. Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, such\nappeals shall have preference over all issues in all courts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>