<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3616"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3616"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3616"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3616/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3616/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3616/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3616/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3616">
        <num>3616</num>
        <heading>Provision of certified home health agency services, long term home health care programs and AIDS home care programs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3616__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are diagnosed by a\nphysician as having acquired immune deficiency syndrome, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3616__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are\ndeemed by a physician, within his judgment, to be infected with the\netiologic agent of acquired immune deficiency syndrome, and whose\nillness, infirmity or disability can be reasonably ascertained to be\nassociated with such infection. Provision of certified home health\nagency services, a long term home health care program or an AIDS home\ncare program paid for by government funds shall be based upon, but not\nlimited to, a comprehensive assessment that shall include, but not be\nlimited to, an evaluation of the medical, social and environmental needs\nof each applicant for such services or program. This assessment shall\nalso serve as the basis for the development and provision of an\nappropriate plan of care for the applicant. In cases in which the\napplicant is a patient in a hospital or residential health care\nfacility, the assessment shall be completed by persons designated by the\ncommissioner, including, but not limited to, the applicant's physician,\nthe discharge coordinator of the hospital or residential health care\nfacility referring the applicant, a representative of the local\ndepartment of social services, and a representative of the provider of a\nlong term home health care program, AIDS home care program, or the\ncertified home health agency that will provide services for the patient.\nIn cases in which the applicant is not a patient in a hospital or\nresidential health care facility, the assessment shall be completed by\npersons designated by the commissioner including, but not limited to,\nthe applicant's physician, a representative of the local department of\nsocial services and a representative of the provider of a long term home\nhealth care program, AIDS home care program or the certified home health\nagency that will provide services for the patient. The assessment shall\nbe completed prior to or within thirty days after the provision of\nservices begins. Payment for services provided prior to the completion\nof the assessment shall ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>