<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3655"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3655"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3655"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3655/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3655/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3655/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3655/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3655">
        <num>3655</num>
        <heading>Medical equipment service agency advisory board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3655. Medical equipment service agency advisory board. 1. There is\nhereby created in the department a medical equipment service advisory\nboard to consist of the commissioner or his or her designee as an\nex-officio member, and eight other members appointed by the\ncommissioner. The members shall include four representatives of the home\nmedical equipment service industry and/or home medical equipment service\nproviders, a rehabilitation technology specialist, a respiratory\ntherapist, a physician, and a representative of the public. The\ncommissioner shall designate one member to serve as chair.\n  2. The term of office of each member shall be for three years,\nprovided however, that of the members first appointed, three shall be\nappointed for terms which expire December thirty-first, two thousand\nthree, two shall be appointed for terms which expire December\nthirty-first, two thousand four, and three shall be appointed for terms\nwhich expire December thirty-first, two thousand five. Vacancies shall\nbe filled by appointment for the unexpired term. The members shall\ncontinue in office until the expiration of their terms and until their\nsuccessors are appointed. A member may be dismissed by the commissioner\nfor cause, or for repeated absence.\n  3. The board shall meet as frequently as its business shall require,\nin no case less than on a semi-annual basis. The members of the board\nshall receive no compensation for their services as members of the\nboard, but shall be reimbursed for necessary and actual expenses\nincurred in the performance of his or her duties.\n  4. The commissioner, upon request of the board, may designate an\nemployee of the department to assist the board in carrying out its\nresponsibilities.\n  5. The board, upon an affirmative vote of a majority of its members,\nmay make recommendations to the commissioner regarding the adoption,\namendment and/or repeal of any rules, regulations, standards and\npolicies regarding the provision of home medical equipment services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>