<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3907"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3907"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3907"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-3907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3907">
        <num>3907</num>
        <heading>Agricultural health and safety advisory board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3907. Agricultural health and safety advisory board. 1. There is\nhereby created an advisory board to be known as the "agricultural health\nand safety advisory board", to be comprised of twelve members consisting\nof the following named persons or their designees: the commissioner of\nhealth; the commissioner of agriculture and markets; the dean of the\nschool of public health sciences at the state university of New York at\nAlbany; the dean of the college of agriculture and life sciences at\nCornell university; and eight additional members, one of whom shall be\nappointed by the governor and shall be a representative of a county\ncooperative extension, one of whom shall be appointed by the governor\nand shall be a representative of rural New York, six of whom shall be\nrepresentatives of general farm organizations, or individual farmers\nwith annual gross sales of ten thousand dollars or more, or individuals\ninvolved in providing health and safety services in counties with fewer\nthan two hundred thousand persons, or members of farm workers\norganizations, to be appointed as follows: two by the temporary\npresident of the senate, two by the speaker of the assembly, one by the\nminority leader of the senate, and one by the minority leader of the\nassembly. Members of the board shall elect a chairperson on an annual\nbasis.\n  2. Members of the board shall receive no salary, but shall be\nreimbursed by the director for expenses actually and necessarily\nincurred by them in the performance of their duties as described\nhereunder.\n  3. Vacancies on the board shall be filled in the same manner as the\noriginal appointments.\n  4. The director shall cause the center to provide staff assistance\nnecessary for the efficient and effective operation of the board.\n  5. The board shall render advice regarding:\n  a. statewide needs to be addressed by the center;\n  b. the coordination of program activities with state agencies,\nnot-for-profit corporations and other interested parties;\n  c. dissemination of research results and educational information; and\n  d. identification of funding sources for center program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>