<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-393"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-393"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="393"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-393/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-393/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-393/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-393/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_393">
        <num>393</num>
        <heading>Consolidated health district; board of health; terms of office</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 393. Consolidated health district; board of health; terms of office.\n1. Of the new reduced three member board of health of a consolidated\nhealth district first elected, one member shall be elected to serve\nuntil one year from the first day of January following his election, one\nto serve two years, and one to serve three years from such first day of\nJanuary, and until his successor has been elected and has qualified.\n  2. Prior to December first each year the village mayors and\nsupervisors of the municipalities included in the consolidated health\ndistrict shall meet and elect one member of the board of health who\nshall serve three years from the January first following and until his\nsuccessor has been elected and has qualified.\n  3. An elective member shall serve for a term of two years from the\nfirst day of January preceding his election and until his successor\nshall have been appointed, provided that if at any time the number of\nmembers of the board of health, excluding the elective member, shall\nbecome an odd number, the term of office of the elective member shall\nthereupon cease.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>