<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4101"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4101">
        <num>4101</num>
        <heading>Vital statistics; enforcement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4101. Vital statistics; enforcement. 1. The commissioner is hereby\ncharged with the execution of the provisions of this article and is\nhereby granted supervisory power over registrars, deputy registrars, and\nsubregistrars, to the extent that there shall be uniform compliance with\nall of the requirements of this article.\n  2. Each registrar is hereby charged with the enforcement of the\nprovisions of this article in his registration district, under the\nsupervision and direction of the commissioner. He shall make an\nimmediate report to the commissioner of any violation of any provision\nof this article coming to his knowledge, by observation, or upon\ncomplaint of any person, or otherwise.\n  3. The commissioner, either personally or by an accredited\nrepresentative, shall have authority to investigate cases of\nirregularity, or violation of law, and all registrars shall aid him,\nupon request, in such investigations.\n  4. When he shall deem it necessary, the commissioner shall report\ncases of violation of any of the provisions of this article to the\ndistrict attorney of the county, with a statement of the facts and\ncircumstances. When any such case is reported to him by the\ncommissioner, the district attorney shall forthwith initiate and\npromptly proceed with the necessary court proceedings against the\nperson, firm or corporation responsible for the alleged violation of\nlaw.\n  5. Upon request of the commissioner, the attorney general shall assist\nin the enforcement of the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>