<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4130"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4130">
        <num>4130</num>
        <heading>Births; registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4130. Births; registration. 1. Live birth is defined as the complete\nexpulsion or extraction from its mother of a product of conception,\nirrespective of the duration of pregnancy, which, after such separation,\nbreathes or shows any other evidence of life such as beating of the\nheart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, or definite movement of\nvoluntary muscles, whether or not the umbilical cord has been cut or the\nplacenta is attached; each product of such a birth is considered live\nborn.\n  2. The birth of each child born alive in this state shall be\nregistered within five days after the date of birth by filing with the\nregistrar of the district in which the birth occurred a certificate of\nsuch birth, which certificate shall be upon the form prescribed therefor\nby the commissioner.\n  3. In each case where a physician or nurse-midwife was in attendance\nupon the birth, it shall be the duty of such physician or nurse-midwife\nto file said certificate.\n  4. In each case where there was no physician or nurse-midwife in\nattendance upon the birth, it shall be the duty of the father or mother\nof the child, the householder or owner of the premises where the birth\noccurred, or the director or person in charge of the public or private\ninstitution where the birth occurred, each in the order named, within\nfive days after the date of such birth, to report to the local registrar\nthe fact of such birth and to file said certificate.\n  5. When a birth occurs in a hospital, the person in charge of such\nhospital or his designated representative shall obtain the personal\ndata, prepare the certificate, secure the signatures required by the\ncertificate and file it with the registrar. The physician in attendance\nor a physician acting in his behalf shall certify to the facts of birth\nand provide the medical information required by the certificate within\nfive days after the birth.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>