<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4136"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4136"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4136"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4136/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4136/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4136/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4136/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4136">
        <num>4136</num>
        <heading>Birth certificate; statement as to blood test</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4136. Birth certificate; statement as to blood test. 1. In reporting\nevery birth and fetal death, physicians and others permitted to attend\npregnancy cases and required to report births and fetal deaths shall\nstate on the birth certificate or fetal death certificate, as the case\nmay be, whether a blood test for syphilis has been made during such\npregnancy upon a specimen of blood taken from the woman who bore the\nchild for which a birth or fetal death certificate is filed.\n  2. In addition to the information provided to be contained in each\ncertificate of birth by this article every certificate of birth shall\nstate whether such test was made during pregnancy or at delivery, and in\nthe case where no blood test has been made such fact shall be reported\ntogether with the reason why such test has not been taken in compliance\nwith the provisions of section two thousand three hundred eight of this\nchapter.\n  3. If such test has been made during pregnancy, those required to\nreport births and fetal deaths shall state the date on which the test\nwas made.\n  4. In no event shall the birth certificate state the result of the\nblood test.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>