<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4138-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4138_D">
        <num>4138-D</num>
        <heading>Mutual consent voluntary adoption registry</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the agency determines that the agency was not involved in such\nadoption, it shall notify the registrant that no record exists of the\nadoption and refer the registrant to the department's adoption\ninformation registry operated pursuant to section forty-one hundred\nthirty-eight-c of this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the agency determines that the agency was involved in such\nadoption, it shall transmit the registration to the adoption information\nregistry operated by the department and the agency shall release the\nnon-identifying information, as defined in section forty-one hundred\nthirty-eight-c of this title, to the adopted person.\n  4. Upon acceptance of a registration pursuant to this section, the\ndepartment shall search the records of the department to determine\nwhether the adoptee's adoption occurred within the state. The department\nshall establish an authorized agency fee schedule for search costs and\nregistry costs of an authorized agency.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the department determines that there is a corresponding\nregistration for the adoptee, for either of the birth parents and/or for\na biological sibling of the adoptee, it shall notify the court wherein\nthe adoption occurred and the department shall notify the agency that a\ncorresponding match has been made. The agency shall notify all such\nregistrants that a corresponding match has been made and request such\npersons' final consent to the release of identifying information.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the department determines that there is no corresponding\nregistration for the adoptee, for either of the birth parents and/or for\na biological sibling of the adoptee, it shall notify the agency which\nshall notify the registering person that no corresponding match has been\nmade. The agency shall not solicit or request the consent of the\nnon-registered person or persons.\n  5. Upon receipt of a final consent by the adoptee, by either of the\nbirth parents and/or by a biological sibling of the adoptee, the agency\nshall release identifying information about the consenting registrants\nto the consenting registrants. Such identifying information shall be\nlimited to the names and addresses of the consenting registrants and\nshall not include any other information contained in the adoption or\nbirth records. However, nothing in this section shall be construed to\nprevent the release of adoption records as otherwise permitted by law.\n  6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any employee of the agency who solicits or causes another to\nsolicit a registration for the purposes of this section, except as\notherwise permitted by law, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, provided,\nhowever, that solicitation shall not include disclosure of the existence\nof the adoption information registry.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who unlawfully discloses any information in the mutual\nconsent voluntary adoption registry shall be guilty of a class A\nmisdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision, any employee of the\ndepartment who unlawfully discloses any information in the mutual\nconsent voluntary adoption registry shall be subject to dismissal for\nsuch violation.\n  7. Upon receipt of identifying information from the department\npursuant to section four thousand one hundred thirty-eight-c of this\narticle, the agency shall promptly release identifying information to\nall the registrants. Such identifying information shall be limited to\nthe names and addresses of the registrants and shall not include any\nother information contained in the adoption or birth records or other\nrecords maintained by the agency. However, nothing in this section shall\nbe construed to prevent the release of adoption records as otherwise\npermitted by law.\n  8. For purposes of this section: "authorized agency" or "agency" means\nan authorized agency as defined in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\nten of section three hundred seventy-one of the social services law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>