<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4138-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4138-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4138_E">
        <num>4138-E</num>
        <heading>Adoptee's right to a certified copy of his or her birth certificate</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the commissioner or\na local registrar or any person authorized by the commissioner or a\nlocal registrar, upon application, proof of identity and payment of a\nnominal fee, shall issue certified copies of original long form line by\nline, vault copy birth certificates, including any change attached to\nthat certificate by a birth parent or parents, and any information\nprovided to the commissioner or a local registrar pursuant to\nsubdivision one of section one hundred fourteen of the domestic\nrelations law, to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an adopted person, if eighteen years of age or\nmore, or (ii) if the adopted person is deceased, the adopted person's\ndirect line descendants, or (iii) the lawful representatives of such\nadopted person, or lawful representatives of such deceased adopted\nperson's direct line descendants, as the case may be.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When it shall be impossible for the commissioner or a local\nregistrar to provide a copy of an adult adopted person's original long\nform birth certificate (as may occur in the case of an adopted person\nborn outside of, but adopted within, the state and such certificate is\nnot part of the records of the commissioner or a local registrar), the\ntrue and correct information about the adopted person and the adopted\nperson's birth parents, including their identifying information, that\nwould have appeared on such original birth certificate shall be provided\nto:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the adopted person, if eighteen years of age or more, or (ii) if\nthe adopted person is deceased, the adopted person's direct line\ndescendants, or (iii) the lawful representatives of such adopted person,\nor lawful representatives of such deceased adopted person's direct line\ndescendants, as the case may be by any authorized agency as defined in\nparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision ten of section three hundred\nseventy-one of the social services law. In such case, the agency shall\nbe held harmless from any liability arising out of the disclosure.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4138_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this subdivision, the term "commissioner" shall\ninclude the state commissioner of health, the commissioner of health and\nmental hygiene of the city of New York and for records of birth prior to\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred fourteen, the local registrars of the\ncities of Albany, Buffalo and Yonkers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>