<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4148"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4148"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4148"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4148/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4148/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4148/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4148/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4148">
        <num>4148</num>
        <heading>Electronic death registration system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4148. Electronic death registration system. 1. The department is\nhereby authorized and directed to design, implement and maintain an\nelectronic death registration system for collecting, storing, recording,\ntransmitting, amending, correcting and authenticating information, as\nnecessary and appropriate to complete a death registration, and to\ngenerate such documents as determined by the department in relation to a\ndeath occurring in this state. As part of the design and implementation\nof the system established by this section, the department shall consult\nwith all persons authorized to use such system to the extent practicable\nand feasible. Except as specifically provided in this section, the\nexisting general duties of, and remuneration received by, local\nregistrars in accepting and filing certificates of death and issuing\nburial and removal permits pursuant to any statute or regulation shall\nbe maintained, and not altered or abridged in any way by this section.\n  2. Commencing on the implementation date, the department shall require\nthat deaths occurring within this state must be registered using the\nelectronic death registration system established in this section.\nElectronic death registration may be phased in, as determined by the\ncommissioner, for deaths occurring in the state until the electronic\ndeath registration system is fully implemented in the state. As used in\nthis section, "implementation date" means the first day in January in\nthe second year after this section becomes a law, or as soon thereafter\nas the commissioner reasonably determines by regulation is feasible in\nlight of the intent of this section.\n  3. Commencing on the implementation date, all persons required to\nregister a death or file a certificate of death under this article, and\nsuch others as may be authorized by the commissioner, shall have access\nto the electronic death registration system for the purpose of entering\ninformation required to execute, complete and file a certificate of\ndeath or to retrieve such information or generate documentation from the\nelectronic death registration system. The confidentiality provisions in\nsection forty-one hundred forty-seven of this title shall apply to\ninformation maintained in this system.\n  4. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, commencing on\nor after January first, two thousand fifteen, or on such date determined\nby the commissioner pursuant to subdivision two of this section, any\nrequirement of this title for a signature of any person shall be deemed\nsatisfied by the use by such person of digital signature provided such\nperson is authorized in accordance with this section to use the\nelectronic death registration system.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>