<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4160"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4160"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4160"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4160">
        <num>4160</num>
        <heading>Pregnancy loss; reporting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4160. Pregnancy loss; reporting. 1. Pregnancy loss is defined as the\nloss of a pregnancy at any gestation, as confirmed by a health care\nprovider licensed pursuant to title eight of the education law and\nacting within such health care provider's scope of practice, including\nspontaneous miscarriage, still birth, or any termination of pregnancy\nwhich is consistent with the requirements of article twenty-five-A of\nthis chapter.\n  * 2. A pregnancy loss caused by spontaneous miscarriage or still birth\nshall be registered within seventy-two hours of the pregnancy loss by\nelectronically filing directly with the department of health, a report\nof such loss.\n  * NB Effective until March 30, 2027\n  * 2. A fetal death shall be registered within seventy-two hours after\nexpulsion of such fetus, by filing directly with the commissioner a\ncertificate of such death. In addition, a report of fetal death shall be\nreported to the registrar in the district in which the fetal death\noccurred.\n  * NB Effective March 30, 2027\n  * 3. A pregnancy loss due to an induced termination of pregnancy shall\nbe registered within seventy-two hours of such pregnancy loss if the\nindividual experiencing the pregnancy loss requests such registration to\nfacilitate disposition of the products of conception in accordance with\nsection forty-one hundred sixty-two of this title, by filing directly\nwith the department of health, a report of such loss. Such report shall\nbe limited to the information strictly necessary to facilitate\ndisposition.\n  * NB Effective until March 30, 2027\n  * 3. A pregnancy loss due to an induced termination of pregnancy shall\nbe registered within seventy-two hours of such pregnancy loss if the\nindividual experiencing the pregnancy loss requests such registration to\nfacilitate disposition of the products of conception in accordance with\nsection forty-one hundred sixty-two of this title, by electronically\nfiling directly with the department of health, a report of such loss.\nSuch report shall be limited to the information strictly necessary to\nfacilitate disposition.\n  * NB Effective March 30, 2027\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the disclosure\nof information filed pursuant to this section shall be limited to the\nindividual who experienced the pregnancy loss, such individual's lawful\nrepresentative and to authorized personnel of the department. Nothing in\nthis section shall prohibit disclosure of deidentified information in\ncompliance with federal reporting requirements.\n  6. A local registrar shall not charge a fee for the issuance of a\ncertificate of pregnancy loss under this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>