<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-420"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-420"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="420"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-420/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-420/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-420/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-420/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_420">
        <num>420</num>
        <heading>Boards of visitors; appointment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the\nprovisions of this chapter, each hospital in the department shall\ncontinue to have a board of seven visitors, to be appointed by the\ngovernor by and with the advice and consent of the senate; provided\nhowever that in the case of the state institute for the study of\nmalignant diseases one of the seven members of the board of visitors\nshall be the commissioner, ex-officio.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At least two members of the board of visitors of the Helen Hayes\nhospital shall be duly licensed physicians and at least two members\nshall be women. This provision shall not affect the offices of the\npresent members; but appointments hereafter shall be so made as to\ncomply herewith as soon as practicable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At least two of the members of the board of visitors of the state\ninstitute for the study of malignant diseases shall be residents of the\ncity of Buffalo or vicinity and one member of the board of visitors\nshall be a member of the medical faculty or of the council of the\nUniversity of Buffalo.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The terms of office of the members of the boards of visitors,\nother than the members of the board of visitors of the state institute\nfor the study of malignant diseases, shall be seven years, and they\nshall be so appointed that the term of at least one of the members of\nthe board of visitors shall expire on the thirty-first day of December\nof each year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The terms of office of the members of the board of visitors of the\nstate institute for the study of malignant diseases shall be five years\nand they shall be so appointed that the term of at least one of the\nmembers shall expire on the thirty-first of December of each year.\n  3. All vacancies on the several boards of visitors of hospitals in the\ndepartment shall be filled by the governor in the same manner as\noriginal appointments, and the person appointed to fill a vacancy in the\nboard of visitors of a hospital in the department shall hold office for\nthe remainder of the term of the person whom he succeeds.\n  4. The governor may remove any member or members of a board of\nvisitors for cause after an opportunity to be heard.\n  5. This section shall not affect the terms of the present members of\nsuch board.\n  6. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this section or any\nother provision of law to the contrary, upon the transfer to the Roswell\nPark Cancer Institute corporation of the operations of the Roswell Park\nCancer Institute, the board of visitors of Roswell Park Cancer Institute\nshall cease to operate and the terms of the current members of the board\nof visitors shall terminate. In the event that the operations of the\nRoswell Park Cancer Institute revert to the department of health, the\nboard of visitors shall be reconstituted and the governor shall make new\nappointments pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>