<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-425"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-425"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="425"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-425/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-425/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-425/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-425/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_425">
        <num>425</num>
        <heading>Boards of visitors; reports to commissioner and governor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 425. Boards of visitors; reports to commissioner and governor.  1.\nThe board of visitors of each hospital in the department shall make a\nwritten report to the commissioner and to the governor within ten days\nafter each inspection, such report to be signed by each member making\nthe inspection. Such report shall state in detail the condition of the\nhospital and of its patients, and such other matters pertaining to the\nmanagement and affairs thereof as in the opinion of the board of\nvisitors should be brought to the attention of the commissioner or the\ngovernor, and may contain recommendations as to needed improvement in\nthe hospital or in its management.\n  2. Each board of visitors shall make to the commissioner in January of\neach year a detailed report of the results of its visits and\ninspections, with suitable suggestions and such other matters as may be\nrequired of it by the commissioner for the year ending on the\nthirty-first day of December preceding the day of such report. Such\nreport shall be prepared by a committee of the board of visitors,\nsubject to the approval of the board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>