<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4301"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4301">
        <num>4301</num>
        <heading>Persons who may execute an anatomical gift</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any\nindividual of sound mind and eighteen years of age or more may make an\nanatomical gift to take effect upon their death for any purpose\nspecified in section forty-three hundred two of this article, limit an\nanatomical gift to one or more of those purposes, or refuse to make an\nanatomical gift. In any case where the donor has a properly executed\ndocument of gift authorization for donation shall not be rescinded or\namended by any other person except upon a showing that the donor revoked\nthe authorization pursuant to section forty-three hundred five of this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who is sixteen or seventeen years of age and of sound\nmind may make an anatomical gift to take effect upon their death for any\npurpose specified in section forty-three hundred two of this article,\nlimit an anatomical gift to one or more of those purposes, or refuse to\nmake an anatomical gift. In any case where the donor has a properly\nexecuted document of gift, notice of such gift shall be provided to the\ndonor's parents or guardians, and authorization for donation may be\nrescinded or amended by an objection by a parent or guardian of the\ndonor at the time of death and prior to the recovery of any organ or\ntissue if the donor is less than eighteen years of age. An anatomical\ngift made by an individual more than sixteen years of age but less than\neighteen shall otherwise not be rescinded, except upon a showing that\nthe donor revoked the authorization pursuant to section forty-three\nhundred five of this article. Upon the donor reaching the age of\neighteen, the donor's consent to donate his or her organs or tissue\nshall be regarded as consent for authorization to make an anatomical\ngift pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the absence of an express, contrary indication by the donor, an\nanatomical gift of a part is neither a refusal to give other parts nor a\nlimitation on an individual's ability to make an anatomical gift under\nsubdivision two of this section.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the absence of a gift made by the donor under subdivision\none of this section, and in the absence of actual notice of contrary\nindications by the decedent, including religious or moral objections, an\nanatomical gift of the decedent's body may be made by any member of the\nfollowing classes of persons who is reasonably available, in the order\nof priority listed, for any purpose specified in section forty-three\nhundred two of this article:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the person designated as the decedent's health care agent under\narticle twenty-nine-C of this chapter, subject to any written statement\nin the health care proxy form,\n  (ii) the person designated as the decedent's agent in a written\ninstrument under article forty-two of this chapter, subject to any\nwritten statement in the written instrument,\n  (iii) the spouse, if not legally separated from the patient, or the\ndomestic partner,\n  (iv) a son or daughter eighteen years of age or older,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>either parent,\n  (vi) a brother or sister eighteen years of age or older,\n  (vii) an adult grandchild of the decedent,\n  (viii) a grandparent of the decedent,\n  * (ix) a guardian of the person of the decedent at the time of his or\nher death, or\n  * NB Effective until January 1, 2026\n  * (ix) a guardian of the person of the decedent at the time of his or\nher death,\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other person authorized or under the obligation to dispose\nof the body.\n  * NB Effective until January 1, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a close friend as defined in subdivision four of section\ntwenty-nine hundred ninety-four-a of this chapter, or\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2026\n  * (xi) any other person authorized or under the obligation to dispose\nof the body.\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If there is more than one member of a class listed in\nsubparagraph (iv), (vi), (vii), or (viii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision entitled to make an anatomical gift, an anatomical gift may\nbe made by a member of the class unless that member or person knows of\nan objection by another member of the class. If an objection is known,\nthe gift may be made only by a majority of the members of the class who\nare reasonably available.\n  * NB Effective until January 1, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If there is more than one member of a class listed in\nsubparagraph (iv), (vi), (vii), (viii), or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision entitled to make an anatomical gift, an anatomical gift may\nbe made by a member of the class unless that member or person knows of\nan objection by another member of the class. If an objection is known,\nthe gift may be made only by a majority of the members of the class who\nare reasonably available.\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2026\n  3. An anatomical gift may not be made by a person listed in\nsubdivision two of this section if:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person in a prior class is reasonably available;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the person proposing to make an anatomical gift knows of a refusal\nor contrary indications by the decedent, including that an anatomical\ngift is contrary to the decedent's religious or moral beliefs.\n  4. Any gift by a person designated in subdivision two of this section\nshall be by a document signed by him or her or made by his or her\ntelegraphic, recorded telephonic, or other recorded message. Where a\ngift is made under this subdivision, either:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the authorizing party\nshall indicate in the document or message that he or she has no actual\nnotice of contrary indications by the decedent and no reason to believe\nthat an anatomical gift is contrary to the decedent's religious or moral\nbeliefs; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an agent of the organ procurement organization or of the\ndonee shall make reasonable efforts to inquire of the authorizing party\nor otherwise determine that the authorizing party has no actual notice\nof contrary indications by the decedent and no reason to believe that an\nanatomical gift is contrary to the decedent's religious or moral\nbeliefs.\n  5. The donee shall not accept the gift under the following\ncircumstances:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the donee has actual notice of contrary indication by the\ndecedent;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>where an anatomical gift is not properly made pursuant to this\nsection; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4301__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the donee has reason to believe that an anatomical gift is\ncontrary to the decedent's religious or moral beliefs.\n  6. A gift of all or part of a body authorizes any examination\nnecessary to assure medical acceptability of gift for the purposes\nintended.\n  7. The rights of the donee created by the gift are paramount to the\nrights of others except as provided by section forty-three hundred eight\nof this article.\n  8. The person who documents the making, amending or revoking of an\nanatomical gift, acting reasonably and in good faith in accordance with\nthis article, may accept an anatomical gift under this article made by a\nperson who represents that he or she is entitled to consent to the\ndonation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>