<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4306"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4306">
        <num>4306</num>
        <heading>Rights and duties at death</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4306__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4306__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person who acts in good faith in accord with the terms of\nthis article or with the anatomical gift laws of another state, is not\nliable for damages in any civil action or subject to prosecution in any\ncriminal proceeding for his or her act.\n  (ii) A person who acts in good faith in accord with the anatomical\ngift laws of another country is not liable for damages in any civil\naction or subject to prosecution in any criminal proceeding for his or\nher act provided that:\n  (A) such country has anatomical gift laws similar in requirements and\neffects to the anatomical gift laws of this state;\n  (B) such country appears on a list of such countries promulgated as a\nregulation by the department for such purpose; and\n  (C) such country appeared on such list at the time of such act.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4306__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person who documents the making, amending or revoking of an\nanatomical gift, acting reasonably and in good faith in accordance with\nthis article, may accept an anatomical gift under this article made by a\nperson who represents that the person is an authorized person under\nsection forty-three hundred one of this article and is entitled to\nconsent to the donation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4306__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An entity under section forty-three hundred two or forty-three\nhundred ten of this article or a health care professional, or an agent\nor employee thereof, who or which documents, records, recovers,\nprocures, obtains, or utilizes an organ or tissue in reasonable and good\nfaith reliance on information provided to or contained in the New York\nstate donate life registry shall not be liable in any civil or criminal\naction or proceeding for action based on such reliance.\n  4. Any employee or agent of an organ procurement organization, eye\nbank or tissue bank acting pursuant to this article shall be held to the\nsame standard of confidentiality as that imposed on employees of a\nhospital.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>