<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4406-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4406-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4406_E">
        <num>4406-E</num>
        <heading>Access to end of life care</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4406_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of\nsection forty-nine hundred fourteen of this chapter, provided further,\nthat until such decision is rendered, the admission of or provision or\ncontinuation of the care by the facility shall not be denied by the\nhealth care plan and the health care plan shall provide coverage and\nreimburse the facility for services provided subject to the provisions\nof this section and other limitations otherwise applicable under the\nenrollee's contract.  The decision of the external appeal agent shall be\nbinding on all parties. If the health care plan does not initiate an\nexpedited external appeal, the health care plan shall reimburse the\nfacility for services provided subject to the provisions of this section\nand other limitations otherwise applicable under the enrollee's\ncontract.\n  4. A health care plan shall provide reimbursement for those services\nprescribed by this section at rates negotiated between the health care\nplan and the facility. In the absence of agreed upon rates, a health\ncare plan shall pay for acute care at the facility's acute care rate\nunder the Medicare program (Title XVIII of the federal Social Security\nAct), including the Part A rate for Part A services and the Part B rate\nfor Part B services, and shall pay for alternate level care days at\nseventy-five percent of the acute care rate, including the Part A rate\nfor Part A services and the Part B rate for Part B services.\n  5. Payment by a health care plan pursuant to this section shall be\npayment in full for the services provided to the enrollee. An acute care\nfacility reimbursed pursuant to this section shall not charge or seek\nany reimbursement from, or have any recourse against an enrollee for the\nservices provided by the acute care facility pursuant to this section,\nexcept for the collection of copayments, coinsurance or visit fees, or\ndeductibles for which the enrollee is responsible under the terms of the\napplicable contract.\n  6. No provision of this se...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>