<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4410"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4410"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4410"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4410">
        <num>4410</num>
        <heading>Health maintenance organizations; professional services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4410__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall have access to patient-specific medical\ninformation, including encounter data, maintained by a health\nmaintenance organization or other organization certified pursuant to\nthis article for the purposes of quality assurance and oversight,\nsubject to any other limitations of federal and state law regarding\ndisclosure thereof to third parties and subject to the provisions of\nthis subdivision. The provisions of sections thirty-one hundred one, and\nforty-five hundred four, forty-five hundred seven and forty-five hundred\neight of the civil practice law and rules, subdivision three of this\nsection and section 33.13 of the mental hygiene law, shall not bar\ndisclosure by the health maintenance organization to the commissioner\nfor such purposes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4410__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may only obtain enrollee information subject to\nthe establishment of protocols that will ensure that such\npatient-specific information is not disclosed to third parties other\nthan to entities serving as agents of the state for the purposes of\nquality assurance and oversight. Such protocols shall be developed in\nconsultation with representatives of health maintenance organizations,\nhealth care provider organizations and consumer organizations and shall,\nwhere possible, include the development of a unique confidential\nidentifier to be used in connection with patient-specific data. These\nprotocols shall address issues relating to the collection, maintenance,\nand disclosure of such patient-specific information. Such protocols\nshall be promulgated as regulations, provided however, that protocols or\nregulations in use prior to the effective date of this subdivision shall\nremain in effect until the regulations developed hereunder are\npromulgated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4410__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any other sanction or penalty as provided by law,\nany employee of the department who willfully violates this regulation or\nany other rule or procedure pertaining to the disclosure of any material\ncollected pursuant to this subdivision shall be deemed to have committed\nan act of misconduct and shall be disciplined in accordance with the\nprovisions of the civil service law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>