<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4603"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4603"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4603"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4603/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4603/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4603/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4603/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4603">
        <num>4603</num>
        <heading>Continuing care retirement community council; powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4603. Continuing care retirement community council; powers and\nduties.  1. The continuing care retirement community council is hereby\nestablished, to consist of the following, or their designees: the\nattorney general; the commissioner; the director of the office for the\naging; and eight public members appointed by the governor with the\nadvice and consent of the senate. Such public members shall be\nrepresentative of the public, and have a demonstrated expertise or\ninterest in continuing care retirement communities; provided that no\nmore than one such member shall be a sponsor, owner, operator, manager,\nmember of a board of directors, or shareholder of a continuing care\nretirement community. At least two public members shall be residents of\na continuing care retirement community. At least one of the public\nmembers shall be a representative of an organization with demonstrated\nexperience in representing the interests of senior citizens. The public\nmembers of the council shall have fixed terms of four years. The council\nshall be chaired by the commissioner or the designee of such\ncommissioner.\n  Members of such council shall serve without compensation for their\nservices as members of the council, except that each of them may be\nallowed the necessary and actual expenses which such member shall incur\nin the performance of their duties under this article.\n  2. The council shall meet as often as may be deemed necessary to\nfulfill its responsibilities. The council shall have the following\npowers and duties:\n  a. to assist the commissioner on policy matters related to the\nestablishment and operation of continuing care retirement communities;\n  b. to assist the commissioner in the development of the state's\noverall policy regarding continuing care retirement communities and\ncause studies and research to be conducted as it may deem advisable and\nnecessary; and\n  c. to make such recommendations to the governor and the legislature as\nmay be necessary to encourage or further regulate the development of\ncontinuing care retirement communities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>