<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4607"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4607"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4607"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4607">
        <num>4607</num>
        <heading>Annual statement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4607__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an accountant's opinion and, in accordance with generally accepted\naccounting principles:\n  (A) a balance sheet,\n  (B) a statement of income and expenses,\n  (C) a statement of equity or fund balances,\n  (D) a statement of changes in financial position,\n  (ii) notes to the financial statements considered customary or\nnecessary to ensure full disclosure of the financial statements,\nfinancial condition, and operation;\n  c. A detailed listing of the assets maintained for the reserves;\n  d. A copy of the most recent actuarial review of the community,\nincluding such information as may be required by the superintendent\nincluding an opinion of a qualified consulting actuary, as to the\ncurrent and projected soundness of the community, provided however that\na new actuarial review must be submitted triennially; and\n  e. Such other reasonable financial and other information as the\ncouncil may require with respect to the operator or the community, or\nits directors, controlling persons, trustees, members, branches,\nsubsidiaries or affiliates to determine the financial status of the\ncommunity and the management capabilities of the operator.\n  3. Sixty days before commencement of each calendar or fiscal year or\nofficial opening date, whichever is applicable, each operator shall file\nwith the commissioner and superintendent a computation of the annual\nlong-term debt service and a projected annual revenue and expense\nsummary for the next ten years.\n  * NB Effective until June 1, 2026\n  * ยง 4607. Annual statement. 1. Within four months of close of the\noperator's fiscal year, unless an extension of time to file has been\ngranted, the operator shall file an annual statement with the\ncommissioner showing the condition as of the last day of the preceding\ncalendar or fiscal year. If the commissioner does not receive the annual\nstatement within four months of the end of the operator's fiscal year or\nhave not granted an extension of time to file, the commission...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4607__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an accountant's opinion and, in accordance with generally accepted\naccounting principles:\n  (A) a balance sheet,\n  (B) a statement of income and expenses,\n  (C) a statement of equity or fund balances,\n  (D) a statement of changes in financial position,\n  (ii) notes to the financial statements considered customary or\nnecessary to ensure full disclosure of the financial statements,\nfinancial condition, and operation;\n  c. A detailed listing of the assets maintained for the reserves;\n  d. A copy of the most recent actuarial review of the community,\nincluding such information as may be required by the commissioner\nincluding an opinion of a qualified consulting actuary, as to the\ncurrent and projected soundness of the community, provided however that\na new actuarial review must be submitted triennially; and\n  e. Such other reasonable financial and other information as the\ncommissioner may require with respect to the operator or the community,\nor its directors, controlling persons, trustees, members, branches,\nsubsidiaries or affiliates to determine the financial status of the\ncommunity and the management capabilities of the operator.\n  3. Sixty days before commencement of each calendar or fiscal year or\nofficial opening date, whichever is applicable, each operator shall file\nwith the commissioner a computation of the annual long-term debt service\nand a projected annual revenue and expense summary for the next ten\nyears.\n  * NB Effective June 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>