<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-464"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-464"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="464"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-464/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-464/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-464/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-464/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_464">
        <num>464</num>
        <heading>Permits; display; renewal; duplicates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 464. Permits; display; renewal; duplicates. 1. All permits shall be\nfor a period of two years.\n  2. No permit shall be assignable or transferable.\n  3. Each permit issued pursuant to this article shall be posted and\nkept posted in some conspicuous place in the body piercing studio or\ntattoo studio in which the permittee is engaged in the practice of body\npiercing or tattooing.\n  4. Any permit which has not been suspended or revoked, may, upon the\npayment of the renewal fee prescribed by the commissioner, be renewed\nfor additional periods of two years from its expiration, upon the filing\non any application for such renewal, on a form to be prescribed by the\ncommissioner.\n  5. Any person, firm, corporation, partnership or other association\nfailing to file application and fee for renewal of a permit within one\nyear immediately following the expiration of his last permit shall pay\nan additional fee as prescribed by the commissioner.\n  6. A duplicate permit may be issued for one lost, destroyed or\nmutilated upon application therefor on a form prescribed by the\ncommissioner and the payment of the fee prescribed therefor by the\ncommissioner. Each such duplicate permit shall have the word "duplicate"\nstamped across the face thereof and shall bear the same number as the\none it replaces.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>