<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4659*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4659*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4659*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4659*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4659*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4659*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4659*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4659*2">
        <num>4659*2</num>
        <heading>Individualized service plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 4659. Individualized service plan. 1. A written individualized\nservice plan shall be developed for each resident of an assisted living\nresidence upon admission.\n  2. The individualized service plan shall be developed with the\nresident, the resident's representative and resident's legal\nrepresentative if any, the assisted living operator, and if necessary a\nhome care services agency. The initial individualized service plan shall\nbe developed in consultation with the resident's physician; provided\nsuch consultation is documented in writing by the residence. If a\nresident is determined by his or her physician not to be in need of home\ncare services, the participation of a home care services agency in an\nevaluation conducted pursuant to this subdivision shall not be\nnecessary.\n  3. The individualized service plan shall be developed in accordance\nwith the medical, nutritional, rehabilitation, functional, cognitive and\nother needs of the resident.\n  4. The individualized service plan shall include the services to be\nprovided, and how and by whom services will be provided and accessed.\n  5. The individualized service plan shall be reviewed and revised as\nfrequently as necessary to reflect the changing care needs of the\nresident, but no less frequently than every six months. To the extent\nnecessary, such review and revision shall be undertaken in consultation\nwith the resident's physician.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 4659's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>