<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4675"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4675"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4675"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4675/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4675/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4675/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4675/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4675">
        <num>4675</num>
        <heading>Priority reservation agreements; after obtaining a certificate of authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4675__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the operator has satisfied the requirements of this section and\nany applicable regulations; and\n  (ii) the operator can be expected to meet its obligations in\naccordance with this section and in accordance with its priority\nreservation agreements with prospective residents.\n  b. If the commissioner approves an application, the commissioner shall\nissue a written authorization to the operator authorizing the operator\nto enter into cancelable priority reservation agreements and collect\nrefundable priority reservation fees from prospective residents\nconcerning the fee-for-service continuing care retirement community.\n  c. The commissioner's authorization shall remain in effect as long as\nthe operator's certificate of authority for its community remains in\neffect; provided that the commissioner may rescind the authorization at\nany time for just cause, including any material misstatement of fact or\nmisrepresentation in any of the application materials or any materials\nsubsequently disseminated.\n  d. The operator shall provide written notice to all parties who have\nentered into cancelable priority reservation agreements of the\ncommissioner's recision of authorization to enter into cancelable\npriority reservation agreements.\n  e. The commissioner shall provide written notice to the escrow agent\nof the commissioner's recision of authorization to enter into cancelable\npriority reservation agreements, including instructions to release funds\nheld in escrow to the persons who have paid refundable priority\nreservation fees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>