<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4714"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4714"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4714"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4714">
        <num>4714</num>
        <heading>Shared health facilities advisory council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4714. Shared health facilities advisory council. 1. There is hereby\ncreated a shared health facilities advisory council consisting of\nnineteen members appointed by the commissioner for terms of three years.\nFour of the members shall represent the public interest and shall not be\na provider, consumer, or purveyor. Eight of the members shall represent\nconsumers receiving services at shared health facilities, and seven\nshall be selected from among recommendations made by organizations\nrepresenting providers and purveyors. Of the members first appointed,\nseven shall be appointed for terms expiring August thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-nine, and six shall be appointed for terms\nexpiring August thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight. Vacancies\nshall be filled by appointment for the unexpired terms. The shared\nhealth facilities advisory council shall select a chairman from among\nits members.\n  2. The shared health facilities advisory council shall meet as\nfrequently as its business may require, but in any event at least three\ntimes annually.  Meetings may be held at the call of the chairman or the\ncommissioner.  The commissioner shall designate an officer or employee\nof the department to act as secretary of the council. Each member shall\nbe reimbursed for expenses actually and necessarily incurred by him in\nthe performance of his official duties.\n  3. The shared health facilities advisory council shall have no\nexecutive, administrative or appointive duties. It shall have the duty\nto advise the department on all aspects of shared health facilities\nregulation and operation, including the rendering of recommendations\nconcerning proposed department rules and regulations. The shared health\nfacilities advisory council shall perform such other functions as the\ncommissioner may prescribe.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>