<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4902"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4902"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4902"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4902/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4902/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4902/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-4902/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4902">
        <num>4902</num>
        <heading>Utilization review program standards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Appointment of a medical director, who is a licensed physician;\nprovided, however, that the utilization review agent may appoint a\nclinical director when the utilization review performed is for a\ndiscrete category of health care service and provided further that the\nclinical director is a licensed health care professional who typically\nmanages the category of service. Responsibilities of the medical\ndirector, or, where appropriate, the clinical director, shall include,\nbut not be limited to, the supervision and oversight of the utilization\nreview process;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Development of written policies and procedures that govern all\naspects of the utilization review process and a requirement that a\nutilization review agent shall maintain and make available to enrollees\nand health care providers a written description of such procedures\nincluding procedures to appeal an adverse determination together with a\ndescription, jointly promulgated by the commissioner and the\nsuperintendent of financial services as required pursuant to subdivision\nfive of section forty-nine hundred fourteen of this article, of the\nexternal appeal process established pursuant to title two of this\narticle and the time frames for such appeals;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Utilization of written clinical review criteria developed pursuant\nto a utilization review plan;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishment of a process for rendering utilization review\ndeterminations which shall, at a minimum, include: written procedures to\nassure that utilization reviews and determinations are conducted within\nthe timeframes established herein; procedures to notify an enrollee, an\nenrollee's designee and/or an enrollee's health care provider of adverse\ndeterminations; and procedures for appeal of adverse determinations\nincluding the establishment of an expedited appeals process for denials\nof continued inpatient care or where there is imminent or serious threat\nto the health of the enrollee;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishment of a written procedure to assure that the notice\nof an adverse determination includes:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4902__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the reasons for the\ndetermination including the clinical rationale, if any;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4902__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>instructions\non how to initiate standard and expedited appeals pursuant to section\nforty-nine hundred four and an external appeal pursuant to section\nforty-nine hundred fourteen of this article;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4902__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>notice of the\navailability, upon request of the enrollee or the enrollee's designee,\nof the clinical review criteria relied upon to make such determination;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4902__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>what, if any, additional necessary information must be provided to,\nor obtained by, the utilization review agent in order to render a\ndecision on an appeal; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4902__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for an adverse determination related to a\nstep therapy protocol override determination, information that includes\nthe clinical review criteria relied upon to make such determination and\nany applicable alternative prescription drugs subject to the step\ntherapy protocol of the utilization review agent.\n  (ii) A utilization review agent may provide notice of an adverse\ndetermination related to a step therapy protocol override determination\nelectronically pursuant to subdivision nine of section forty-nine\nhundred three of this title, including by electronic mail or through the\nhealth care plan's member portal and provider portal. An electronic\nnotice of such an adverse determination may meet the requirements of\nclause five of subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph by linking to\ninformation posted on the website of the health care plan;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishment of a requirement that appropriate personnel of the\nutilization review agent are reasonably accessible by toll-free\ntelephone:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not less than forty hours per week during normal business hours to\ndiscuss patient care and allow response to telephone requests, and to\nensure that such utilization review agent has a telephone system capable\nof accepting, recording or providing instruction to incoming telephone\ncalls during other than normal business hours and to ensure response to\naccepted or recorded messages not less than one business day after the\ndate on which the call was received; or\n  (ii) notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nparagraph, not less than forty hours per week during normal business\nhours, to discuss patient care and allow response to telephone requests,\nand to ensure that, in the case of a request submitted pursuant to\nsubdivision three of section forty-nine hundred three of this title or\nan expedited appeal filed pursuant to subdivision two of section\nforty-nine hundred four of this title, on a twenty-four hour a day,\nseven day a week basis;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishment of appropriate policies and procedures to ensure\nthat all applicable state and federal laws to protect the\nconfidentiality of individual medical records are followed;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishment of a requirement that emergency services rendered to\nan enrollee shall not be subject to prior authorization nor shall\nreimbursement for such services be denied on retrospective review;\nprovided, however, that such services are medically necessary to\nstabilize or treat an emergency condition.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When conducting utilization review for purposes of determining\nhealth care coverage for substance use disorder treatment, a utilization\nreview agent shall utilize an evidence-based and peer reviewed clinical\nreview tool that is appropriate to the age of the patient. When\nconducting such utilization review for treatment provided in this state,\na utilization review agent shall utilize an evidence-based and peer\nreviewed clinical tool designated by the office of alcoholism and\nsubstance abuse services that is consistent with the treatment service\nlevels within the office of alcoholism and substance abuse services\nsystem. All approved tools shall have inter rater reliability testing\ncompleted by December thirty-first, two thousand sixteen.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When conducting utilization review for purposes of determining\nhealth care coverage for a mental health condition, a utilization review\nagent shall utilize evidence-based and peer reviewed clinical review\ncriteria that is appropriate to the age of the patient. The utilization\nreview agent shall use clinical review criteria deemed appropriate and\napproved for such use by the commissioner of the office of mental\nhealth, in consultation with the commissioner and the superintendent of\nfinancial services. Approved clinical review criteria shall have inter\nrater reliability testing completed by December thirty-first, two\nthousand nineteen.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishment of a requirement that emergency department and\ninpatient hospital services rendered by a general hospital certified\npursuant to article twenty-eight of this chapter to an enrollee to treat\nCOVID-19 during a declared state disaster emergency related to COVID-19\nshall not be denied on retrospective review on the basis that such\nservices were not medically necessary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, in consultation with the superintendent of\nfinancial services, may, as necessary, promulgate by regulation special\nconsiderations and processes for utilization review related to medically\nfragile children. Such regulations may include, at a minimum,\nconsiderations and processes related to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>medically necessary covered services to medically fragile\nchildren;\n  (ii) determinations specific to the needs of medically fragile\nchildren;\n  (iii) stabilization and discharge plans; and\n  (iv) payment for the care of medically fragile children.\n  2. Each utilization review agent shall assure adherence to the\nrequirements stated in subdivision one of this section by all\ncontractors, subcontractors, subvendors, agents and employees affiliated\nby contract or otherwise with such utilization review agent.\n  3. When establishing a step therapy protocol, a utilization review\nagent shall utilize recognized evidence-based and peer reviewed clinical\nreview criteria that takes into account the needs of atypical patient\npopulations and diagnoses as well when establishing the clinical review\ncriteria.\n  4. When conducting utilization review for a step therapy protocol\noverride determination, a utilization review agent shall utilize, in\naddition to any other requirements of this article, recognized\nevidence-based and peer reviewed clinical review criteria that is\nappropriate for the enrollee and the enrollee's medical condition.\n  * 5. When establishing a step therapy protocol, a utilization review\nagent shall ensure that the protocol cannot:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require a prescription drug that has not been approved by the\nUnited States Food and Drug Administration for the medical condition\nbeing treated or is not supported by current evidence-based guidelines\nfor the medical condition being treated;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require an enrollee to try and fail on more than two drugs used to\ntreat the same medical condition or disease before providing coverage to\nthe enrollee for the prescribed drug;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require the use of a step therapy-required drug for longer than\nthirty days or a duration of treatment supported by current\nevidence-based treatment guidelines appropriate to the specific disease\nstate being treated;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be imposed on an enrollee if a therapeutic equivalent to the\nprescribed drug is not available; or if the health care plan has\ndocumentation that it has covered the drug for the enrollee within the\npast three hundred sixty-five days;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require a newly enrolled enrollee to repeat a step therapy\nprotocol for a prescribed drug where that enrollee already completed a\nstep therapy protocol for that drug under a prior health care plan, so\nlong as the enrollee or provider submits information demonstrating\ncompletion of a step therapy protocol of the prior health care plan\nwithin the past three hundred sixty-five days; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4902__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be imposed on an enrollee for a prescribed drug that was\npreviously approved for coverage by the enrollee's current health care\nplan for the enrollee's specific medical condition after the enrollee's\ncurrent health care plan implements a formulary or utilization\nmanagement change that impacts the coverage criteria for the prescribed\ndrug until the approved override expires, unless a specifically\nidentified and evidence-based safety concern exists and a different\ntherapeutic alternative drug exists.\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2026\n  * 6. When establishing a step therapy protocol, a utilization review\nagent shall ensure that the protocol accepts any written or electronic\nattestation submitted by the enrollee's health care professional, as\ndefined in section forty-nine hundred of this title, who prescribed the\ndrug and stating that a required drug has failed, as evidence that the\nrequired drug has failed.\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>