<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-573"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-573"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="573"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-573/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-573/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-573/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-573/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_573">
        <num>573</num>
        <heading>Issuance of certificates of qualification</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 573. Issuance of certificates of qualification. 1. The department\nshall issue a certificate of qualification to any person who meets\nminimum qualifications, prescribed by the department and in accordance\nwith federal regulations, including board certification as required, and\nwho otherwise demonstrates to the department that such person possesses\nthe character, competence, training and ability to administer properly\nthe technical and scientific operation of a clinical laboratory or blood\nbank, including supervision of procedures and reporting of findings of\ntests.\n  2. Application for a certificate of qualification shall be made on\nforms provided by the department and such other information as the\ndepartment may require.\n  3. The certificate shall be valid for a period of two years from the\ndate of issuance and may be renewed for successive two-year periods\nthereafter. The original application and each renewal application shall\nbe accompanied by a registration fee of one hundred fifty dollars.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the commissioner\nmay issue a temporary certificate of qualification to any person pending\nthe issuance of a certificate as provided in this section. A temporary\ncertificate shall be valid for a period of thirty days from the date of\nits issuance and may be renewed for a maximum of four successive periods\nof thirty days.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>