<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-575"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-575"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="575"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-575/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-575/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-575/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-575/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_575">
        <num>575</num>
        <heading>Issuance of permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 575. Issuance of permits. 1. Application for a permit shall be made\nby the owner and the director of the clinical laboratory or blood bank\nin a manner and format prescribed by the department. The application\nshall contain the name of the owner, the name of the director, the\nprocedures or categories of procedures or services for which the permit\nis sought, the location or locations and physical description of the\nfacility or location or locations at which tests are to be performed or\nat which a blood bank is to be operated, and such other information as\nthe department may require.\n  2. A permit shall not be issued unless a valid certificate of\nqualification has been issued pursuant to the provisions of section five\nhundred seventy-three of this title, unless all fees and outstanding\npenalties, if any, have been paid, and the department finds that the\nclinical laboratory or blood bank is competently staffed and properly\nequipped, and will be operated in the manner required by this title.\n  3. The permit shall be issued jointly to the owner and the director\nand they jointly and severally shall be responsible to the department\nfor the maintenance and operation of the clinical laboratory or blood\nbank and for any violations of this title and the rules and regulations\npromulgated thereunder.\n  4. A permit shall be valid for the year for which it is issued. The\ninitial application for a permit shall be accompanied by a registration\nfee of one hundred dollars.\n  5. The permit shall specify the names of the owners and the director,\nthe procedures or categories of procedures or services authorized, and\nthe locations at which such procedures or services may be performed. The\npermit and the certificate of qualification shall be displayed at all\ntimes in a prominent place in the laboratory.\n  6. A permit shall become void by a change in the director, owner, or\nlocation. A category on a permit shall become void by a change in the\ndirector for that category. The department may, pursuant to regulations\nadopted under this title, extend the date on which a permit or category\non a permit shall become void for a period not to exceed sixty days from\nthe date of a change of the director, owner or location. An application\nfor a new permit must be made in the manner provided by this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>