<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-580"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-580"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="580"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-580/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-580/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-580/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-580/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_580">
        <num>580</num>
        <heading>Construction</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_580__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this title shall be construed to impair or affect\nthe power or authority of the city of New York or a department or agency\nthereof, to enact or enforce additional laws, codes or regulations\naffecting clinical laboratories or blood banks, not inconsistent with\nthe provisions of this title or any regulations promulgated hereunder,\nrelated to the control, prevention or reporting of diseases or medical\nconditions or to the control or abatement of public health nuisances.\nNoncompliance with such laws, codes or regulations as documented by the\nlocal public health officer may be a basis for the department's denial\nor non-renewal of a laboratory permit or a certificate of qualification.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such local laws, codes or regulations which are more restrictive\nthan or additional to the requirements set forth in this title or the\nregulations promulgated hereunder shall be deemed not inconsistent.\n  4. The collection, processing, storage, distribution or use of blood,\nblood components or blood derivatives for the purpose of diagnosis,\nprevention or treatment of disease is hereby declared to be a public\nhealth service and shall not be construed to be, and is declared not to\nbe, a sale of such blood, blood components or blood derivatives, for any\npurpose or purposes whatsoever.\n  5. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of the education law,\nindividuals performing only waived tests or provider-performed\nmicroscopy procedures in accordance with the provisions of subdivision\nthree of section five hundred seventy-nine of this title shall not be\nrequired to be licensed or certified as a clinical laboratory\npractitioner pursuant to the education law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>