<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-602"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-602"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="602"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_602">
        <num>602</num>
        <heading>Core public health services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Family health, which shall include activities designed to reduce\nperinatal, infant and maternal mortality and morbidity and to promote\nthe health of infants, children, adolescents, and people of childbearing\nage. Such activities shall include family centered perinatal services\nand other services appropriate to promote the birth of a healthy baby to\na healthy mother, and services to assure that infants, young children,\nand school age children are enrolled in appropriate health insurance\nprograms and other health benefit programs for which they are eligible,\nand that the parents or guardians of such children are provided with\ninformation concerning health care providers in their area that are\nwilling and able to provide health services to such children. Provision\nof primary and preventive clinical health care services shall be\neligible for state aid for uninsured persons under the age of\ntwenty-one, provided that the municipality makes good faith efforts to\nassist such persons with insurance enrollment and only until such time\nas enrollment becomes effective. Provision of prenatal clinical health\ncare services shall be eligible for state aid for uninsured women of any\nage, provided that the municipality makes good faith efforts to assist\nsuch women with insurance enrollment and only until such time as\nenrollment becomes effective.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Communicable disease control, which shall include activities to\ncontrol and mitigate the extent of infectious diseases. Such activities\nshall include, but not be limited to, surveillance and epidemiological\nprograms, programs to detect diseases in their early stages,\nimmunizations against infectious diseases, investigation of diseases and\nprevention of transmission, prevention and treatment of sexually\ntransmissible diseases, and arthropod vector-borne disease prevention.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Chronic disease prevention, which shall include promoting public,\nhealth care provider and other community service provider activities\nthat encourage chronic disease prevention, early detection and quality\ncare delivery. Such activities include, but are not limited to, those\nthat promote healthy communities and reduce risk factors such as tobacco\nuse, poor nutrition and physical inactivity. Provision of clinical\nservices shall not be eligible for state aid, subject to such exceptions\nas the commissioner may deem appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Community health assessment, as described in section six hundred\ntwo-a of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Environmental health, which shall include activities that promote\nhealth and prevent illness and injury by assuring that safe and sanitary\nconditions are maintained at public drinking water supplies, food\nservice establishments, and other regulated facilities; investigating\npublic health nuisances to assure abatement by responsible parties;\nprotecting the public from unnecessary exposure to radiation, chemicals,\nand other harmful contaminants; and conducting investigations of\nincidents that result in illness, injury or death in order to identify\nand mitigate the environmental causes to prevent additional morbidity\nand mortality.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Public health emergency preparedness and response, including\nplanning, training, and maintaining readiness for public health\nemergencies.\n  2. The municipality must incorporate into each core public health\nservice the following general activities:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ongoing assessment of community health needs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>education on public health issues;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>development of policies and plans to address health needs; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_602__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>actions to assure that services necessary to achieve agreed upon\ngoals are provided.\n  3. The commissioner may approve a state aid application in which the\nmunicipality actually provides fewer services than those set forth in\nsubdivision one of this section as long as the application identifies\nthe availability of other services, who will provide those services and\nthe manner in which the services will be provided and financed.\n  4. The commissioner shall consult with the county health\ncommissioners, public health directors, and boards of public health when\npromulgating rules and regulations to effectuate the provisions and\npurposes of this article. The commissioner shall not have the power to\nprescribe the number of persons to be employed by any municipality.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>