<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-608"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-608"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="608"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_608">
        <num>608</num>
        <heading>State aid; children and youth with special health care needs support services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 608. State aid; children and youth with special health care needs\nsupport services. 1. Whenever the commissioner of health of any county\nor part-county health district or, in a county lacking a county or\npart-county health district, the medical director of the children and\nyouth with special health care needs support services program, or the\ndepartment of health of the city of New York, issues an authorization\nfor medical service for a child with physical disabilities, such county\nor the city of New York shall be granted state aid in an amount of fifty\nper centum of the amount expended in accordance with the rules and\nregulations established by the commissioner, except that such state aid\nreimbursement may be withheld if, on post-audit and review, the\ncommissioner finds that the medical service rendered and furnished was\nnot in conformance with a plan submitted by the municipality and with\nthe rules and regulations established by the commissioner or that the\nrecipient of the medical service was not a child with a physical\ndisability as defined in section two thousand five hundred eighty-one of\nthis chapter.\n  2. Whenever a court of any county issues an order for medical services\nfor any Indian child with a physical disability, residing on an Indian\nreservation, such county shall be granted state aid in the amount of one\nhundred percent of the amount expended in accordance with the standards\nestablished by the commissioner. Such reimbursement shall be made from\nany funds appropriated to the department for payment of state aid for\nchildren with physical disabilities.\n  3. The clerk of the board of supervisors or other similar governing\nbody of each county, or chief fiscal officer of the city of New York\nwhich has paid claims as provided herein shall, not oftener than once in\neach month, transmit to the commissioner a certified statement in the\nform prescribed by him, stating the amount expended for the purposes\nspecified herein, the date of each expenditure, and the purpose for\nwhich it was made. Upon the receipt of such certified statement the\ncommissioner shall examine the same, and if such expenditures were made\nas required by law he shall approve it and transmit it to the\ncomptroller for audit. The comptroller shall thereupon issue his warrant\nin the amount specified in such approved statement for the payment\nthereof out of moneys appropriated therefor to the county treasurer of\nthe county or chief fiscal officer of the city of New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>