<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-802"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-802"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="802"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_802">
        <num>802</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 802. Powers and duties. 1. The council shall have the power and duty\nto:\n  a. identify strategic areas for health research;\n  b. conduct ongoing surveys of the state allocation of health research\nsources;\n  c. develop health research programs and establish priorities for such\nprograms;\n  d. assure that women's health needs as well as men's have been\nconsidered in research programs which the council develops and in the\npriorities it establishes;\n  e. review and disseminate the results of health research programs;\n  f. stimulate independent health research;\n  g. coordinate health research within New York state to avoid\nunnecessary duplication of effort and facilities;\n  h. encourage health research in designated priority areas by assisting\nresearch projects in obtaining grants or fellowships;\n  i. develop a model health research plan for the state;\n  j. hold meetings at least semiannually. Special meetings may be called\nby the chairman;\n  k. encourage education and training in the area of health research;\n  l. accept on behalf of the state any grant, gift, devise or bequest,\nmade to the health research council; and to cause the department of\ntaxation and finance to establish from all such monies a special trust\nfund to be used under the direction of the council for the purpose of\nhealth research and training. Such grants, gifts, devises or bequests\nshall be accepted subject to the provisions of section fifty-three-a of\nthe state finance law and subject to audit by the state comptroller;\n  m. make rules and regulations for the exercise of the council's powers\nand performance of its duties in order to carry out the provisions of\nthis article; and\n  n. exercise and perform such other functions, powers, and duties as\nmay from time to time be conferred or imposed by law.\n  2. For the purposes of this section research shall not include the\nactual delivery of health care or equipment for health care provided by\nexisting institutes established by this chapter to conduct research,\nscientific investigations, seek methods of medical care or provide for\nthe treatment of patients.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>