<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBH">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-904"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-904"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="904"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBH"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-904/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-904/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-904/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbh/section-904/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_904">
        <num>904</num>
        <heading>Primary care practitioner scholarship program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_904__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be a resident of New York state\nwho attends or plans to attend a primary care practitioner program; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_904__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>agree to practice as a primary care practitioner in an underserved\narea of New York state.\n  4. In selecting students to be awarded scholarships, preference shall\nbe given to students who attend or plan to attend a primary care\npractitioner program located in New York state. Priority in the\nselection of recipients shall be given to recipients applying for second\nyear funding. Scholarships shall be awarded competitively using\nselection criteria that include, but are not limited to: academic\nperformance, previous work experience in their chosen profession, and a\ndemonstrated interest or commitment in working with underserved\npopulations or in underserved areas.\n  5. Within such time as the commissioner shall by regulation provide, a\nrecipient of an award shall agree to practice in an underserved area of\nthis state for a period of eighteen months for each annual award to be\nreceived by the recipient. In no case shall the total number of months\nof service be less than eighteen. The commissioner shall secure from\neach recipient a written agreement to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_904__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide primary care services in an area designated as having a\nshortage of primary care practitioners;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_904__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>work in a practice site that accepts payment on behalf of\nbeneficiaries of title XVIII of the federal social security act\n(medicare) and individuals eligible for medical assistance pursuant to\ntitle eleven of article five of the social services law; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_904__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide thirty-five hours per week of direct patient care in the\ndesignated shortage area being served.\n  6. If a recipient fails to comply fully with such conditions, the\npresident shall be entitled to receive from such recipient an amount to\nbe determined by the formula:\n                               A = 2B(t-s)\n                                  -----\n                                    t\nin  which "A" is the amount the president is entitled to recover, "B" is\nthe sum of all awards made to the recipient and  the  interest  on  such\namount which would be payable if at the times such awards were paid they\nwere  loans  bearing interest at the maximum prevailing rate; "t" is the\ntotal number of months in the recipient's period of obligated  services;\nand  "s"  is  the  number  of months of service actually rendered by the\nrecipient. Any amount which the president is entitled to  recover  under\nthis  paragraph  shall  be paid within the five-year period beginning on\nthe  date  that  the  recipient  failed  to  comply  with  this  service\ncondition.  Nothing  in  the written agreement shall affect the terms of\nemployment of the individual who shall  negotiate,  separate  and  apart\nfrom  the  program, his or her salary and other forms of employment with\nan agency, institution or  a  program  in  which  he  or  she  shall  be\nemployed.  Any  obligation to comply with such provisions as outlined in\nthis section shall be canceled upon the  death  of  the  recipient.  The\ncommissioner  shall  promulgate regulations to provide for the waiver or\nsuspension of any financial obligation  when  compliance  would  involve\nextreme hardship.\n  7. A recipient of an award shall report annually to the New York state\nhigher education services corporation, on forms prescribed by the\npresident, as to the performance of the required services, commencing\nwith the calendar year in which the recipient begins to provide primary\ncare services in an underserved are...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>