<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-14"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-14"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14">
        <num>14</num>
        <heading>Time of performing conditions of grant</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14. Time of performing conditions of grant.  1. The commissioner of\ngeneral services may, unless otherwise provided, fix a reasonable time,\nnot less than one year, for the performance of conditions by the\ngrantees of lands, including lands under water, directed to be granted\non the performance of conditions.  If such conditions are not performed\nwithin the time limited, the persons entitled to any benefit under such\ngrant shall forfeit all right to and title in the premises. If the\ncommissioner, after having caused an inspection to be made of the lands\ngranted, determines that the conditions contained in the letters-patent\nhave been complied with, he may issue a certificate to that effect. If\ncomplete compliance has not been had, the commissioner, in his\ndiscretion, may make an order to the effect that compliance had been had\nwith the conditions in such definitely described portion of lands\ngranted as have been improved. Such order shall be conclusive evidence\nof the performance of the conditions contained in such letters-patent to\nthe extent stated in such order and as to lands described therein. When\nthe time within which any condition contained in any grant of land is\nfixed by the terms of the grant, the commissioner may, for good cause\nshown before the expiration of such time, extend the time within which\nsuch condition is to be performed, not exceeding three years.\n  2. The commissioner may, in his discretion, upon application of the\ngrantee or his successor in interest, by order, alter, amend or cancel\nany condition or conditions contained in letters-patent for land,\nincluding lands under water, if satisfied by the reason or proof\nsubmitted that such alteration, amendment or cancellation of condition\nor conditions is just and is not detrimental to the interests of the\nstate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>