<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-15-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-15-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-15-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-15-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-15-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-15-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_A">
        <num>15-A</num>
        <heading>Filling in the state owned bed of Lake George prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 15-a. Filling in the state owned bed of Lake George prohibited.  1.\nNo person or corporation shall fill in or cause to be filled in any land\nof the state of New York lying below the mean low water line of Lake\nGeorge by dumping or placing rock, stone, concrete, dirt or other\nsimilar material on said land without first obtaining a grant or lease\nof the land to be filled in or an easement, license or permit to fill in\nsuch land from the commissioner of general services.\n  2. This section shall not apply to a person or corporation placing\nwooden or precast concrete timbers, logs or beams or cribs of wooden or\nprecast concrete timbers, logs or beams filled with rocks or stones on\nthe bed of Lake George for the sole purpose of constructing,\nreconstructing or repairing the foundation, cribs or supports of a\nprivate dock or a private one-story boat house legally erected or\nmaintained on the bed of said lake.\n  3. Any person or corporation violating the provisions of this section\non or after September first, nineteen hundred sixty-three shall be\nguilty of a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than five\nhundred dollars and by an additional fine of not more than twenty-five\ndollars for each day that such fill is left on land of the state lying\nbelow the mean low water line of Lake George after a written notice to\nremove the same has been personally served on the person who or\ncorporation which made said fill or caused said fill to be made by the\ncommissioner of general services or pursuant to his direction.\n  4. For the purposes of this section mean low water line of Lake George\nshall mean the water level of Lake George at one and eighty-one\nhundredths feet on the gage of the United States Geological Survey at\nRogers Rock on Lake George known as Rogers Rock gage.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>