<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_A">
        <num>2-A</num>
        <heading>Certain transfers of jurisdiction over state-owned lands and declarations of abandonment by the commissioner of general services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-a. Certain transfers of jurisdiction over state-owned lands and\ndeclarations of abandonment by the commissioner of general services.  1.\nWhen the commissioner of general services proposes to transfer\njurisdiction over state lands pursuant to subdivision four of section\nthree without the application or consent therein provided or when the\ncommissioner proposes to declare real property as abandoned pursuant to\nsubdivision two of section thirty-a, he shall give written notice of\nsuch intention to the agency having jurisdiction over such land, and in\nthe case of a transfer of jurisdiction pursuant to subdivision four of\nsection three, to the state agency to which jurisdiction is proposed to\nbe transferred.\n  2. Unless within thirty days from the date such notice is given, an\nagency entitled to notice pursuant to subdivision one hereof objects to\nsuch proposed action, the commissioner of general services may effect\nsuch transfer of jurisdiction or declaration of abandonment.\n  3. If within thirty days of the giving of such notice, any state\nagency entitled to notice pursuant to subdivision one hereof objects to\nthe action proposed by the commissioner by filing notice to such effect\nwith the commissioner of general services, such proposed action shall be\nreviewed by the director of the budget, and the secretary of state. They\nshall affirm or reverse the proposed action by the commissioner and that\ndecision shall be final. If they affirm the proposed action or fail to\nrender a determination within six months of the date of the notice\nreferred to in subdivision one, the commissioner may thereupon effect\nsuch transfer or declaration of abandonment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>