<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2">
        <num>2</num>
        <heading>State-owned real property inventory and management program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2. State-owned real property inventory and management program.  1.\nDefinitions.  As used in this section, unless the context otherwise\nrequires:\n  a. "State agency" shall mean any department, division, board,\ncommission, bureau, office or other agency of the state other than a\npublic authority or public benefit corporation, except that for the\npurpose of subdivision two hereof, the term shall include any public\nauthority or public benefit corporation any member or director of which\nis appointed by the governor and having jurisdiction, custody or control\nof any state-owned real property.\n  b. "State-owned real property" shall include all lands and buildings,\nstructures, facilities, and improvements thereon, title to which is\nvested in the people of the state of New York.\n  2. State-owned real property inventory. The commissioner of general\nservices shall establish, maintain and have the custody of an inventory\nof all state-owned real property, as an aid in the utilization and\nmanagement of the land resources of the state. The inventory shall\ninclude any state-owned real property under the jurisdiction, custody or\nmanagement of any state agency, whether acquired by appropriation,\npurchase, gift or otherwise. In order to provide an accurate and current\ninventory for use by the commissioner of general services, state\nagencies and the legislature, the commissioner may by rule or regulation\nprescribe the elements, extent and format of the information to be\nincluded and the procedures for collection, presentation and\nverification of the information to be contained in the inventory.  The\ncommissioner shall by rule or regulation, and upon the advice of the\ncomptroller, prescribe the elements, extent and format of the\ninformation to be included and the procedures for collection,\npresentation, and verification of such information necessary to\nestablish and maintain a set of general fixed asset accounts that comply\nwith generally accepted accounting principles. Each state agency shall\ndeliver to the commissioner of general services such information at the\ntimes and in the manner as determined by him to be necessary for the\nestablishment and maintenance of the inventory and shall permit the\ncommissioner and his agents to make such physical and records\ninspections as deemed necessary by the commissioner for the purposes of\nthe inventory program.\n  3. State-owned real property management program. The commissioner of\ngeneral services is authorized and directed to study, evaluate and\ncoordinate state agency management practices, plans and procedures for\nthe acquisition, utilization and disposition of state-owned real\nproperty, and to advise and assist state agencies in the improvement of\nsuch management practices, plans and procedures.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>