<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="24"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_24">
        <num>24</num>
        <heading>Sale or exchange of certain detached parcels of forest preserve lands</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 24. Sale or exchange of certain detached parcels of forest preserve\nlands.  Any state department or agency, at the time having jurisdiction\nover any of the lands hereinafter specified, may consent to a sale or\nexchange by the commissioner of general services of any lands of the\nstate, now owned or hereafter acquired, constituting the forest\npreserve, but outside of the Adirondack and Catskill parks as now fixed\nby law and not acquired or dedicated for the practice of forest or wild\nlife conservation, and consisting in any case of not more than one\nhundred contiguous acres entirely separated from any other portion of\nthe forest preserve.  Upon such consent being filed with the\ncommissioner in writing, accompanied by a description of such lands, the\ncommissioner may in his discretion sell or exchange any of such lands in\naccordance with the consent.\n  All sales shall be subject to and governed by the provisions of\nsections thirty-three, thirty-five, thirty-seven, thirty-seven-a,\nthirty-eight, thirty-eight-a and thirty-nine of this chapter, being\ngeneral provisions governing the sale of unappropriated state lands.\nAll moneys derived by the commissioner from such sales, not including\nany refunds made pursuant to section twenty-six of this law, shall be\npaid first to repay any expenditures made by the office of general\nservices with relation to forest preserve lands from moneys appropriated\nto said office in the first instance for the administration, management,\nutilization and disposition of real property of the state and any rights\nor interests therein, and any balance of such moneys remaining after\nrepayment of the first instance expenditures shall be paid through the\noffice of general services into a special fund of the state treasury,\nprovided for that purpose by the state finance law and known as the\nforest preserve expansion fund, and shall be expended only as provided\nin that law.  All of such moneys received during any month shall be so\npaid on or before the fifteenth day of the succeeding month.\n  All exchanges shall be only for additional lands for the forest\npreserve within either the Adirondack or Catskill park as now fixed by\nlaw and shall be subject to approval by the attorney general of the\ntitle to the lands thus to be acquired by the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>