<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-27"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-27"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-27/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-27/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-27/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-27/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27">
        <num>27</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of real property by purchase or appropriation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by the staff, forces and\nequipment of the office of general services; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by the commissioner\nof general services contracting for the management, supervision and\nenforcement thereof with any person, firm or corporation; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a\ncombination of such methods.\n  The use and occupancy of such property under the provisions of this\nsection and the right of the state or its duly authorized agent to\nrecover possession thereof shall not be subject to the emergency housing\nrent control law.\n  Expenses which are determined by the commissioner to have been\nincurred in connection with the use and occupancy of such property may\nbe paid out of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from\nmoneys appropriated for the duly authorized project for which the\nproperty was acquired. However, such expenses incurred under a contract\nfor management and supervision of such property may be paid out of the\ngross revenue therefrom. All moneys received by the commissioner for\nsuch use or occupancy shall be paid into the treasury of the state to\nthe credit of the capital projects fund.\n  12. Authorization is hereby given to the commissioner of general\nservices to make supplemental relocation payments, separately computed\nand stated, to displaced owners and tenants of residential property\nacquired pursuant to this section who are entitled thereto, as\ndetermined by him. The commissioner, with the approval of the director\nof the budget, may establish and from time to time amend rules and\nregulations providing for such supplemental relocation payments or\nreplacement housing. Such rules and regulations may further define the\nterms used in this subdivision. In the case of property acquired\npursuant to this section which is improved by a dwelling actually owned\nand occupied by the displaced owner for not less than one hundred eighty\ndays immediately prior to initiation of negotiations for the acquisition\nof such property, such payment to such owner shall not exceed twenty-two\nthousand five hundred dollars. Such payment shall be the amount, if any,\nwhich, when added to the acquisition payment equals the average price,\nestablished by the commissioner on a class, group or individual basi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>