<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="34-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_A">
        <num>34-A</num>
        <heading>Leasing and granting of unappropriated state lands to the United States or any instrumentality thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 34-a. Leasing and granting of unappropriated state lands to the\nUnited States or any instrumentality thereof.  The commissioner of\ngeneral services may grant and convey in fee title or such lesser\ninterest than fee title or, notwithstanding any other provision of law\nto the contrary, lease without bid, for such periods of time as he may\ndeem appropriate to the United States of America, its departments,\nagencies and other instrumentalities, including the United States Postal\nService, authorized by law to take such fee title, lesser interest than\nfee title or leasehold interest in real property, upon application by an\nauthorized officer or employee thereof, and upon such terms and\nconditions as the commissioner deems proper, any parcel or parcels of\nunappropriated state land which are needed to carry out the functions of\nsuch department, agency or instrumentality. The use of any property\nconveyed under this section shall be subject to local land use\nregulation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>