<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="34"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-34/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34">
        <num>34</num>
        <heading>Transfer of unappropriated state lands for mental health, developmental disabilities, park, recreation, playground, reforestation, street...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 34. Transfer of unappropriated state lands for mental health,\ndevelopmental disabilities, park, recreation, playground, reforestation,\nstreet or highway purposes. 1. Such commissioner of general services\nmay, from time to time, transfer and convey to a city, incorporated\nvillage, town or county, in consideration of one dollar to be paid to\nthe state of New York, and on such terms and conditions as such\ncommissioner may impose, a part or all of any parcel or parcels of\nunappropriated state lands upon certification that such parcel or\nparcels are useful for local mental health facilities, developmental\ndisabilities facilities, park, recreation, playground, reforestation,\nstreet or highway purposes, and that they will be properly improved and\nmaintained for one or more of such purposes and provided that this\ndisposition of such parcel or parcels is not otherwise prohibited.\nCertification shall be evidenced by a formal request from the board of\nestimate, common council, village board, town board or county board of\nsupervisors, setting forth in detail the parcel or parcels to be\nreleased, transferred and conveyed and the availability and usefulness\nof such parcel or parcels for one or more of such purposes. In the city\nof New York however, certification shall be evidenced by a formal\nrequest from the mayor. In the event that lands transferred under the\nprovisions of this section are not properly improved and maintained for\none or more of the purposes contemplated by this section by the city,\nvillage, town or county to which they were transferred, the title\nthereto shall revert to the people of the state of New York, and the\nattorney-general may institute an action in the supreme court for a\njudgment declaring a revesting of such title in the state. Such\ncommissioner may also transfer any unappropriated state lands to the\noffice of parks, recreation and historic preservation or the department\nof environmental conservation, upon the application of the commissioner\nthereof indicating that such unappropriated state lands are required for\nstate park purposes within the area of jurisdiction of such office or\ndepartment.\n  2. The commissioner of general services may, in his or her discretion,\nand upon such terms and conditions as such commissioner may impose, upon\napplication of the mayor of the city of New York, grant to the city of\nNew York, for public streets, parks, parkways, playgrounds, recreation\nand conservation purposes, all of the right, title and interest of the\npeople of the state of New York, of, in and to any portion of the lands\nand lands under water in Jamaica bay and Rockaway inlets and the\ntributaries thereto.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>