<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-75"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-75"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-75/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-75/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-75/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-75/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75">
        <num>75</num>
        <heading>Grants of land under water</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of general services may grant in perpetuity or\notherwise, to the owners of the land adjacent to the land underwater\nspecified in this section, to promote the commerce of this state or for\nthe purpose of beneficial enjoyment thereof by such owners, or for\nagricultural purposes, or for public park, beach, street, highway,\nparkway, playground, recreation or conservation purposes, so much of\nsaid land underwater as the commissioner deems necessary for that\npurpose. No such grant shall be made to any person other than the\nproprietor of the adjacent land. Any such grant made to any other person\nshall be void, except that, subject to the other provisions of this\nsection, the commissioner of general services may transfer jurisdiction\nover state-owned lands underwater to a state agency for the purpose of\nprotecting environmentally sensitive lands underwater even if the state\nagency is not the proprietor of the adjacent upland. The commissioner\nmay also lease such land underwater to such owner of the adjacent upland\nor, with the consent of such owner of the adjacent upland, to others,\nfor terms up to forty years. No such grant or lease shall be made of any\nlands belonging to the city of New York, or so as to interfere with the\nrights of that city or of the Hudson River Railroad Company, or of its\nsuccessor the New York Central and Hudson River Railroad Company. In\nmaking any grant, lease, permit or other conveyance, the commissioner of\ngeneral services shall, upon administrative findings, and to the extent\npracticable, reserve such interests or attach such conditions to\npreserve the public interest in use of state-owned lands underwater and\nwaterways for navigation, commerce, fishing, bathing, recreation,\nenvironmental protection and access to the navigable waters of the\nstate, with due regard for the need of affected owners of private\nproperty to safeguard their property. The commissioner shall by official\nrules establish criteria...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No wharf, dock, pier, jetty, platform, breakwater, mooring or\nother structure shall be constructed, erected, anchored, suspended,\nplaced or substantially replaced, altered, modified, enlarged, or\nexpanded in, on or above state-owned lands underwater, nor shall any\nfill be placed on such lands underwater, unless a lease, easement,\npermit, or other interest is obtained from the commissioner, which\nauthorizes the use and occupancy of those state-owned lands underwater\nto be affected by such act or acts, provided however, that there shall\nbe excepted in the uniform regulations issued pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision any existing structure for non-commercial use\nconstructed prior to June seventeenth, nineteen hundred ninety-two, by\nor on behalf of the owner of adjacent upland who owned prior to June\nseventeenth, nineteen hundred ninety-two, which has a surface area, as\nmeasured at the outermost perimeter, including surface waters between or\nencompassed within the structure of less than five thousand square feet\nin area, and with respect to docking facilities, has a capacity of no\nmore than seven boats thirty feet in length. For the purposes of this\nsubdivision, the term "structure" shall not include discharge or intake\npipes, pipelines, cables, or conduits. Thereafter there shall be so\nexcepted any structure constructed by or on behalf of the owner of\nadjacent uplands that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has a surface area, as measured at the outermost perimeter,\nincluding surface waters directly between or encompassed within the\nstructure, of less than four thousand square feet in area and not\nexceeding fifteen feet in height, as measured at the uppermost point,\nabove the mean high water line and, with respect to docking facilities,\nhas a capacity of five or fewer boats thirty feet in length and, with\nrespect to mooring facilities, has a capacity of fewer than ten boats\nthirty feet in length; provided that the commissioner may by rule\npromulgated pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision determine,\nbased on a different surface area or other criteria of size and use,\nthat other types of structure in particular circumstances do not\nrepresent significant encroachments on state-owned lands underwater, and\n  (ii) is water dependent, which shall mean, for purposes of this\nsection, an activity which can only be conducted on, in, over or\nadjacent to a water body because such activity requires direct access to\nthat water body, and which involves, as an integral part of such\nactivity, the use of the water.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The requirements of obtaining a lease, easement, permit or other\ninterest from the commissioner pursuant to the rules set forth in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall not apply to the person or\nentity who was the upland owner on June seventeenth, nineteen hundred\nninety-two, of lands adjacent to filled state-owned lands underwater or\nformerly underwater, in respect of those filled lands, including\naccompanying seawalls; provided however, that any right, title and\ninterest of the state in and to any such state-owned lands shall in no\nrespect be diminished or impaired by the provisions of this section, nor\nby any exemption in the uniform regulations authorized by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision.\n  Upon any transfer of such lands, or at the request of the owner of the\nadjacent upland, the commissioner may convey such lesser interest as may\nbe minimally required to allow a conveyance of marketable title by that\nowner of the adjacent land. Consideration charged in such instances\nshall reflect the interest so conveyed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of environmental conservation and the\nsecretary of state shall review any proposed lease, easement, permit or\nother interest, except for facilities in existence on June seventeenth,\nnineteen hundred ninety-two, and which are not the subject of an action\nby the attorney general for unlawful occupation of state lands under\nwater on the effective date of this paragraph. The commissioner of\nenvironmental conservation shall recommend conditions to protect the\nenvironment and natural resources. The commissioner of general services\nshall incorporate those conditions in any lease, easement, permit or\nother interest, giving due regard as well to the recommendations of the\nsecretary of state with respect to coastal issues, or shall deny the\nproposal if the commissioner of environmental conservation, upon\nadministrative findings, determines that the environment or natural\nresources cannot be adequately protected. Such lease, easement, permit,\nor other conveyance of an interest shall state the purpose for which it\nis made, and shall also be subject to all applicable federal, state and\nlocal laws, rules, regulations and codes.\n  (ii) The owner, occupier or any other person or entity (except those\nagainst whom there has been commenced on the effective date of this\nparagraph an action by the attorney general, for unlawful occupation of\nstate lands under water) with a legal or beneficial interest in any\nstructure not excepted by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision and\noccupying state lands underwater on the effective date of the rules\nauthorized by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, as adopted pursuant to\nsubdivision five of section two hundred two of the state administrative\nprocedure act, shall make application for such lease, easement, permit\nor other interest within one year from that effective date.\n  Except where timely application for such an interest has been made\nwithin one year pursuant to this subdivision, the commissioner is\nauthorized to require the term of such lease, easement, permit, or other\ninterest to be retroactive to the effective date of the rules so\nadopted. Any instrument conveying an interest in real property which is\nmade retroactive shall include provision for payment of consideration\nfor the portion of the term which extends retroactively including, where\nappropriate, interest on such consideration at the same rate then\ncurrently in effect and applied to judgments rendered in the court of\nclaims.\n  (iii) The commissioner shall make reasonable efforts to provide notice\nto persons affected by the requirements of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may impose a fee in connection with the\nissuance of any such lease, easement, permit, or other interest, which\nfee shall be established by rule pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, and which shall take into account other factors affecting\nvalue including but not limited to classes of structure, types of use\n(including whether the use is for public or private purposes), location\nand region, size, usefulness of the parcel standing alone and such other\ncriteria as the commissioner may determine, but which shall exclude the\nvalue of improvements thereon constructed and maintained by the\nadjoining upland owner. The rules and regulations required by paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall prescribe that in the event an applicant\nfor a lease, easement or other interest in real property shall dispute\nand request a reduction of the commissioner's determination of the value\nof the interest to be conveyed, the commissioner shall, upon the\napplicant's submission of an appraisal of the value of such property\ninterest conducted in accord with standard and accepted appraisal\nmethodology by an independent appraiser qualified as prescribed in this\nparagraph and which appraisal varies in its conclusion as to value by\nten percent or more of the value previously established by the\ncommissioner, and upon the applicant's agreement to be bound thereby,\ncontract with a second independent appraiser, qualified as prescribed in\nthis paragraph, to render an appraisal of the value of the interest\nproposed to be conveyed, the results of which appraisal shall be binding\nupon both the applicant and the commissioner of general services. Such\nappraiser shall be selected by the commissioner of general services from\namong a group of at least three appraisers identified by the applicant\nall of whom must be qualified as prescribed in this paragraph and each\nof whom must agree to employ standard appraisal methodology. For the\npurposes of this provision a qualified appraiser shall be certified by\nthe secretary of state to transact business as a real estate general\nappraiser and shall conduct a regular business of the appraisal of real\nproperty interests. In the event that the appraisal contracted for in\nsuch manner shall conclude that the value of the property interest in\nquestion is equal to the value previously determined by the commissioner\nplus or minus ten percent, the entire cost of such appraisal shall be\nborne by the applicant, otherwise, the entire cost thereof shall be\nborne by the commissioner of general services.\n  (ii) For leases, easements and conveyances of such interests for\ncommercial use of structures on state-ow...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section provided timely application pursuant to\nthat subdivision has been made: .2 (two-tenths) of one percent; second\nyear: .4 (four-tenths) of one percent; third-year: .6 (six-tenths) of\none percent; fourth year: .8 (eight-tenths) of one percent; fifth year,\nand thereafter: one percent; provided that all such percentages in this\nparagraph shall be that percentage of the net income derived from the\nstructure or structures on state-owned lands, excluding transactions\ninvolving sales or repair of boats, and sale of gasoline; and the dollar\nvaluation of the interest conveyed shall not be increased from year to\nyear during that five year period. The fee charged shall be discounted\nten percent for annual permits.\n  (iii) For leases, easements and conveyances of such interests for\nresidential use of non-exempt structures in existence and residential\nuse on the effective date of this paragraph, the annual fee shall not\nexceed the lesser of twenty dollars per slip or one hundred dollars.\n  (iv) Nothing in this paragraph shall preclude the commissioner of\ngeneral services from agreeing, upon the request of and negotiation with\nthe owner or user of adjacent upland, to such other conveyances or\nagreements consistent with this section providing for different periodic\npayments, or a more flexible payment structure, than the fee caps and\nfees, respectively, set forth for commercial and residential facilities\nherein. Moreover, notwithstanding the fee caps set in this section, the\ncommissioner may exceed those caps if required to cover the yearly pro\nrata share, over the term of the conveyance or interest, of the\nadministrative costs in connection with that conveyance or interest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of\nenvironmental conservation, the secretary of state, the office of parks,\nrecreation and historic preservation and other interested state agencies\nadministering state-owned lands underwater, shall promulgate pursuant to\narticle two of the state administrative procedure act such rules with\nrespect to grants, leases, easements and lesser interests for the use of\nstate-owned land underwater, and the cession of jurisdiction thereof, as\nin his or her judgment are reasonable and necessary to protect the\ninterests of the people in such lands underwater. Such regulations shall\ninclude without being limited to: the fees to be charged, consistent\nwith the provisions of this section, including mitigation of such fees\nin the event of economic hardship on existing commercial enterprises;\nfee limitations to administrative expenses for municipal uses which are\npublic, non-commercial and offer services free or for nominal fees, and\nfor uses undertaken and operated for public and non-commercial purposes\nby not-for-profit corporations characterized as charitable corporations\nas defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section one hundred two (Definitions) of\nthe not-for-profit corporation law, and for uses undertaken and operated\nfor public purposes by a corporation formed pursuant to the religious\ncorporation law or by a corporation formed pursuant to a special act of\nthis state and which has as its principal purpose a religious purpose;\nsuch further exemptions for projects as the commissioner determines do\nnot represent significant encroachments; limitations on grants,\nincluding conversion grants, with respect to underwater lands consistent\nwith the public purposes of this subdivision and limiting such grants to\nexceptional circumstances; and factors to be examined in considering an\napplication for a lease, easement or other interest. Those factors shall\ninclude without limitation the following:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the environmental impact\nof the project; (ii) the values for natural resource management,\nrecreational uses, and commercial uses of the pertinent underwater land;\n(iii) the size, character and effects of the project in relation to\nneighboring uses; (iv) the potential for interference with navigation,\npublic uses of the waterway and rights of other riparian owners;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\neffect of the project on the natural resource interests of the state in\nthe lands; (vi) the water-dependent nature of the use; (vii) and any\nadverse economic impact on existing commercial enterprises. The final\npromulgation of rules establishing fees or fee structures shall be\nsubject to the approval of the director of the budget.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>From one year after the effective date of the rules authorized\nby paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_75__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision and adopted pursuant to subdivision\nfive of section two hundred two of the state administrative procedure\nact, and thereafter, any person who violates any of the provisions of\nthis subdivision; or who fails to perform any duty imposed by this\nsubdivision; or who violates or fails to comply with any rule,\nregulation, determination or order of the commissioner promulgated\npursuant to this subdivision may be enjoined from continuing such\nviolation, and in any event shall be liable for a civil penalty of not\nmore than five hundred dollars for each such violation and an additional\ncivil penalty of not more than one hundred dollars for each day during\nwhich such violation continues; provided, however, that such penalties\nshall be imposed by the commissioner only after written notice and an\nopportunity to be heard are given to the owner, occupier or other person\nor entity having a legal or beneficial interest in a prohibited\nstructure or area of fill which notice shall be transmitted by certified\nmail, return receipt requested and which shall set forth the provisions\nof this section, a description of the prohibited structure or area of\nfill, the amount of the penalty, that the person must comply with the\nprovisions of this section within thirty days, and the specific date\nthirty days thereafter following which the person shall be subject to\nsuch penalty and after which further penalties shall accrue on a daily\nbasis.\n  (ii) If the commissioner of environmental conservation notifies the\ncommissioner of any failure to comply with conditions of a lease,\neasement or other interest, the commissioner shall investigate such\nsuspected violation. The commissioner, on his or her own initiative or\nat the request of the commissioner of environmental conservation, shall\nthereafter take enforcement action as described herein or request the\nattorney general to institute an action to enjoin such violation and to\nrecover any damages therefor...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>