<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-82"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-82"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="82"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-82/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-82/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-82/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pbl/section-82/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_82">
        <num>82</num>
        <heading>Notice of discovery; filing; fee; bounty to discoverer; royalty to state</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_82__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The name and address of the filer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The name of the owner of the land.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An accurate description together with a map made on tracing cloth\nwith india ink of the land against which the notice is filed, in form\nsufficient for the convenient location of the land, which land shall, so\nfar as practicable, be of equal length and width and shall comprise not\nmore than forty acres.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_82__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement subscribed by the filer and affirmed by him to be true\nunder the penalties of perjury that he has read or knows the provisions\nof this article and is familiar with the conditions to be by him\nperformed precedent to the acquisition, continuation and preservation of\nany rights flowing from his filing of such notice.\n  3. A fee of fifty dollars shall be paid to the secretary of state with\neach such notice.\n  4. The filer shall have the sole benefit of minerals extracted from a\nmine or deposit on state land on the payment to the state of such annual\nrental and such royalty as the commissioner shall deem reasonable and\nproper provided, however, that the minimum royalty shall not be less\nthan two per centum of the market value of all such minerals. The filer\nshall be exempted from paying a royalty to the people of the state on\nthe market value of all gold and silver extracted from a gold mine or a\nsilver mine on private lands for a term of five years under notices of\ndiscovery filed on or after April sixteen, nineteen hundred forty-five,\nto be computed from the date of filing of the notice of discovery; and\nafter the expiration of such term, the filer shall pay to the people of\nthe state a royalty of one per centum of the market value of such\nproducts.\n  A statement of all minerals extracted from the premises covered by\nnotice of discovery, together with the market value thereof, shall be\nmade within six months from the time such products shall first be\nextracted, and semi-annually thereafter, under oath, to the\ncommissioner, and payments of such royalty shall be made semi-annually\nto the commissioner at the time of making of such statement of minerals\nextracted. Such payments of royalty shall thereafter be transmitted to\nthe state department of taxation and finance by the commissioner. Any\nwilful falsehood in the contents of such statement made by the filer to\nthe commissioner shall work a forfeiture to the state of the value of\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>