<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10">
        <num>10</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of property by two or more religious corporations for a common parsonage</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 10. Acquisition of property by two or more religious corporations\nfor a common parsonage.  Two or more religious corporations may acquire\nsuch real property as may be necessary for use as a parsonage, and the\nright, title and interest of each corporation therein shall be in\nproportion to its contribution to the cost of such property. The\ntrustees of each corporation shall, from time to time, appoint one of\ntheir number to be a trustee of such common parsonage property, to hold\noffice during the pleasure of the appointing trustees or until his\nsuccessor be appointed. The trustees so appointed shall have the care\nand management of such property and may make such improvements thereupon\nas they deem necessary, and determine the proportion of the expense of\nthe maintenance thereof which each corporation shall bear. If at any\ntime either of such corporations acquires or desires to acquire for its\nown exclusive use as a parsonage other real property, it may, in\npursuance of the provisions of law, relating to the disposition of real\nproperty by religious corporations, sell and convey its interest in such\ncommon parsonage property to any one or more of the other corporations\nhaving an interest therein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>