<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="101"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_101">
        <num>101</num>
        <heading>Government of incorporated Ruthenian Greek Catholic churches</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 101. Government of incorporated Ruthenian Greek Catholic churches.\nThe bishop, or in case of vacancy in the office of the bishop, then the\nadministrator, the chancellor of the diocese to which any incorporated\nRuthenian Greek Catholic church belongs, together with the pastor of\nsaid church, shall by virtue of their office be trustees of such church;\ntwo laymen members of such incorporated church selected by such\nofficers, or by a majority of them, shall also be trustees of such\nincorporated church, and such officers, pastor and such laymen trustees\nshall together constitute the board of trustees thereof.  The two laymen\nsigning the certificate of incorporation of a Ruthenian Greek Catholic\nchurch shall be the two laymen trustees thereof during the first year of\nits corporate existence. The term of office of the two laymen trustees\nof an incorporated Ruthenian Greek Catholic church shall be one year.\nWhenever the office of any such layman trustee shall become vacant by\nexpiration of term of office or otherwise his successor shall be\nappointed from members of the church by such officers or a majority of\nthem. No act or proceeding of the trustees of any such incorporated\nchurch shall be valid without the sanction or approval in writing of the\nbishop of the diocese to which said church belongs, or, in case of his\nabsence or disability to act, of his vicar-general or of the\nadministrator of such diocese.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>