<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="107"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_107">
        <num>107</num>
        <heading>Government of incorporated churches of Orthodox Church in America; powers and duties of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 107. Government of incorporated churches of Orthodox Church in\nAmerica; powers and duties of trustees. 1. Every American Orthodox\nchurch in this state, whether incorporated before or after the said\nproclamation of autocephaly, and whether incorporated or reincorporated\npursuant to this article or any other article of the religious\ncorporations law, or any general or private law, shall recognize and be\nand remain subject to the jurisdiction and authority of the general\ncouncil, metropolitan archbishop or other primate or hierarch, the\ncouncil of bishops, the executive council and other governing bodies and\nauthorities of the Orthodox Church in America, pursuant to the statute\nfor the government thereof, and any amendments thereto and any other\nstatutes or rules adopted by a general council of the Orthodox Church in\nAmerica and shall in all other respects conform to, maintain and follow\nthe faith, doctrine, ritual, communion, discipline, canon law,\ntraditions and usages of the Eastern Confession (Eastern Orthodox or\nGreek Catholic Church); provided, however, that the provisions of this\nsection shall not be applicable to any church incorporated in this state\nwhich was excluded from the autocephaly of the Orthodox Church in\nAmerica by said proclamation of autocephaly, namely, St. Nicholas\nCathedral of the Russian Orthodox Church in North America and St. Mark\nChapel, both of the County of New York, City of New York, St. John the\nBaptist Chapel, County of Bronx, City of New York, Church of St. George\nthe Great Martyr, County of Queens, City of New York, Church of All\nSaints Glorified in the Russian Land, Village of Pine Bush, County of\nOrange, House Chapel of St. Seraphim of Sarov, Village of Westtown,\nCounty of Orange, and Church of St. George the Great Martyr, City of\nBuffalo, County of Erie, unless any such church shall reincorporate\npursuant to this article and the certificate therefor shall set forth,\nin addition to the other statements required to be set forth therein,\nthat the corporation is being reincorporated pursuant to this article\nwith the permission of the governing authority of the Russian Orthodox\nChurch.\n  2. The six lay members of every church incorporated pursuant to this\narticle signing the certificate of incorporation and the rector shall be\nthe trustees of such church for the first year or until their successors\nare selected according to the by-laws of such church or the rules and\nusages of the Orthodox Church in America.\n  3. The trustees of every American Orthodox church shall have the\ncustody and control of all temporalities and property, real and\npersonal, belonging to such church and of the revenues therefrom and\nshall administer the same in accordance with the by-laws of such\nchurch,, and any amendments thereto and all other rules, statutes,\nregulations and usages of the Orthodox Church in America.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>