<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="108"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_108">
        <num>108</num>
        <heading>Reincorporation of existing corporations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 108. Reincorporation of existing corporations. Any heretofore\nincorporated American Orthodox church may reincorporate under the\nprovisions of this article, by filing in the office of the county clerk\nin the county in which its principal place of worship is located, a\ncertificate, signed by the trustees in office at the time of such\nreincorporation, or by the majority of them, setting forth that they\ndesire to reincorporate under the provisions of this article, the\ncorporate name by which such church shall be known, the county, town,\ncity or village where its principal place of worship is located and the\nnumber and the names of the trustees who are to hold office until the\nnext annual meeting of said church. Immediately upon the filing of such\ncertificate all the right, title, equity and interest of such church in\nany estate, real or personal, together with all franchise and charter\nrights, shall be vested in the body corporate and politic so created\nunder this article and the original incorporation of such church shall\nbe null and void.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>