<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="110"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_110">
        <num>110</num>
        <heading>Decision by a Reformed Dutch or Reformed Presbyterian church as to system of incorporation and government</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 110. Decision by a Reformed Dutch or Reformed Presbyterian church as\nto system of incorporation and government. The minister or ministers, if\nthere be any, and the elders and deacons of an unincorporated church in\nconnection with the Reformed church in America, the true Reformed Dutch\nchurch in the United States of America, or with the Reformed\nPresbyterian church, may determine to incorporate such church in\npursuance of this article, or to call a meeting of such unincorporated\nchurch for the purpose of deciding whether such church shall be\nincorporated in pursuance of article ten of this chapter, entitled\n"Special provisions for the incorporation and government of churches of\nother denominations."\n  If such ministers, elders and deacons determine to call such meeting\nfor such purpose, then such church may be incorporated and shall be\ngoverned after its incorporation in pursuance of the provisions of\narticle ten of this chapter, except such provisions thereof as are\napplicable to churches of a single denomination only, and except that\nthe notice of the meeting for incorporation shall be signed by such\nministers, elders and deacons or a majority of them, and no other\nsignatures thereto shall be necessary to its validity; and, if it be a\nReformed church in America, it shall, after incorporation, be governed\nby such of the provisions of this article as relates to its consistory\nand to the choice of its minister.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>