<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-112"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-112"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="112"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_112">
        <num>112</num>
        <heading>Incorporation of Reformed Dutch, Reformed Presbyterian and Evangelical Lutheran churches under this article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 112. Incorporation of Reformed Dutch, Reformed Presbyterian and\nEvangelical Lutheran churches under this article. If any unincorporated\nchurch in connection with the Reformed church in America, the true\nReformed Dutch church in the United States of America, the Reformed\nPresbyterian church, or with the Evangelical Lutheran church, determine\nto incorporate in pursuance of this article, the minister or ministers\nand the elders and deacons thereof shall execute, acknowledge and cause\nto be filed and recorded, a certificate in pursuance of this article.\nThe deacons of a Reformed Presbyterian church may alone sign such\ncertificate if authorized so to do by such church. Such certificate of\nincorporation shall state the name of the proposed corporation, the\ncounty and town, city or village where its principal place of worship is\nor is intended to be located, and, if it be an Evangelical Lutheran\nchurch, the fact that a meeting of such church duly called decided that\nit be incorporated under this article.  If it be signed by the deacons\nof a Reformed Presbyterian church, it shall state that they were\nauthorized so to do by such church. On filing such certificate such\nchurch shall be a corporation by the name stated therein, and the\nminister or ministers, if any, and the elders and deacons of such church\nshall by virtue of their offices be the trustees of such corporation,\nexcept that if it be a Reformed Presbyterian church, the certificate of\nincorporation of which shall have been, in pursuance of law, signed by\nits deacons only, the deacons of such church shall, by virtue of their\noffices, be the trustees of such corporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>