<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-116"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-116"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="116"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_116">
        <num>116</num>
        <heading>Evangelical Lutheran church, changing system of electing trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 116. Evangelical Lutheran church, changing system of electing\ntrustees. If the trustees of an incorporated Evangelical Lutheran church\nshall at any time be elective in pursuance of article ten of this\nchapter, the church may, at an annual corporate meeting, if notice\nthereof be given with the notice of such meeting determine that the\nminister or ministers and elders and deacons thereof shall thereafter\nconstitute the trustees thereof, and thereon the trustees of such church\nshall sign, acknowledge and cause to be filed and recorded, a\ncertificate stating the fact of such determination, and the name of the\nminister or ministers, if any, and of the elders and deacons of such\nchurch; and thereon the terms of office of such elective trustees shall\ncease, and the minister or ministers and the elders and deacons of such\nchurch, and their successors in office shall, by virtue of their\nrespective offices, be the trustees of such church. If, at any time, the\nofficers of an incorporated Evangelical Lutheran church which officers\nby virtue of their offices constitute the trustees thereof shall\ndetermine to submit to a meeting of such church corporation, the\nquestion whether the trustees of such church shall be thereafter\nelective in pursuance of article ten of this chapter, they shall cause a\ncorporate meeting of such church to be called and held in the manner\nprovided in sections one hundred and ninety-four and one hundred and\nninety-five of this chapter, and such corporate meeting shall determine\nwhether the trustees of such church shall thereafter be elective in\npursuance of article ten of this chapter, and also whether the number of\nsuch trustees shall be three, six or nine, and the date of the annual\ncorporate meeting of the church. If such meeting shall determine that\nsuch trustees shall thereafter be elective, the presiding officer\nthereof and at least two other persons present and voting thereat, shall\nsign, acknowledge and cause to be filed and recorded in the office of\nthe clerk of the county in which the certificate of incorporation of\nsuch church is filed, a certificate of such determination of such\nmeeting; and thereafter the trustees of such church shall be elective in\npursuance of article ten of this chapter. At the next annual corporate\nmeeting after the filing of such certificate, one-third of the number of\ntrustees so determined on shall be elected to hold office for one year,\none-third for two years, and one-third for three years, and the officers\nof such church who by virtue of their offices have been trustees of such\nchurch, shall then cease to be such trustees, and thereafter article ten\nof this chapter shall apply to such church. At each subsequent annual\ncorporate meeting of such church, one-third of the number of trustees so\ndetermined on shall be elected to hold office for three years.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>