<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-133"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-133"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="133"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_133">
        <num>133</num>
        <heading>Time, place and notice of corporate meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 133. Time, place and notice of corporate meetings.  The annual\ncorporate meeting of every incorporated Baptist church shall be held at\nthe time and place fixed by or in pursuance of law therefor, if such\ntime and place be so fixed, and otherwise, at a time and place to be\nfixed by its trustees. A special corporate meeting of any such church\nmay be called by the board of trustees thereof, on its own motion, and\nshall be called on the written request of at least ten qualified voters\nof such church. The trustees shall cause notice of the time and place of\nits annual corporate meeting, and of the names of any trustees whose\nsuccessors are to be elected thereat; and, if a special meeting, of the\nbusiness to be transacted thereat, to be publicly read by the minister\nof such church or any trustee thereof at a regular meeting of the church\nfor public worship, on the two successive Sundays immediately preceding\nsuch meeting; or if no such meeting for public worship shall have been\nheld during such period, by conspicuously posting such notice, in\nwriting, upon the outer entrance of the principal place of worship of\nsuch church and by mailing a copy of such notice to each member of such\nchurch in a securely sealed envelope, postage prepaid, addressed to his\nlast known place of residence, at least two weeks before such meeting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>