<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-134"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-134"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="134"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-134/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-134/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-134/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-134/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_134">
        <num>134</num>
        <heading>Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications of voters thereat</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 134. Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications\nof voters thereat.  At a corporate meeting of an incorporated Baptist\nchurch the qualified voters shall be all persons who are then members of\nsuch church in good and regular standing by admission into full\ncommunion or membership therewith, or who have statedly worshipped with\nsuch church and have regularly contributed to the financial support\nthereof during the year next preceding such meeting; but any\nincorporated Baptist church may at any annual corporate meeting thereof,\nif notice of the intention so to do has been given with the notice of\nsuch meeting, decide that thereafter only members of such church in good\nand regular standing by admission into full communion or membership\ntherewith shall be qualified voters at the corporate meetings. At such\ncorporate meetings the presence of at least six persons qualified to\nvote thereat shall be necessary to constitute a quorum, and all matters\nor questions shall be decided by a majority of the qualified voters\nvoting thereon. There shall be elected at said meeting from the\nqualified voters then present, a presiding officer, a clerk to keep the\nrecords of the proceedings of the meeting and two inspectors of election\nto receive the ballots cast.  The presiding officer and the inspectors\nof election shall declare the result of the ballots cast on any matter\nand shall be the judge of the qualifications of voters. At each annual\ncorporate meeting, successors to those trustees whose terms of office\nthen expire, shall be elected by ballot from the qualified voters, for a\nterm of three years thereafter, and until their successors shall be\nelected.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>