<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-136"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-136"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="136"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-136/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-136/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-136/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-136/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_136">
        <num>136</num>
        <heading>Changing number of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 136. Changing number of trustees.  An incorporated Baptist church\nmay, at an annual corporate meeting, change the number of its trustees\nto not less than three, nor more than eighteen, or classify them so that\nthe terms of one-third expire each year, provided that notice of such\nintended change or classification be included in the notice of such\nannual corporate meeting. No such change shall affect the terms of the\ntrustees then in office, and if the change reduces the number of\ntrustees, elections shall not be held to fill vacancies caused by the\nexpiration of the terms of trustees until the number of trustees equals\nthe number to which the trustees were reduced. Whenever the number of\ntrustees in office is less than the number so determined on, sufficient\nadditional trustees shall be elected to make the number of trustees\nequal to the number so determined on. The trustees so elected up to and\nincluding one-third of the number so determined on, shall be elected for\nthree years, the remainder up to and including one-third of the number\nso determined on for two years, and the remainder for one year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>