<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15">
        <num>15</num>
        <heading>Corporations with governing authority over, or advisory relations with, churches or synods, or both</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the jurisdiction of the Orthodox Oecumenical Patriarchate of\nConstantinople exercised in the Americas and all the territorial\npossessions and/or dependencies or protectorates of the United States of\nAmerica, by its duly authorized exarch, metropolitan, archbishop or\nbishop,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the jurisdiction of the apostolic Orthodox Patriarchate of\nAntioch, exercised in the Americas and all the territorial possessions\nand/or dependencies or protectorates of the United States of America, by\nits duly authorized exarch, metropolitan, archbishop or bishop,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the jurisdiction of the Patriarchate of Moscow exercised in the\nAmericas and all the territorial possessions and/or dependencies or\nprotectorates of the United States of America, by its duly authorized\nexarch, metropolitan, archbishop or bishop,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the jurisdiction of the Patriarchate of Serbia (Jugoslavia)\nexercised in the Americas and all the territorial possessions and/or\ndependencies or protectorates of the United States of America, by its\nduly authorized exarch, metropolitan, archbishop or bishop.\n  All other Orthodox Greek Catholic jurisdictions, bishoprics, dioceses\nand missions, officially and canonically in communion with and\nacknowledged by all four of said primary jurisdictions, if certified by\nthe secretariat thereof as affiliated with the Federated Orthodox Greek\nCatholic Primary Jurisdictions in America, may incorporate or\nre-incorporate under this section as affiliates thereof.\n  4. The trustees of every incorporated governing body of the four\nprimary jurisdictions, respectively, specified in subdivision three of\nthis section, or of any of the affiliates of said jurisdictions, shall\nconsist of the hierarch or ecclesiastical administrator, who shall be\nex-officio president of the corporation, the chancellor of the\narchdiocese, the dean of the archdiocesan theological faculty or one of\nthe members thereof, and the secretary of the archdiocese, who are to be\nappointed by said hierarch and to serve at his pleasure and, in\naddition, not less than three nor more than nine other persons,\ncommunicants of the Orthodox Church, to be elected by said governing\nbody or by the diocesan convention; the term of such elective first\ntrustees shall be one-third for one year, one-third for two years, and\none-third for three years, respectively, and the term of office of their\nsuccessors shall be three years.\n  5. The trustees of every incorporated governing body of the\nEvangelical Lutheran Church in America shall consist of not less than\nthree nor more than thirty persons. If the constitution or by-laws of\nsuch governing body so provides, the Bishop or president,\nvice-president, treasurer and secretary of such governing body shall be\nex-officio trustees of such governing body. The re...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>