<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-164"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-164"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="164"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-164/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-164/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-164/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-164/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_164">
        <num>164</num>
        <heading>Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications of voters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 164. Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications\nof voters.  At every corporate meeting of a church to which this article\nis applicable the following persons, and no others shall be qualified\nvoters, to wit:  all persons who are then members in good and regular\nstanding of such church by admission into full communion or membership\ntherewith in accordance with the by-laws thereof, provided that if the\nby-laws so provide, persons who have statedly worshiped with such church\nand have regularly contributed to its financial support for not less\nthan one year preceding such meeting shall also be qualified voters.\n  At such corporate meetings, the presence of at least six persons\nqualified to vote thereat shall be necessary to constitute a quorum; and\nall matters or questions shall be decided by a majority of the qualified\nvoters voting thereon, except that by-laws can be adopted or amended\nonly by a two-thirds vote. The clerk of the corporation shall call the\nmeeting to order; and under his supervision the qualified voters then\npresent shall choose a presiding officer and two inspectors of election\nto receive the ballots cast. The presiding officer and the inspectors of\nelection shall declare the result of the ballots cast on any matter and\nshall be the judges of the qualifications of voters.  At each annual\ncorporate meeting, successors to those trustees whose terms of office\nthen expire shall be elected by ballot from the qualified voters, for a\nterm of three years thereafter, and until their successors shall be\nelected. A clerk of the corporation shall be elected by ballot, who\nshall hold office until the closing of the next annual meeting, and\nuntil his successor shall be elected.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>