<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-166"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-166"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="166"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-166/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-166/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-166/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-166/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_166">
        <num>166</num>
        <heading>Changing number of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 166. Changing number of trustees.  Any such incorporated church may,\nat an annual corporate meeting, change the number of its trustees to\nthree, six, nine, twelve or fifteen, classifying them so that the terms\nof one-third expire each year, provided that notice of such intended\nchange be included in the notice of such annual corporate meeting. No\nsuch change shall affect the terms of the trustees then in office; and\nif the change reduces the number of trustees, elections shall not be\nheld to fill the vacancies caused by the expiration of the terms of\ntrustees, until the number of trustees equals the number to which the\ntrustees were reduced.  Whenever the number of trustees in office is\nless than the number so determined on, sufficient additional trustees\nshall be elected to make the number of trustees equal to the number so\ndetermined on. The trustees so elected, up to and including one-third of\nthe number so determined on, shall be elected for three years, the\nremainder up to and including one-third of the number so determined on\nfor two years, and the remainder for one year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>