<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_B">
        <num>17-B</num>
        <heading>Property of extinct Presbyterian churches in connection with the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church (U</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 17-b. Property of extinct Presbyterian churches in connection with\nthe General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.). Whenever the\npresbytery having jurisdiction over a particular church in connection\nwith the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.) dissolves\nor declares extinct the particular church, upon petition by the\npresbytery to the supreme or county court and upon satisfactory proof of\nthe facts leading to said dissolution, the court shall have jurisdiction\nto grant an order to the effect that all property of whatever kind which\nmay have belonged to, or have been held by, said church shall vest in\nthe presbytery of jurisdiction in as full and ample a manner as the same\nshall theretofore have been vested in the church so declared to be\ndissolved and extinct. The stated clerk of the presbytery of\njurisdiction shall record in the office of the county clerk, in which\nthe church is located, a certified copy of the resolution of the\npresbytery declaring such church extinct and the court order\ntransferring the title of the church property; and the recording of such\na resolution and court order shall be proof of the vesting of the title\nof the real property of such church in the presbytery of jurisdiction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>