<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-17-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_C">
        <num>17-C</num>
        <heading>Property of Lutheran congregations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nThe relationship between a congregation of the Evangelical Lutheran\nchurch in America and the church may be terminated in one of the\nfollowing ways:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The congregation takes action to dissolve;\n  (ii) The congregation ceases to exist;\n  (iii) The membership of the congregation becomes so scattered or\ndiminished in numbers as to make it impracticable for such congregation\nto fulfill the purposes for which it was organized. In such case, the\nsynod in order to protect the property from waste and deterioration,\nthrough the synod council or trustees appointed by it, may take charge\nand control of the property of the congregation to hold, manage, and\nconvey the same on behalf of the synod. The congregation shall have the\nright to appeal the decision to the synod assembly;\n  (iv) The congregation is no longer recognized by the church under the\ndisciplinary provisions of the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America;\nor\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The congregation terminates its relationship according to the\nprocedure outlined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A congregation may terminate its relationship with the church by\nthe following procedure:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A resolution indicating desire to terminate its relationship must\nbe adopted at a legally called and conducted special meeting of the\ncongregation by a two-thirds majority of the voting members present;\n  (ii) The secretary of the congregation shall submit a copy of the\nresolution to the synodical bishop and shall mail a copy of the\nresolution to voting members of the congregation.  This notice shall be\nsubmitted within ten days after the resolution has been adopted;\n  (iii) The bishop of the synod shall consult with the congregation\nduring a period of at least ninety days;\n  (iv) If the congregation, after consultation, still desires to\nterminate its relationship, such action may be taken at a legally called\nand conducted special meeting of the congregation by a two-thirds\nmajority of the voting members present, at which meeting the synodical\nbishop or an authorized representative shall be present.  Notice of the\nmeeting shall be mailed to all voting members at least ten days in\nadvance of the meeting;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A certified copy of the resolution to terminate its relationship\nshall be sent to the synodical bishop, at which time the relationship\nbetween the congregation and this church shall be terminated;\n  (vi) Notice of termination shall be forwarded by the synodical bishop\nto the secretary of the church and published in the periodical of the\nchurch; and\n  (vii) Congregations which had been members of the Lutheran Church in\nAmerica shall be required, in addition to the foregoing provisions, to\nreceive synodical approval before terminating their membership in the\nchurch.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the provisions of the governing documents of\ncongregations recognized at the establishment of the Evangelical\nLutheran Church in America, the following shall govern the ownership of\nproperty by congregations of the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Title to property shall reside in the congregation.  The\ncongregation may dispose of its property as it determines, subject to\nany self-accepted indebtedness or other self-accepted restrictions;\n  (ii) Title to the undisposed property of a congregation that ceases to\nexist by virtue of subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, (ii) or (iii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, shall pass to the synod of this church to which the\ncongregation is related;\n  (iii) Title to the property of a congregation that is no longer\nrecognized by this church as a result of discipline shall continue to\nreside in the congregation;\n  (iv) Title to the property of a congregation that has acted to\nterminate its relationship with this church by the provisions of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision and to relate to another Lutheran\nchurch body shall continue to reside in the congregation; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Title to the property of a congregation that has acted to\nterminate its relationship with this church by the provisions of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision and to become independent or to relate\nto a non-Lutheran church body shall continue to reside in the\ncongregation only with the consent of the Synod Council. The Synod\nCouncil, after consultation with the congregation by an established\nsynodical process, may give approval to the request to become\nindependent or to relate to a non-Lutheran church body, in which case\ntitle shall remain with the majority of the congregation. If the Synod\nCouncil fails to give such approval, title shall remain with those\nmembers who desire to continue as a congregation of this church.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>