<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-176"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-176"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="176"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_176">
        <num>176</num>
        <heading>Notice of meeting for incorporation and provisions governing meetings for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 176. Notice of meeting for incorporation and provisions governing\nmeetings for incorporation. 1. Notice of a meeting for the purpose of\nincorporating an unincorporated Ukrainian Orthodox church under this\narticle shall be in writing and shall state in substance that a meeting\nof such unincorporated church will be held at its usual place of worship\nat a specified day and hour, for the purpose of incorporating such a\nchurch and selecting a name therefor and electing trustees thereof.\n  2. Such notice shall be publicly read at a regular service of such\nunincorporated church on a Sunday next preceding such meeting and a copy\nof such notice shall be sent by mail postpaid at least ten days prior to\nthe date fixed for such meeting to each member of such church in good\nand regular standing at his last known address as same appears in the\nchurch record.\n  3. At the meeting for incorporation held in pursuance of such notice,\nall persons of full age, who are then members in good and regular\nstanding of such church, shall be qualified voters. All the duly\nqualified voters present at such meeting, at least six in number, shall\nconstitute a quorum, and all matters or questions shall be decided by a\nmajority of the qualified voters voting thereon.\n  4. There shall be elected at such meeting from the qualified voters\nthen present a presiding officer and a clerk to keep the records of the\nproceedings of the meeting. The presiding officer shall decide the\nresults of the votes cast on any matter and shall be the judge of the\nqualifications of the voters.\n  5. If the meeting shall decide that such unincorporated church shall\nbecome incorporated, the meeting shall also decide upon the name of the\nproposed corporation, the number of trustees thereof which shall be\neither three, five or seven, and the date, not more than fifteen months\nthereafter, on which the first annual election of the trustees shall be\nheld.\n  6. Such meeting shall thereupon elect from the persons qualified to\nvote thereat the trustees who shall hold office until the first annual\nelection of the trustees thereafter, or until their successors are\nelected and take office.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>