<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-179"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-179"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="179"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_179">
        <num>179</num>
        <heading>Reincorporation of existing corporations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 179. Reincorporation of existing corporations. Any Ukrainian\nOrthodox church heretofore incorporated, other than those incorporated\nunder the provisions of article five of the religious corporations law,\nmay reincorporate under the provisions of this article, by filing in the\ncounty clerk's office in the county in which its principal place of\nworship is located, a certificate, signed by the trustees in office at\nthe time of such reincorporation, or by the majority of them, setting\nforth that they desire to reincorporate under the provisions of this\narticle, the corporate name by which such church shall be known, the\ncounty, town, city or village where its place of worship is or is\nintended to be located, and the number and the names of the trustees who\nare to hold office until the next annual meeting of said corporation. If\nthe bishop or archbishop having ecclesiastical jurisdiction over such\nchurch is not one of the trustees signing the certificate of\nreincorporation, such certificate shall not be valid until said bishop\nor archbishop has given his assent in writing to such reincorporation\nand the same is made a part of the certificate. Immediately upon the\nfiling of such certificate all the right, title and interest of such\norganization or corporation in any estate, real or personal, shall, with\nall franchise and charter rights, be vested in said body corporate and\npolitic so created under this article and the original incorporation of\nsuch organization shall be null and void.\n  The incorporation of a new church or reincorporation of an old church\nunder this article shall not be valid until the same has been approved\nby a justice of the supreme court.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>