<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-185"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-185"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="185"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-185/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-185/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-185/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-185/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_185">
        <num>185</num>
        <heading>Notice of meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 185. Notice of meeting for incorporation. Notice of a meeting for\nthe purpose of incorporating an unincorporated Church of Christ,\nScientist or Christian Science Society, shall be given as follows: The\nnotice shall be in writing, and shall state, in substance, that a\nmeeting of such unincorporated church or society will be held at its\nusual place of worship at a specified day and hour, for the purpose of\nincorporating such church or society, electing trustees thereof, and\nselecting a corporate name therefor.\n  The notice must be signed by at least six persons of full age who are\nthen members in good and regular standing of such church or society by\nadmission into full membership therewith, in accordance with the rules\nand regulations of such church or society. A copy of such notice shall\nbe publicly read at each regular service of such unincorporated church\nor society on the two successive Sundays next preceding such meeting by\nthe person acting as first reader, and a copy of such notice shall be\nsent by mail post paid at least ten days prior to the date fixed for\nsuch meeting to each member of such church or society in good and\nregular standing at his last known address as same appears in the church\nor society records.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>