<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-186"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-186"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="186"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-186/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-186/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-186/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-186/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_186">
        <num>186</num>
        <heading>Meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 186. Meeting for incorporation. At the meeting for incorporation\nheld in pursuance of such notice, the following persons, and no others,\nshall be qualified voters, to wit: All persons of full age, who are then\nmembers in good and regular standing of such church or society by\nadmission into full membership therewith, in accordance with the rules\nand regulations thereof.\n  At such meeting, the presence of a majority of such qualified voters,\nat least six in number, shall be necessary to constitute a quorum.  The\naction of the meeting upon any matter or question shall be decided by a\nmajority of the qualified voters voting thereon, a quorum being present.\nThe meeting shall be called to order by one of the signers of the call.\nThere shall be elected at such meeting, from the qualified voters then\npresent, a presiding officer, a clerk to keep the record of the\nproceedings, of the meeting and two inspectors of election to receive\nthe ballots cast. The presiding officer of the meeting and the\ninspectors shall decide the results of the ballots cast on any matter,\nand shall be the judges of the qualifications of voters.\n  Such meeting shall decide whether such unincorporated church or\nsociety shall become incorporated. If such decision shall be in favor of\nincorporation such meeting shall decide upon the name of the proposed\ncorporation which shall be "Church of Christ, Scientist," prefixed by\n"First," "Second," "Third" or other numerical designation, or "Christian\nScience Society" as the case may be, and followed by the name of the\nplace where it shall be located; the meeting also shall decide the\nnumber of the trustees of such church or society, which shall be any\nnumber from three to twelve, and shall determine the date, not more than\nfifteen months thereafter, on which the first annual election of the\ntrustees thereof after such meeting shall be held. Such meeting shall\nthereupon elect by ballot, from the persons qualified to vote thereat,\none-third of the number of trustees as nearly as possible so decided\nupon who shall hold office until the first annual election of trustees\nthereafter, one-third of such number of trustees as nearly as possible\nwho shall hold office until the second annual election of trustees\nthereafter, and the remainder of such trustees who shall hold office\nuntil the third annual election of trustees thereafter, or until the\nrespective successors of such trustees shall be elected and take office.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>