<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-188"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-188"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="188"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-188/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-188/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-188/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-188/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_188">
        <num>188</num>
        <heading>Time, place and notice of corporate meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 188. Time, place and notice of corporate meetings. The annual\ncorporate meeting of every incorporated church or society to which this\narticle is applicable shall be held at the time and place fixed by its\nby-laws. A special corporate meeting of any such church or society may\nbe called by the board of trustees thereof, on its own motion, and shall\nbe called on the written request of at least ten qualified voters of\nsuch church or society. The trustees shall cause written notice of the\ntime and place of any corporate meeting, therein specifying, if an\nannual meeting, the names of any trustees whose successors are to be\nelected thereat, and, if a special meeting, specifying the business to\nbe transacted thereat, to be served, either personally or by mail, upon\neach qualified voter of the church or society entitled to vote at the\nmeeting, not less than ten nor more than forty days before the meeting.\nIf mailed, the notice shall be directed to each qualified voter entitled\nto notice at his address as it appears on the books or records of the\nchurch or society.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>