<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="189-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_189_B">
        <num>189-B</num>
        <heading>Changing number of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 189-b. Changing number of trustees. Any incorporated church or\nsociety to which this article is applicable may, at an annual corporate\nmeeting, change the number of its trustees to any number from three to\ntwelve and classify them so that the terms of one-third as nearly as\npossible expire each year, provided that notice of such intended change\nbe included in the notice of such annual corporate meeting. No such\nchange shall affect the terms of the trustees then in office, and if the\nchange reduces the number of trustees, election shall not be held to\nfill the vacancies caused by the expiration of the terms of trustees,\nuntil the number of trustees equals the number to which the trustees\nwere reduced. Whenever the number of trustees in office is less than the\nnumber so determined on, sufficient additional trustees shall be elected\nto make the number of trustees for the ensuing year equal to the number\nso determined on. The trustees so elected up to and including as nearly\nas possible one-third of the number so determined on, shall be elected\nfor three years, the remainder up to and including as nearly as possible\none-third of the number so determined on for two years and the remainder\nfor one year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>