<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="189"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-189/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_189">
        <num>189</num>
        <heading>Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications of voters thereat</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 189. Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications\nof voters thereat. At a corporate meeting of every incorporated church\nor society to which this article is applicable, the following persons,\nand no others, shall be qualified voters, to wit: All persons who are\nthen members in good and regular standing of such church or society by\nadmission into full membership therewith. The presence at such meetings\nof at least six persons qualified to vote thereat shall be necessary to\nconstitute a quorum, provided that any church or society to which this\narticle is applicable may by its by-laws fix the number of members\nnecessary to constitute a quorum. The action of the meeting upon any\nmatter or question shall be decided by a majority of the qualified\nvoters voting thereon, a quorum being present, except that by-laws may\nprovide specifically for action being taken upon any matter or question\nby more than a majority vote, in which event such by-law provisions\nshall govern any such action; and further excepted that by-laws can be\nadopted or amended only by a two-thirds vote, as hereinbefore provided\nby this chapter. The clerk of the church or society shall call the\nmeeting to order, and then turn it over to a presiding officer chosen by\nthe qualified voters then present or to the one designated under the\nprovisions of the by-laws; and if an election is to be held at such\nmeeting, two inspectors of election shall be chosen by the qualified\nvoters then present, unless otherwise designated under the provisions of\nthe by-laws. The presiding officer and the inspectors of election shall\nreceive the votes, shall be the judges of the qualifications of voters\nand shall decide the result of the votes cast at any election. The polls\nof an annual corporate meeting shall remain open for such time as may be\ndetermined by a majority of the qualified voters present. At each annual\ncorporate meeting successors to those trustees whose terms of office\nthen expire, shall be elected from the qualified voters by ballot, for a\nterm of three years thereafter, and until their successors shall be\nelected and take office.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>