<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-190"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-190"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="190"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-190/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-190/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-190/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-190/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_190">
        <num>190</num>
        <heading>Application of this article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 190. Application of this article.  This article is not applicable to\na Baptist church, a Congregational Christian church, whether or not a\npart of the United Church of Christ, a church of the United Church of\nChrist incorporated after September first, nineteen hundred seventy-one,\nan Independent church, a United Methodist church, a Protestant Episcopal\nchurch, a Roman Catholic church, a Presbyterian church in connection\nwith the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church in the United\nStates of America, a Christian Orthodox Catholic church of the Eastern\nConfession, a Ruthenian Greek Catholic church, or a Church of Christ,\nScientist. No provision of this article is applicable to a reformed\nchurch in America, a True Reformed Dutch church in the United States of\nAmerica, a Reformed Presbyterian church, or to an Evangelical Lutheran\nchurch, incorporated after October first, eighteen hundred and\nninety-five, except as declared to be so applicable by article six of\nthis chapter; this article is applicable to an Evangelical Lutheran\nchurch incorporated before October first, eighteen hundred ninety-five,\nif the trustees thereof were then elective as such and so long as they\ncontinue to be elective as such. Article six of this chapter is\napplicable to an Evangelical Lutheran church incorporated before October\nfirst, eighteen hundred and ninety-five, if its trustees were not then\nelective as such and so long as its trustees continue not to be elective\nas such. This article is applicable to churches of all other\ndenominations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>