<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-191"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-191"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="191"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-191/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-191/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-191/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-191/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_191">
        <num>191</num>
        <heading>Notice of meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 191. Notice of meeting for incorporation.  Notice of a meeting for\nthe purpose of incorporating an unincorporated church, to which this\narticle is applicable, shall be given as follows:\n  The notice shall be in writing, and shall state, in substance, that a\nmeeting of such unincorporated church will be held at its usual place of\nworship at a specified day and hour, for the purpose of incorporating\nsuch church and electing trustees thereof.\n  The notice must be signed by at least six persons of full age, who are\nthen members in good and regular standing of such church by admission\ninto full communion or membership therewith, in accordance with the\nrules and regulations of such church, and of the governing\necclesiastical body of the denomination or order, if any, to which the\nchurch belongs, or who have statedly worshiped with such church and have\nregularly contributed to the financial support thereof during the year\nnext prior thereto, or from the time of the formation thereof.\n  A copy of such notice shall be posted conspicuously on the outside of\nthe main entrance to such place of worship, at least fifteen days before\nthe day so specified for such meeting, and shall be publicly read at\neach of the two next preceding regular meetings of such unincorporated\nchurch for public worship, at least one week apart, at morning service,\nif such service be held, on Sunday, if Sunday be the day for such\nregular meetings, by the first named of the following persons who is\npresent thereat, to wit: The minister of such church, the officiating\nminister thereof, the elders thereof in the order of their age beginning\nwith the oldest, the deacons of the church in the order of their age\nbeginning with the oldest, any person qualified to sign such notice.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>