<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-192"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-192"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="192"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-192/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-192/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-192/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-192/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_192">
        <num>192</num>
        <heading>The meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 192. The meeting for incorporation.  At the meeting for\nincorporation held in pursuance of such notice, the following persons,\nand no others, shall be qualified voters, to wit: All persons of full\nage, who are then members in good and regular standing of such church by\nadmission into full communion or membership therewith, in accordance\nwith the rules and regulations thereof, and of the governing\necclesiastical body, if any, of the denomination or order, to which the\nchurch belongs, or who have statedly worshiped with such church and have\nregularly contributed to the financial support thereof during the year\nnext preceding such meeting, or from the time of the formation thereof.\n  The presence of a majority of such qualified voters, at least six in\nnumber, shall be necessary to constitute a quorum of such meeting.  The\naction of the meeting upon any matter or question shall be decided by a\nmajority of the qualified voters voting thereon, a quorum being present.\n  The first named of the following persons who is present at such\nmeeting shall preside thereat, to wit: The minister of the church, the\nofficiating minister thereof, the elders thereof in the order of their\nage, beginning with the oldest, the deacons thereof in the order of\ntheir age, beginning with the oldest, any qualified voter elected to\npreside. The presiding officer of the meeting shall receive the votes,\nbe the judge of the qualifications of voters and declare the result of\nthe votes cast on any matter. The polls of the meeting shall remain open\nfor one hour, and longer, in the discretion of the presiding officer, or\nif required by a majority of the voters present.\n  Such meeting shall decide whether such unincorporated church shall\nbecome incorporated. If such decision shall be in favor of incorporation\nsuch meeting shall decide upon the name of the proposed corporation, the\nnumber of the trustees thereof, which shall be three, six or nine, and\nshall determine the date, not more than fifteen months thereafter, on\nwhich the first annual election of the trustees thereof after such\nmeeting shall be held. Such meeting shall elect from the persons\nqualified to vote at such meeting, one-third of the number of trustees\nso decided on who shall hold office until the first annual election of\ntrustees thereafter, one-third of such number of trustees to hold office\nuntil the second annual election of trustees thereafter, and one-third\nof such number of trustees to hold office until the third annual\nelection of trustees thereafter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>