<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-194"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-194"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="194"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-194/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-194/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-194/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-194/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_194">
        <num>194</num>
        <heading>Time, place and notice of corporate meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 194. Time, place and notice of corporate meetings. The annual\ncorporate meeting of every incorporated church to which this article is\napplicable, shall be held at the time and place fixed by or in pursuance\nof law therefor, if such time and place be so fixed, and otherwise, at a\ntime and place to be fixed by its trustees.  A special corporate meeting\nof any such church may be called by the board of trustees thereof, on\nits own motion or on the written request of at least ten qualified\nvoters of such church. The trustees shall cause notice of the time and\nplace of its annual corporate meeting, therein specifying the names of\nany trustees, whose successors are to be elected thereat, and, if a\nspecial meeting, specifying the business to be transacted thereat, to be\ngiven at a regular meeting of the church for public worship, at morning\nservice, if such service be held, on each of the two successive Sundays\nnext preceding such meeting, if Sunday be the regular day for such\npublic worship, and public worship be had thereon, or otherwise at a\nregular meeting of such church for public worship on each of two days,\nat least one week apart, next preceding such meeting, or if no such\npublic worship be held during such period, by conspicuously posting such\nnotice, in writing, upon the outer entrance to the principal place of\nworship of such church. Such notice shall be given by the minister of\nthe church, if there be one, or if not, by the officiating minister\nthereof, if there be one, or if not, or if any such minister refuse to\ngive such notice, by any officer of such church. But a special corporate\nmeeting of an incorporated Presbyterian church, to elect a pastor of\nsuch church or to take action in reference to the dissolution of the\nrelations of the pastor and the church, may be called only by the\nsession of such church. They may call such meeting whenever they deem it\nadvisable to do so, or upon the request to them, by petition, of a\nmajority of the qualified voters of such corporation, they must call\nsuch meeting.  They shall give notice of such meeting in either case, in\nthe manner in this section provided in a notice of a special meeting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>