<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-195"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-195"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="195"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-195/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-195/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-195/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-195/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_195">
        <num>195</num>
        <heading>Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualification of voters thereat</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 195. Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualification\nof voters thereat.  At a corporate meeting of an incorporated church to\nwhich this article is applicable the following persons, and no others,\nshall be qualified voters, to wit: All persons who are then members in\ngood and regular standing of such church by admission into full\ncommunion or membership therewith in accordance with the rules and\nregulations thereof, and of the governing ecclesiastical body, if any,\nof the denomination or order to which the church belongs, or who have\nbeen stated attendants on divine worship in such church and have\nregularly contributed to the financial support thereof during the year\nnext preceding such meeting; and any other church incorporated under\nthis article, may at any annual corporate meeting thereof, or any\ncorporate meeting called pursuant to the provisions of this article, if\nnotice of the intention so to do has been given with the notice of such\nmeeting, determine that thereafter only members of such church shall be\nqualified voters at corporate meetings thereof. The presence at such\nmeetings of at least six persons qualified to vote thereat shall be\nnecessary to constitute a quorum. The action of the meeting upon any\nmatter or question shall be decided by a majority of the qualified\nvoters voting thereon, a quorum being present. The first named of the\nfollowing persons who is present at such meeting shall preside thereat,\nto wit:  The minister of such church, the officiating minister thereof;\nthe officers thereof in the order of their age beginning with the\noldest, any qualified voters elected therefor at the meeting. The\npresiding officer of the meeting shall receive the votes, be the judge\nof qualifications of voters and declare the result of the votes cast on\nany matter. The polls of an annual corporate meeting shall continue open\nfor one hour, and longer in the discretion of the presiding officer, or\nif required by a majority of the qualified voters present.  At each\nannual corporate meeting, successors to those trustees whose terms of\noffice then expire, shall be elected from the qualified voters by\nballot, for a term of three years thereafter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>