<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-201-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-201-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="201-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-201-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-201-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-201-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-201-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_201_A">
        <num>201-A</num>
        <heading>Incorporation of the Religious Society of Friends</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 201-a Incorporation of the Religious Society of Friends. An\nunincorporated meeting of the Religious Society of Friends in this state\nmay be incorporated by executing, acknowledging and filing a certificate\nof incorporation, stating the corporate name by which such meeting shall\nbe known, and the county, town, city or village where its principal\nplace of worship or principal office is or is intended to be located.\nSuch certificate of incorporation shall be executed and acknowledged by\nthe clerk of such meeting, and shall have attached thereto a statement,\nduly executed and acknowledged by the secretary, assistant clerk or such\nperson as shall have the duty of recording the transactions of business\nsessions of meetings of such meeting, certifying that at a business\nsession or meeting of such meeting, duly held and upon not less than\nthirty days notice, to the members thereof, as hereinafter provided, by\na minute of the proceedings thereat, duly approved according to the\nusage and custom of such meeting, the clerk of such meeting was\nauthorized and directed to execute and file such certificate of\nincorporation. Such notice shall be in writing, shall be given by mail\naddressed to the last known address of each member of such meeting\naccording to the records thereof, and shall state in substance that a\nmeeting of such unincorporated meeting will be held at its usual place\nof convening at a specified date and hour for the purpose of\nincorporating such meeting. On the filing of such certificate in\naccordance with the provisions of this chapter, such meeting shall be a\ncorporation by the name stated in the certificate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>