<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="203"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Conveyance or incumbrance of trust property of Friends</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 203. Conveyance or incumbrance of trust property of Friends.  The\ntrustee or trustees, or survivor of any trustees, of any meeting of the\nReligious Society of Friends, appointed pursuant to the last preceding\nsection, may sell, convey and grant, mortgage, or demise any or all of\nthe trust property described in said trust deed or declaration of trust,\nto any person absolutely or in trust for such meeting, whenever any\nmeeting of said society by resolution so directs. Any conveyance or\nmortgage of real estate or property so held in trust by any meeting of\nthe Religious Society of Friends, which is hereafter made in pursuance\nof a resolution of such meeting as provided herein, shall be as valid\nand effectual for the conveyance or mortgage of the title of any real\nestate so held in trust, as if the heirs of any trustee who has died\nprior to the passage of such resolution had joined in the execution of\nsuch conveyance, mortgage or demise. Any instrument for the sale,\nmortgage or demise of such property shall embody such resolution, and be\nexecuted and acknowledged by such trustee or trustees; and in such\nacknowledgment such trustee or trustees shall make an affidavit that the\nperson or persons executing such conveyance, mortgage or demise are the\ntrustee or trustees of the trust property, and that the resolution\nembodied in such conveyance, mortgage or demise was duly passed by such\nmeeting. Such affidavit shall be prima facie evidence of the facts\ntherein stated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>