<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-204-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-204-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="204-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-204-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-204-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-204-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-204-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_204_B">
        <num>204-B</num>
        <heading>Change of name of churches and affiliated and subsidiary organizations of the church of the United Brethren in Christ and the Evangelical...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 204-b. Change of name of churches and affiliated and subsidiary\norganizations of the church of the United Brethren in Christ and the\nEvangelical Church. Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter or of\nany general, special or local law, the two denominations known as the\nChurch of the United Brethren in Christ and the Evangelical Church\nhaving united under the name of the Evangelical United Brethren Church,\nall existing corporations, institutions, unincorporated boards,\nsocieties, associations, churches or administrative agencies formerly\naffiliated either with the Church of the United Brethren in Christ or\nthe Evangelical Church, and all societies, conferences, boards,\nassociations, corporations or organizations directly connected therewith\nor subsidiary thereto, shall be known as the Evangelical United Brethren\nChurch or an affiliate thereof and all such churches, corporations,\nunincorporated associations, and other organizations shall hereafter be\nknown by such names as changed and amended by this section.\n  The changes in names provided for by this section shall not in any\nrespect change the identity of or affect, abate, defeat, alter or amend\nany of the rights, privileges, powers, property, rights, obligations,\nliabilities, or duties of any of said churches, corporations,\norganizations, or unincorporated associations aforesaid, all of which\nshall remain in full force and effect as though their respective names\nhad not been so changed.\n  All churches, corporations, organizations, or unincorporated\nassociations using the changed names as provided in this section shall\ncontinue to have and be possessed of all the interest, property, and\nrights to which they are or may become entitled under their former\ncorporate names or other respective designations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>