<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="206"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_206">
        <num>206</num>
        <heading>Termination and dissolution of churches of the General Assembly of the Christian Church (Disciples of Christ), Inc</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_206__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon such notice as the supreme court in the judicial district\nwhere the church property or the religious society property is situated,\nmay prescribe and upon application made by petition of the officers or\nthe board of trustees or five members of such church or religious\nsociety, stating fully the facts in the case and on evidence being\nfurnished, including but not limited to appropriate affidavits that the\nconditions as set forth in subdivision one or two above have been\nestablished and are currently existing, upon satisfactory proof of the\nfacts leading to said application, the court shall have jurisdiction to\ngrant an order declaring the church or society extinct and the corporate\nentity dissolved if the petitioner is a religious corporation and said\norder shall direct the transfer of both real and personal property of\nthe petitioner to the CHRISTIAN CHURCH (DISCIPLES OF CHRIST) -\nNORTHEASTERN REGION, INC. or direct that the real property and personal\nproperty be sold and that the proceeds be paid over to the CHRISTIAN\nCHURCH (DISCIPLES OF CHRIST) - NORTHEASTERN REGION, INC. after the full\npayment of all liens on the real property and of all of the outstanding\ndebts of the petitioners.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such order shall operate to transfer the interest of such extinct\nchurch and/or religious society in such property or proceeds to the\nCHRISTIAN CHURCH (DISCIPLES OF CHRIST) - NORTHEASTERN REGION, INC.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The order shall also direct that the real property and personal\nproperty or the proceeds obtained from the sale thereof after the\npayment of all of the debts, obligations and liabilities of the\npetitioner, shall be used by the CHRISTIAN CHURCH (DISCIPLES OF CHRIST)\n- NORTHEASTERN REGION, INC. exclusively for the purpose or purposes for\nwhich the CHRISTIAN CHURCH (DISCIPLES OF CHRIST) - NORTHEASTERN REGION,\nINC. was organized and incorporated.\n  4. Nothing in this section, however, shall be construed to impair or\nin any way effect any existing claim upon or lien against any property\nso transferred or conveyed to the CHRISTIAN CHURCH (DISCIPLES OF CHRIST)\n- NORTHEASTERN REGION, INC. or any action or legal proceedings that may\nbe pending at the time of the transfer referred to herein.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The use of proxy or absentee ballots shall not be used relative\nto any resolution involving matters set forth in subdivisions one and\ntwo of this section unless the use of such proxy or absentee ballots is\nauthorized in the constitution and by-laws of the church or religious\nsociety proceeding under the provisions of subdivisions one and two of\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The relief sought in subdivisions one and two of this section must\nbe accomplished by formal action taken at a special meeting of the\ncongregation of the church or of the members of the religious society\ncalled for such purpose. (See Article 10 Section 194 - "Time, Place and\nNotice of Corporate Meetings".)\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To vote at any meeting held to accomplish the purposes of\nsubdivisions one and two of this section, persons otherwise qualified to\nvote must be at least eighteen years of age.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>