<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-208"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-208"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="208"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Consolidation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 208. Consolidation. Any two or more religious corporations of the\nJewish faith, incorporated under or by general or special laws, may\nenter into an agreement for the consolidation or merger of such\ncorporations, setting forth the terms and conditions of consolidation,\nthe name of the proposed or surviving corporation, the number of its\ntrustees, the time of the annual election and the names of the persons\nto be its trustees until the first or next annual meeting. Each\ncorporation may petition the supreme court for an order consolidating or\nmerging the corporations, setting forth the agreement for consolidation\nor merger and a statement of its real property and of its liabilities.\nBefore the presentation of the petition to the court the agreement and\npetition must be approved by two-thirds of the votes cast in person or\nby proxy at a meeting of the members of each corporation called for the\npurpose of considering the proposed consolidation or merger in the\nmanner prescribed by section six hundred five of the not-for-profit\ncorporation law. An affidavit by the president and the secretary of each\ncorporation stating that such approval has been given shall be annexed\nto the petition. On presentation to the court of such petition and\nagreement for consolidation or merger and on such notice as the court\nmay direct, the court after hearing all the parties interested desiring\nto be heard, may make an order approving the consolidation or merger.\nWhen such order is made and duly entered and a certified copy thereof\nfiled with the secretary of state and in the offices of the clerks of\nthe counties in which the certificates of incorporation of the several\nconstituent corporations were recorded, or if no such certificate was\nrecorded, then in the office of the clerk of the county in which the\nprincipal place of worship of the new or surviving corporation is\nintended to be situated, such corporations shall become one corporation\nby the name designated in the order and the trustees named in the\nagreement for consolidation or merger shall be the trustees of the\nconsolidated corporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>