<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209">
        <num>209</num>
        <heading>Effect of consolidation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209. Effect of consolidation. The consolidated or merged corporation\nshall possess all the powers of the constituent corporations and shall\nhave the power and be subject to the duties and obligations of a\ncongregation of the Jewish faith formed for like purposes under the\nreligious corporations law. All the rights, privileges and interests of\neach of the constituent corporations, all the property, real, personal\nand mixed, and all the debts due on whatever account to either of them,\nand all things in action, belonging to either of them, shall be deemed\nto be transferred to and vested in such new corporation without further\nact or deed; and all claims, demands, property, and every other\ninterest, belonging to the several constituent corporations, shall be as\neffectually the property of the new corporation as they were of the\nconstituent corporations, and the title to all real property, held or\ntaken by deed or otherwise under the laws of this state, vested in the\nseveral constituent corporations shall not be deemed to revert or to be\nin any way impaired by reason of the consolidation but shall be vested\nin the new corporation. Any devise, bequest, gift, grant, or declaration\nof trust, contained in any deed, will, or other instrument, in trust or\notherwise, made before or after such consolidation, or merger to or for\nany of the constituent corporations, shall inure to the benefit of the\nconsolidated or merged corporation. The consolidated corporation shall\nbe deemed to have assumed and shall be liable for all debts and\nobligations of the constituent corporations in the same manner as if\nsuch new corporation had itself incurred such debts or obligations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>