<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_A">
        <num>21-A</num>
        <heading>Corporations for acquiring lands for parsonage or camp-meeting purposes for the Free Methodist denomination</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 21-a. Corporations for acquiring lands for parsonage or camp-meeting\npurposes for the Free Methodist denomination. The district elder and a\nmajority of the stewards residing in the district elder's district,\nelected by an annual conference of the Free Methodist Church\ndenomination, may become incorporated, for the purpose of acquiring,\nmaintaining and improving real property, to be used for the purpose of a\ndistrict elder's parsonage or for camp-meeting purposes, or for both\nsuch purposes, by acknowledging and filing a certificate, stating the\nname and object of the corporation, the name of such annual conference,\nand of such district elder's district, the names, residences and\nofficial relations to such district of the signers thereof, the number\nof trustees of said incorporation, which shall be three, or some\nmultiple of three, not to exceed twelve, the names of such trustees,\ndesignating one-third to hold office for three years, one-third to hold\noffice for two years and one-third to hold office for one year.\n  On filing such certificate, the district elder and all the stewards of\nsuch district, by virtue of their respective offices, shall be a\ncorporation by the name, and for the purposes therein stated, and the\npersons therein named as trustees shall be the first trustees thereof.\n  A person holding property in trust for the purpose of a parsonage for\nthe district elder of the district, or for camp meeting purposes, and\nhis successors in office, for the Free Methodist church denomination,\nmay convey the same to a corporation organized for this purpose of\nacquiring property within the district in which such property is\nsituated.\n  Meetings held under the direction of such corporation, upon camp\ngrounds owned by such corporation, shall be deemed to be religious\nmeetings, within the provisions of the law relating to the disturbance\nof religious meetings.\n  When such corporation or camp ground association owns land bordering\non any navigable waters to be used for camp meeting purposes only, such\ncorporation or association may regulate or prohibit the landing of\npersons or vessels at the wharves, piers or shores upon such ground\nduring the holding of religious services thereon.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>