<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-21/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21">
        <num>21</num>
        <heading>Corporations for acquiring camp-meeting grounds for the Reformed Methodist denomination</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 21. Corporations for acquiring camp-meeting grounds for the Reformed\nMethodist denomination. The visiting elder of a visiting elder's\ndistrict, erected by an annual conference of the Reformed Methodist\ndenomination, and three members or more in good and regular standing of\nthree or more churches of such denomination, may become incorporated for\nthe purposes of acquiring, maintaining and improving real property, to\nbe used as a camp ground for camp-meeting purposes, by executing,\nacknowledging and filing a certificate stating the name and object of\nthe corporation to be formed, the name of such annual conference, and of\nsuch visiting elder's district, the names, residences and particular\nchurch membership of the signers thereof, the number of trustees of such\ncorporation, which shall be three, or some multiple of three, not more\nthan twenty-one, the names of such trustees, designating one-third to\nhold office for three years, one-third to hold office for two years, and\none-third to hold office for one year.  On filing such certificate, the\nvisiting elder and the trustees named therein, and their successors in\noffice, shall be a corporation by the name and for the purposes therein\nstated. A person holding property in trust for camp-meeting purposes for\nthe Reformed Methodist denomination, may convey the same to a\ncorporation formed for the purpose of acquiring such property within the\nvisiting elder's district where the property is situated. Meetings held\nunder the direction of such a corporation upon camp grounds owned by it,\nshall be deemed religious meetings within the religious law, relating to\nthe disturbance of religious meetings.  Whenever such a corporation, or\nany camp ground association of the Reformed Methodist denomination, owns\nland bordering upon any navigable waters to be used for camp-meeting\npurposes only, such corporation or association may regulate or prohibit\nthe landing of persons or vessels at the wharves, piers or shores upon\nsuch grounds during the holding of religious services thereon.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>