<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="210"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_210">
        <num>210</num>
        <heading>Incorporation of church connected with supreme council of Independent Associated Spiritualists</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 210. Incorporation of church connected with supreme council of\nIndependent Associated Spiritualists.  A meeting for incorporating or\nreincorporating a church in connection with the supreme council of the\nIndependent Associated Spiritualists, Incorporated, shall be held in\npursuance of the preceding provisions of this article. Such meeting\nshall be held and such church shall be subject to the following\nprovisions:\n  1. Notice of meeting for incorporation. Notice of the meeting must\nhave attached thereto the endorsement and consent of the supreme council\nof the Independent Associated Spiritualists;\n  2. The meeting for incorporation. The meeting shall be called to order\nby a person delegated to do so by the supreme councilor or his\nrepresentative;\n  3. The certificate of incorporation. The certificate of incorporation\nshall have attached thereto the endorsement and consent of the supreme\ncouncil of the Independent Associated Spiritualists and the name of such\nchurch as adopted shall thereafter have affixed "In connection with the\nsupreme council of the Independent Associated Spiritualists,\nIncorporated," or "Affiliated with the supreme council of the\nIndependent Associated Spiritualists, Incorporated," as the case may be;\n  4. Rules and regulations. A church incorporated or reincorporated\nunder the provisions of this section shall be subject to the rules and\nregulations of the supreme council of the Independent Associated\nSpiritualists;\n  5. Trustees. The trustees of a church incorporated under this section\nshall also be the spiritual officers of such church;\n  6. Election of ministers. No church may engage or retain a minister\nnot certified as in good standing by the supreme council;\n  7. Licenses and certificates. Only persons holding a minister's\nlicense or a certificate of proficiency from the supreme council shall\nconduct services or classes in any church, incorporated under this\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>