<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-06-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="211"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_211">
        <num>211</num>
        <heading>Incorporation of church in connection with Spiritual Science Mother Church, Inc</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 211. Incorporation of church in connection with Spiritual Science\nMother Church, Inc. A meeting for incorporating or reincorporating a\nchurch in connection with Spiritual Science Mother Church, Inc., shall\nbe held in pursuance of the preceding provisions of this article. Such\nmeeting shall be held and such church shall be subject to the following\nprovisions:\n  1. Notice of meeting for incorporation. Notice of the meeting must\nhave attached thereto the endorsement and consent of Spiritual Science\nMother Church, Inc.\n  2. The meeting for incorporation. The meeting shall be called to order\nby an authorized delegate of the board of directors of Spiritual Science\nMother Church, Inc., the supreme ecclesiastical council governing\nSpiritual Science Mother Church and its branch churches.\n  3. The certificate of incorporation. The certificate of incorporation\nshall have attached thereto the endorsement and consent of the board of\ndirectors of Spiritual Science Mother Church, Inc., and the name of such\nchurch as adopted shall thereafter have affixed: "Branch Church of\nSpiritual Science Mother Church, Inc., of New York."\n  4. Rules and regulations. A church incorporated or reincorporated\nunder the provisions of this section shall be subject to the rules and\nregulations of the board of directors of Spiritual Science Mother\nChurch, Inc.\n  5. Trustees. The trustees of such branch church incorporated under\nthis section shall also be the spiritual officers of such church.\n  6. Election of ministers. No branch church of Spiritual Science may\nengage or retain, under this section, any minister not certified as in\ngood standing by Spiritual Science Mother Church board of directors.\n  7. Licenses and certificates. Only persons holding a minister's\nlicense or a certificate of proficiency from the ecclesiastical council\nof Spiritual Science Mother Church, Inc., shall conduct services in any\nchurch incorporated under this section.\n  8. Recording of licenses. Such license or certificate shall be made a\nmatter of public record either in the office of the county clerk or such\nother place as by law may be provided for such record.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>