<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220">
        <num>220</num>
        <heading>Joint meeting for the purposes of incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 220. Joint meeting for the purposes of incorporation. Two or more\nunincorporated churches, which separately agree on a plan of union and\ndetermine to meet together for the purpose of being incorporated as a\nunion church, may be incorporated as a union church in pursuance of the\nprovisions of article ten, and thereafter such union church shall be\ngoverned by the general provisions of such article, as near as may be,\nexcept as otherwise provided in this article. A notice of such joint\nmeeting shall be given to the congregation of each church, in pursuance\nof the provisions of article ten of this chapter, relating to notice of\nmeeting for incorporations, in every respect as if it were a notice of a\nmeeting for the separate incorporation of such church under such\narticle, except that the notice shall state in substance that a joint\nmeeting of such unincorporated churches, which shall be specified in the\nnotice, will be held for the purpose of incorporating such churches as a\nunion church, and electing trustees thereof at a time and place\nspecified in the notice, which place may be the usual place of worship\nof either of such churches or any other reasonably convenient place.\nSuch notice must be signed by at least six persons from each of such\nchurches who would be authorized to sign a notice for the meeting of\neach church, respectively, for the purpose of incorporating it under\nsuch article.\n  The provisions of article ten hereof shall be applicable to the\norganization and conduct of such meeting, the matters to be determined\nupon and the certificate of incorporation to be executed and filed\naccordingly, except that the presiding officer of such joint meeting\nshall be the oldest person present at such meeting who would be entitled\nto preside at a meeting of either of such churches singly for the\npurposes of incorporation in pursuance of such article. All persons who\nwould be qualified to vote at such meeting of either of such churches\nheld singly, shall be qualified voters at such joint meeting, and the\nnumber of trustees of the union church after incorporation, to be\nselected from each such church, may be agreed on by such unincorporated\nchurches, and the trustees shall be selected by each of such churches\naccordingly.\n  The certificate of incorporation shall set forth the plan of union\nagreed on and the number of trustees of the incorporated union church to\nbe selected by each unincorporated church.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>