<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225_L">
        <num>225-L</num>
        <heading>Conveyance of property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 225-l. Conveyance of property. Whenever it may become necessary or\nadvisable to mortgage or dispose of any church property, the trustees\nmay mortgage or sell and convey the same by first securing the authority\nof the society for such sale or mortgage and the approval of the\ndistrict superintendent of the district in which the church is located,\nand obtaining leave of the supreme or county court therefor pursuant to\nthe provisions of this chapter; provided that in all cases the proceeds\nof such sale or mortgage shall be used either for the payment of debts\nor for the purchase or improvement of property for the same uses and\ndeeded to the same corporation; or if not so used, shall be held subject\nto the order of the annual conference in whose territory such property\nmay be situated. Provided however that, if the deed of the property to\nbe sold shall convey the property to the local corporate society to be\nheld in trust for the use and benefit of the membership of the Free\nMethodist Church of North America, it shall also be necessary for the\ntrustees to secure the consent of the free Methodist general conference\nof North America, or in the intervals of its sessions, of such person or\npersons as are authorized by said general conference to grant such\npermission, in order to mortgage or sell and convey such property.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>