<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225_B">
        <num>225-B</num>
        <heading>Meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 225-b. Meeting for incorporation. 1. Notice of a meeting for the\npurpose of incorporating an unincorporated free Methodist church shall\nbe in writing and shall state in substance, that a meeting of such\nunincorporated church will be held at its usual place of worship at a\nspecified day and hour, for the purpose of incorporating such a church\nand selecting a name therefor and electing trustees thereof.\n  2. Such notice must be signed by at least six members, either in full\nconnection or on probation, of the local society of full age and in good\nand regular standing. This notice shall be publicly read at a regular\nmeeting of such unincorporated church for public worship, at least ten\ndays, and not more than thirty days, before the date of such meeting\nupon Sunday, if such service be held on Sunday, by the pastor or by one\nof the signers thereof; and a copy of such notice shall be posted\nconspicuously on the outside of the main entrance to such place of\nworship at least fifteen days before the date of such meeting.\n  3. At the meeting for incorporation held in pursuance of such notice,\nthe following persons, and no others, shall be qualified voters, to wit:\nall persons of full age, who are then members of such church, either in\nfull connection or on probation, and in good and regular standing. The\npresence of the majority of such qualified voters, at least six in\nnumber, shall be necessary to constitute a quorum of such meeting,\nwithout which no action can be taken. Each action of the meeting upon\nany matter or question shall be decided by a majority of the qualified\nvoters present and voting thereon. At such meeting the pastor shall\npreside, or in the absence of a pastor or in case of his declining to\npreside, any qualified voter may be elected to preside. The presiding\nofficer shall be the judge of the qualifications of voters, subject to\nappeal to the vote of the members present whose qualifications as voters\nare not challenged, and shall receive the votes cast and declare the\nresult of the same.\n  4. If such meeting shall decide to incorporate such unincorporated\nchurch, it shall also decide upon the name of the proposed\nincorporation, the number of trustees thereof, which shall be three, six\nor nine.  Such meeting shall elect by ballot the number of trustees\ndecided upon, at least two-thirds of whom shall be members in full\nconnection of the free Methodist church and in good and regular\nstanding. One-third of these shall hold office until the first annual\nelection of trustees thereafter, one-third until the second annual\nelection, and one-third until the third annual election.\n  5. The first annual meeting for the election of trustees shall be held\nat the date fixed for the annual society meeting which shall be within\nthree months prior to the session of the annual conference.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>