<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225_C">
        <num>225-C</num>
        <heading>Certificate of incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 225-c. Certificate of incorporation. 1. The presiding officer of\nsuch a meeting and at least two other persons present and voting thereat\nshall be appointed by such meeting to execute and acknowledge, before\nany person authorized to take acknowledgment of deeds, a certificate of\nincorporation whereby they shall agree to be governed by the discipline,\nrules and usages of the Free Methodist Church of North America. To such\ncertificate of incorporation there shall be attached a certificate\nsigned by the district superintendent of the district in which said\nchurch is to be located, stating that the said church is incorporated by\nand with the consent of said district superintendent.\n  2. This certificate of incorporation shall contain the following\nitems: The name of said church; the township, village or city, and the\ncounty in which said church shall be located; and agreement to worship\nand labor together according to the discipline, rules and usages of the\nFree Methodist Church of North America; the statement that there were\nsix or more qualified voters present at the meeting where they were\nelected and this act of incorporation was authorized; the names and\nrespective periods of office of the trustees elected; the place and date\nof said meeting for incorporation; and the signatures and residences of\nthose authorized to execute and acknowledge this certificate of\nincorporation.\n  3. This certificate of incorporation shall be executed in duplicate.\nOne of such duplicate copies shall be retained by such corporation and\none copy shall be recorded in the office of the county clerk of the\ncounty where such corporation is formed. On filing such certificate the\nmembers either in full connection or on probation of such church\nqualified to vote at such meeting and who shall thereafter, from time to\ntime, be qualified voters at the corporate meetings thereof shall be a\ncorporation by the name stated in such certificate, and the persons\ntherein stated to be elected trustees of such church shall be the\ntrustees thereof, for the terms for which they were respectively\nelected, and until their successors are elected.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>