<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-225-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225_I">
        <num>225-I</num>
        <heading>Trustee meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 225-i. Trustee meetings. 1. Meetings of the trustees of an\nincorporated free Methodist church shall be called by giving at least\nforty-eight hours' notice thereof personally or by mail to all the\ntrustees, and such notice may be given by the pastor, the secretary of\nthe board of trustees or by any two of the trustees, but by the\nunanimous consent of the trustees a meeting may be held without previous\nnotice thereof. The pastor may preside at a trustee meeting and in his\nabsence the senior trustee in service, or some member, the board of\ntrustees elects for that purpose, shall be chairman. A majority of the\nwhole number of trustees shall constitute a quorum for the transaction\nof business at any meeting lawfully convened.\n  2. The effect of a tie vote creating a deadlock shall be to carry the\nquestion involved (with all pending questions appertaining thereto) over\nto the next sitting or meeting of the board. In case of such a deadlock\nextending beyond three successive sittings or meetings of the board of\ntrustees, the whole matter involved shall be settled in a meeting of the\ncorporate society.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>