<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="24"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_24">
        <num>24</num>
        <heading>Government of churches incorporated prior to January first, eighteen hundred and twenty-eight</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 24. Government of churches incorporated prior to January first,\neighteen hundred and twenty-eight. Any provision of this chapter shall\nnot be deemed to apply to any church incorporated under any general or\nspecial law, prior to January first, eighteen hundred and twenty-eight,\nif such provision is inconsistent with or in derogation of any of the\nrights and privileges of such corporation as they existed under the law\nby or pursuant to which such corporation was formed, unless such\ncorporation subsequent to such date, shall have lawfully reincorporated\nunder a law enacted since the first day of January, eighteen hundred and\ntwenty-eight, or unless the trustees of such corporation shall, by\nresolution, determine that the provisions of this chapter applying to\nchurches of the same denomination and to the trustees thereof shall\napply to such church, and unless such resolution shall be submitted to\nthe next ensuing annual meeting of such church, and ratified by a\nmajority of the votes of the qualified voters present and voting\nthereon. Notice of the adoption of such resolution and of the proposed\nsubmission thereof for ratification, shall be given with the notice of\nsuch annual meeting, and in addition thereto, mailed to each member of\nsuch church corporation at his last known post-office address, at least\ntwo weeks prior to such annual meeting, and published once a week for\ntwo successive weeks immediately preceding such meeting in a newspaper,\nif any, published in the city, village or town in which the principal\nplace of worship of such corporation is located, and otherwise in a\nnewspaper published in an adjoining town. If such resolution is so\nratified, the trustees of such church shall cause a certificate setting\nforth a copy of such resolution, its adoption by the board of trustees\nand its due ratification by the members of such corporation, to be filed\nin the office of the clerk of the county in which the principal place of\nworship of such corporation is located. Such county clerk shall cause\nsuch certificate to be recorded in the book in which certificates of\nincorporation of religious corporations are recorded in pursuance of\nlaw.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>