<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-263"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-263"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="263"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-263/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-263/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-263/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-263/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_263">
        <num>263</num>
        <heading>Incorporation of unincorporated Spiritualist churches and system of incorporation and government</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 263. Incorporation of unincorporated Spiritualist churches and\nsystem of incorporation and government. A meeting for the purpose of\nincorporating an unincorporated Spiritualist church in connection with\nthe General Assembly of Spiritualists must be called and held in\npursuance of the provisions of this article:\n  1. The notice and call of such meeting shall be in writing and shall\nstate in substance, that a meeting of such unincorporated church will be\nheld at its usual place of worship at a specified day and hour for the\npurpose of incorporating such church and designating trustees thereof.\n  2. The notice must be signed at least by seven persons of full age who\nare then members in good and regular standing of such church by\nadmission into full membership therewith, in accordance with the rules\nand regulations of such church, and who have in good faith expressed in\nopen meeting their belief in the tenets of faith adopted by the General\nAssembly of Spiritualists.\n  3. The notice must have endorsed thereon the approval of the body of\nthe General Assembly of Spiritualists governing the admission of\nchurches.\n  4. A copy of such notice with the approval endorsed thereon shall be\npublicly read at a regular meeting of such unincorporated church for\npublic worship, on the two successive Sundays immediately preceding the\nmeeting by any person qualified to sign such notice.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>