<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-264"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-264"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="264"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-264/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-264/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-264/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-264/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_264">
        <num>264</num>
        <heading>At the meeting for incorporation, held in pursuance to such notice, the qualified voters unless otherwise decided as hereinafter provided...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 264. At the meeting for incorporation, held in pursuance to such\nnotice, the qualified voters unless otherwise decided as hereinafter\nprovided shall all be persons of full age who have worshipped with such\nchurch, and have regularly contributed to its support according to its\nusages, for at least one year or since it was formed, and who have in\ngood faith in open meeting expressed their belief in the tenets of faith\nadopted by the General Assembly of Spiritualists. At such meeting the\npresence of a majority of such qualified voters, at least seven in\nnumber, shall be necessary to constitute a quorum, and all matters or\nquestions shall be decided by a majority of the qualified voters voting\nthereon. The meeting shall be called to order by a person delegated so\nto do by the president of the General Assembly of Spiritualists. There\nshall be elected at such meeting, from the qualified voters then present\na presiding officer, a clerk to keep the records of the proceedings of\nthe meeting and two inspectors of election to receive the ballots cast.\nThe presiding officer and the inspectors shall decide the result of the\nballots cast on any matter, and shall be the judges of the\nqualifications of the voters. If the meeting shall decide that such\nunincorporated church shall become incorporated, the meeting shall also\ndecide upon the name of the proposed corporation, the number of the\ntrustees thereof, which shall be three, six or nine, and the date, not\nmore than fifteen months thereafter, on which the first annual election\nof the trustees thereof shall be held; and it may, by a two-thirds vote,\ndecide that all members of the unincorporated church, of full age, in\ngood and regular standing, who have worshipped with such church but who\nhave not contributed to the financial support thereof, shall also be\nqualified voters at such meeting. Such meeting shall thereupon elect by\nballot from the persons qualified to vote thereat, of the number of\ntrustees so decided on who shall hold office until the first annual\nelection of trustees thereafter, one-third of such number of trustees\nwho shall hold office until the second annual election of trustees\nthereafter, and one-third of such number of trustees who shall hold\noffice until the third annual election of trustees thereafter, or until\nthe respective successors of such trustees shall be elected. Such\nmeeting shall also elect by ballot a clerk or secretary of the\ncorporation, who shall hold his office until the close of the next\nannual meeting.\n  * NB Enacted without section heading.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>