<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-267"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-267"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="267"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-267/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-267/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-267/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-267/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_267">
        <num>267</num>
        <heading>Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications of voters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 267. Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications\nof voters. At every corporate meeting of a church incorporated under\nthis article all persons who for one year next preceding such meeting\nhave worshipped with such church and have regularly contributed to its\nfinancial support, according to its usages, shall be qualified voters;\nbut, if so decided, by a two-thirds vote at the original meeting or at\nany annual corporate meeting thereof, after notice of such meeting all\nmembers of such church and in good and regular standing, by admission to\nmembership therewith, who have worshipped with such church for one year\nnext preceding the meeting at which they vote, may also be admitted as\nqualified voters at corporate meetings. At such corporate meetings, the\npresence of at least seven persons qualified to vote thereat shall be\nnecessary to constitute a quorum; and all matters or questions shall be\ndecided by a majority of the qualified voters voting thereon, except\nthat by-laws can only be adopted or amended by a two-thirds vote. The\nclerk or secretary of the corporation shall call the meeting to order;\nand under his supervision the qualified voters then present shall choose\na presiding officer and two inspectors of election to receive the\nballots cast.  The presiding officer and the inspectors of election\nshall declare the result of the ballots cast on any matter and shall be\nthe judges of the qualifications of the voters. At such annual corporate\nmeeting, successors to those trustees whose terms of office then expire\nshall be elected by ballot from the qualified voters, for a term of\nthree years thereafter, and until their successors shall be elected. A\nclerk or secretary of the corporation shall be elected by ballot, who\nshall hold office until the close of the next annual meeting, and until\nhis successor shall be elected.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>