<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-276"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-276"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="276"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-276/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-276/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-276/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-276/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_276">
        <num>276</num>
        <heading>Reincorporation of present incorporated churches of the Nazarene</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 276. Reincorporation of present incorporated churches of the\nNazarene. Any church of the Nazarene heretofore incorporated may\nreincorporate under the provisions of this article, by filing in the\ncounty clerk's office in the county in which its principal place of\nworship is located, a certificate, signed by the district superintendent\nof the district in which its principal place of worship is located, or\nin case of his absence or inability to act, by one of the general\nsuperintendents of the church of the Nazarene of the United States, and\nby all the trustees in office at the time of such reincorporation,\nsetting forth that they desire to reincorporate under the provisions of\nthis act, the corporate name by which such church shall be known, and\nthe county, town, city or village where its principal place of worship\nis or is intended to be located; the number and the names of the laymen\ntrustees who are to hold office until the next annual meeting of said\ncorporation. Immediately upon the filing of such certificate, the board\nof trustees of said church, shall consist of the district superintendent\nof the district in which the principal place of worship is located, and\nthe laymen trustees selected as above provided, and the office of the\ntrustees of said church heretofore appointed or selected shall become\nvacant and cease to exist.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>