<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-278"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-278"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="278"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-278/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-278/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-278/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-278/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_278">
        <num>278</num>
        <heading>Corporations for acquiring camp meeting grounds for camp meeting purposes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 278. Corporations for acquiring camp meeting grounds for camp\nmeeting purposes. The district superintendent and the members of the\ncamp meeting board duly elected by a district assembly of the Church of\nthe Nazarene may become incorporated for the purposes of acquiring,\nmaintaining and improving real property to be used as a camp ground for\ncamp meeting purposes, by executing, acknowledging and filing a\ncertificate stating the name and object of the corporation, the name of\nsuch district assembly and of such district, the names and residences of\nthe signers thereof, the number of trustees of such corporation, which\nshall be three, or some multiple of three, not more than twenty-one, the\nnames of such trustees, designating one-third to hold office for one\nyear, one-third to hold office for two years and one-third to hold\noffice for three years. On filing such a certificate the district\nsuperintendent and the members of such camp meeting board shall be a\ncorporation by the name and for the purposes therein stated and the\ntrustees therein named shall be the first trustees thereof.\n  A person holding property in trust for camp meeting purposes or other\nreligious purposes for the Church of the Nazarene may convey the same to\na corporation organized for the purpose of acquiring such property\nwithin the district in which the property is situated.\n  Meetings held under the direction of such a corporation upon grounds\nowned by it shall be deemed religious meetings within the provisions of\nthe law relating to disturbance of religious meetings.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>