<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-279"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-279"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="279"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-279/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-279/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-279/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-279/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_279">
        <num>279</num>
        <heading>Incorporation of advisory board of a district of the Church of the Nazarene</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 279. Incorporation of advisory board of a district of the Church of\nthe Nazarene. 1. The district superintendent and the members of the\nadvisory board duly elected by a district assembly of the Church of the\nNazarene may incorporate for the purpose of advancing the development of\nthe Churches of Nazarene in such district.\n  2. The certificate of incorporation shall state the object of the\ncorporation, the name of such district assembly and of such district,\nthe names and residences of the signers thereof, the number of trustees\nwhich shall be not less than three or more than five, designating them\nto hold office for one year. On executing, acknowledging and filing such\ncertificate the advisory board of such district shall be a corporation\nand the trustees therein stated shall be the first trustees thereof.\n  3. Such corporation may acquire property for churches, parsonages,\nmissions, Sunday schools, denominational educational institutions\n(subject to the consent of the university of New York), residences of\nchurch workers, dispensaries of medicine for the poor, rescue homes,\nhomes for the aged or for needy and orphan children, subject to the\nconsent of the state board of social welfare, and property for\ncemeteries, camp grounds or for other religious purposes. Such a\ncorporation shall have power to establish, maintain and manage by its\ntrustees or other officers such institutions as a part of its religious\npurpose, and may take and hold by conveyance, donation, bequest or\ndevise real and personal property for such purposes, and may purchase\nand may erect suitable buildings therefor. Any such corporation may take\nand hold any grant, donation, bequest or devise of real or personal\nproperty heretofore or hereafter made upon trust, and apply the same, or\nthe income thereof, under the direction of its trustees or other\nofficers. Such trustees or other officers shall have power to mortgage\nor sell and convey any property under the care, when directed so to do\nby the corporation that elected them, having first obtained leave of the\nsupreme or county court therefor pursuant to the provisions of this\nchapter; provided that in all cases the proceeds of such sale or\nmortgage shall be used either for the payment of debts or for the\npurchase or improvement of property for the same uses and deeded to the\nsame corporation; or if not used, shall be held subject to the order of\nthe annual assembly of the district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>