<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-292"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-292"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="292"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-292/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-292/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-292/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-292/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_292">
        <num>292</num>
        <heading>Notice of meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 292. Notice of meeting for incorporation. Notice of a meeting for\nthe purpose of incorporating an unincorporated parish, congregation,\nchurch, society or committee to which this article is applicable shall\nbe given as follows:\n  1. The notice shall be in writing and shall state in substance that a\nmeeting of the members of such church, congregation, parish, society or\ncommittee will be held at a stated place, date and hour for the purpose\nof incorporating, electing trustees and selecting a corporate name.\n  2. The notice shall also state that the appropriate ecclesiastical\nauthority has given sanction and permission, required under this\narticle, for the incorporation.\n  3. The notice must be signed by at least six persons of legal age who,\neither from the time of the formation of said church or for a period of\nat least one year have been communicants in canonical standing within\nthe Eastern Orthodox communion and are resident members of the parish,\nchurch, society or committee which proposes to incorporate.\n  4. Such notice shall be publicly read, by the minister in charge of\nsuch church or by one of the members signing the same, at two successive\nregular meetings for public worship or at special meetings of said\nparish or society on the two Sundays immediately preceding the meeting\nfor incorporation; and at least fifteen days before the meeting for\nincorporation, a copy of such notice shall be posted at the place of\nworship or at the place where such special meetings are to be held.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>