<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-294"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-294"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="294"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-294/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-294/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-294/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-294/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_294">
        <num>294</num>
        <heading>Certificate of incorporation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_294__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name by which the proposed corporation shall be known.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_294__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of trustees thereof; the names and addresses of the\npersons elected as trustees; and the term of office for which they were\nrespectively elected.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_294__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name of county, town, city or village in which the principal\nplace of worship or office is or is intended to be located.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_294__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the purpose and intent for which said corporation is created, to\nbe set forth as follows:\n  "The purpose and intent of this corporation is to maintain, propagate,\npractice and forever perpetuate religious worship, services, sacraments\nand teaching in full accordance and unity with the doctrine, ritual,\ncanon law, faith, practice, discipline, and traditions and usages of the\nOrthodox Greek Catholic (Eastern Orthodox) Church; and for the carrying\nout of said purpose and intent, to form and maintain a religious\norganization or church adherent and obedient to the Orthodox\necclesiastical jurisdiction and authority, and to the Orthodox hierarch,\nbishop or administrator, selected by the members applying for\nincorporation, and certified by the Orthodox Greek Catholic Primary\nJurisdictions in America, through the secretariat thereof, as canonical\nand appropriate for the Orthodox communicant members comprising this\ncorporation."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_294__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the certificate of incorporation of societies or organizations,\nother than parishes, special purposes, additional to the above, may be\nset forth.\n  2. On filing such certificate in the office of the county clerk of the\ncounty in which the place of worship or office of such corporation is or\nis intended to be located, such church, society or committee shall be a\ncorporation by the name stated in the certificate and the persons\ntherein declared to be trustees of such corporation shall be trustees\nuntil their successors are elected.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>