<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-295"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-295"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="295"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-295/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-295/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-295/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-295/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_295">
        <num>295</num>
        <heading>Government: powers and duties of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 295. Government: powers and duties of trustees. 1. Every church,\nparish, congregation, society, or committee incorporated or\nre-incorporated, pursuant to this article, shall recognize and be and\nremain subject to the jurisdiction and authority of the duly appointed\nand canonical hierarch, bishop or other administrator, certified through\nthe secretariat of the Federated Orthodox Greek Catholic Primary\nJurisdictions in America, as appropriate for its members, or his\nsuccessor in office whose authority is likewise certified; shall accept,\nsecure or receive the sacramental, pastoral, or ministerial services of\nsuch clergy only as are so certified to be of lawful and canonical\nstatus or authority in the Orthodox Greek Catholic (Eastern Orthodox)\nChurch; and shall retain or secure as pastors only such clergy as have,\nin addition, the permission of the hierarch, bishop or administrator\ncertified to be appropriate; and shall in all other respects conform to,\nmaintain, and follow the faith, doctrine, ritual, communion, discipline,\ncanon law, traditions and usages of the Orthodox Greek Catholic (Eastern\nOrthodox) Church.\n  2. Any action of the trustees or parish committees regarding the\ncalling, appointment, removal or compensation of parish clergy shall be\nsubject to approval, in writing, by the appropriate bishop or\nadministrator exercising jurisdiction.\n  3. The trustees of every such incorporated or re-incorporated church,\nsociety or committee shall have the custody and control of all the\ntemporalities and property, real and personal, belonging to the\ncorporation, and of all the revenues therefrom; and shall administer the\nsame strictly in accordance with the by-laws of the corporation and the\nrules, regulations and usages of the orthodox jurisdiction or\necclesiastical governing body to which such church, society or committee\nis subject.\n  4. The number of first trustees shall be a multiple of three;\none-third of such first trustees to hold office for three years;\none-third thereof to hold office for two years; and one-third thereof to\nhold office for one year from the first election following the\nincorporation; and thereafter at each annual election there shall be\nelected for a term of three years one-third of the number of trustees.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>