<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3">
        <num>3</num>
        <heading>Filing and recording certificates of incorporation of religious corporations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3. Filing and recording certificates of incorporation of religious\ncorporations. The certificate of incorporation of a religious\ncorporation shall be acknowledged or proved before an officer authorized\nto take the acknowledgment or proof of deeds or conveyances of real\nestate, to be recorded in the county in which the principal office or\nplace of worship of said corporation is or is intended to be situated,\nand shall be filed and recorded in the office of the clerk of said\ncounty. If there is not, or is not intended to be, any such office or\nplace of worship, the certificate shall be filed and recorded in the\noffice of the secretary of state. Where a religious corporation removes\nto another county within the state a duplicate copy of its certificate\nof incorporation together with a statement of such removal duly signed\nand acknowledged by the directors and officers of said corporation may\nbe filed in the office of the clerk of said county to which it has\nremoved.\n  The recording of any certificate of a religious corporation organized\nunder provisions of "An act to provide for the incorporation of\nreligious societies," passed April fifth, eighteen hundred and thirteen,\nand of the acts amending the same, in the office of a clerk of a county\nprior to the passage of chapter thirty-five of the laws of eighteen\nhundred and ninety-seven, instead of in the office of the register of\nsuch county, shall be regarded and construed and such recording is\nhereby declared to be of the same validity, force and effect as would\nhave been the recording of such certificate in the proper office. And\nevery act, deed, matter and thing done or performed by every such\nreligious society or corporation since the recording of its certificate\nin the office of said county clerk is hereby ratified, confirmed and\ndeclared to be as valid in all respects as if the said certificate had\nbeen properly and appropriately recorded in the office of the register\nof the county in which said religious society or corporation was\norganized; but this section shall not affect any suit or proceeding\nalready commenced arising out of such original mistake.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>