<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="303"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_303">
        <num>303</num>
        <heading>Incorporation meeting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 303. Incorporation meeting. 1. At the incorporation meeting, held in\npursuance of such notice, the qualified voters shall be all persons of\nlegal age who are in good and regular standing in such church in\naccordance with the rules and regulations of such church and who have in\ngood faith in open meeting expressed their belief in the tenets of faith\nand the declaration of principles adopted by the National Spiritualist\nAssociation. At such meeting the presence of a majority of the qualified\nvoters, at least eight in number, shall be necessary to constitute a\nquorum, and all matters or questions shall be decided by a majority of\nthe qualified voters voting thereon.\n  2. The meeting shall be called to order by the minister of such\nchurch, or in his absence, by one of the signers of the notice and shall\nelect from the qualified voters, a chairman, a secretary and two\ninspectors of election. The chairman and the inspectors of election\nshall decide the qualifications of the voters and the result of the\nballots cast on any matter.\n  3. If the meeting shall decide that such church shall become\nincorporated, the meeting shall also decide upon the name of the\nproposed corporation, the number and term of officers and trustees, and\nthe name of the county and the city, town or village in which the\nprincipal place of worship is or is intended to be located. The meeting\nshall also elect the officers and trustees. The meeting may also adopt\nby-laws for the government of the church.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>