<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-322"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-322"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="322"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_322">
        <num>322</num>
        <heading>Meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 322. Meeting for incorporation. 1. Notice of a meeting for the\npurpose of incorporating an unincorporated United Methodist church shall\nbe in writing and shall state in substance, that a meeting of such\nunincorporated church will be held at its usual place of worship at a\nspecified day and hour, for the purpose of incorporating such a church\nand selecting a name therefor and electing trustees thereof.\n  2. Such notice must be signed by at least six full members of the\nchurch who are all of full age and in good and regular standing. This\nnotice shall be publicly read at each of the two next preceding regular\nmeetings of such unincorporated church for public worship, at least one\nweek apart, at morning service, if such service be held, on Sunday, if\nSunday be the day for such regular meetings by the pastor or by one of\nthe signers thereof.\n  3. At the meeting for incorporation held in pursuance of such notice,\nthe following persons, and no others, shall be qualified voters, to wit:\nall persons of full age who are then full members in good and regular\nstanding in such church. The presence of at least six persons qualified\nto vote thereat shall be necessary to constitute a quorum of such a\nmeeting. Each action of the meeting upon any matter or question shall be\ndecided by a majority of the qualified voters present and voting\nthereon. At such a meeting the district superintendent or the pastor\nshall preside, or in the absence of both or in case of either or both\ndeclining to preside, any qualified voter may be elected to preside.\nThe presiding officer shall be the judge of the qualifications of\nvoters, subject to appeal to the vote of the members present whose\nqualifications as voters are not challenged, and shall receive the votes\ncast and declare the result of the same.\n  4. If such meeting shall decide to incorporate such unincorporated\nchurch, it shall also decide upon the name of the proposed\nincorporation, the number of trustees thereof, which shall be three, six\nor nine, and shall determine the date, not more than fifteen months\nthereafter, on which the first annual election of the trustees thereof\nafter such meeting shall be held. Such meeting shall elect by ballot the\nnumber of trustees decided upon, which trustees shall be of full age and\ntwo-thirds of whom shall be members of The United Methodist Church.\nOne-third of these shall be elected to hold office until the first\nannual election of trustees thereafter, one-third until the second\nannual election, and one-third until the third annual election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>