<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-323"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-323"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="323"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-323/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-323/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-323/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-323/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_323">
        <num>323</num>
        <heading>Certificate of incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 323. Certificate of incorporation. The presiding officer of such a\nmeeting and at least two other persons present and voting thereat shall\nbe appointed at such a meeting to execute and acknowledge, before any\nperson authorized to take acknowledgment of deeds, a certificate of\nincorporation which shall have been submitted to and approved by such\nmeeting. Such certificate shall set forth: the place and date of said\nmeeting for incorporation; the name of said church; the township,\nvillage or city, and the county in which said church shall be located;\nthe statement that there were six or more qualified voters present at\nthe meeting where this act of incorporation was authorized; the names\nand respective periods of office of the trustees elected; the signatures\nand residences of those authorized to execute and acknowledge the\ncertificate of incorporation; the approval of the district\nsuperintendent of the district in which the church is located; and a\nstatement that the corporation shall support the doctrine and shall be\nsubject to the laws, usages and ministerial appointments of The United\nMethodist Church as from time to time established, made and declared by\nthe lawful authority of said church. On the filing of such certificate\nin the office of the county clerk of the county in which such church\nshall be located the members of such church qualified to vote at such\nmeeting and those who shall thereafter, from time to time, be qualified\nvoters, at the corporate meetings thereof, shall be a corporation by the\nname stated in such certificate, and the persons therein stated to be\nelected trustees of such church shall be the trustees thereof, for the\nterms for which they were respectively elected, and until their\nsuccessors are elected.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>