<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-330"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-330"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="330"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_330">
        <num>330</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 330. Powers and duties of trustees. 1. The trustees of an\nincorporated United Methodist church shall have the custody and control\nof all the temporalities and property belonging to the corporation and\nof the revenues from such property, and shall administer the same in\naccordance with the discipline, rules and usages of The United Methodist\nChurch, and with the provisions of law relating thereto, for the support\nand maintenance of the corporation or providing the members thereof at a\ncorporate meeting thereof shall so authorize, of some religious,\ncharitable or benevolent object, conducted by such church, or connected\nwith it, or with The United Methodist Church, and they shall not use\nsuch property for any other purpose or divert the same from such uses.\n  2. The trustees shall be responsible to the charge conference of the\nchurch in a manner not inconsistent with any directions of a corporate\nmeeting, and shall annually make a written report to the charge\nconference which report shall include the items required by the\ndiscipline of The United Methodist Church.\n  3. The trustees shall not prevent or interfere with the pastor or\nother duly authorized ministers of The United Methodist Church in the\nuse of said property for religious services or other proper meetings\nrecognized by the law and usage of The United Methodist Church.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>