<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-343"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-343"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="343"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-343/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-343/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-343/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-343/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_343">
        <num>343</num>
        <heading>Time, place and notice of corporate meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 343. Time, place and notice of corporate meetings. 1. The annual\ncorporate meeting of every church incorporated under this article shall\nbe held at the time and place fixed by its by-laws, or if no time and\nplace be so fixed, then at a time and place to be first fixed by its\ntrustees, but to be changed only by a by-law adopted at an annual\nmeeting.\n  2. A special corporate meeting of any such church may be called by the\nboard of trustees thereof, on its own motion, and shall be called on the\nwritten request of at least ten qualified voters of such church.\n  3. The trustees shall cause notice of the time and place of such\nannual corporate meeting, therein specifying the names of any trustees,\nwhose successors are to be elected thereat and the business to be\ntransacted thereat, and, if a special meeting, specifying business to be\ntransacted thereat, to be publicly read at two successive regular\nmeetings for public worship or at special meetings of such church on the\ntwo Sundays immediately preceding the annual or special corporate\nmeeting, by the rector of such church or if there be none or he be\nnecessarily absent, by the officiating minister thereof, if there be\none, or if not, or if any such minister refuse to give such notice, by\nany officer of such church. If no public worship be held during said\nperiod, or if it be the notice of special corporate meeting, a copy of\nsuch notice shall be posted conspicuously on the outside of the main\nentrance to the usual or principal place of worship at least fifteen\ndays before such meeting and a copy of such notice shall be sent by mail\npostpaid at least ten days prior to the date set for such meeting to\neach member of such church in good and regular standing by admission\ninto full communion and membership therewith, in accordance with the\nrules and regulations thereof, and of the governing ecclesiastical body\nof the Byelorussian Autocephalic Orthodox Church, and who has been\nstated attendant at divine worship in such church and has regularly\ncontributed to the financial support thereof during the year next\npreceding such meeting, at his last known address as same appears in the\nrecords of the church.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>