<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-347"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-347"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="347"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-347/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-347/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-347/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-347/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_347">
        <num>347</num>
        <heading>The powers and duties of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 347. The powers and duties of trustees. 1. The trustees of an\nincorporated church to which this article is applicable shall have the\ncustody and control of all the temporalities and property, real or\npersonal, belonging to the corporation and of all the revenues therefrom\nand shall administer the same strictly in accordance with the\ndiscipline, rules, usages, laws and constitution of the Byelorussian\nAutocephalic Orthodox Church in America, and with the provisions of law\nrelating thereto, for the support and maintenance of the church\ncorporation or providing the members thereof at a corporate meeting\nthereof shall so authorize, of some religious, charitable, benevolent or\neducational object, conducted by such church, or connected with it, or\nthe governing ecclesiastical body of the Byelorussian Autocephalic\nOrthodox Church in America, and they shall not use such property or\nrevenue for any other purpose or divert the same from such uses.\n  2. By-laws or directions adopted at any corporate meeting of any such\nincorporated church shall control the subsequent action of its trustees,\nas to the temporalities and property or revenues therefrom, and as to\nthe care thereof, and changes in either thereof and disposition thereof.\n  3. The trustees of any such church shall have no power, without the\nconsent of a corporate meeting, to incur debts beyond what is necessary\nfor the care of the property of the corporation.\n  4. The trustees shall not prevent or interfere with the rector or\nother duly authorized ministers in the use of said property for\nreligious services or other proper meetings recognized by the law and\nusages of the Byelorussian Autocephalic Orthodox Church in America.\n  5. The trustees of an incorporated church to which this article is\napplicable, shall have no power to settle or remove or fix the salary of\nthe minister. The trustees shall also have no power to fix or change the\ntime, nature or order of the public or social worship of such church,\nexcept when such trustees are also the spiritual officers of such\nchurch.\n  6. The trustees of any such church shall be responsible to the\ndiocesan council or the convention (sobor) of the diocese within bounds\nof which such church is situated in accordance with the discipline,\nrules, usages, laws and constitution of the Byelorussian Autocephalic\nOrthodox Church in America and shall make reports to said diocesan\ncouncil or convention (sobor) which reports shall include all the items\nrequired.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>