<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-348"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-348"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="348"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-348/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-348/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-348/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-348/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_348">
        <num>348</num>
        <heading>Meetings of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 348. Meetings of trustees. 1. Meetings of the trustees of an\nincorporated church to which this article is applicable may be held at\nstated intervals, or shall be called by the chairman of the board of\ntrustees on his own motion, or upon request of one of the clergymen\ntrustees or any two of the laymen trustees by giving at least\ntwenty-four hours notice thereof personally or by mail to all trustees,\nbut by the unanimous consent of the trustees a meeting may be held\nwithout previous notice thereof.\n  2. To duly constitute such regular or special meeting of the trustees\nfor the transaction of business, at any meeting lawfully convened, there\nshall be present a majority of the laymen trustees, the archbishop, or\nbishop, who is administrator of the Byelorussian Autocephalic Orthodox\nChurch in America, the rector of the church, unless there is no rector\nat that time, or he shall be necessarily absent, and the clerk of the\ncorporation. If the archbishop, or bishop, cannot be present, he may\nsend his proxy to one of the laymen trustees.\n  3. The chairman of the board of trustees shall preside or if he shall\nbe necessarily absent, the rector shall preside at the meeting.\n  4. No act or procedure other than regular routine matters in regard to\nthe administration of the temporal affairs of the church and for the\ncare of the property of the corporation, as included in the budget\nitems, shall be valid without the sanction of the archbishop, or bishop,\nwho is administrator of the Byelorussian Autocephalic Orthodox Church in\nAmerica.\n  5. The effect of a tie vote creating a deadlock shall be to carry the\nquestion involved (with all pending questions appertaining thereto) over\nto the next meeting of the board. In case of such a deadlock extending\nbeyond three successive meetings of the board of trustees, the whole\nmatter involved shall be settled in a meeting of the corporate society.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>