<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-402"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-402"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="402"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_402">
        <num>402</num>
        <heading>Meeting for incorporation of unincorporated society</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 402. Meeting for incorporation of unincorporated society. At a\nmeeting for incorporation held pursuant to section four hundred one, the\nqualified voters, until otherwise decided as hereafter provided, shall\nbe all persons of full age who are members of the unincorporated\nsociety, according to its rules or usages, for at least one year prior\nto the meeting or since it was formed.\n  At such meeting the presence of a majority of such qualified voters,\nin person, at least six in number, shall be necessary to constitute a\nquorum, and all matters or questions shall be decided by a majority of\nthe qualified voters voting thereon. The meeting shall be called to\norder by one of the signers of the call. There shall be elected at such\nmeeting, from the qualified voters then present, a presiding officer, a\nclerk to keep the record of the proceedings of the meeting and two\ninspectors of election to receive the ballots cast. The presiding\nofficer and the inspectors shall decide the result of the ballots cast\non any matter, and shall be the judges of the qualifications of the\nvoters.\n  If the meeting shall decide that such unincorporated society shall\nbecome incorporated, the meeting shall also decide upon the name of the\nproposed corporation, the number of the trustees thereof, which shall be\nnot less than three and not more than twelve, and the date, not more\nthan fifteen months thereafter, on which the first annual election of\nthe trustees thereof shall be held.\n  Such meeting shall also adopt by-laws and then elect by ballot\ntrustees in accordance with the provisions of such by-laws.\n  Thereafter, the officers of the corporation shall be elected in\naccordance with the by-laws.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>