<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-406"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-406"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="406"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-406/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-406/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-406/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-406/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_406">
        <num>406</num>
        <heading>Time, place and notice of corporate meetings</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_406__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The annual\ncorporate meeting of every society incorporated under this article shall\nbe held at the time and place fixed by its by-laws, or if no time and\nplace be so fixed, then at a time and place to be first fixed by its\ntrustees, but to be changed only by a by-law adopted at an annual\nmeeting.\n  A special corporate meeting of any such society may be called by the\nboard of trustees thereof, on its own motion, and shall be called on the\nwritten request of at least ten qualified voters of such society and in\nsuch other manner as the by-laws may prescribe.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_406__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The notices of any annual or special meeting shall state the time\nand place where it is to be held and shall be mailed to each member\nentitled to vote not less than ten nor more than fifty days before the\nmeeting. Notices shall be mailed to each member at the address which\nappears on the books or records of the corporation.  The by-laws may\nprovide for additional methods of giving notice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_406__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notice of any special meeting shall state the purpose or purposes\nfor which the meeting is called and no business shall be transacted at\nsuch special meeting except that contained in such notice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_406__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any provision in the statute or a by-law that a particular action\ncan be taken only at a meeting "called for that purpose" shall be deemed\nto require notice of such purpose as provided in this section four\nhundred six. This does not preclude the transaction of other business at\nthe same meeting if the notice so states.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>