<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-413"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-413"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="413"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-413/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-413/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-413/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-413/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_413">
        <num>413</num>
        <heading>Dissolution</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_413__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever two-thirds of the voting members of\nthe society, present at a meeting called for that purpose, decide to\ndissolve the corporation, they may, by its duly elected officers or\ntrustees or such agents as may be elected at such meeting, make a\npetition to the supreme court for an order of dissolution.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_413__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such petition shall state:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_413__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The particular reasons or causes why dissolution is sought.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_413__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The location, extent and estimated value of the property of the\nsociety.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_413__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The particular object or purposes to which it is proposed to\ndevote any surplus of the proceeds of such property, such purposes to be\nconsistent with the general purposes of the Unitarian Universalist\nAssociation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_413__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The due compliance with the provisions of this section as to the\nauthorization of the filing of the certificate of amendment.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_413__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Copy of the petition shall be mailed to all members of the\ncorporation and shall be published at least once in a newspaper of\ngeneral circulation in the county where the society is located.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_413__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A copy of the petition shall also be mailed, by registered mail,\nto the Unitarian Universalist Association. The dissolution shall not\nrequire the consent of the Unitarian Universalist Association, but the\nUnitarian Universalist Association shall have a right to be heard in the\nproceedings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_413__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Proof of the notices required by subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_413__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_413__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof\nshall be filed with the supreme court and no hearing on the petition\nshall be held by the supreme court until four weeks have elapsed after\nthe giving of all such notices.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_413__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon consideration of the petition presented to the court, and\nafter any hearing which the court may in its discretion deem to be\nnecessary or appropriate to determine any facts pertinent to the relief\nrequested in the petition, the court may order the dissolution of the\nsociety, and for that purpose and upon such terms and conditions deemed\nappropriate order and direct a sale and conveyance of any and all\nproperty belonging to such society.  After providing for the\nascertaining and payment of the debts of the society and the necessary\ncosts and expenses of such sale and proceedings for dissolution, the\ncourt may direct any surplus of the proceeds of such sale remaining\nafter paying such debts, costs and expenses, to be devoted and applied\nto any such religious, benevolent, educational or charitable objects or\npurposes consistent with the general purposes of the Unitarian\nUniversalist Association as the petitioners may suggest and the court\nmay approve.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>