<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-42-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-42-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="42-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-42-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-42-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-42-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-42-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_42_A">
        <num>42-A</num>
        <heading>Additional powers of the corporate trustees and vestry</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 42-a. Additional powers of the corporate trustees and vestry.\nNotwithstanding and in addition to the provisions of section five of\nthis chapter, and subject always to the trust in which all real and\npersonal property is held for the Protestant Episcopal Church and the\nDiocese thereof in which the parish, mission or congregation is located,\nthe vestry or trustees of any incorporated Protestant Episcopal parish\nor church, the trustees of every incorporated governing body of the\nProtestant Episcopal Church and each diocese are authorized to\nadminister the temporalities and property, real and personal, belonging\nto the corporation, for the support and maintenance of the corporation\nand, provided it is in accordance with the discipline, rules and usages\nof the Protestant Episcopal Church and with the provisions of law\nrelating thereto, for the support and maintenance of other religious,\ncharitable, benevolent or educational objects whether or not conducted\nby the corporation or in connection with it or with the Protestant\nEpiscopal Church.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>