<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-421"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-421"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="421"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-421/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-421/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-421/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-421/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_421">
        <num>421</num>
        <heading>Assemblies of God schools; seminaries and agencies of social relief</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 421. Assemblies of God schools; seminaries and agencies of social\nrelief. 1. Any church school, biblical seminary for the preparation of\ncandidates for the ministry leading to ordination and the granting of\ncredentials of ecclesiastical degrees in theology, other than those\nauthorized by the rules of the board of regents, or association\nestablished for evangelical efforts or for the relief of the poor and\nthe socially needy, which is intended to be an auxiliary organization of\nthe Assemblies of God and where a chapel for the conduct of worship is\nprovided, shall be deemed a church to all intents and purposes and be\nsubject thereby to all the provisions of this article, except where\notherwise indicated, and may be incorporated or reincorporated in the\nmanner prescribed in this article as a church of the Assemblies of God.\n  2. Such church school, biblical seminary or association, shall be\nrequired to adopt a constitution and by-laws not inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this article. The constitution and by-laws must be\nsubmitted to the New York district of the Assemblies of God for approval\nin writing, and become effective and binding only upon receipt of such\napproval. All future amendments to the constitution and by-laws shall\nnot be inconsistent with the provisions of this article.\n  3. In any case where such church school, biblical seminary or\nassociation does not have within its organization the positions of a\nminister or officiating minister and where the provisions of any section\nof this article designate such person or persons to fulfill any function\npertaining to incorporation or corporate affairs, there shall be\nsubstituted therefor the names of whatever persons or positions are\ndesignated in the organization's duly approved constitution and by-laws\nto fulfill functions of leadership.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>