<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-424"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-424"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="424"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-424/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-424/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-424/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-424/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_424">
        <num>424</num>
        <heading>Notice of meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 424. Notice of meeting for incorporation. Notice of a meeting for\nthe purpose of incorporating an unincorporated church shall be given as\nfollows:\n  1. The notice shall be in writing and shall state, in substance, that\na meeting of such unincorporated church will be held at its usual place\nof worship at a specified day and hour for the purpose of incorporating\nsuch church and electing any multiple of three trustees thereof but not\nto exceed twenty-four.\n  2. The notice must by signed by at least six qualified voters. A copy\nof such notice shall be publicly read at each of the two consecutive\nSunday mornings, or main worship services of such unincorporated church\npreceding the meeting to incorporate, by the first named of the\nfollowing persons who is present thereat, to wit: the minister of such\nchurch, the officiating minister thereof, the members of the church in\nthe order of their age beginning with the oldest, or any person\nqualified to sign such notice.\n  3. In the case where a church school, biblical seminary or association\nof the type set forth in subdivision one of section four hundred\ntwenty-one of this article does not hold regular Sunday worship\nservices, written notice of the time and place of the meeting for\nincorporation shall be delivered or read according to the manner\nprescribed by the duly approved constitution and by-laws of such body\nintending to incorporate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>