<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-427"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-427"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="427"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-427/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-427/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-427/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-427/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_427">
        <num>427</num>
        <heading>Reincorporation of present incorporated churches</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 427. Reincorporation of present incorporated churches. Any church\nheretofore incorporated may, subject to restrictions and limitations of\nexisting laws, reincorporate under the provisions of this article, by\nfiling in the county clerk's office in the county in which its principal\nplace of worship is located, a certificate, signed and acknowledged by\nthe district superintendent of the New York district of the Assemblies\nof God, and signed and acknowledged by all the trustees of said church\nin office at the time of such reincorporation, setting forth that the\nsaid church by majority vote desires to reincorporate under the\nprovision of this article, the corporate name by which such church shall\nbe known, the county, town, city or village where its principal place of\nworship is or is intended to be located and the names and addresses of\nthe trustees who are to hold office until the next annual meeting of\nsaid corporation. Such certificate shall not be filed unless endorsed\nthereon is the written consent of the New York district of the\nAssemblies of God.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>