<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-428"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-428"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="428"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-428/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-428/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-428/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-428/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_428">
        <num>428</num>
        <heading>Time; place and notice of corporate meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 428. Time; place and notice of corporate meetings. 1. The annual\ncorporate meeting of every incorporated church or body to which this\narticle is applicable shall be held at the time and place fixed by its\nby-laws.\n  2. Notice of the time and place of the annual corporate meeting\ncontaining therein the number of any trustees whose terms of office\nshall expire and whose successors are to be elected thereat, shall be\nposted and given by means of a public reading of such notice at all\nservices on at least two consecutive Sundays preceding such meetings of\nthe church or body, by the first named of the following persons who are\npresent thereat, to wit: the minister of such church, the officiating\nminister thereof, if there be one, or by any corporate officer of such\nchurch or body.\n  3. In the event of the absence of Sunday worship services, written\nnotice of the time and place of the annual corporate meeting shall be\ngiven by the board of trustees, either personally or by mail, to each\nqualified voter not less than ten nor more than twenty days before such\nmeeting.\n  4. A special corporate meeting of the church or body may be called by\nthe minister of such church or body, the board of trustees, or on the\nwritten application of at least twenty percent of the qualified voters,\nbut in no event by less than five qualified voters.\n  5. Written notice of the time and place of the special meeting,\ntogether with a statement of the business to be transacted thereat,\nshall be given by the board of trustees either by posting a public\nannouncement at all services on at least two consecutive Sundays\npreceding such meeting or by mail, upon each qualified voter, not less\nthan ten nor more than twenty days before the special meeting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>