<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-429"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-429"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="429"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-429/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-429/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-429/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-429/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_429">
        <num>429</num>
        <heading>Corporate meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 429. Corporate meetings. 1. Each church shall determine the\nrequirements for a quorum in their by-laws.\n  2. The action of the meeting upon any matter or question shall be\ndecided in a manner provided by the by-laws.\n  3. The first named of the following persons who are present at such\nmeeting shall preside thereat: the minister of such church, a qualified\nvoter designated by the minister, or voter elected thereto at the\nmeeting. The presiding officer of the meeting shall receive the votes,\nbe the judge of qualifications of voters and declare the result of the\nvotes cast on any matter.\n  4. At each annual corporate meeting, successors to those trustees\nwhose terms of office then expires, shall be elected from the qualified\nvoters for a term of three years thereafter.\n  5. If at any meeting of the church the actions of the minister are to\nbe voted upon because of disagreements with the congregation, or a\nchange in his teachings from the doctrines of the Assemblies of God, or\nhis conduct, the minister shall not chair such meeting. A district\nofficial is to be invited to chair such a meeting. The minister, being a\nmember of said congregation, may speak at such meeting.\n  6. Only the members of the church at its annual meeting, or at a\nspecial meeting called for that purpose, have the power to call or\nremove its pastor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>