<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-430"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-430"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="430"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-430/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-430/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-430/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-430/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_430">
        <num>430</num>
        <heading>Ownership of property</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_430__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That in the event that any church shall make a final decision to\nsever its affiliation with the general council of the Assemblies of God,\nthe trustees shall be deemed to hold title and retain ownership of all\ncorporate property, both real and personal, for the use and benefit of\nany members whose teaching and practice is in accord with the articles\nand tenets of faith set forth in the constitution of the general council\nof the Assemblies of God, as from time to time amended; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_430__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That in the event that any church shall make a final decision to\nsever its affiliation with the general council of the Assemblies of God,\nthe trustees shall be deemed to hold title and retain ownership of all\ncorporate property, both real and personal, for the use and benefit of\nthe majority of its membership.\n  3. Any church incorporated or reincorporated under this article shall\nprovide in its certificate of incorporation or reincorporation, that\nprior to any final decision by the church to sever its affiliation with\nthe general council of the Assemblies of God, the pastor and/or the\nchurch council shall invite the officiary of the New York district of\nthe Assemblies of God or its successor, to participate in a specially\ncalled business meeting for the express purpose of giving the district\nofficiary the opportunity to present the case for continued general\ncouncil affiliation.\n  4. In the event that members of a body incorporated or reincorporated\nunder this article shall commence or advocate a doctrinal teaching or a\nreligious or social activity which contravenes the accepted teaching and\npractices of the general council of the Assemblies of God, and should\nserious and apparently irreconcilable differences within the local body\nresult therefrom, and if the local corporate body is unable to resolve\nthe dispute, and there is need to determine which faction of such\ndispute is in accord with the provisions of the constitution of the\ngeneral council, either side of the dispute may appeal in writing to the\nsuperintendent of the New York district of the Assemblies of God, or its\nsuccessor. Upon receipt of such appeal, or by invitation of the pastor\nand/or the church council, in accordance with the general council\nconstitution and by-laws provisions, the district superintendent shall\nform a board of arbiters consisting of five in number and serve as\nchairman of such board. The board of arbiters shall consist of one\nrepresentative chosen by e...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>