<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-431"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-431"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="431"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-431/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-431/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-431/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-431/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_431">
        <num>431</num>
        <heading>Property of extinct Assemblies of God churches</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 431. Property of extinct Assemblies of God churches. 1. All\nproperty, both real and personal, belonging to or held in trust for any\nAssemblies of God church, incorporated or reincorporated or supervisory\nunder this article, that has or shall become extinct, shall at the\noption of the New York district of the Assemblies of God, vest in and\nbecome the property of the New York district of the Assemblies of God\nand its successors and assigns; provided that this section shall not\naffect the reversionary interests of any person or corporation in such\nproperty or any valid lien thereon.\n  2. An Assemblies of God church, incorporated or reincorporated under\nthis article, which fails to hold regular worship services, such\nservices being distinguished from committee or business meetings, for a\nperiod of six months, may be declared by the New York district of the\nAssemblies of God to be dissolved and extinct, said New York district of\nthe Assemblies of God being the immediate supervisory body over the\nlocal church within this state.\n  3. Whenever the New York district of the Assemblies of God dissolves\nor declares extinct a particular church under this section; upon\npetition by the New York district of the Assemblies of God to the\nsupreme or county court and upon satisfactory proof of the facts leading\nto such dissolution, the court shall have jurisdiction to grant an order\nto the effect that all property of whatever kind which may have belonged\nto or have been held by said church shall vest in the New York district\nof the Assemblies of God in as full and ample a manner as the same shall\ntheretofore have been vested in the church so declared to be dissolved\nand extinct. There shall be recorded in the office of the clerk of the\ncounty in which the church is located, a certified copy of the\nresolution of the New York district of the Assemblies of God declaring\nsuch church extinct and the court order transferring the title of the\nchurch property; and the recording of such a resolution and court order\nshall be proof of the vesting of title of the real property of such\nchurch in the New York district of the Assemblies of God.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>