<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-434"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-434"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="434"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-434/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-434/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-434/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-434/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_434">
        <num>434</num>
        <heading>Right of affiliation; relationships between churches, district corporations and the general council of the Assemblies of God</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 434. Right of affiliation; relationships between churches, district\ncorporations and the general council of the Assemblies of God. Churches\nshall be deemed to be sovereign, autonomous, self governing and self\ndetermining bodies. The affiliation of each church with the general\ncouncil of the Assemblies of God and the New York district of the\nAssemblies of God shall be in matters of doctrine and conduct. In the\nevent determination of disaffiliation with the general council of the\nAssemblies of God is under consideration by an affiliated assembly, the\npastor and/or the church council shall invite the district officiary to\nparticipate in a special called church meeting for the express matter of\ngiving the district officiary the opportunity to present the case for\ncontinued general council affiliation. Final disposition of the matter\nmay then proceed in accordance with the by-laws of the local church not\ninconsistent with this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>