<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-436"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-436"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="436"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-436/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-436/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-436/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-436/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_436">
        <num>436</num>
        <heading>District government</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_436__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be a district council\nfor the election of trustees, officers and for the general government as\nhereinafter set forth. The district council shall be the parent body and\nshall control the rights, duties and prerogatives of all its officers\nand subdivisions, in conformity with the constitution and by-laws of the\ndistrict, and the constitution and by-laws of the general council of the\nAssemblies of God, with headquarters in Springfield, Missouri.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_436__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The district council in session shall consist of all ordained and\nlicensed ministers of the district, other individual members as may be\nprovided for by the constitution and by-laws of the district corporation\nand such delegates as may be elected by assemblies to represent them and\nwho are present in the meetings of the district council. Delegates shall\nbe elected upon a basis of representation as may be agreed upon by the\ndistrict council, and as fixed by the by-laws of the said district.\n  2. The district corporation shall designate territorial limits of the\nregional sections within this state. Each section is entitled to one\ntrustee on the board of trustees of the district corporation.\n  3. The government of the district between district council sessions\nshall be vested in a board designated district presbytery. The district\npresbytery shall consist of the district superintendent, district\nassistant superintendent, the district secretary and the treasurer, the\nlast two offices may be combined, the general presbyters and the\npresbyters of the district sections, and others as may be provided for\nby the constitution and by-laws of the district corporation.\n  4. The above named officers and presbyters shall constitute the board\nof trustees of the corporation.\n  5. All officers shall be elected by the district council according to\nthe constitution and by-laws of the New York district of the Assemblies\nof God or its successor corporation. In the event that a trustee moves\noutside the territorial limits of the section from which he was first\nelected, resigns or is removed, his office shall be declared vacant and\nthe remaining trustees of the district shall according to the rules and\nregulations of the constitution and by-laws of the New York district of\nthe Assemblies of God or its successor corporation, elect a trustee to\nfill such unexpired term.\n  6. In addition to said trustees, said corporation shall have the\nfollowing officers: preside...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>