<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-451"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-451"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="451"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-451/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-451/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-451/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-451/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_451">
        <num>451</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 451. Definitions. As used in this article, the following terms shall\nhave the following meanings:\n  1. "Coptic Orthodox Church" refers to the Apostolic Church presided\nover by His Holiness, the Pope of Alexandria (Egypt) and the Patriarch\nof the See of St. Mark, the legislative body of which is known as the\nHoly Synod. The Coptic Orthodox Church is a hierarchical church.\n  2. "Holy Synod" is the highest legislative and executive authority in\nthe Coptic Orthodox Church, presided over by His Holiness, the Pope of\nAlexandria and the Patriarch of the See of St. Mark and is more formally\nknown as "The Holy Synod for the Coptic Orthodox Church of Alexandria\nand the See of St. Mark."\n  3. "The Synodical Committee for the Coptic Churches in Immigration"\nis, according to the constitution and bylaws of the Holy Synod, formed\nand presided over by His Holiness, the Pope of Alexandria and the\nPatriarch of the See of St. Mark from among the members of the Holy\nSynod, to assist him in marshalling the affairs of the churches abroad.\n  4. "Unincorporated Coptic Orthodox Church" in this state and a "Coptic\nOrthodox Church" heretofore incorporated in this state refers to a\nchurch, cathedral, chapel or other religious organization founded and\nestablished for the purpose of and with the intent of adhering to, and\nbeing subject to the administrative jurisdiction of the Synodical\nCommittee for the Coptic Churches in Immigration.\n  5. A "Bishop of the Coptic Orthodox Diocese" refers to that person who\nis serving as such bishop pursuant to the authority of and in accordance\nwith the rules and regulations of Synodical Committee for the Coptic\nChurches in Immigration. In accordance with the laws of the Holy Synod,\nthe Pope of Alexandria (Egypt) is the presiding bishop of any new\ndiocese during the foundation period and until a bishop is ordained for\nsuch diocese. Likewise, and pursuant to such laws, the Pope of\nAlexandria (Egypt) is the presiding bishop of any existing diocese which\nhas no bishop.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>