<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-453"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-453"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="453"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_453">
        <num>453</num>
        <heading>Reincorporation of existing corporations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 453. Reincorporation of existing corporations. Any Coptic Orthodox\nChurch heretofore incorporated in this state, with the consent of the\nbishop of the Coptic Orthodox Diocese in which its place of worship is\nlocated, may reincorporate under the provisions of this article by\nfiling in the office of the county clerk in the county in which its\nprincipal place of worship is located, a certificate, signed by the\ntrustees in office at the time of such reincorporation whereby the\nmajority of them setting forth that they desire to reincorporate under\nthe provisions of this article, the corporate name by which such a\nchurch shall be known, the county, town, city or village where its\nprincipal place of worship is located and the names of the bishop and\ntwo or more persons appointed by the bishop from among the priests and\ndeacons of such church, who shall constitute the initial board of\ntrustees of said church. Immediately upon the filing of such certificate\nall the right, title, equity and interest of such a church in any\nestate, real or personal, together with all franchise and charter\nrights, shall be vested in the body corporate so created under this\narticle and the original incorporation of such a church be null and\nvoid.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>