<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-464"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-464"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-11-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="464"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-464/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-464/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-464/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-464/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_464">
        <num>464</num>
        <heading>Meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 464. Meeting for incorporation. 1. At the meeting for incorporation\nheld in pursuance of such notice, only qualified voters shall be\neligible to vote.\n  2. The presence of one-third of the qualified voters or six qualified\nvoters, whichever number is higher, shall be necessary to constitute a\nquorum of such meeting. The action of the meeting upon any matter or\nquestion shall be decided by a majority of the qualified voters present.\n  3. The minister of the church, or if none, the officiating minister,\nshall act as presiding officer of the meeting to incorporate. The\npresiding officer shall call the meeting to order and shall be the judge\nof the qualification of voters.\n  4. Such meeting shall decide by ballot whether the church shall be\nincorporated, the name of the proposed corporation, the names of the\ninitial trustees, and the date, not more than fifteen months thereafter,\non which the first annual election or affirmation of the trustees\nthereof after such meeting shall be held. The trustees shall hold office\nuntil their successors are elected or affirmed.\n  5. At the meeting for incorporation, a constitution and by-laws shall\nbe adopted setting forth a form of church governance that is consistent\nwith section four hundred sixty-five of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>