<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-AA"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-AA"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-AA"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_AA">
        <num>50-AA</num>
        <heading>Application for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-aa. Application for incorporation. An unincorporated congregation\nof the Holy Orthodox Church in America, or a congregation acknowledging\nthe historic apostolic eastern confession and order in this state, may\napply to the archbishop who is the ecclestiastical administrator of\nMetropolitan Synod, Holy Orthodox Church in America for permission and\nsanction to incorporate such church. When such permission aforesaid has\nbeen obtained in writing over the signature and seal of such archbishop,\nsuch church may become an incorporated church by executing,\nacknowledging and filing a certificate of incorporation as hereinafter\nprovided.\n  Any religious order, biblical seminary for the preparation of\ncandidates for the ministry, leading to ordination and the granting of\ncredentials of ecclesiastical degrees of orders in sacred theology, or\nreligious society established for evangelical efforts or the relief of\nthe poor and needy, which is intended to be an auxiliary organization of\nthe Holy Orthodox Church in America, where a chapel for the conduct of\nworship is provided, shall be deemed a congregation to all intents and\npurposes, and may be incorporated in the manner prescribed in this\narticle as a congregation of the Holy Orthodox Church in America.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>