<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-BB"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-BB"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-BB"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_BB">
        <num>50-BB</num>
        <heading>Notice of meeting for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-bb. Notice of meeting for incorporation. Notice of a meeting for\nthe purpose of incorporating an unincorporated Holy Orthodox Church in\nAmerica, parish or congregation acknowledging the apostolic eastern\nconfession and order, shall be given as follows:\n  1. The notice shall be in writing and shall state in substance that a\nmeeting of such unincorporated church or congregation will be held at\nits usual place of worship at a specific day and hour, for the purpose\nof incorporating such church or congregation, electing laymen trustees\nthereof and selecting a corporate name therefor.\n  2. The notice shall also state that the archbishop who is the\necclesiastical administrator aforesaid has given sanction and permission\nin writing to proceed with the incorporation of such church.\n  3. The notice must be signed by at least six persons of full age, who\nare baptised, have statedly worshipped with such church or congregation\nand have regularly contributed to its support, according to its usages,\nfor at least one year or since it was formed.\n  4. A copy of such notice shall be publicly read at a regular meeting\nof such unincorporated church for public worship, on the two successive\nSundays immediately preceding the meeting, by the minister in charge of\nsuch church, or by any one of the persons qualified to sign such notice.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>