<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-DD"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-DD"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-DD"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_DD">
        <num>50-DD</num>
        <heading>Resolution to be adopted at incorporation meeting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-dd. Resolution to be adopted at incorporation meeting. At such\nmeeting held for the incorporation of such parish, church or\ncongregation as of the Holy Orthodox Church in America, by whatever\ncorporate name said church shall take, the following resolution shall be\npassed by a majority of the qualified voters of such meeting, to wit:\n  "Resolved, that whereas, it has been decided by a majority vote to\nincorporate said church under the name of (here give the corporate name\nby which such church is to be known) as a congregation of the Holy\nOrthodox Church in America and under the spiritual jurisdiction of\nMetropolitan Synod of such denomination; we likewise, by a majority vote\nof the duly qualified voters at this meeting, held for the incorporation\nof said church, now decide that the clergymen trustees of this said\nchurch shall be the archbishop who is the ecclesiastical administrator,\nthe vicar-general and the chancellor of the aforesaid metropolitan synod\nand the rector or vicar of this church, and their successors in office,\nshall by virtue of their offices, be the clergymen trustees of this\nchurch, which said four officers together with the ................\nlaymen trustees elected at this incorporation meeting, shall constitute\nthe trustees thereof. Said clergymen trustees' term of office shall\ncontinue until their successors in said office are elected by the\nMetropolitan Synod Holy Orthodox Church in America, and said laymen\ntrustees term of office shall be that fixed by statute. "\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>