<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-FF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-FF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-FF"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-FF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-FF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-FF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-FF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_FF">
        <num>50-FF</num>
        <heading>Annual and special corporate meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-ff. Annual and special corporate meetings. 1. The annual\ncorporate meeting of every church or congregation incorporated under\nthis article shall be held at the time and place fixed by its by-laws,\nor if no time and place is so fixed, then at a time and place to be\nfixed by its trustees, but to be changed only by a by-law adopted at an\nannual meeting; or if not otherwise fixed, such annual corporate meeting\nshall be held on the date said certificate of incorporation was\nexecuted, unless the same fall due on a Sunday or legal holiday in any\nyear, in which case said annual corporate meeting shall be held the day\nfollowing.\n  2. A special corporate meeting of any such church may be called by the\ntrustees thereof, on their own motion, and shall be called on the\nwritten request of at least ten qualified voters of such church.\n  3. The trustees shall cause notice of the time and place of its annual\ncorporate meeting, and the names of any trustees whose successors are to\nbe elected thereat, and if a special meeting, of the business to be\ntransacted thereat, to be publicly read by the minister of such church\nor any of the trustees thereof at a regular meeting of the church for\npublic worship, on the two successive Sundays immediately preceding such\nmeeting.\n  4. The annual corporate meeting shall be governed with respect to its\norganization and election of laymen trustees, clerk of the corporation\nand qualifications of voters (except with respect to age qualifications\nof voters as provided in section four-a) by the same provisions as set\nforth in this article for the incorporation of said church, except, that\nthe duly ordained and regularly appointed rector or vicar shall preside,\nor if there be a vacancy in such office, one of the wardens shall\npreside, the congregation in such case voting by ballot for its\npresiding officer.\n  5. The same provisions shall apply to a special corporate meeting.\n  6. At the annual corporate meeting the trustees shall cause to be\nprepared and read thereat a budget giving the approximate amount of\nmoney needed for the maintenance of worship, the administration of the\ntemporal affairs of the church and for the care of the property, and\nsuch other regular and special items as shall be brought to the\nattention of the meeting, which budget shall be discussed and decided\nupon, ratified or amended by the said meeting by majority vote, with\nample provision made to raise such funds by whatever usages the church\nshall elect.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>