<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-II"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-II"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-II"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-II/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-II/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-II/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-II/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_II">
        <num>50-II</num>
        <heading>Meetings of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-ii. Meetings of trustees. Meetings of the trustees of such\nincorporated church shall be called by giving at least three days'\nnotice thereof in writing, served personally or by mail to all of the\ntrustees, unless, by a regularly adopted standing resolution a fixed\ndate for such meeting is the approved order, in which case a written\nnotice may be dispensed with. To duly constitute such regular or special\nmeeting of the trustees for the transaction of business, at any meeting\nlawfully convened, there shall be present a majority of the laymen\ntrustees, the rector or vicar of the church, the clerk of the\ncorporation and either the archbishop who is the ecclesiastical\nadministrator, the vicar-general or the chancellor of the Metropolitan\nSynod Holy Orthodox Church of America. But if the church has no rector\nor vicar, at least one of the trustees who is a warden must be present.\nIf either the archbishop, vicar-general or the chancellor cannot be\npresent, the archbishop who is the ecclesiastical administrator may send\nhis proxy to one of the laymen trustees. No act or procedure other than\nregular routine matters in regard to the administration of the temporal\naffairs of the church and for the care of the property of the\ncorporation, as included in the budget items, shall be valid without the\nsanction of the archbishop and ecclesiastical administrator of the synod\nor diocese to which the church belongs; nor shall the trustees, without\nthe consent of the corporate meeting incur debts for items not provided\nin the adopted budget. Trustees of such incorporated church shall have\nno power to call, settle or remove a minister or to fix his salary; or\nto fix, change the time, nature or order of the public or social\nworship, rites and religious observances of such church which are or\nshall be established by the governing ecclesiastical body.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>