<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-KK"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-KK"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-KK"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-KK/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-KK/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-KK/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-KK/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_KK">
        <num>50-KK</num>
        <heading>Rector; vicar; ministers; their appointment, removal and compensation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-kk. Rector; vicar; ministers; their appointment, removal and\ncompensation. The rector or vicar or other ministers of any such church,\nby whatever title they are called in ecclesiastical language, shall be\ncalled, settled or removed and their salaries fixed, only by the vote of\na majority of the members of such corporation duly qualified to vote at\nelections present and voting at a meeting of such corporation\nspecifically called for that purpose, subject to the consent of the\narchbishop who is the ecclesiastical administrator of Metropolitan Synod\nHoly Orthodox Church in America, given in writing. A rector or vicar or\nother minister so called, with the sanction of the archbishop in\nwriting, shall be deemed settled definitely in such church, when he has\naccepted such call in writing. Unless there is sufficient cause to\nterminate the relationship of such clergyman and such church such\nrelationship shall be deemed permanent and governed entirely by the\nrules and usages of the Holy Orthodox Church in America, subject to the\narchbishop and Metropolitan Synod.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>