<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-MM"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-MM"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-MM"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-MM/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-MM/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-MM/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50-MM/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_MM">
        <num>50-MM</num>
        <heading>Transfer of property of extinct parishes and churches</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-mm. Transfer of property of extinct parishes and churches. The\nMetropolitan Synod Holy Orthodox Church in America may decide that a\nparish or church in connection with it or over which it has\necclesiastical jurisdiction, and to which this article is applicable,\nhas become extinct, if it has failed for two consecutive years next\nprior thereto, to maintain religious services according to the\ndiscipline, customs and usages of such synod, or has had less than ten\nresident attending members making annual or regular contributions\ntowards its support, and may take possession of the temporalities and\nproperty belonging to such church or parish and manage the same; or may,\nin pursuance of the provisions of this chapter relating to the\ndisposition of real property, sell or dispose of the same and apply the\nproceeds thereof to any of the purposes to which the property of such\nsynod is devoted, and it shall not divert such property to any other\nobject. For the purpose of obtaining a record title to the land and the\nchurch edifice, or other buildings thereon, by such synod, the surviving\ntrustee or trustees of said extinct church or if there be no surviving\ntrustee, then a surviving member of said extinct church, may, without a\nconsideration being paid therefor by such synod, convey to it said land\nand church edifice, or other buildings thereon, subject, however, to an\norder of the supreme or county court based upon a petition reciting that\nsaid church has become extinct; the name of its surviving trustee or\ntrustees; and the names of its members (who must have given their\nconsent to the making of said conveyance).  Upon the recital of said\nfacts in said petition, the court shall have jurisdiction to grant an\norder allowing said conveyance to be made without a consideration; and\nshould there be no surviving members, as well as no surviving trustee of\nsaid extinct church, said petition may be made by an officer of said\nsynod, in which event the court, upon the recital of said fact, shall\nhave jurisdiction to appoint a suitable person as trustee for the\npurpose of making said conveyance.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>