<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50">
        <num>50</num>
        <heading>Application for incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50. Application for incorporation. An unincorporated Apostolic\nEpiscopal Church, or a congregation acknowledging the historic apostolic\neastern confession and order in this state, may apply to the bishop who\nis the ecclesiastical administrator of Metropolitan Synod Apostolic\nEpiscopal Church for permission and sanction to incorporate such church.\nWhen such permission aforesaid has been obtained in writing over the\nsignature and seal of such bishop, such church may become an\nincorporated church by executing, acknowledging and filing a certificate\nof incorporation as hereinafter provided.\n  Any religious order, biblical seminary for the preparation of\ncandidates for the ministry, leading to ordination and the granting of\ncredentials of ecclesiastical degrees of orders in sacred theology, or\nreligious society established for evangelical efforts or the relief of\nthe poor and needy, which is intended to be an auxiliary organization of\nthe Apostolic Episcopal Church, where a chapel for the conduct of\nworship is provided, shall be deemed a congregation to all intents and\npurposes, and may be incorporated in the manner prescribed in this\narticle as a congregation of the Apostolic Episcopal Church.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>