<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-53"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-53"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="53"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53">
        <num>53</num>
        <heading>Resolution to be adopted at incorporation meeting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 53. Resolution to be adopted at incorporation meeting. At such\nmeeting held for the incorporation of such parish, church or\ncongregation as an Apostolic Episcopal Church, by whatever corporate\nname said church shall take, the following resolution shall be passed by\na majority of the qualified voters of such meeting, to wit:\n  "Resolved, that whereas, it has been decided by a majority vote to\nincorporate said church under the name of (here give the corporate name\nby which such church is to be known) as a congregation of the Apostolic\nEpiscopal Church and under the spiritual jurisdiction of metropolitan\nsynod of such denomination; we likewise, by a majority vote of the duly\nqualified voters at this meeting, held for the incorporation of said\nchurch, now decide that the clergymen trustees of this said church shall\nbe the bishop who is the ecclesiastical administrator, the vicar-general\nand the chancellor of the aforesaid metropolitan synod and the rector or\nvicar of this church, and their successors in office, shall by virtue of\ntheir offices, be the clergymen trustees of this church, which said four\nofficers together with the ............ laymen trustees elected at this\nincorporation meeting, shall constitute the trustees thereof. Said\nclergymen trustees' term of office shall continue until their successors\nin said office are elected by the Metropolitan Synod Apostolic Episcopal\nChurch, and said laymen trustees term of office shall be that fixed by\nstatute."\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>