<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-59"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-59"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="59"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-59/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-59/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-59/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-59/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_59">
        <num>59</num>
        <heading>Rector; vicar; ministers; their appointment, removal and compensation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 59. Rector; vicar; ministers; their appointment, removal and\ncompensation. The rector or vicar or other ministers of any such church,\nby whatever title they are called in ecclesiastical language, shall be\ncalled, settled or removed and their salaries fixed, only by the vote of\na majority of the members of such corporation duly qualified to vote at\nelections present and voting at a meeting of such corporation\nspecifically called for that purpose, subject to the consent of the\nbishop who is the ecclesiastical administrator of Metropolitan Synod\nApostolic Episcopal Church, given in writing. A rector or vicar or other\nminister so called, with the sanction of the bishop in writing, shall be\ndeemed settled definitely in such church, when he has accepted such call\nin writing. Unless there is sufficient cause to terminate the\nrelationship of such clergyman and such church such relationship shall\nbe deemed permanent and governed entirely by the rules and usages of the\nApostolic Episcopal Church, subject to the bishop and metropolitan\nsynod.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>