<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-6"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-6"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-6/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-6/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-6/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-6/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6">
        <num>6</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of property by religious corporations for branch institutions; establishment, maintenance and management thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6. Acquisition of property by religious corporations for branch\ninstitutions; establishment, maintenance and management thereof. Any\nreligious corporation may acquire property for associate houses, church\nbuildings, chapels, mission-houses, school-houses for Sunday or\nparochial schools, or dispensaries of medicine for its ministers, their\nwives, husbands and dependent children and for the poor, or property for\nthe residence of its ministers, their wives, husbands and dependent\nchildren, teachers or employees, or property for a home for the aged or\nnursery school or day care center. The persons attending public worship\nin any such associate house, mission-house, church building, or chapel\nconnected therewith shall not by reason thereof have any rights as\nmembers of the parent corporation. The persons statedly worshiping in\nany such house, mission-house, church building or chapel may, with the\nconsent of the trustees of such corporation, become separately\nincorporated as a church, and the parent corporation may, in pursuance\nof the provisions of law regulating the disposition of real property by\nreligious corporations, rent or convey to the new corporation, with or\nwithout consideration, any such associate house, church building,\nchapel, mission-house, school-house or dispensary and the lot connected\ntherewith, subject to such regulations as the trustees of the parent\ncorporation may make. Any religious corporation shall have power to\nestablish, maintain and manage by its trustees or other officers as a\npart of its religious purpose a home for the aged or nursery school or\nday care center, and may take and hold by conveyance, donation, bequest\nor devise real and personal property for such purpose, and may purchase\nand may erect suitable buildings therefor. Any such corporation may take\nand hold any grant, donation, bequest or devise of real or personal\nproperty heretofore or hereafter made upon trust, and apply the same, or\nthe income thereof, under the direction of its trustees or other\nofficers, for the purpose of establishing, maintaining and managing such\na home, school or center and for the erection, preservation, repair or\nextension of any building or buildings for such purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>