<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-64"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-64"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="64"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_64">
        <num>64</num>
        <heading>Changing system of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 64. Changing system of trustees. 1. If the trustees of an\nincorporated Presbyterian church in connection with the Presbyterian\nChurch (U.S.A.) shall at any time be elective as trustees and not\ntrustees by virtue of being spiritual officers, the church may, at an\nannual corporate meeting if notice thereof be given with the notice of\nsuch meeting, determine that the board of deacons thereof, or the\nsession with the board of deacons thereof, or the session thereof shall\nthereafter constitute the trustees thereof, and thereupon the presiding\nofficer of such meeting and at least two other persons present thereat\nshall sign, acknowledge and cause to be filed and recorded a certificate\nstating the fact of such determination, the names of the officers\ndetermined upon to be the ex officio trustees thereof and thereon the\nterms of office of such elective trustees shall cease, and the officers\ndetermined upon by such corporate meeting and their successors in office\nshall, by virtue of their respective offices, be the trustees of such\nchurch.\n  2. If, at any time, the spiritual officers of an incorporated\nPresbyterian church in connection with the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.),\nwhich officers by virtue of their offices constitute the trustees\nthereof, shall determine to submit to a meeting of such church\ncorporation the question whether the trustees of such church shall be\nthereafter elective as such trustees, they shall cause a special\ncorporate meeting of such church to be called and held in the manner\nprovided in section sixty-five of this chapter, and such corporate\nmeeting shall determine whether the trustees of such church shall\nthereafter be elective in pursuance of this article and also whether the\nnumber of such trustees shall be three, six, nine, twelve, fifteen,\neighteen, twenty-one, or twenty-four and the date of the annual\ncorporate meeting of the church. If such meeting shall determine that\nsuch trustees shall thereafter be elective as such trustees, the number\nof such trustees and the date of the first annual corporate meeting of\nthe church, the presiding officer thereof and at least two other persons\npresent and voting thereat shall sign, acknowledge and cause to be filed\nand recorded in the office of the clerk of the county in which the\ncertificate of incorporation of such church is filed a certificate of\nsuch determination of such meeting; thereafter the trustees of such\nchurch shall be elective in pursuance of this article.  At the next\nannual corporate meeting after the filing of such certificate, one-third\nof the number of trustees so determined on shall be elected to hold\noffice for one year, one-third for two years and one-third for three\nyears, the officers of such church who by virtue of their offices have\nbeen trustees of such church shall then cease to be such trustees and\nthereafter the trustees of such church and their successors shall be\nelective as such trustees as in this article provided. At each\nsubsequent annual corporate meeting of such church, one-third of the\nnumber of trustees so determined on shall be elected to hold office for\nthree years. The nomination and election of trustees shall be conducted\nas provided in the constitution of the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.).\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>