<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-66"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-66"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="66"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-66/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-66/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-66/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-66/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_66">
        <num>66</num>
        <heading>Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications of voters thereat</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 66. Organization and conduct of corporate meetings; qualifications\nof voters thereat. 1. At a corporate meeting of an incorporated church\nto which this article is applicable the following persons and no others\nshall be qualified voters, to wit: All persons who are then members in\ngood and regular standing of such church by admission into full\ncommunion and membership therewith, in accordance with the constitution\nof the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.).\n  2. The presence at any corporate meeting of an incorporated church of\nat least six communicant members of full age shall be necessary to\nconstitute a quorum. The action of the meeting upon any matter or\nquestion shall be decided by a majority of the qualified voters present.\n  3. At any corporate meeting of an incorporated church to which this\narticle is applicable, the pastor of such church, the officiating\nminister thereof, or the president of the board of trustees shall\npreside thereat.\n  4. Nothing contained in this article shall prevent the qualified\nvoters at any meeting held pursuant to this article from choosing a\nperson to preside at any corporate meeting of any incorporated church,\nother than the person or officer designated in this article to preside\nthereat, and when such other person shall be chosen he shall exercise\nall the powers in this article conferred upon the presiding officer of\nsuch meeting.\n  5. The presiding officer of a corporate meeting shall receive the\nvotes, be the judge of the qualifications of voters, and declare the\nresult of the votes cast on any matter. The polls of an annual corporate\nmeeting shall continue open until all qualified voters present shall\nhave had a full opportunity to vote.\n  6. At each annual corporate meeting successors to those trustees whose\nterms of office then expire shall be elected from the qualified voters\nby ballot for a term of three years thereafter. The nomination and\nelection of trustees shall be conducted as provided in the constitution\nof the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.).\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>