<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-69"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-69"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="69"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-69/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-69/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-69/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-69/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_69">
        <num>69</num>
        <heading>Trustees, their meetings, vacancies and filling thereof, their powers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 69. Trustees, their meetings, vacancies and filling thereof, their\npowers.  1. Two trustees of an incorporated church, to which this\narticle is applicable, may call a meeting of such trustees by giving at\nleast twenty-four hours' notice thereof personally or by mail to the\nother trustees. A majority of the trustees lawfully convened shall\nconstitute a quorum for the transaction of business. In case of a tie\nvote at a meeting of the trustees, the presiding officer of such meeting\nshall, notwithstanding he has voted once, have an additional casting\nvote.\n  2. If any trustee of an incorporated church to which this article is\napplicable, declines to act, resigns or dies, or ceases to be such\nmember, his office shall be vacant. Such vacancy may be filled at a duly\ncalled special meeting of the corporation.\n  3. Subject to the authority of the session, the trustees of an\nincorporated church to which this article is applicable shall have the\ncustody and control of all the temporalities and property belonging to\nthe corporation and of the revenues from such property and shall\nadminister the same in accordance with the constitution of the\nPresbyterian Church (U.S.A.), and with the provisions of law relating\nthereto, for the support and maintenance of the church corporation or,\nproviding the members thereof at a corporate meeting thereof shall so\nauthorize, of some religious, charitable, benevolent or educational\nobject conducted by such church or connected with it or with the\ndenomination with which it is connected, and they shall not use such\nproperty or revenue for any other purpose or divert the same from such\nuses.\n  4. The words "temporalities," "property," "revenue" and "revenues," as\nused in this section, or elsewhere in this article, shall not be\nconstrued to include the contributions in such church or elsewhere for\nbenevolent or other purposes, which shall be contributed and paid to the\npastor or pastors, ruling elders, the church session, or the deacons of\nany such church, either in the church services or otherwise, to be\ndistributed, or used, or administered, by them, or any, or either of\nthem, nor to any funds or property devised, bequeathed or contributed,\nto be administered or expended by such pastor or pastors, ruling elders,\nchurch session, deacons or other spiritual officers of such church.\n  5. The trustees of any such church shall have no power, without the\nconsent of a corporate meeting, to incur debts beyond what is necessary\nfor the care of the property of the corporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>