<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="RCO">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-92"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-92"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="92"/>
          <FRBRname value="RCO"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-92/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-92/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-92/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/rco/section-92/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_92">
        <num>92</num>
        <heading>Division of Roman Catholic parish; disposition of property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 92. Division of Roman Catholic parish; disposition of property.\nWherever a Roman Catholic parish has been heretofore or shall hereafter\nbe duly divided by the Roman Catholic bishop having jurisdiction over\nsaid parish, and the original Roman Catholic church corporation is given\none part of the old parish, and a new or second Roman Catholic church\ncorporation is given the remaining part of the old parish, and it\nfurther appears that by reason of the said division the original Roman\nCatholic church corporation holds title to real property situate within\nthe part of the old parish that was given to the new or second Roman\nCatholic church corporation, then the said Roman Catholic bishop or his\nsuccessor shall have the right and power, of himself, independently of\nany action or consent on the part of the trustees of the original Roman\nCatholic church corporation, to transfer the title of the said real\nproperty, with or without valuable consideration, to the said new or\nsecond Roman Catholic church corporation. Said transfer shall be made by\nthe said Roman Catholic bishop or his successor after having complied\nwith the requirements of this chapter in the same manner as the trustees\nof any religious corporation are compelled to do before making a\ntransfer of church property. If a valuable consideration is paid for the\ntransfer the same shall be received by the said Roman Catholic bishop or\nhis successor and distributed between the said original Roman Catholic\nchurch corporation and the new or second Roman Catholic church\ncorporation in such proportions as in the discretion of the said bishop\nor his successor may seem proper.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>