<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-1-201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-1-201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1-201"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-1-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-1-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-1-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-1-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1_201">
        <num>1-201</num>
        <heading>Construction of act of reconsolidation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1-201. Construction of act of reconsolidation. 1. This chapter shall\nbe construed as a continuation and re-enactment of the provisions\nrepealed by article nineteen hereof as such provisions existed on\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-two.\n  2. The repeal by this chapter of provisions specified in article\nnineteen hereof and the enactment of this chapter shall not affect any\naction or proceeding pending under any such provision at the time this\nchapter shall take effect.\n  3. Any act of the legislature of the year nineteen hundred sixty-three\nor nineteen hundred sixty-four which in form amends or repeals or\npurports to amend or repeal any provision or provisions repealed by\narticle nineteen of this chapter shall be legally effective\nnotwithstanding the repeal of such provision or provisions and shall be\nconstrued as an amendment or repeal, as the case may be, of the\ncorresponding provision or provisions of this chapter, and such\ncorresponding provisions shall be construed to be amended, modified,\nchanged or repealed as though they had been expressly and in terms so\namended or repealed.\n  4. Reference by any law, general or special, in force on December\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-two, or in any act of the\nlegislature of the year nineteen hundred sixty-three or nineteen hundred\nsixty-four, to a provision repealed by article nineteen of this chapter,\nas in force immediately before the time this chapter shall take effect,\nshall be construed to refer to the corresponding provision of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>