<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-101"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_101">
        <num>11-101</num>
        <heading>Compensation for injury caused by the illegal sale of intoxicating liquor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-101. Compensation for injury caused by the illegal sale of\nintoxicating liquor. 1. Any person who shall be injured in person,\nproperty, means of support, or otherwise by any intoxicated person, or\nby reason of the intoxication of any person, whether resulting in his\ndeath or not, shall have a right of action against any person who shall,\nby unlawful selling to or unlawfully assisting in procuring liquor for\nsuch intoxicated person, have caused or contributed to such\nintoxication; and in any such action such person shall have a right to\nrecover actual and exemplary damages.\n  2. In case of the death of either party, the action or right of action\ngiven by this section shall survive to or against his or her executor or\nadministrator, and the amount so recovered by either a husband, wife or\nchild shall be his or her sole and separate property.\n  3. Such action may be brought in any court of competent jurisdiction.\n  4. In any case where parents shall be entitled to such damages, either\nthe father or mother may sue alone therefor, but recovery by one of such\nparties shall be a bar to suit brought by the other.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>