<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-104"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-104"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-104"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-11-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_104">
        <num>11-104</num>
        <heading>Additional liability of drawer</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_104__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The drawer gave such check as payment for the rental of\nresidential premises; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_104__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The drawer gave such check as payment for residential service\nsupplied by a gas, electric, steam, telephone or water corporation; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_104__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The drawer gave such check as repayment of all, or a portion of, a\ndebt secured by collateral which the payee has repossessed.\n  5. Defenses which may be asserted against any person not having the\nrights of a holder in due course, as specified in sections 3-306 and\n3-408 of the uniform commercial code, shall be available to a defendant\nin any action or proceeding in which additional liability is claimed\nunder this section.\n  6. The additional liquidated damages provided for in this section\nshall be available only to those persons or entities which post or\notherwise give conspicuous notice to the public of the additional,\nliquidated damages which may be imposed pursuant to this section. Such\nnotice shall set forth the additional liquidated damages that may be\nimposed if a check is dishonored and the section of law authorizing\nimposition of such damages, and provide notice that criminal penalties\nalso may apply.\n  7. The first written demand for payment on the dishonored check shall\nbe in the form prescribed by subdivision eight of this section and shall\nbe sent to the drawer's last known residence address or last known place\nof business by first class mail and by certified mail return receipt\nrequested with delivery restricted to the drawer, on or after the date\nthe payee received notice that such check had been dishonored. The\nsecond written demand for payment on the dishonored check shall be in\nthe form provided in subdivision eight of this section and shall be sent\nto the drawer at the drawer's last known residence address or last known\nplace of business by first class mail on or after the fifteenth day\nfollowing the date of receipt of the first written demand for payment.\n  8. The written demands for payment required by subdivision seven of\nthis section, shall be in the following form and shall be printed in at\nleast ten point type in both the English and Spanish languages:\n                  DEMAND FOR PAYMENT OF DISHONORED CHECK\nDAT...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>