<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-15-702"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-15-702"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-702"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-15-702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-15-702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-15-702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-15-702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_702">
        <num>15-702</num>
        <heading>Surety disclosure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_702__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of a\nconsumer credit transaction becomes obligated on the transaction as a\nco-signer, co-maker, guarantor, endorser or surety, but who does not\nreceive the property, services, or money that is the subject of the\ntransaction. The term does not include a seller, holder or lender who\nbecomes obligated to an assignee of such party's rights; or (ii) in the\ncase of a consumer credit account becomes obligated under the agreement\nas a co-signer, co-maker, guarantor, endorser or surety with respect\neither to all purchases and loans, or a specified maximum dollar amount\nof purchases and loans that will be obtained from time to time pursuant\nto the agreement whether or not it is contemplated that the co-signer\nmay receive any of the property, services or money to be obtained. The\nterm does not include a seller, holder or lender who becomes obligated\nto an assignee of such party's rights or a joint applicant for credit\nwho is intended to be primarily liable under the agreement.\n  2. The creditor shall:\n  a. before a co-signer becomes obligated on a consumer credit\ntransaction, deliver to the co-signer a completed copy of each note,\ncontract, or other writing evidencing the obligation of the consumer or\nof the co-signer on the transaction, and a written notice that\nidentifies the debt the co-signer may have to pay and reasonably informs\nthe co-signer of his or her obligation with respect to it;\n  b. before a co-signer becomes obligated on a consumer credit account,\ndeliver to the co-signer a completed copy of the agreement establishing\nthe account, any other writing evidencing the co-signer's obligation and\na written notice that identifies the account the co-signer may have to\npay and reasonably informs the co-signer of his or her obligation with\nrespect to it.\n  If the creditor does not comply with the provisions of this section,\nthe co-signer shall not be obligated as a guarantor of payment as\ndescribed in subdivision one of section 3-...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_702__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as to a consumer credit transaction:\n                                 NOTICE\nYou agree to pay the debt identified below although you may not\npersonally receive any property, services, or money. You may be sued for\npayment although the person who receives the property, services, or\nmoney is able to pay. You should know that the Total of Payments listed\nbelow does not include finance charges resulting from delinquency, late\ncharges, repossession or foreclosure costs, court costs or attorney's\nfees, or other charges that may be stated in the note or contract. You\nwill also have to pay some or all of these costs and charges if the note\nor contract, the payment of which you are guaranteeing, requires the\nborrower to pay such costs and charges. If this debt is ever in default,\nthat fact may become a part of your credit record. This notice is not\nthe note, contract, or other writing that obligates you to pay the debt.\nRead that writing for the exact terms of your obligation.\n              IDENTIFICATION OF DEBT(S) YOU MAY HAVE TO PAY\n________________________________________________________________________\n                            (Name of Debtor)\n________________________________________________________________________\n                           (Name of Creditor)\n________________________________________________________________________\n                                 (Date)\n_________________________________ $ ____________________________________\n            (Kind of Debt)                    (Total of Payments)\nI  have  been  given a completed copy of this notice and of each writing\nthat obligates me or the Debtor on this debt.\n_________________________________  _____________________________________\n               (Date)                             (Signed)\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_702__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as to a consumer credit account:\n                                 NOTICE\nYou agree to pay the debts incurred from time to  time  on  the  account\nidentified  below  although you may not personally receive any property,\nservices, or money. You may be sued  for  payment  although  the  person\nopening  the  account  is able to pay. You should know that the Limit of\nLiability listed below does not include court costs or attorney's  fees,\nor  other costs or charges that may be stated in the agreement. You will\nalso have to pay some or all of these costs and charges if the agreement\nfor the consumer credit account, payment of which you are  guaranteeing,\nrequires  the  borrower  to  pay  such  costs  and  charges. If any debt\nincurred on the account is ever in default, that fact may become a  part\nof  your  credit  record.  This  notice  is  not the agreement, or other\nwriting that obligates you to pay. Read that writing for the exact terms\nof your obligations and of your rights to limit or end your obligations.\n            IDENTIFICATION OF ACCOUNT(S) YOU MAY HAVE TO PAY\n________________________________________________________________________\n                            (Name of Debtor)\n________________________________________________________________________\n                           (Name of Creditor)\n________________________________________________________________________\n                                 (Date)\n_________________________________ $ ____________________________________\n            (Kind of Account)                 (Limit of Liability)\nI  have  been  given a completed copy of this notice and of each writing\nthat obligates me or the Debtor on this account.\n_________________________________  _____________________________________\n               (Date)                             (Signed)\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>