<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-10-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="18-303"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_18_303">
        <num>18-303</num>
        <heading>Responsibilities of operators and visitors of agricultural tourism areas</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 18-303. Responsibilities of operators and visitors of agricultural\ntourism areas. 1. Operators of agricultural tourism areas shall have the\nfollowing additional responsibilities:\n  a. To post and maintain way finding signage to delineate the paths,\nareas and buildings that are open to the public;\n  b. To adequately train employees who are actively involved in\nagricultural tourism activities;\n  c. To post at every point of sale or distribution of tickets, whether\non or off the premises of the agricultural tourism area, a conspicuous\n"Warning to Visitors" relative to the inherent risks of participating in\nactivities on working farms and to provide written information having\nsuch text and graphics as the commissioner of agriculture and markets\nshall specify, which shall conspicuously direct the attention of all\nvisitors to the required "Warning to Visitors";\n  d. To post at every point of sale or distribution of tickets at an\nagricultural tourism area a conspicuous notice to visitors that pursuant\nto this article such visitors have a responsibility to exercise\nreasonable care regarding the disclosed risks of the agricultural\nactivity, and reasonably comply with posted way finding signs,\nreasonably remain in areas designated for the agricultural tourism\nactivity, reasonably follow any and all written and conspicuously posted\nrules of conduct provided by such operator to visitors or verbal or\nother communication for persons with disabilities, and not to willfully\nremove, deface, alter or otherwise damage signage, warning devices or\nimplements, or other safety devices;\n  e. To take reasonable care to prevent reasonably foreseeable risks to\nvisitors, consistent with the responsibility of a landowner to keep his\nor her premises reasonably safe for intended and reasonably foreseeable\nuses and users, and to post conspicuous notice to visitors of the right\nto a refund to the purchaser in the amount paid in the initial sale of\nany tickets returned to the operator of the agricultural tourism area,\nintact and unused, upon declaration by such purchaser that he or she\nbelieves that he or she is unprepared or that he or she is unwilling to\nparticipate in the agricultural tourism activity due to the risks\ninherent in the activities or the duties imposed upon him or her by this\nsection; and\n  f. Owners and operators of agricultural tourism areas shall not be\nliable for an injury to or death of a visitor if the provisions of this\nsubdivision are complied with.\n  2. Visitors to agricultural tourism areas have the responsibility to\nexercise reasonable care regarding the disclosed risks of the\nagricultural activity and:\n  a. to reasonably comply with posted way finding signs and reasonably\nremain in areas designated for the agricultural tourism activity;\n  b. to reasonably follow any and all written information or\nconspicuously posted rules of conduct provided by such operator to\nvisitors, or verbal or other form of communication of rules of conduct\nwhere needed for effective communication for people with disabilities;\nand\n  c. not to willfully remove, deface, alter or otherwise damage signage,\nwarning devices or implements or other safety devices.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>