<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-402"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-402"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="18-402"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-18-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_18_402">
        <num>18-402</num>
        <heading>Continuity of contract and safe harbor</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_18_402__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be deemed to impair or affect the right of any person to receive a\npayment, or affect the amount or timing of such payment, under any\ncontract, security, or instrument; or\n  (ii) have the effect of (A) discharging or excusing performance under\nany contract, security or instrument for any reason, claim or defense,\nincluding, but not limited to, any force majeure or other provision in\nany contract, security or instrument; (B) giving any person the right to\nunilaterally terminate or suspend performance under any contract,\nsecurity or instrument; (C) constituting a breach of a contract,\nsecurity or instrument; or (D) voiding or nullifying any contract,\nsecurity or instrument.\n  3. No person shall have any liability for damages to any person or be\nsubject to any claim or request for equitable relief arising out of or\nrelated to the selection or use of a recommended benchmark replacement\nor the determination, implementation or performance of benchmark\nreplacement conforming changes, in each case, by operation of section\n18-401 of this article, and such selection or use of the recommended\nbenchmark replacement or such determination implementation or\nperformance of benchmark replacement conforming changes shall not give\nrise to any claim or cause of action by any person in law or in equity.\n  4. The selection or use of a recommended benchmark replacement or the\ndetermination, implementation, or performance of benchmark replacement\nconforming changes, by operation of section 18-401 of this article,\nshall be deemed to:\n  a. not be an amendment or modification of any contract, security or\ninstrument; and\n  b. not prejudice, impair or affect any person's rights, interests or\nobligations under or in respect of any contract, security or instrument.\n  5. Except as provided in either subdivision one or subdivision three\nof section 18-401 of this article, the provisions of this article shall\nnot be interpreted as creating any negative inference or negat...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>