<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-107"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_107">
        <num>3-107</num>
        <heading>Certain contracts of parents or guardians respecting employment of infants not enforceable unless approved</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-107. Certain contracts of parents or guardians respecting\nemployment of infants not enforceable unless approved.  Where a contract\nproviding for performance or rendering of services by an infant is one\nwhich the supreme court or surrogate's court has jurisdiction to approve\nas provided in section 3-105 of this chapter, no parent or guardian of\nthe infant with respect to whose services the contract is made shall,\nunless the contract is so approved, be liable on the contract either as\na party or as a guarantor of its performance:\n  1. If the infant was a resident of the state at the time the contract\nwas made or at the time of the event by reason of which liability is\nsought to be imposed, by reason of any disaffirmance, repudiation or\nbreach of the contract or any term thereof, or any failure or refusal of\nthe infant to perform, or\n  2. In any other case, by reason of any failure or refusal of the\ninfant to perform or render services required or permitted by the\ncontract to be performed or rendered in this state or any failure or\nrefusal of the parent or guardian to cause such services to be rendered\nor performed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>