<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-112"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-112"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-112"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_112">
        <num>3-112</num>
        <heading>Liability of parents and legal guardians having custody of an infant for certain damages caused by such infant</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision two of section 65.10 of the penal law.  It shall also be a\ndefense to an action brought under this section that such infant had\nvoluntarily and without good cause abandoned the home of the parent or\nguardian and without good cause refused to submit to the guidance and\ncontrol of the parent or guardian prior to and at the time of the\noccurrence of such damages or destruction.  In no event shall it be a\ndefense that the parent or legal guardian has exercised due diligent\nsupervision over the activities of such infant, provided, however, that\nin the interests of justice, the court may consider mitigating\ncircumstances that bear directly upon the actions of the parent or legal\nguardian in supervising such unemancipated infant.\n  4. For the purposes of this section the following definitions shall\napply:\n  a. The terms "enters or remains unlawfully" and "building" shall have\nthe same meaning as ascribed to such terms in section 140.00 of the\npenal law.\n  b. "Public officer, organization or authority" shall include but not\nbe limited to: those having by law the care and custody of a municipal\ndistrict or corporation; those having by law the care and custody of the\npublic property of the state or of any agency, department, board,\nbureau, commission, division, office, council, committee of the state,\nor of a public benefit corporation or public authority; and the board of\neducation or trustees of any city, union free or common school district\nor the city board of any New York City community school district.\n  c. "Private individual or organization" shall include, but not be\nlimited to: any individual, private or public corporation or partnership\nor sole proprietorship, organized church, synagogue or temple,\nnot-for-profit organization or corporation, cemetery corporation, or, if\nsuch liability is as a result of damage upon any cemetery plot or\nmausoleum, the next of kin of a person upon whose gravesite such damage\nor destruction ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>