<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-315"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-315"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-315"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-3-315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_315">
        <num>3-315</num>
        <heading>Married woman's right of action for wages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-315. Married woman's right of action for wages. 1. A married woman\nshall have a cause of action in her own sole and separate right for all\nwages, salary, profits, compensation or other remuneration for which she\nmay render work, labor or services or which may be derived from any\ntrade, business or occupation carried on by her, and her husband shall\nhave no right of action therefor unless she or he with her knowledge and\nconsent has otherwise expressly agreed with the person obligated to pay\nsuch wages, salary, profits, compensation or other remuneration.\n  2. In any action or proceeding in which a married woman or her husband\nshall seek to recover wages, salary, profits, compensation or other\nremuneration for which such married woman has rendered work, labor or\nservices or which was derived from any trade, business or occupation\ncarried on by her or in which the loss of such wages, salary, profits,\ncompensation or other remuneration shall be an item of damage claimed by\na married woman or her husband, the presumption of law in all such cases\nshall be that such married woman is alone entitled thereto, unless the\ncontrary expressly appears.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>