<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-1511"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-1511"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-1511"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-1511/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-1511/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-1511/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-1511/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_1511">
        <num>5-1511</num>
        <heading>Termination or revocation of power of attorney; notice</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the principal dies;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the principal becomes incapacitated, if the power of attorney is\nnot durable;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the principal revokes the power of attorney;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the principal revokes the agent's authority and there is no\nco-agent or successor agent, or no co-agent or successor agent who is\nwilling or able to serve;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the agent dies, becomes incapacitated or resigns and there is no\nco-agent or successor agent or no co-agent or successor agent who is\nwilling or able to serve;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the authority of the agent terminates and there is no co-agent or\nsuccessor agent or no co-agent or successor agent who is willing or able\nto serve;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the purpose of the power of attorney is accomplished; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a court order revokes the power of attorney as provided in section\n5-1510 of this title or in section 81.29 of the mental hygiene law.\n  2. An agent's authority terminates when:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the principal revokes the agent's authority;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the agent dies, becomes incapacitated or resigns;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the agent's marriage to the principal is terminated by divorce or\nannulment, as defined in subparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\n5-1.4 of the estates, powers and trusts law, unless the power of\nattorney expressly provides otherwise. If the authority of an agent is\nrevoked solely by this subdivision, it shall be revived by the\nprincipal's remarriage to the former spouse; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the power of attorney terminates.\n  3. A principal may revoke a power of attorney:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in accordance with the terms of the power of attorney; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by delivering a revocation of the power of attorney to the agent\nin person or by sending a signed and dated revocation by mail, courier,\nelectronic transmission or facsimile to the agent's last known address.\nThe agent must comply with the principal's revocation notwithstanding\nthe actual or perceived incapacity of the principal unless the principal\nis subject to a guardianship under article eighty-one of the mental\nhygiene law.\n  4. Where a power of attorney has been recorded pursuant to section two\nhundred ninety-four of the real property law, the principal shall also\nrecord the revocation in the office in which the power of attorney is\nrecorded pursuant to section three hundred twenty-six of the real\nproperty law, provided the revocation complies with section three\nhundred seven of the state technology law.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Termination of an agent's authority or of the power of attorney\nis not effective as to any third party who has not received actual\nnotice of the termination and acts in good faith under the power of\nattorney. Any action so taken, unless otherwise invalid or\nunenforceable, shall bind the principal and the principal's successors\nin interest. A financial institution is deemed to have actual notice\nafter it has had a reasonable opportunity to act on a written notice of\nthe revocation or termination following receipt of the same at its\noffice where an account is located.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_1511__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Termination of an agent's authority or of the power of attorney is\nnot effective as to the agent until the agent has received a revocation\nas required by subdivision three of this section. An agent is deemed to\nhave received a revocation when it has been delivered to the agent in\nperson, or within a reasonable time after it has been sent by mail,\ncourier, electronic transmission or facsimile in accordance with\nsubdivision three of this section.\n  6. The execution of a power of attorney does not revoke any power of\nattorney previously executed by the principal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>