<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-302"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-302"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-302"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_302">
        <num>5-302</num>
        <heading>Contracts for the creation and use of digital replicas</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_302__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provision allows for the creation and use of a digital replica\nof the individual's voice or likeness in place of work the individual\nwould otherwise have performed in person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_302__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provision does not include a reasonably specific description\nof the intended use of the digital replica. Failure to include a\nreasonably specific description of the intended uses of a digital\nreplica shall not render the provision unenforceable when the uses are\nconsistent with the terms of the contract for the performance of\npersonal or professional services and consistent with the fundamental\ncharacter of the photography or sound track as recorded or performed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_302__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The individual was not:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_302__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>represented by legal counsel who negotiated on behalf of the\nindividual licensing the individual's digital replica rights and the\nlicensing terms are not stated clearly and conspicuously in an\nemployment contract that is separately signed or initialed by the\nindividual or in a separate writing that is signed by the individual; or\n  (ii) represented by a labor organization representing workers who do\nthe proposed work and the terms of their collective bargaining agreement\nexpressly address uses of digital replicas.\n  2. This section shall not affect provisions of a contract other than a\nprovision that falls under subdivision one of this section.\n  3. As used in this section, "digital replica" means a digital\nsimulation of the voice or likeness of an individual that so closely\nresembles the individual's voice or likeness that a layperson would not\nbe able to readily distinguish the digital simulation from the\nindividual's authentic voice or likeness.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>