<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-903"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-5-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_903">
        <num>5-903</num>
        <heading>Automatic renewal provision of contract for service, maintenance or repair unenforceable by contractor unless notice thereof given to rec...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-903. Automatic renewal provision of contract for service,\nmaintenance or repair unenforceable by contractor unless notice thereof\ngiven to recipient of services. 1. As used in this section, "person"\nmeans an individual, firm, company, partnership or corporation.\n  2. No provision of a contract for service, maintenance or repair to or\nfor any real or personal property which states that the term of the\ncontract shall be deemed renewed for a specified additional period\nunless the person receiving the service, maintenance or repair gives\nnotice to the person furnishing such contract service, maintenance or\nrepair of his intention to terminate the contract at the expiration of\nsuch term, shall be enforceable against the person receiving the\nservice, maintenance or repair, unless the person furnishing the\nservice, maintenance or repair, at least fifteen days and not more than\nthirty days previous to the time specified for serving such notice upon\nhim, shall give to the person receiving the service, maintenance or\nrepair written notice, served personally or by certified mail, calling\nthe attention of that person to the existence of such provision in the\ncontract.\n  3. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to apply to a contract\nin which the automatic renewal period specified is one month or less.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>