<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GOB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-7-101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-7-101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-08-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-101"/>
          <FRBRname value="GOB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-7-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-7-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-7-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gob/section-7-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_101">
        <num>7-101</num>
        <heading>Money deposited or advanced for use or rental of personal property; waiver void</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is not revocable by the person making such payment\nand is not otherwise subject to being returned or refunded to such\nperson, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>otherwise satisfies or discharges an equivalent liability\nunder such contract when such payment is made, whether or not such\nliability is otherwise then due and payable under the terms of such\ncontract.\n  1-c. This section shall apply to money deposited or advanced on\ncontracts for the use or rental of personal property as security for\nperformance of the contract or to be applied to payments upon such\ncontract when due, only if</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such contract is governed by the laws of\nthis state as the result of a choice of law provision in such contract,\nin accordance with section 1--301 of the uniform commercial code\n(subject to the limitations on choice of law by the parties to a\nconsumer lease under section 2-A-106 of the uniform commercial code), or\nsuch contract is otherwise governed by the laws of this state in\naccordance with applicable conflict of laws rules, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the lessee\nunder such contract is located within this state, within the meaning of\nthe uniform commercial code (with respect to the location of debtors),\nexcept that a foreign air carrier under the Federal Aviation Act of\n1958, as amended, shall not be deemed located in this state solely as a\nresult of having a designated office of an agent upon whom service of\nprocess may be made located in this state.\n  2. Any provision of a contract whereby a person who has deposited or\nadvanced money on a contract for the use or rental of personal property\nas security for the performance of the contract waives any provision of\nthis section is absolutely void.\n  3. This section shall not be applicable to any deposit or advance of\nmoney made in connection with the borrowing of securities for any lawful\npurpose.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>