<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LLC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1101"/>
          <FRBRname value="LLC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1101">
        <num>1101</num>
        <heading>Fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the reservation of a limited liability company name pursuant\nto section two hundred five of this chapter, twenty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the change of address of the post office address to which the\nsecretary of state shall mail a copy of any process against the limited\nliability company served upon him or her pursuant to section three\nhundred one of this chapter, twenty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the statement of address of the post office address to which\nthe secretary of state shall mail a copy of any process against the\nlimited liability company served upon him or her pursuant to section\nthree hundred one of this chapter, nine dollars. This fee shall not\napply to statements submitted through the department of taxation and\nfinance pursuant to paragraph two of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three\nhundred one of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the change of address of a registered agent for service of\nprocess by such registered agent pursuant to section three hundred two\nof this chapter, twenty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the resignation of a registered agent for service of process\npursuant to section three hundred two of this chapter, twenty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing articles of organization pursuant to section two\nhundred nine of this chapter, two hundred dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of amendment pursuant to section two\nhundred eleven of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing articles of dissolution pursuant to section seven\nhundred five of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing restated articles of organization pursuant to section\ntwo hundred fourteen of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a judicial dissolution pursuant to section seven\nhundred two of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing an application for authority pursuant to section eight\nhundred two of this chapter, two hundred fifty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing an amendment to an application for authority pursuant\nto section eight hundred four of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of surrender of authority pursuant to\nsection eight hundred six of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of termination of existence pursuant to\nsection eight hundred seven of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of merger or consolidation pursuant to\nsection ten hundred three of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_p">
          <num>(p)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing an application for cancellation of reservation of name\npursuant to section two hundred five of this chapter, twenty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_q">
          <num>(q)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of correction pursuant to section two\nhundred twelve of this chapter, sixty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_r">
          <num>(r)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of conversion pursuant to section one\nthousand six of this chapter, two hundred dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of publication with affidavits of\npublication annexed thereto pursuant to section two hundred six, eight\nhundred two, twelve hundred three or thirteen hundred six of this\nchapter, fifty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_t">
          <num>(t)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of resignation for receipt for process\npursuant to section three hundred one-A of this chapter, ten dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_u">
          <num>(u)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For service of process on the secretary of state pursuant to\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred one-A or pursuant to section\nthree hundred three of this chapter, forty dollars. No fee shall be\ncollected for process served on behalf of a county, city, town or\nvillage or other political subdivision of the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For filing a certificate of change pursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection two hundred eleven-A or subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eight hundred\nfour-A of this chapter, thirty dollars, and for filing a certificate of\nchange pursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section two hundred eleven-A or\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eight hundred four-A of this chapter, five\ndollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>