<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LLC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1308"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1308"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1308"/>
          <FRBRname value="LLC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1308/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1308/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1308/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-1308/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1308">
        <num>1308</num>
        <heading>Regulation of professions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1308__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This article shall not repeal,\nmodify or restrict any provision of the education law or the judiciary\nlaw or any rules or regulations adopted thereunder regulating the\nprofessions referred to in the education law or the judiciary law except\nto the extent in conflict herewith.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1308__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign professional service limited liability company, other\nthan a foreign professional service limited liability company authorized\nto practice law, shall be under the supervision of the regents of the\nuniversity of the state of New York and be subject to disciplinary\nproceedings and penalties, and its authority to do business shall be\nsubject to suspension, revocation or annulment for cause, in the same\nmanner and to the same extent as is provided with respect to individuals\nand their licenses, certificates and registrations in title eight of the\neducation law relating to the applicable profession.  Notwithstanding\nthe provisions of this subdivision, a foreign professional service\nlimited liability company authorized to practice medicine shall be\nsubject to the pre-hearing procedures and hearing procedures as are\nprovided with respect to individual physicians and their licenses in\nTitle II-A of article two of the public health law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1308__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign professional service limited liability company\nauthorized to practice law shall be subject to the regulation and\ncontrol of, and its authority to do business shall be subject to\nsuspension, revocation or annulment for cause by, the appellate division\nof the supreme court and the court of appeals in the same manner and to\nthe same extent provided in the judiciary law with respect to individual\nattorneys and counselors-at-law. Such limited liability company need not\nqualify for any certification under section four hundred sixty-four of\nthe judiciary law, take an oath of office under section four hundred\nsixty-six of the judiciary law or register under section four hundred\nsixty-seven of the judiciary law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>