<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LLC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-211-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-211-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="211-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="LLC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-211-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-211-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-211-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-211-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_211_A">
        <num>211-A</num>
        <heading>Certificate of change</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A limited liability company may\namend its articles of organization from time to time to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>specify or\nchange the location of the limited liability company's office; (ii)\nspecify or change the post office address to which the secretary of\nstate shall mail a copy of any process against the limited liability\ncompany served upon him or her; (iii) specify, change or delete the\nemail address to which the secretary of state shall email a notice of\nthe fact that process against the limited liability company has been\nelectronically served upon him or her; and (iv) make, revoke or change\nthe designation of a registered agent, or specify or change the address\nof the registered agent. Any one or more such changes may be\naccomplished by filing a certificate of change which shall be entitled\n"Certificate of Change of ....... (name of limited liability company)\nunder section 211-A of the Limited Liability Company Law" and shall be\nsigned and delivered to the department of state. It shall set forth:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name of the limited liability company, and if it has been\nchanged, the name under which it was formed;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the date the articles of organization were filed by the department\nof state; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_A__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>each change effected thereby.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A certificate of change which changes only the post office address\nto which the secretary of state shall mail a copy of any process against\na limited liability company served upon him or her, and/or the email\naddress to which the secretary of state shall email a notice of the fact\nthat process against it has been electronically served upon the\nsecretary of state and/or the address of the registered agent, provided\nsuch address being changed, and/or the email address being changed is\nthe email address of a person, partnership or other corporation whose\nemail address, as agent, is the email address to be changed, is the\naddress of a person, partnership or corporation whose address, as agent,\nis the address to be changed or who has been designated as registered\nagent for such limited liability company may be signed and delivered to\nthe department of state by such agent. The certificate of change shall\nset forth the statements required under subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section;\nthat a notice of the proposed change was mailed to the domestic limited\nliability company by the party signing the certificate not less than\nthirty days prior to the date of delivery to the department of state and\nthat such domestic limited liability company has not objected thereto;\nand that the party signing the certificate is the agent of such limited\nliability company to whose address the secretary of state is required to\nmail copies of process, and/or the agent of the limited liability\ncompany to whose email address of the secretary of state is required to\nemail a notice of the fact that process against it has been\nelectronically served upon the secretary of state, or the registered\nagent, if such be the case. A certificate signed and delivered under\nthis subdivision shall not be deemed to effect a change of location of\nthe office of the limited liability company in whose behalf such\ncertificate is filed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>