<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LLC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="303"/>
          <FRBRname value="LLC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_303">
        <num>303</num>
        <heading>Service of process on limited liability companies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_303__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Service\nof process on the secretary of state as agent of a domestic limited\nliability company or authorized foreign limited liability company shall\nbe made in the manner provided by paragraph one or two of this\nsubdivision. Either option of service authorized pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be available at no extra cost to the consumer.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_303__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nPersonally delivering to and leaving with the secretary of state or his\nor her deputy, or with any person authorized by the secretary of state\nto receive such service, at the office of the department of state in the\ncity of Albany, duplicate copies of such process together with the\nstatutory fee, which fee shall be a taxable disbursement. Service of\nprocess on such limited liability company shall be complete when the\nsecretary of state is so served. The secretary of state shall promptly\nsend one of such copies by certified mail, return receipt requested, to\nsuch limited liability company at the post office address on file in the\ndepartment of state specified for that purpose.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_303__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Electronically\nsubmitting a copy of the process to the department of state together\nwith the statutory fee, which fee shall be a taxable disbursement,\nthrough an electronic system operated by the department of state,\nprovided the domestic or authorized foreign limited liability company\nhas an email address on file in the department of state to which the\nsecretary of state shall email a notice of the fact that process has\nbeen served electronically on the secretary of state. Service of process\non such limited liability company shall be complete when the secretary\nof state has reviewed and accepted service of such process. The\nsecretary of state shall promptly send a notice of the fact that process\nagainst such limited liability company has been served electronically on\nhim or her to such limited liability company at the email address on\nfile in the department of state, specified for the purpose and shall\nmake a copy of the process available to such limited liability compan...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_303__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this section shall limit or affect the right to serve\nany process required or permitted by law to be served upon a limited\nliability company in any other manner now or hereafter permitted by law\nor applicable rules of procedure.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>