<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LLC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-804-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-804-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="804-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="LLC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_804_A">
        <num>804-A</num>
        <heading>Certificate of change</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_804_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign limited liability\ncompany may amend its application for authority from time to time to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_804_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nspecify or change the location of the limited liability company's\noffice; (ii) specify or change the post office address to which the\nsecretary of state shall mail a copy of any process against the limited\nliability company served upon him or her; (iii) specify, change or\ndelete the email address to which the secretary of state shall email a\nnotice of the fact that process against the limited liability company\nhas been electronically served upon him or her; and (iv) to make, revoke\nor change the designation of a registered agent, or to specify or change\nthe address of a registered agent. Any one or more such changes may be\naccomplished by filing a certificate of change which shall be entitled\n"Certificate of Change of ........ (name of limited liability company)\nunder section 804-A of the Limited Liability Company Law" and shall be\nsigned and delivered to the department of state. It shall set forth:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_804_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name of the foreign limited liability company and, if\napplicable, the fictitious name the limited liability company has agreed\nto use in this state pursuant to section eight hundred two of this\narticle;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_804_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the date its application for authority was filed by the department\nof state; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_804_A__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>each change effected thereby,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_804_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A certificate of change which changes only the post office address\nto which the secretary of state shall mail a copy of any process against\na foreign limited liability company served upon him or her, and/or the\nemail address to which the secretary of state shall email a notice of\nthe fact that process against it has been electronically served upon the\nsecretary of state, and/or the address of the registered agent, provided\nsuch address being changed is the address of a person, partnership or\ncorporation whose address, as agent, is the address to be changed,\nand/or the email address being changed is the email address of a person,\npartnership or other corporation whose email address, as agent, is the\nemail address to be changed, or who has been designated as registered\nagent for such limited liability company may be signed and delivered to\nthe department of state by such agent. The certificate of change shall\nset forth the statements required under subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_804_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section;\nthat a notice of the proposed change was mailed to the foreign limited\nliability company by the party signing the certificate not less than\nthirty days prior to the date of delivery to the department of state and\nthat such foreign limited liability company has not objected thereto;\nand that the party signing the certificate is the agent of such foreign\nlimited liability company to whose address the secretary of state is\nrequired to mail copies of process, and/or the agent of such foreign\nlimited liability company to whose email address the secretary of state\nis required to email a notice of the fact that process against it has\nbeen electronically served upon the secretary of state, or the\nregistered agent, if such be the case. A certificate signed and\ndelivered under this subdivision shall not be deemed to effect a change\nof location of the office of the foreign limited liability company in\nwhose behalf such certificate is filed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>