<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LLC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-805"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-805"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="805"/>
          <FRBRname value="LLC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-805/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-805/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-805/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-805/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_805">
        <num>805</num>
        <heading>Issuance of certificate of authority; effect</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon filing\nwith the department of state of the application for authority, the\ndepartment of state shall issue a filing receipt entitled "Certificate\nof authority of... (name of foreign limited liability company) under\nsection eight hundred five of the Limited Liability Company Law," and\nthe foreign limited liability company shall be authorized to do business\nin this state. Such authority shall continue so long as the foreign\nlimited liability company retains its authority to do business in the\njurisdiction of its formation and its authority to do business has not\nbeen surrendered, suspended or annulled in accordance with the law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign limited liability company that has received a\ncertificate of authority shall have such powers to conduct business in\nthis state as are permitted by the laws of the jurisdiction in which it\nwas organized but no greater than those of a domestic limited liability\ncompany; provided, that this subdivision shall not affect the powers of\nthe foreign limited liability company outside this state; and provided,\nfurther, that a foreign related limited liability partnership</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall\nhave such powers to conduct business in this state as are permitted by\nthe laws of the jurisdiction whose laws govern the agreement under which\nsuch foreign related limited liability partnership operates but no\ngreater than those of a partnership without limited partners operating\nunder an agreement governed by the laws of this state and provided that\nsuch foreign related limited liability partnership shall not engage in\nany profession or professions and (ii) shall be deemed to be a foreign\nlimited liability partnership for purposes of subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_805__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof section 121-1502 of the partnership law which subdivisions shall be\napplicable to foreign related limited liability partnerships.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>