<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LLC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-806"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-806"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="806"/>
          <FRBRname value="LLC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-806/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-806/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-806/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/llc/section-806/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_806">
        <num>806</num>
        <heading>Surrender of certificate of authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A foreign limited\nliability company may surrender its certificate of authority by filing\nwith the department of state a certificate entitled "Certificate of\nsurrender of authority of... (name of foreign limited liability company)\nunder section eight hundred six of the Limited Liability Company Law"\nsigned by an authorized person, or by a trustee, receiver or other\nperson authorized by law to wind up such limited liability company. The\nauthority of the foreign limited liability company to do business in\nthis state shall terminate on such filing of the certificate of\nsurrender of authority. A surrender shall not terminate the authority of\nthe secretary of state to accept service of process on the foreign\nlimited liability company with respect to causes of action arising out\nof doing business in this state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_806__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The certificate of surrender of authority shall set forth:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_806__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name of the foreign limited liability company as it appears on\nthe index of names of existing domestic and authorized foreign limited\nliability companies of any type or kind in the department of state, and\nthe fictitious name the foreign limited liability company has agreed to\nuse in this state pursuant to section eight hundred two of this article;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_806__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the jurisdiction where it was organized;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_806__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the date on which its certificate of authority to do business in\nthis state was filed with the department of state;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_806__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that it surrenders its authority to do business in this state;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_806__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that it revokes the authority of its registered agent, if any,\npreviously designated, and that it consents that process against it in\nany action or special proceeding based upon any liability or obligation\nincurred by it within this state before the filing of the certificate of\nsurrender may be served on the secretary of state in the manner set\nforth in article three of this chapter; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_806__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a post office address within or without this state to which the\nsecretary of state shall mail a copy of any process against it served\nupon him or her. The limited liability company may include an email\naddress to which the secretary of state shall email a notice of the fact\nthat process against it has been electronically served upon him or her.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>