<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_107">
        <num>10-107</num>
        <heading>Military voters; designation of means of transmission by military voters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 10-107. Military voters; designation of means of transmission by\nmilitary voters. 1. A military voter may designate a preference to\nreceive a voter registration application, a military ballot application\nor a military ballot by mail, facsimile transmission or electronic mail.\nSuch designation shall remain in effect until revoked or changed by the\nmilitary voter. If a military voter does not designate a preference, the\nboard of elections shall transmit the voter registration application,\nmilitary ballot application or military ballot by mail. If a military\nvoter designates a preference for facsimile transmission or electronic\nmail but does not provide the necessary facsimile number or e-mail\naddress, the board of elections shall transmit the voter registration\napplication, military ballot application or military ballot by mail and\nrequest the omitted information. All communications to the military\nvoter shall include the mailing address of the board of elections.\n  2. Irrespective of the preferred method of transmission designated by\na military voter, a military voter's original completed voter\nregistration application, military ballot application and military\nballot must be returned by mail or in person notwithstanding that a\nprior copy was sent to the board of elections by facsimile transmission\nor electronic mail.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>