<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-109"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-109"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-109"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_109">
        <num>10-109</num>
        <heading>Military voters; cancellation of registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 10-109. Military voters; cancellation of registration. 1. Voters\nregistered pursuant to this article shall be eligible to vote in every\nelection in which military voters are eligible to vote which is held\nmore than ten days after the date of the receipt of their applications\nfor such registration.\n  2. If any ballot, application form or other mail sent to a military\nvoter at his military address by the board of elections is returned by\nthe post office as undeliverable, the board of elections shall ascertain\nwhether the military voter is residing at the address given on his\nregistration records as his permanent address. If he is residing at such\naddress, the board shall not send him any further military ballots\nunless he applies for them in the regular way, giving a new military\naddress. If such military voter is not residing at such permanent\naddress, the board of elections shall send a confirmation notice to such\nmilitary voter at his last military address pursuant to the provisions\nof section 5-712 of this chapter and shall place the registration of\nsuch voter in inactive status.  However, if such a voter notifies the\nboard of elections that he has moved to a new military address, the\nboard shall restore the registration of such voter to active status in\nthe manner prescribed by section 5-213 of this chapter.\n  3. The board of elections shall process and preserve the records of\nsuch registrations, including the original applications for such\nregistrations, in the same manner and for the same period of time as the\nrecords of other voters registered under permanent personal\nregistration.\n  4. A military voter whose registration is cancelled pursuant to the\nprovisions of section 5-400 of this chapter shall be eligible to\nreregister in the manner provided by this article.\n  5. Upon cancelling the registration of a military voter pursuant to\nthe provisions of section 5-400 of this chapter, the board of elections\nshall forthwith notify such voter at his last military address and at\nhis permanent residence address of the fact of the cancellation, the\nreason therefor, and of his right to reregister pursuant to this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>