<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-106"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-10-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_106">
        <num>10-106</num>
        <heading>Military voters; registration and application for ballots</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any other method of registering to vote or of\napplying for a military ballot, a military voter may request a voter\nregistration application or military ballot application by facsimile\ntransmission to the board of elections or pursuant to the Uniformed and\nOverseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act or by electronic mail. When making\nsuch a request, the military voter may designate a preference for\ntransmission of such voter registration application and military ballot\napplication pursuant to section 10-107 of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The military ballot application shall allow the military voter to\ndesignate a preference for transmission of the military ballot pursuant\nto section 10-107 of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_106__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The procedures for receiving documents from and transmitting\ndocuments to a military voter shall, to the extent practicable, protect\nthe security and integrity of the military voter registration and\nmilitary ballot application request process and protect the privacy of\nthe military voter, including the voter's identity and other personal\ndata. Nothing in this paragraph shall limit the information that may be\nobtained pursuant to section 3-220 of this chapter.\n  4. Not earlier than the ninetieth or later than the seventy-fifth day\nbefore each general election, each county or city board of elections\nshall send, in accordance with the preferred method of transmission\ndesignated by the voter pursuant to section 10-107 of this article, to\neach person who is registered as a military voter and to every other\nmilitary voter in such county or city for whom it has a military\naddress, an application for a military ballot for such general election\nin a form prescribed by the state board of elections, which shall\ninclude a place for such military voter to enroll in a party, and shall\ninclude the return address of such board of elections.\n  5. The state board of elections shall forward to the appropriate board\nof elections all applications for military ballots received by it. An\napplication from a military voter not previously registered must be\nreceived by the appropriate board of elections not later than ten days\nbefore a general, primary, or special election in order to entitle the\napplicant to vote at such election. An application from a military voter\nwho is already registered must be received at least seven days before an\nelection in order to entitle the applicant to vote at such election;\nexcept that an application from such a military voter who delivers their\napplication to the board of elections in person, must be received not\nlater than the day before the election.\n  6. The board of elections shall immediately add to such registration\nrecord...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>