<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-104"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-104"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-104"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_104">
        <num>11-104</num>
        <heading>Registration and application for special presidential ballot</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-104. Registration and application for special presidential\nballot. 1. a. A person who, pursuant to the provisions of this title, is\nqualified to vote for president and vice president of the United States\nmay apply to the board of elections of his county of residence next\npreceding the place of his current residence for a special ballot for\npresident and vice president. Such applications must be mailed to such\nboard of elections not later than the seventh day before the election or\ndelivered to such board not later than the day of such election.\n  b. Insofar as the provisions of this chapter providing for voting in\nperson or by absentee ballot do not conflict with any provision of this\nsection, such provisions apply to a person authorized to vote under this\narticle.  In the case of any such conflict, the provision of this\nsection shall prevail and such other provision of this chapter shall not\napply.\n  2. a. A form of application for a special ballot under this section\nshall be furnished by the board of elections to the applicant who shall\nrequest such form within the time prescribed therefor. In addition,\napplication forms shall be supplied to the applicant's spouse, parent or\nchild, a person residing with the applicant as a member of his\nhousehold, or the applicant's duly authorized agent.\n  b. The board of elections shall mail a special presidential ballot to\nevery qualified voter otherwise eligible for such a ballot, who requests\nsuch a special presidential ballot from such board of elections in a\nletter, which is signed by the voter and received by the board of\nelections not earlier than the thirtieth day nor later than the seventh\nday before the election and which states the address where the voter is\nregistered and the address to which the voter has moved and the date of\nsuch move. The board of elections shall enclose with such ballot a form\nof application for special presidential ballot.\n  c. The application shall be made and signed by the applicant at the\nplaces thereon provided for such purpose and he shall set forth therein\nall of the facts required to establish his qualifications to register\nand vote under this article.\n  d. The form for use under subdivision one of this section shall be of\na distinctive color and in the form prescribed by the state board of\nelections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>