<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-106"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_106">
        <num>11-106</num>
        <heading>Processing of applications by board of elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-106. Processing of applications by board of elections. 1. The\napplication forms shall be in a form prescribed by the state board of\nelections.\n  2. Upon receipt of the application, the board of elections shall\ndetermine upon such inquiry as it deems proper whether the applicant has\nanswered all the questions contained in the application and whether the\napplicant is legally qualified to receive and vote a special\npresidential ballot, and, if it finds he is not so qualified, shall\nreject the application and shall notify the applicant of such rejection\nand give the reason or reasons therefor. All investigations by the board\nof elections shall be concluded and all determinations made not later\nthan the sixth day before election.\n  3. If the board of elections shall determine that the applicant making\nthe application provided for in this section is qualified to receive and\nvote a special presidential ballot, it shall, as soon as practicable\nafter it shall have so determined, mail to him at the residence address\nshown in his application, or deliver to him, or to any person designated\nby him in writing for such purpose, at the office of the board, such a\nspecial presidential ballot and an envelope therefor.\n  4. The board of elections shall keep a register of the persons who\nhave made and signed applications for special presidential ballots and\nof the applicants who have been determined to be qualified. The board\nshall keep open to public inspection such register of applicants with\ntheir names, addresses and application dates and shall give to the\nchairman of each political party in the county a complete list of\napplicants for special presidential ballots, containing their names and\nplaces of residence, including the election district and ward, if any,\nand, in the city of New York and the county of Nassau, the assembly\ndistrict.\n  5. The board of elections shall file each original application filed\nwith it and shall maintain an alphabetical index thereof for a period of\nthree years after the election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>