<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-203"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_203">
        <num>11-203</num>
        <heading>Special federal voters; designation of means of transmission by special federal voters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-203. Special federal voters; designation of means of transmission\nby special federal voters. 1. A special federal voter may designate a\npreference to receive a voter registration application, a special\nfederal ballot application or a special federal ballot by mail,\nfacsimile transmission or electronic mail. Such designation shall remain\nin effect until revoked or changed by the special federal voter. If a\nspecial federal voter does not designate a preference, the board of\nelections shall transmit the voter registration application, special\nfederal ballot application or special federal ballot by mail. If a\nspecial federal voter designates a preference for facsimile transmission\nor electronic mail but does not provide the necessary facsimile number\nor e-mail address, the board of elections shall transmit the voter\nregistration application, special federal ballot application or special\nfederal ballot by mail and request the omitted information. All\ncommunications to the special federal voter shall include the mailing\naddress of the board of elections.\n  2. Irrespective of the preferred method of transmission designated by\na special federal voter, a special federal voter's original completed\nvoter registration application, special federal ballot application and\nspecial federal ballot must be returned by mail or in person\nnotwithstanding that a prior copy was sent to the board of elections by\nfacsimile transmission or electronic mail.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>