<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-202"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_202">
        <num>11-202</num>
        <heading>Registration and enrollment of special federal voters and application for special federal ballot</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-202. Registration and enrollment of special federal voters and\napplication for special federal ballot. 1. a. A person, who, pursuant to\nthis title, is qualified to vote as a special federal voter may, by\napplication received by the state board of elections or any local board\nof elections on or before the tenth day next preceding any election in\nwhich such person would be entitled to vote or the last day of local\nregistration for such election, whichever is later, apply to the board\nof elections of the county in which they resided in person or by\npersonal application by mail for registration and enrollment as a\nspecial federal voter. An application for registration and enrollment\npursuant to this article shall be treated as an application for a\nspecial federal ballot for every election in which the applicant would\nbe eligible to vote which is held through and including the next two\nregularly scheduled general elections held in even numbered years,\nincluding any run-offs which may occur.\n  b. A person who, pursuant to the provisions of this title, is already\nregistered as a special federal voter, may, by application received by\nthe state board of elections or any local board of elections, apply to\nthe board of elections of the county in which he is so registered in\nperson or by mail for a special federal ballot. Such an application\nshall entitle such a voter to receive a ballot for every election in\nwhich such voter is entitled to vote which is held through and including\nthe next two regularly scheduled general elections held in even numbered\nyears, including any run-offs which may occur, provided, however, such\napplication shall not apply to any election held on or before the\nseventh day after receipt of such application.\n  c. Insofar as the provisions of this chapter providing for permanent\npersonal registration and enrollment, and enrollment by mail or special\nenrollment, and voting in person or by absentee ballot do not conflict\nwith any provision of this title, such provisions shall apply to a\nperson authorized to register and vote under this title; in the case of\nany such conflict, the provision of this title shall prevail and such\nother provision of this chapter shall not apply. For the purposes of\nthis title, any person eligible pursuant to the provisions of this\nchapter to vote by absentee ballot shall be eligible for absentee\nregistration and enrollment.\n  d. In addition to any other method of registering to vote or of\napplying for a special federal ballot, a special federal voter may\nrequest a voter registration application or request a special federal\nballot application by facsimile transmission to the board of elections\nor pursuant to the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act\nor by electronic mail. When making such a request, the special federal\nvoter may designate a preference for transmission of such voter\nregistration application and special federal ballot application pursuant\nto section 11-203 of this title.\n  e. The special federal ballot application shall allow the special\nfederal voter to designate a preference to receive the special federal\nballot pursuant to section 11-203 of this title.\n  f. The procedures for receiving documents from and transmitting\ndocuments to a special federal voter shall, to the extent practicable,\nprotect the security and integrity of the special federal voter\nregistration and special federal ballot application request process and\nprotect the privacy of the special federal voter, including the voter's\nidentity and other personal data. Nothing in this paragraph shall limit\nthe information that may be obtained pursuant to section 3-220 of this\nchapter.\n  2. a. A form of application for registration and enrollment as a\nspecial federal voter and for a special federal ballot or a form of\napplication for a special federal ballot by persons registered pursuant\nto this title shall be furnished by the board of elections to the\napplicant who shall request such form within the time limited therefor.\nThe application shall be made and signed by the applicant at the places\nthereon provided for such purpose and such applicant shall set forth\ntherein all of the facts required to establish his qualifications to\nregister and vote under this title.\n  b. The forms for use under this section shall be of a distinctive\ncolor and substantially in the form prescribed by the state board of\nelections and shall elicit all the information which may be necessary to\ndetermine eligibility to register and vote pursuant to the provisions of\nthis title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>