<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-208"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-208"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-208"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_208">
        <num>11-208</num>
        <heading>Special federal voters; cancellation of registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-208. Special federal voters; cancellation of registration. 1.\nVoters registered pursuant to this title shall be eligible to vote in\nevery election in which special federal voters are eligible to vote\nwhich is held on or after the thirtieth day after receipt of their\napplications for such registration.\n  2.  If any ballot, application form or other mail sent to a special\nfederal voter at his address outside the United States by such board is\nreturned by the post office as undeliverable, the board of elections\nshall send a confirmation notice to such special federal voter at such\naddress pursuant to the provisions of section 5-712 of this chapter and\nshall place the registration of such voter in inactive status. If the\nboard of elections subsequently receives notice of a new address outside\nthe United States for such voter, or notice that the voter is still at\nthe same address outside the United States, the board shall restore the\nregistration of such voter to active status in the manner prescribed by\nsection 5-213 of this chapter.\n  3. The board of elections shall process and preserve the records of\nsuch registrations, including the original applications for such\nregistrations, in the same manner and for the same period of time as the\nrecords of other voters registered under permanent personal\nregistration.\n  4. A special federal voter whose registration is cancelled pursuant to\nthe provisions of section 5-400 of this chapter shall be eligible to\nreregister in the manner provided by this title.\n  5. Upon cancelling the registration of a special federal voter\npursuant to the provisions of section 5-400 of this chapter, the board\nof elections shall forthwith notify such voter at his last address\noutside the United States of the fact of the cancellation, the reason\ntherefor, and of his right to reregister pursuant to this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>