<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-200"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_200">
        <num>11-200</num>
        <heading>Special federal voters; qualifications</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-200. Special federal voters; qualifications. 1. Every citizen of\nthe United States now residing outside the United States whose last\ndomicile in the United States immediately prior to his departure from\nthe United States was in the state of New York, shall be entitled to\nvote from such last domicile, as a special federal voter in all primary,\nspecial and general elections for the public offices or party positions\nof president and vice-president of the United States, United States\nsenator, representative in congress and delegates and alternate\ndelegates to a national convention, provided such citizen, at the time\nof such departure from the United States, could have met all the present\nqualifications of this chapter to vote in federal elections from such\nlast domicile, except the qualification with respect to minimum voting\nage, even though such citizen does not now maintain a place of abode or\ndomicile in the state of New York, and provided further that such\ncitizen does not maintain a place of abode or domicile, is not\nregistered to vote and is not voting in any other election district,\nstate, territory or possession of the United States and provided further\nthat such citizen has a valid passport or card of identity and\nregistration issued under the authority of the secretary of state of the\nUnited States.\n  1-a. Every citizen of the United States of voting age, residing\noutside of the United States, who has never resided within the United\nStates, and who has one parent who qualifies as a special federal voter\nunder subdivision one of this section, may register and vote as a\nspecial federal voter, from the qualifying parent's New York address,\nprovided that person is otherwise qualified and eligible to vote.\n  2. Every person registered pursuant to this title shall continue to be\neligible to vote in all elections in which special federal voters are\neligible to vote except that in order to vote at a primary election of a\nparty, a voter registered pursuant to this title must have been so\nregistered and enrolled in such party before the previous general\nelection; or, if such voter was not registered in New York state for the\nprevious general election, such voter must so register and enroll in\nsuch party not later than ten days before such primary; or, if such\nvoter was registered in New York state for the last general election,\nsuch voter must have had the same party enrollment with such\nregistration as such voter sets forth on their application for\nregistration and enrollment as a special federal voter.\n  3. A special federal voter who moves from one address outside the\nUnited States to another address outside the United States shall not\nhave to reregister unless his registration is cancelled pursuant to the\nprovisions of section 5-400 of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>