<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-206"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_206">
        <num>11-206</num>
        <heading>Special federal voters; preparation of registration poll records and central file registration records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-206. Special federal voters; preparation of registration poll\nrecords and central file registration records. 1. The board of elections\nshall prepare a registration poll record and a central file registration\nrecord for each voter registered pursuant to this title or shall enter\nthe name of each such voter into the computer files from which the\ncomputer generated registration list is prepared. Each such registration\nrecord shall be endorsed on both the front and rear with the endorsement\n"special federal voter". The records of special federal voters in such\ncomputer files shall be coded in a manner which distinguishes such\nvoters from the other voters in such files.\n  3. The central file registration records of special federal voters\nshall be maintained in a separate file at the appropriate office of the\nboard of elections.\n  4. The registration poll records of special federal voters shall be\nfiled, in alphabetical order, by election district. At each election at\nwhich special federal voters are eligible to vote, the registration poll\nrecords of all special federal voters shall be delivered to such\ninspectors of election together with the other registration poll records\nor the names of such voters shall be included in the computer generated\nregistration list. Such records shall be delivered either in a separate\npoll ledger or a separate, clearly marked section, of the main poll\nledger or be clearly marked in the computer generated registration list\nas the board of elections shall determine.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>