<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-204"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_204">
        <num>11-204</num>
        <heading>Processing of applications by board of elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-204. Processing of applications by board of elections. 1. The\nregistration application forms shall be in a form prescribed by the\nstate board of elections.\n  2. Upon receipt of an application, the board of elections shall\ndetermine upon such inquiry as it deems proper whether the applicant has\nanswered all the questions contained in the application and whether the\napplicant is legally qualified to receive and vote a special federal\nballot. If it finds he is not so qualified, the board shall reject the\napplication and shall notify the applicant of such rejection and give\nthe reason or reasons therefor in accordance with the preferred method\nof transmission designated by the voter pursuant to section 11-203 of\nthis title. All investigations by the board of elections shall be\nconcluded and all determinations made not later than the twentieth day\nbefore election.\n  3. If a federal post card application form is received from a person\nwho is qualified to vote as a special federal voter but who has not\npreviously registered pursuant to the provisions of this title, such\nfederal post card application form shall be treated in all respects as\nan application for registration and enrollment and a special federal\nballot pursuant to the provisions of this title. If such a federal post\ncard application form is received from a person already registered as a\nspecial federal voter pursuant to the provisions of this title, such\napplication shall be treated in all respects as an application for a\nspecial federal ballot pursuant to the provisions of this title.\n  4. If the board of elections shall determine that the applicant making\nthe application provided for in this section is qualified to receive and\nvote a special federal ballot, it shall, as soon as practicable after it\nshall have so determined, or not later than forty-six days before each\ngeneral or primary election or special election in which such applicant\nis qualified to vote, or three days after receipt of such an\napplication, whichever is later, mail to him or her at the residence\naddress outside the United States shown in his or her application, a\nspecial federal ballot, an inner affirmation envelope and an outer\nenvelope, or otherwise distribute same to the voter in accordance with\nthe preferred method of transmission designated by the voter pursuant to\nsection 11-203 of this title. The board of elections shall also mail, or\notherwise distribute in accordance with the preferred method of\ntransmission designated by the voter pursuant to section 11-203 of this\ntitle, a special federal ballot to every qualified special federal voter\nwho is already registered and who requests such special federal ballot\nfrom such board of elections in a letter, which is signed by the voter\nand received by the board of elections not later than the seventh day\nbefore the election for which the ballot is first requested and which\nstates the address where the voter is registered and the address to\nwhich the ballot is to be mailed. The board of elections shall enclose\nwith such ballot a form of application for a special federal ballot.\n  5. The board of elections shall keep a list of the persons who have\nmade and signed applications for special federal ballots and of the\napplicants who have been determined to be qualified. The board shall\nkeep open to public inspection such list of applicants with their names,\naddresses, party enrollments, and application dates and shall give to\nthe chairman of each political party in the county fifteen days before\neach election, a complete list of special federal voters eligible to\nvote in such election. Such list shall contain the names, party\nenrollments for a primary election and places of previous residence\nincluding the election district and ward, if any, and, in the city of\nNew York and the county of Nassau, the assembly district of all such\nvoters.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>