<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-302"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-302"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-09-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-302"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-11-302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_302">
        <num>11-302</num>
        <heading>Special ballots for board of election employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-302. Special ballots for board of election employees. A person\nwho is an employee of the board of elections or who has been appointed\nto serve as an inspector of elections, poll clerk or election\ncoordinator at a polling place other than the one at which he or she is\nregistered to vote, may deliver to the inspectors of election of the\nelection district in which he or she is registered, or to the board of\nelections, at any time during the period in which an application for an\nabsentee ballot may be so delivered pursuant to the provisions of this\nchapter, a written statement that he or she will be unable to appear at\nthe polling place for such election district on the day of an election\nbecause his or her duties as an employee of such board or as an\ninspector, poll clerk or election coordinator require him or her to be\nelsewhere. The board of elections shall provide such voter a special\nballot any time prior to the close of the polls on election day,\nprovided however that the distribution of such ballots to such voters\nshall be timed to afford such voters sufficient time to cast such\nballots prior to the close of the polls on election day. Such cast\nballots may be delivered to an office of such board of elections or to\nany board of inspectors not later than the close of the polls on\nelection day. Such ballots shall be retained at the board of elections\nand cast and canvassed pursuant to the provisions of section 9-209 of\nthis chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>