<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-12-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-12-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-08-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-106"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-12-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-12-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-12-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-12-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12_106">
        <num>12-106</num>
        <heading>Electoral college; vote of the electors</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 12-106. Electoral college; vote of the electors. Immediately after\nthe organization of the electoral college, the electors shall then and\nthere vote by ballot for president and vice president, but no elector\nshall vote for more than one person who is a resident of this state.\nThey shall name in separate ballots the persons voted for as president\nand vice president. They shall make and sign six certificates of vote of\nall the votes given by them, each of which certificates shall contain\ntwo distinct lists, one with the votes for president and one with the\nvotes for vice president. There shall be annexed to each of the\ncertificates of vote one of the lists of electors which shall have been\nfurnished to them by the state board of elections pursuant to section\n12-102 of this title. They shall seal up the certificates of vote so\nmade and certify upon each that the lists of all the votes of this state\ngiven for president and vice president are contained therein.\n  Notwithstanding any other section of law besides title four of this\narticle, each elector shall cast his or her ballot for president and\nvice president for the candidates for these offices who were nominated\nby the political party that nominated the presidential elector. Refusal\nor failure to vote for the candidates for president and vice president\nwho were nominated by the political party that nominated the\npresidential elector shall constitute a resignation from the office of\nelector, and any such vote by an elector shall not be recorded. The\nballots used by the elector shall bear the name of the elector. The\nremaining electors shall forthwith fill the vacancy in accordance with\nsection 12-104 of this title. Nothing in this subdivision shall be\ninterpreted as modifying or repealing title four of this article, the\nagreement among the states to elect the president by national popular\nvote.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>