<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-13-104"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-13-104"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-104"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-13-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-13-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-13-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-13-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_104">
        <num>13-104</num>
        <heading>Special provisions as to the time for holding a primary election in the city of New York in the year nineteen hundred eighty-one</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 13-104. Special provisions as to the time for holding a primary\nelection in the city of New York in the year nineteen hundred\neighty-one. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this chapter,\nthe times fixed for the annual primary election for the city of New York\nfor all judges of the civil court elected from municipal court districts\nand for delegates and alternate delegates to judicial district\nconventions and certain proceedings relating thereto shall be as\nfollows:\n  1. The first day for signing designating petitions for primary\nelections shall be the sixteenth day of June.\n  2. The first day to sign petitions for opportunity to ballot in\nprimary elections without naming a candidate shall be the seventh day of\nJuly.\n  3. The primary election shall be held on the twenty-second day of\nSeptember.\n  4. A judicial district convention for nominating candidates for public\noffice shall be held not earlier than the twenty-second day of September\nnor later than the sixth day of October.\n  5. A certificate of party nomination made at a judicial district\nconvention for an office to be filled at the general election shall be\nfiled not later than the seventh day of October.\n  6. A certificate of acceptance or declination, whenever required, of a\nparty nomination made at a judicial district convention, for an office\nto be filled at the general election shall be filed not later than the\nninth day of October.\n  7. A certificate to fill a vacancy caused by declination of a party\nnomination made at judicial district convention for an office to be\nfilled at the general election shall be filed not later than the\nthirteenth day of October.\n  * NB Expired December 31, 1981\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>