<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-114"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-114"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-114"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_114">
        <num>14-114</num>
        <heading>Contribution and receipt limitations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_114__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of a nomination or election for state\nsenator, ten thousand dollars, divided equally among the primary and\ngeneral election in an election cycle; and (ii) in the case of a\nnomination or election for member of the assembly, six thousand dollars,\ndivided equally among the primary and general election in an election\ncycle; provided however, that the maximum amount which may be so\ncontributed or accepted, in the aggregate, from such candidate's child,\nparent, grandparent, brother and sister, and the spouse of any such\npersons, shall not exceed in the case of any nomination for state\nsenator or member of the assembly an amount equivalent to the number of\nenrolled voters in the candidate's party in the district in which he or\nshe is a candidate, excluding voters in inactive status, multiplied by\n$.25 and in the case of any election for state senator or member of the\nassembly, an amount equivalent to the number of registered voters in the\ndistrict, excluding voters in inactive status, multiplied by $.25;\nprovided, however, in the case of a nomination or election of a state\nsenator, twenty thousand dollars, whichever is greater, or in the case\nof a nomination or election of a member of the assembly twelve thousand\nfive hundred dollars, whichever is greater, but in no event shall any\nsuch maximum exceed one hundred thousand dollars.\n  c. In any election for a public office to be voted on by the voters of\nthe entire state, or for nomination to any such office, no contributor\nmay make a contribution to any candidate or political committee in\nconnection with a candidate who is not a participating candidate as\ndefined in subdivision fourteen of section 14-200-a of this article, and\nno such candidate or political committee may accept any contribution\nfrom any contributor, which is in the aggregate amount greater than\neighteen thousand dollars, divided equally among the primary and general\nelection in an election cycle; provided however, tha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_114__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the\ncase of any election for party position, or for nomination to public\noffice, the product of the total number of enrolled voters in the\ncandidate's party in the district in which he or she is a candidate,\nexcluding voters in inactive status, multiplied by $.05, and (ii) in the\ncase of any election for a public office, the product of the total\nnumber of registered voters in the district, excluding voters in\ninactive status, multiplied by $.05, however in the case of a nomination\nwithin the city of New York for the office of mayor, public advocate or\ncomptroller, such amount shall be not less than four thousand dollars\nnor more than twelve thousand dollars as increased or decreased by the\ncost of living adjustment described in paragraph f of this subdivision;\nin the case of an election within the city of New York for the office of\nmayor, public advocate or comptroller, twenty-five thousand dollars as\nincreased or decreased by the cost of living adjustment described in\nparagraph f of this subdivision but in no event shall any such maximum\nexceed fifty thousand dollars or be less than one thousand dollars;\nprovided however, that the maximum amount which may be so contributed or\naccepted, in the aggregate, from any candidate's child, parent,\ngrandparent, brother and sister, and the spouse of any such persons,\nshall not exceed in the case of any election for party position or\nnomination for public office an amount equivalent to the number of\nenrolled voters in the candidate's party in the district in which he or\nshe is a candidate, excluding voters in inactive status, multiplied by\n$.25 and in the case of any election to public office, an amount\nequivalent to the number of registered voters in the district, excluding\nvoters in inactive status, multiplied by $.25; or twelve hundred fifty\ndollars, whichever is greater, but in no event shall any such maximum\nexceed one hundred thousand dollars.\n  f.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_14_114__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At the beginning of each fourth calendar year, commencing in\nnineteen hundred ninety-five, the state board shall determine the\npercentage of the difference between the most recent available monthly\nconsumer price index for all urban consumers published by the United\nStates bureau of labor statistics and such consumer price index\npublished for the same month four years previously. The amount of each\ncontribution limit fixed in this subdivision shall be adjusted by the\namount of such percentage difference to the closest one hundred dollars\nby the state board which, not later than the first day of February in\neach such year, shall issue a regulation publishing the amount of each\nsuch contribution limit. Each contribution limit as so adjusted shall be\nthe contribution limit in effect for any election held before the next\nsuch adjustment.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_14_114__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provided, however, that such adjustments shall not occur for\ncandidates seeking statewide office, or the position of state senator or\nmember of the assembly, whether such candidate does or does not\nparticipate in the public finance program established pursuant to title\ntwo of this article.\n  g. Notwithstanding any other contribution limit in this section,\nparticipating candidates as defined in subdivision fourteen of section\n14-200-a of this article may contribute, out of their own money, three\ntimes the applicable contribution limit to their own authorized\ncommittee.\n  2. For purposes of this section, contributions other than of money\nshall be evaluated at their fair market value. The state board of\nelections shall promulgate regulations, consistent with law, governing\nthe manner of computing fair market value.\n  3. As used in this section the term "contributor" shall not include a\nparty committee supporting the candidate of such party or a constituted\ncommittee suppor...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_114__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section one-c of the\nlegislative law or by subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_114__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 3-211 of the\nadministrative code of the city of New York, political action\ncommittees, labor unions, and any person who has registered with the\nstate board of elections as an independent expenditure committee\npursuant to subdivision three of section 14-107 of this article are\nprohibited from making loans to candidates or political committees;\nprovided, however, that a lobbyist shall not be prohibited from making a\nloan to himself or herself or to his or her own political committee when\nsuch lobbyist is a candidate for office.\n  7. For the purposes of this section, the number of registered or\nenrolled voters shall be determined as of the date of the general,\nspecial or primary election, as the case may be or as of the date of the\ngeneral election in any of the preceding four years, whichever date\nshall result in the greatest number and candidates running jointly for\nthe offices of governor and lieutenant governor in a general or special\nelection shall be deemed to be one candidate.\n  8. Except as may otherwise be provided for a candidate and his family,\nno person may contribute, loan or guarantee in excess of one hundred\nfifty thousand dollars within the state in connection with the\nnomination or election of persons to state and local public offices and\nparty positions within the state of New York in any one calendar year.\nFor the purposes of this subdivision "loan" or "guarantee" shall mean a\nloan or guarantee which is not repaid or discharged in the calendar year\nin which it is made.\n  10. a. No contributor may make a contribution to a party or\nconstituted committee and no such committee may accept a contribution\nfrom any contributor which, in the aggregate, is greater than sixty-two\nthousand five hundred dollars per annum.\n  b. At the beginning of each fourth calendar year, commencing in\nnineteen hundred ninety-five, the state board shall determine the\npercentage of the difference between the most recent available monthly\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>