<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-104"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-104"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-104"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_104">
        <num>14-104</num>
        <heading>Statements of campaign receipts, contributions, transfers and expenditures by and to candidates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-104. Statements of campaign receipts, contributions, transfers\nand expenditures by and to candidates. 1. Any candidate for election to\npublic office, or for nomination for public office at a contested\nprimary election or convention, or for election to a party position at a\nprimary election, shall file statements sworn, or subscribed and bearing\na form notice that false statements made therein are punishable as a\nclass A misdemeanor pursuant to section 210.45 of the penal law, at the\ntimes prescribed by this article setting forth the particulars specified\nby section 14-102 of this article, as to all moneys or other valuable\nthings, paid, given, expended or promised by him or her to aid his or\nher own nomination or election, or to promote the success or defeat of a\npolitical party, or to aid or influence the nomination or election or\nthe defeat of any other candidate to be voted for at the election or\nprimary election or at a convention, including contributions to\npolitical committees, officers, members or agents thereof, and\ntransfers, receipts and contributions to him or her to be used for any\nof the purposes above specified, or in lieu thereof, any such candidate\nmay file such a sworn statement at the first filing period, on a form\nprescribed by the state board of elections that such candidate has made\nno such expenditures and does not intend to make any such expenditures,\nexcept through a political committee authorized by such candidate\npursuant to this article. Such candidate may designate a committee of no\nless than three persons who shall be authorized to appoint and remove\nthe treasurer of any authorized committee of the candidate. The\ndesignation or revocation of the committee shall be evidenced in a\nwriting filed with the state board of elections by the candidate\nauthorizing the committee. The candidate may revoke such designation at\nany time. A committee authorized by such a candidate may fulfill all of\nthe filing requirements of this act on behalf of such candidate.\n  2. Statements filed by any political committee authorized by a\ncandidate pursuant to this article which is required to file such\nstatements with any board of elections shall file all such statements\npursuant to the electronic reporting system prescribed by the state\nboard of elections as set forth in subdivision nine-A of section 3-102\nof this chapter. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subdivision,\nupon the filing of a sworn statement by the treasurer of a political\ncommittee authorized by a candidate pursuant to this article which\nstates that such committee does not have access to the technology\nnecessary to comply with the electronic filing requirements of\nsubdivision nine-A of section 3-102 of this chapter and that filing by\nsuch means would constitute a substantial hardship for such committee,\nthe state board of elections may issue an exemption from the electronic\nfiling requirements of this article.\n  4. Political communications required to be filed with the state board\nof elections pursuant to section 14-106 of this article or subdivision\nfive of section 14-107 of this article may be filed electronically with\nthe state board of elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>