<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-108"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_108">
        <num>14-108</num>
        <heading>Time for filing statements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-108. Time for filing statements. 1. The statements required by\nthis article shall be filed at such times as the state board of\nelections, by rule or regulation, shall specify; provided, however, that\nin no event shall the board provide for fewer than three filings in the\naggregate in connection with any primary, general or special election,\nor in connection with a question to be voted on and two of said filings\nshall be before any such election, including one such filing not less\nthan thirty days nor more than forty-five days prior to such election\nand one such filing not less than eleven days nor more than fifteen days\nprior to such election. In addition, the board shall provide that every\npolitical committee which has filed a statement of treasurer and\ndepository shall make at least one filing every six months between the\ntime such statement of treasurer and depository is filed and the time\nsuch committee goes out of business. If any candidate or committee shall\nbe required by the provisions of this section, or by rule or regulation\nhereunder, to effect two filings within a period of five days, the state\nboard of elections may, by rule or regulation, waive the requirement of\nfiling the earlier of such statements. If a statement filed by a\ncandidate or committee after the election to which it pertains is not a\nfinal statement showing satisfaction of all liabilities and disposition\nof all assets, such candidate or committee shall file such additional\nstatements as the board shall, by rule or regulation provide until such\na final statement is filed.\n  2. Each statement shall cover the period up to and including the\nfourth day next preceding the day specified for the filing thereof;\nprovided, however, that any contribution or loan in excess of one\nthousand dollars, if received after the close of the period to be\ncovered in the last statement filed before any primary, general or\nspecial election but before such election, shall be reported, in the\nsame manner as other contributions, within twenty-four hours after\nreceipt.\n  3. Each statement shall be preserved by the officer with whom or the\nboard with which it is required to be filed for a period of five years\nfrom the date of filing thereof.\n  4. Each statement shall constitute a part of the public records of\nsuch officer or board and shall be open to public inspection.\n  5. The state board of elections or other board of elections, as the\ncase may be, shall not later than ten days after the last day to file\nany such statement notify each person required to file any such\nstatement which has not been received by such board by such tenth day in\naccordance with this article of such person's failure to file such\nstatement timely. Such notice shall be in writing and mailed to the last\nknown residence or business address of such person by certified mail,\nreturn receipt requested. Failure to file within five days of receipt of\nsuch notice shall constitute prima facie evidence of a willful failure\nto file. If the person required to file such statement is a treasurer\nwho has stated that the committee has been authorized by one or more\ncandidates, a copy of such notice shall be sent to each such candidate\nby first class mail. A copy of any such notice sent by a board of\nelections other than the state board of elections shall be sent by such\nother board to the state board.\n  6. A statement shall be deemed properly filed when deposited in an\nestablished post-office within the prescribed time, duly stamped,\ncertified and directed to the officer with whom or to the board with\nwhich the statement is required to be filed, but in the event it is not\nreceived, a duplicate of such statement shall be promptly filed upon\nnotice by such officer or such board of its non-receipt.\n  7. On the twentieth day following the date by which such statements\nwere required to be filed, the state board of elections shall prepare\nand make available for public inspection and distribution a list of\nthose persons and committees from whom it has not yet received such\nstatement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>