<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-11-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-210"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_210">
        <num>14-210</num>
        <heading>Reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-210. Reports. The PCFB shall review and evaluate the effect of\nthis title upon the conduct of election campaigns and shall submit a\nreport to the legislature on or before January first, two thousand\ntwenty-five and every second year thereafter, and at any other time upon\nthe request of the governor and at such other times as the PCFB deems\nappropriate. These reports shall include:\n  1. a list of the participating and nonparticipating candidates in\ncovered elections and the votes received by each candidate in those\nelections;\n  2. the amount of contributions and loans received, and expenditures\nmade on behalf of these candidates;\n  3. the amount of public matching funds each participating candidate\nreceived, spent, and repaid pursuant to this program;\n  4. analysis of the effect of this title on political campaigns,\nincluding its effect on the sources and amounts of private financing,\nthe level of campaign expenditures, voter participation, the number of\ncandidates, the candidates' ability to campaign effectively for public\noffice, and the diversity of candidates seeking and elected to office;\nand\n  5. recommendations for further legislative and regulatory enactments,\nincluding changes in contribution limits, thresholds for eligibility,\nand any other features of the system.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>