<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-11-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-200"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_200">
        <num>14-200</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and intent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-200. Legislative findings and intent. The legislature finds that\nreform of New York state's campaign finance system is crucial to\nimproving public confidence in the state's democratic processes and\ncontinuing to ensure a government that is accountable to all of the\nvoters of the state regardless of wealth or position. The legislature\nfinds that New York's current system of campaign finance, with its large\ncontributions to candidates for office and party committees, has created\nthe potential for and the appearance of corruption. The legislature\nfurther finds that, whether or not this system creates actual\ncorruption, the appearance of such corruption can give rise to a\ndistrust in government and citizen apathy that undermines the democratic\noperation of the political process.\n  The legislature also finds that the high cost of running for office in\nNew York discourages qualified candidates from running for office and\ncreates an electoral system that encourages candidates to spend too much\ntime raising money rather than attending to the duties of their office,\nrepresenting the needs of their constituents, and communicating with\nvoters.\n  The legislature amends this article creating a new title to this\narticle to reduce the possibility and appearance that special interests\nexercise undue influence over state officials; to increase the actual\nand apparent responsiveness of elected officials to all voters; to\nencourage qualified candidates to run for office; and to reduce the\npressure on candidates to spend large amounts of time raising large\ncontributions for their campaigns.\n  The legislature also finds that the system of voluntary public\nfinancing furthers the government's interest in encouraging qualified\ncandidates to run for office. The legislature finds that the voluntary\npublic funding program will enlarge the public debate and increase\nparticipation in the democratic process. In addition, the legislature\nfinds that the voluntary expenditure limitations and matching fund\nprogram reduce the burden on candidates and officeholders to spend time\nraising money for their campaigns.\n  Therefore, the legislature declares that these amendments further the\nimportant and valid government interests of reducing voter apathy,\nbuilding confidence in government, reducing the reality and appearance\nof corruption, and encouraging qualified candidates to run for office,\nwhile reducing candidates' and officeholders' fundraising burdens.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>