<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-201"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-14-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_201">
        <num>14-201</num>
        <heading>Political committee registration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_201__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to each authorized and political committee\nreporting to the PCFB every contribution and loan received and every\nexpenditure made in the time and manner prescribed by sections 14-102,\n14-104, and 14-108 of this article, each authorized and political\ncommittee for participating candidates shall also submit disclosure\nreports on March fifteenth of each election year reporting to the PCFB\nevery contribution and loan received and every expenditure made. For\ncontributors who make aggregate contributions of one hundred dollars or\nmore, each authorized and political committee shall report to the PCFB\nthe occupation and business address of each contributor and lender. The\nPCFB shall revise, prepare, and post forms on its webpage that\nfacilitate compliance with the requirements of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_201__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The PCFB shall review each disclosure report filed and shall\ninform authorized and political committees of relevant questions it has\nconcerning:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_201__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>compliance with requirements of this title and of the\nrules issued by the PCFB, and (ii) qualification for receiving public\nmatching funds pursuant to this title. In the course of this review, it\nshall give authorized and political committees an opportunity to respond\nto and correct potential violations and give candidates an opportunity\nto address questions it has concerning their matchable contribution\nclaims or other issues concerning eligibility for receiving public\nmatching funds pursuant to this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_201__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contributions that are not itemized in reports filed with the PCFB\nshall not be matchable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_201__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Participating candidates may file reports of contributions as\nfrequently as once a week on Monday so that their matching funds may be\npaid at the earliest allowable date.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>