<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-116"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-116"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-116"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_116">
        <num>15-116</num>
        <heading>Inspectors of election</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 15-116. Inspectors of election. 1. The board of trustees shall, by\nresolution at least forty days prior to a general village election\nappoint two or four inspectors of election for each village election\ndistrict. Such resolution shall fix the compensation of the inspectors\nand designate a chairman. In addition, the board of trustees may provide\nfor alternative inspectors who shall assume the office of inspector upon\nthe inability or refusal of an inspector to assume or perform his duties\nand for any clerical help which they may deem necessary. Such clerical\nhelp shall perform their duties under direction and control of the\ninspectors of election. It shall be the duty of the inspectors of\nelection to preside at all village elections in the district for which\nthey were appointed until their successors are appointed. If at any\ngeneral village election, both major political parties nominate a\ncandidate or candidates for elective village office then at the next\nvillage election following the election for which the nominations are\nmade the inspectors of election shall be appointed equally from enrolled\nmembers of such parties. Such equal representation shall be required\nonly as long as such parties nominate a candidate or candidates for\nelective village office. In those elections in which both such political\nparties do not nominate candidates, any qualified person may serve as an\ninspector of election.\n  2. In Nassau county, appointments as inspectors of election for\nvillage elections shall be equally divided between the major political\nparties.  All such inspectors shall be residents of the village in which\nthey serve. Such inspectors shall be appointed from among those persons\nappointed as inspectors pursuant to the provisions of section 3-420 of\nthis chapter. If the number of inspectors appointed pursuant to such\nsection 3-420 who are eligible and willing to serve in any village is\ninsufficient to fill all the positions in such village, then additional\ninspectors shall be appointed in the manner so prescribed by such\nsection 3-420.\n  3. Inspectors of election for village elections shall prior to the\nassumption of their duties file a constitutional oath of office with the\nvillage clerk.\n  4. If the board of trustees of any village appoints four inspectors of\nelection for each village election district, they may also determine\nthat two of the four inspectors of election shall serve on registration\nday or days.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>