<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-128"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-128"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-128"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-128/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-128/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-128/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-128/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_128">
        <num>15-128</num>
        <heading>Notice to person chosen to a village office</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 15-128. Notice to person chosen to a village office. The clerk of\nthe village shall, within three days after the election of a village\nofficer, notify each person elected of his election, and of the date\nthereof, and that, in order to qualify, he is required to file his oath\nof office with such clerk before entering upon the duties thereof; and,\nif an official undertaking be required of him by or in pursuance of law,\nthat he is also required to file the same with such clerk and that upon\nhis failure so to do he will be deemed to have declined the office. In\nthe case of a village justice such notice shall further state that the\nfiling of his oath with the county clerk of the county is also required.\nIf an undertaking is required of a village officer after entering upon\nthe duties of his office, the clerk of the village shall thereupon serve\nupon such officer, personally, a written notice that he is required to\nfile such undertaking with the clerk within ten days after the service\nof the notice and that upon his failure to do so his office will become\nvacant.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>