<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-11-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-108"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_108">
        <num>15-108</num>
        <heading>Designation and nomination of candidates</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_108__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A written declination of a party designation must be filed in the\noffice of the village clerk within three days of the date of the filing\nof the designating petition. Upon the filing of such declination, the\nvillage clerk shall, within one day notify the committee to fill\nvacancies named in the petition. A certificate to fill the vacancy\ncaused by a declination or any other reason must be filed with the\nvillage clerk within three days after the date of the notice to the\ncommittee to fill vacancies and shall have appended thereto the written\nconsent of the person or persons designated.\n  8. a. An independent nominating petition for an office to be filled at\nthe time of a general or special village election shall be filed not\nearlier than forty-two days nor later than thirty-five days preceding\nthe election.\n  b. A certificate of acceptance or declination of an independent\nnomination for an office to be filled at the time of a general or\nspecial village election shall be filed not later than three days after\nthe last day to file the petition which made such independent\nnomination.\n  c. A certificate to fill a vacancy caused by a declination of an\nindependent nomination for an office to be filled at the time of a\ngeneral or special village election for offices shall be filed not later\nthan three days after the last day to file the certificate of\ndeclination, and shall have appended thereto the written consent of the\nperson or persons nominated.\n  9. Any village resident who is a registered voter of the village and,\nin the case of a designating petition, an enrolled member of the party\nfiling the petition, may sign an independent nominating petition or a\ndesignating petition providing that:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_108__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such signature was not made\nmore than six weeks prior to the last day to file such petition;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_108__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>he\nhas not signed more than one petition designating or nominating a\ncandidate for mayor or village justice. If he has signed more than one\nsuch petition, only the earliest signature for each such office shall be\nvalid;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_108__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>he has not signed more than one petition designating or\nnominating a candidate for each vacancy which exists for the office of\nvillage trustee or village justice if the village has provided for two\nsuch justices. If he has signed more than one such petition for each\nsuch vacancy, only the earlier signatures shall be valid; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_108__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>he does\nnot vote at a primary election or party caucus where a candidate was\nnominated for the same office or each such vacancy.\n  10.  A written objection to an independent nominating petition,\ndesignating petition or certificate of nomination shall be filed in the\noffice of the village clerk no later than one day following the last\ndate upon which such petition or certificate may be filed or within one\nday after such petition or certificate is received by the village clerk,\nif such petition or certificate is mailed as provided by law, whichever\nis later. Written specifications of the grounds of the objections shall\nbe filed with the village clerk within two days after the filing of the\nwritten objection. A failure to file such written specifications shall\nrender the original objection null and void. Upon receipt of such\nwritten specification, the village clerk shall forthwith notify each\ncandidate named in the petition or certificate and shall notify the\ncounty board of elections of the county in which the village is located.\nFor purposes of this section, a village shall be deemed to be located\nwithin a county if more than fifty percent of the population of the\nvillage as shown by the last federal decennial or special census resides\nin that portion of the village located in that county. Upon receipt of\nthe written specifications as herein required, the county board of\nelections shall immediately take all steps necessary and consistent with\nthis chapter to render a determination on the questions raised in such\nobjections and specifications. When a determination has been made by the\ncounty board of elections that the petition is sufficient or\ninsufficient, it shall immediately notify the village clerk and each\ncandidate named in the petition or certificate, and, if such\ndetermination was made on objection, the objector.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>