<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-124"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-124"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-124"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_124">
        <num>15-124</num>
        <heading>Duties of village clerk</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 15-124. Duties of village clerk. 1. In addition to any duties of the\nvillage clerk specified in this chapter and the village law, the village\nclerk shall be the election officer of the village and shall have the\nresponsibility for the general conduct of all village elections and\nshall have vested in him all authority, consistent with this chapter\nwhich may be reasonable and necessary to provide for the proper and\norderly conduct of such elections and the proceedings preliminary and\nsubsequent thereto.\n  2. The police department and the officers and members of such police\ndepartment, if any, the office of the sheriff in a county in which a\nvillage or part of a village is located or any police agency or\ndepartment charged with the responsibility of law enforcement in any\ncounty in which a village or part of a village is located shall,\nwhenever called upon by the village clerk, render to such village clerk\nall practicable assistance in the enforcement of this chapter. Such\nassistance shall be rendered to the village clerk at no charge to the\nvillage. Such assistance shall include, but not be limited to:\n  a. the police telephone service;\n  b. the investigation of any registrant or any applicant for an early\nmail or absentee ballot to determine his or her qualifications to be\nregistered or vote, and\n  c. the maintenance of order, regulation of traffic and the control of\ncrowds on any day or days designated for voter registration and voting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>