<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-110"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_110">
        <num>15-110</num>
        <heading>Election districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 15-110. Election districts. 1. A village shall constitute a single\nelection district for village elections. However, if at a general\nvillage election the number of votes cast exceeds eight hundred, the\nboard of trustees, by resolution adopted before the next general village\nelection, may divide such village into election districts each\ncontaining not more than eight hundred qualified voters for village\noffices.\n  2. Following the establishment of two or more such districts, the\nnumber thereof or their boundaries or both may be enlarged, diminished,\nincreased or decreased from year to year by resolution of the board of\ntrustees; provided, however, that, if there is more than one district,\nno such district shall contain more than eight hundred qualified voters.\n  3. If village election districts are coterminous with election\ndistricts established for general elections other than general village\nelections, the limitations as to the number of qualified voters set\nforth in subdivisions one and two of this section shall not be\napplicable.\n  4. For the purposes of this section, the number of qualified voters in\neach election district of a village shall be the average of the number\nof persons who voted in such district in the three preceding general\nvillage elections.\n  5. Any resolution adopted pursuant to the authority of this section\nshall be adopted at least one hundred twenty days prior to the general\nvillage election; shall specify the boundaries of each election district\ncreated or altered; and shall be posted and published with the notice of\nsuch election as required.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>