<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-119"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-119"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-119"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_119">
        <num>15-119</num>
        <heading>Early mail voting at village elections</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_119__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Applicant's full name, date of birth, and residence address,\nincluding the street and number, if any, rural delivery route, if any,\nmailing address if different from the residence address and their\nvillage and an address to which the ballot shall be mailed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_119__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement that the applicant is a registered voter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_119__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such application shall permit the applicant to apply for an early\nmail ballot for a single election or for all remaining elections in the\ncalendar year for which the voter is eligible to vote.\n  5. The application for an early mail ballot shall also provide the\napplicant the opportunity to provide their telephone number and e-mail\naddress.\n  6. Printed forms containing the application for the early mail ballot,\nin accordance with the requirements of this section, shall be in the\nform prescribed by the state board of elections and shall be provided by\nthe village clerk and shall be available at the office of the clerk.\nApplication forms for early mail ballots for use pursuant to this\nsection shall be furnished by the village clerk upon request of the\nperson authorized to vote under this section or by any such person's\nspouse, parent, child, authorized agent or any nurse charged with the\ncare of such person.\n  7. An application must be received by the village clerk no earlier\nthan four months before the election for which an early mail ballot is\nsought, except as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_119__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of this\nsection. If the application requests that the early mail ballot be\nmailed, such application must be received not later than seven days\nbefore the election. If the applicant or their agent delivers the\napplication to the village clerk in person, such application must be\nreceived not later than the day before the election. The village clerk\nshall examine each application. If the application is complete, the\napplicant is a registered voter of the village at the address listed in\nthe application, and the applicant is eligible to vote in the election,\nthe application shall be deemed accepted.\n  8. No later than six days before the election for which an application\nhas been received and accepted by the village clerk, the village clerk\nshall mail, by regular mail, an early mail ballot to each applicant who\nhas applied before such day and who has requested that such early mail\nballot be mailed to them at the address set forth in their application.\nIf the applicant or their agent delivers the application to the village\nclerk in person after the seventh day before the village election and\nnot later than the day before the election, the village clerk shall\nforthwith deliver such early mail ballots for those applicants whom they\ndetermine are qualified to make such applications and to receive such\nballots to such applicants or the agents named in the applications when\nsuch applicants or agents appear in the village clerk's office.\n  9. The early mail ballot shall be caused to be prepared and printed by\nthe village clerk as provided by law for paper ballots or machine\nballots, whichever are to be used in said election and appropriate\nmodifications for the purposes of this section. The village clerk shall\nalso cause to be prepared and printed return envelopes addressed to\nthemself, conforming so far as may be practicable to the provisions of\nthis chapter stating thereon that in order for the ballot contained\ntherein to be c...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>