<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-118"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-118"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-118"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_118">
        <num>15-118</num>
        <heading>Registration of voters</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_118__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The dates prior to registration day on which the inspectors of\nelection shall meet to commence the preparation of the register.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_118__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The place in each district where such meetings, registration and\nelection shall be held.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_118__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The hours for such meetings, registration and election; but in no\nevent shall the hours for registration be less than the hours from noon\nuntil five o'clock in the afternoon.\n  5. Registration day shall be held on the tenth day prior to the\ngeneral village election except in those villages which provide, by\nresolution adopted at least thirty-seven days prior to the date of the\nfirst election for which it shall be effective, for an additional day of\nregistration to be held on the twelfth day prior to the general village\nelection. Such resolution shall remain in effect for subsequent general\nvillage elections unless amended, modified or repealed.\n  6. The board of trustees of any village, by resolution or ordinance,\nsubject to permissive referendum, may determine that personal\nregistration shall be required for village elections.\n  7.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_118__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The register for the general village election shall be prepared\nin each village election district by the inspectors of election thereof\nat the times and place designated by the resolution of the board of\ntrustees. Such register must be completed not later than the fourth day\nbefore the village election. In preparing such register the inspectors\nof election shall comply with the following procedure.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_118__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In all villages wherein personal registration is not required,\nthey shall adopt, use or copy from, the registration lists certified and\nsupplied by the county board of elections the names appearing thereon of\nall persons, residing in the village and qualified to vote at such\nforthcoming general village election. In addition, if there is a village\nregistration day in the village, they shall add thereto the names of all\npersons known to them who then are or who will at the time of such\nelection be qualified to vote and the names of all persons proven to\ntheir satisfaction on the registration day to be then, or at the time of\nsuch election, qualified to vote.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_118__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In villages wherein personal registration is required, they shall\nfollow the same procedure set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_118__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>above, except that\nno names shall be added to the register other than the names of persons\npersonally appearing before them on the registration day, if any, and\nproving to their satisfaction to be then, or at the time of the\nelection, qualified to vote.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_118__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The register for each village election district shall include, as\na minimum, space for the name of the voter, his address within the\nvillage and a space for his or her signature to be signed by the voter\non election day. In villages wherein personal registration is required,\nsuch register shall also contain a space for the signature of the voter\nto be signed by such voter on registration day. The village clerk shall\nfurnish a printed certificate to be signed by a voter who appears\npersonally before the inspectors of election on registration day. Such\ncertificate shall contain a statement that the person possesses all the\nnecessary qualifications for voting in village elections. Such\ncertificate shall be accepted for all purposes as the equivalent of an\naffidavit and if it contains a material false statement, shall subject\nthe person signing it to the same penalties as if he had been duly\nsworn, and such provision shall be printed in bold type directly above\nthe signature line of the certificate.\n  8. The village clerk shall furnish the inspectors of election, at\nvillage expense, with all necessary registration books, papers,\nequipment and supplies. The village clerk shall also deliver to the\ninspectors a list of all persons who have applied for early mail or\nabsentee ballots for the election for which the registration meeting is\nbeing held.\n  9. Registration for special village elections for officers shall be\nheld in the same manner as is provided herein for general village\nelections and the registration day therefor shall be the same as if said\nspecial village election were a general village election.\n  10. The board of trustees of any village, if it determines that more\nthan one-half of the voters qualified to vote at a forthcoming village\nelection for village officers were personally registered at the last\npreceding general election other than a village election for officers\nand that taking the registration for such forthcoming electi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>