<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-120"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-15-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_120">
        <num>15-120</num>
        <heading>Absentee voting at village elections</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>absent from the county of his or her residence; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>unable to appear at the polling place because of illness or\nphysical disability, or duties related to the primary care of one or\nmore individuals who are ill or physically disabled, or because he or\nshe will be or is a patient in a hospital; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an incarcerated individual or patient of a veteran's\nadministration hospital; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>absent from his or her voting residence because he or she is\ndetained in jail awaiting action by a grand jury or awaiting trial, or\nconfined in jail or prison after a conviction for an offense other than\na felony, provided that he or she is qualified to vote in the election\ndistrict of his or her residence.\n  2. Each person entitled to vote as an absentee voter pursuant to this\nsection and desirous of obtaining an absentee ballot shall make written\napplication therefor to the village clerk. Application forms for use\npursuant to this section shall be in a form prescribed by the state\nboard of elections. The use of any application which is on a form\nprescribed by the state board of elections shall be acceptable.\n  3. An application for an absentee ballot must be signed by the\napplicant. Such application may require that the applicant submit a\ncertificate in lieu of any affidavit which shall state that the\ninformation contained in the application is true. Such certificate shall\nbe accepted for all purposes as the equivalent of an affidavit and shall\nhave the following language printed in bold face type above the\nsignature line:\n        "I UNDERSTAND THAT THIS CERTIFICATE WILL BE ACCEPTED FOR\n        ALL PURPOSES AS THE EQUIVALENT OF AN AFFIDAVIT AND, IF\n        IT CONTAINS A MATERIAL FALSE STATEMENT, SHALL SUBJECT ME\n        TO THE SAME PENALTIES AS IF I HAD BEEN DULY SWORN."\n  4. The application for an absentee ballot when filed must contain in\neach instance the following information:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Applicant's full name, date of birth, and residence address,\nincluding the street and number, if any, rural delivery route, if any,\nmailing address if different from the residence address and his or her\nvillage and an address to which the ballot shall be mailed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement that the applicant is a qualified and registered\nvoter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement, as appropriate, that on the day of such election the\napplicant expects in good faith to be in one of the following\ncategories:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>absent from the county of his or her residence; provided, however,\nif the applicant expects to be absent from such county for a duration\ncovering more than one election and seeks an absentee ballot for each\nelection, he or she shall state the dates when he or she expects to\nbegin and end such absence; or\n  (ii) unable to appear at a polling place because of illness or\nphysical disability or duties related to the primary care of one or more\nindividuals who are ill or physically disabled; or\n  (iii) an incarcerated individual or patient of a veteran's\nadministration hospital; or\n  (iv) detained in jail awaiting action by a grand jury or awaiting\ntrial or confined in jail or prison after a conviction for an offense\nother than a felony and stating the place where he or she is so detained\nor confined.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15_120__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such application shall permit the applicant to apply for an\nabsentee ballot for either a primary election or the general election in\nany year and for those persons who will be continuously absent from\ntheir county of residence during the period between the fall primary\nelection and the general election in any year to apply for ballots for\nboth such elections in such year. A voter who applies for an absentee\nballot shall be sent an absentee ballot for any special election or\nwinter primary that occurs during the period of absence specified in the\napplication.\n  5. An application must be received by the village clerk no earlier\nthan four months before the election for which an absentee ballot is\nsought.  If the application requests that the absentee ballot be mailed,\nsuch application must be received not later than seven days before the\nelection. If the applicant or his or her agent delivers the application\nto the village clerk in person, such application must be received not\nlater than the day before the election. The village clerk shall examine\neach application and shall determine from the information contained\ntherein whether the applicant is qualified under this section to receive\nan absentee ballot. The clerk in making such decision shall not\ndetermine whether the applicant is a qualified elector, said\ndetermination being reserved to the inspectors of election as is\nhereinafter provided in subdivision nine of this section.\n  6. No later than six days before the election for which an application\nhas been received and for which the village clerk has determined the\napplicant to be qualified to vote by absentee ballot the village clerk\nshall mail, by regular mail, an absentee ballot to each qualified\napplicant who has applied before such day and who has requested that\nsuch absentee ballot be mailed to him or her at the address set forth in\nhis or her application. If the applicant or his or her agent delivers\nthe application to the village...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>