<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-16-110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-16-110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16-110"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-16-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-16-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-16-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-16-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_110">
        <num>16-110</num>
        <heading>Proceedings as to enrollment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 16-110. Proceedings as to enrollment. 1. The supreme court, by a\njustice thereof within the judicial district, or the county court, by a\njudge within his county, in a proceeding instituted by a duly enrolled\nvoter of a party, not later than the second Friday before a primary\nelection, shall direct the enrollment of any voter with such party to be\ncancelled if it appears that any material statement in the declaration\nof the voter upon which he was enrolled is false or that the voter has\ndied or does not reside at the address on his registration record.\n  2. The chairperson of the county committee of a party with which a\nvoter is enrolled in such county, or, in the absence of a county\ncommittee in such county, a person elected for such purpose by a\nmajority vote of the state committee of the party at a regular or\nspecial meeting of the party at which a quorum is present, may, upon a\nwritten complaint by an enrolled member of such party in such county and\nafter a hearing held by such person or by a sub-committee appointed by\nsuch person upon at least two days' notice to the voter, personally or\nby mail, determine that the voter is not in sympathy with the principles\nof such party. The Supreme Court or a justice thereof within the\njudicial district, in a proceeding instituted by a duly enrolled voter\nof the party at least ten days before a primary election, shall direct\nthe enrollment of such voter to be cancelled if it appears from the\nproceedings before such person or sub-committee, and other proofs, if\nany, presented, that such determination is just.\n  3. The state committee of a party may elect, by majority vote at a\nregular or special meeting at which a quorum is present, a person or\npersons to receive complaints, hold hearings and institute proceedings\nunder this section for any county or counties in which there is no\ncounty committee of such party.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>