<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-108"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_108">
        <num>17-108</num>
        <heading>False affidavits; mutilation, destruction or loss of registry list or affidavits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 17-108. False affidavits; mutilation, destruction or loss of\nregistry list or affidavits. 1. Any person who wilfully loses, alters,\ndestroys or mutilates the list of voters or registration poll ledgers in\nany election district, or a certified copy thereof, is guilty of a\nmisdemeanor.\n  2. An applicant for registration who shall make, incorporate or cause\nto be incorporated a material false statement in an application for\nregistration, or in any challenge or other affidavit required for or\nmade or filed in connection with registration or voting, and any person\nwho knowingly takes a false oath before a board of inspectors of\nelection, and any person who makes a material false statement in a\nmedical certificate or an affidavit filed in connection with an\napplication for registration, is guilty of a misdemeanor.\n  3. A person who shall wilfully suppress, mutilate or alter, or, except\nas authorized by this chapter, shall destroy, any signed challenge or\nother affidavit required for or made or filed in connection with\nregistration or voting, and any person who, except as authorized by this\nchapter, shall remove such an affidavit from the place of registration\nor polling place, is guilty of a felony.\n  4. A person other than the applicant who, prior to the filing of the\napplication, shall willfully suppress, mutilate, materially alter, or,\nexcept as authorized by this chapter, destroy a signed application for\nregistration by mail, is guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>