<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-208"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-208"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-06-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-208"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-17-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_208">
        <num>17-208</num>
        <heading>Assistance for language-minority groups</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_208__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>more than two percent, but in no instance fewer than three hundred\nindividuals, of the citizens of voting age of a political subdivision\nare members of a single language-minority group and are limited English\nproficient.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_208__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>more than four thousand of the citizens of voting age of such\npolitical subdivision are members of a single language-minority group\nand are limited English proficient.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_208__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of a political subdivision that contains all or any\npart of a Native American reservation, more than two percent of the\nNative American citizens of voting age within the Native American\nreservation are members of a single language-minority group and are\nlimited English proficient. For the purposes of this paragraph, "Native\nAmerican" is defined to include any persons recognized by the United\nStates census bureau or New York as "American Indian" or "Alaska\nNative".\n  2. Language assistance to be provided. A board of elections or\npolitical subdivision required to provide language assistance to a\nparticular language-minority group pursuant to this section shall\nprovide voting materials in the covered language of an equal quality of\nthe corresponding English language materials, including registration or\nvoting notices, forms, instructions, assistance, or other materials or\ninformation relating to the electoral process, including ballots. Any\nregistration or voting notices, forms, instructions, assistance, or\nother materials or information relating to the electoral process,\nincluding ballots, in a covered political subdivision, shall be provided\nin the language of the applicable language-minority group as well as in\nthe English language, provided that where the language of the applicable\nlanguage-minority group is historically oral or unwritten, the board of\nelections or political subdivision shall only be required to furnish\noral instructions, assistance, or other information relating to\nregistration and voting.\n  3. Action for declaratory judgment for English-only voting materials.\nA board of elections or political subdivision subject to the\nrequirements of this section which seeks to provide English-only\nmaterials may file an action against the state for a declaratory\njudgment permitting such provision. The court shall grant the requested\nrelief if it finds that the determination was unreasonable or an abuse\nof discretion.\n  ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>