<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-102"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_102">
        <num>2-102</num>
        <heading>State committee; creation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-102. State committee; creation. 1. The members of the state\ncommittee of each party shall be elected from such units of\nrepresentation as the state committee shall by rule provide. The number\nof members representing each unit may vary, but each member shall be\nentitled to an equal vote within his unit. Each member of the state\ncommittee shall be entitled to cast one vote unless the rules of the\nparty shall provide otherwise.\n  2. Each member shall be, at the time of his election and continuously\nthereafter, an enrolled member of the party and a resident of the unit\nfrom which he is elected except as hereinafter provided.\n  3. To be eligible for election as a member of the state committee at\nthe first election next ensuing after a readjustment or alteration of\nthe units of representation becomes effective, a candidate must only\nhave been a resident of the county in which the unit, or any part\nthereof, is contained for the twelve months immediately preceding the\nelection.\n  4. When any rule of the state committee provides for representation by\ngender, the designating petitions and primary ballots shall list\ncandidates for such party positions separately by gender marker. In\nproviding for such representation, the state committee shall establish\nrules that provide for the ability of individuals who do not exclusively\nidentify as a binary gender to run for those positions and which respect\nindividuals' gender identity.\n  5. The state committee may provide for the holding of a state\nconvention and the election of delegates and alternate delegates thereto\nin any year and may empower such convention to adopt party platforms and\npolicies and to transact such other business as it may prescribe.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>