<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-118"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-118"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-118"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_118">
        <num>2-118</num>
        <heading>Committees; vacancies, how filled and effect of change of boundaries</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-118. Committees; vacancies, how filled and effect of change of\nboundaries. 1. In the case of the death, declination, enrollment in\nanother party, removal from the unit or removal from office of a member\nof a committee, or the failure to nominate or elect a member, the\nvacancy created thereby shall be filled by the remaining members of the\ncommittee by the selection of an enrolled voter of the party qualified\nfor election from the unit of representation in which such vacancy shall\nhave occurred. When a state committee fills a vacancy pursuant to this\nsubdivision, the chairman or secretary of such committee shall, within\nten days after such vacancy is filled, file a certificate with the state\nboard of elections setting forth the name, address, and unit of\nrepresentation of the person so selected.\n  2. If the boundaries of any unit of representation be changed after\nthe election of members of a state committee or assembly district\nleaders or associate assembly district leaders, the terms of members,\nassembly district leaders or associate assembly district leaders elected\nin such units of representation and the units of representation which\nsuch members, assembly district leaders or associate assembly district\nleaders represent shall continue until the next regularly scheduled\nelection for such party positions and until their successors are\nelected.\n  3. The county committee, upon its organization after the election of\nits members, or at any time thereafter, may determine that a vacancy or\nvacancies in such committee exists by reason of an increase in the\nnumber of election districts within the county occasioned by a change of\nthe boundaries of one or more election districts, taking effect after\nsuch election, and may determine the districts that the elected members\nshall represent until the next election at which members of such\ncommittee are elected. A vacancy so determined to exist shall be filled\nas provided in subdivision one.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>