<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-114"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-114"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-114"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_114">
        <num>2-114</num>
        <heading>Committees; rules of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-114. Committees; rules of. 1. Each committee may prepare rules for\ngoverning the party within its political unit. Within ten days after the\nadoption of any rule or amendment thereto a certified copy thereof shall\nbe filed by the state committee in the office of the state board of\nelections, and by the county committee in the office of the state board\nof elections, and in the office of the board of elections of the county.\nIf a section or portion of such rules relate to the nomination of\ncandidates for village office, such section or portion of such rules\nshall be filed in the office of the village clerk of all villages in\nwhich elections are conducted by the village and in which the party\nmakes any nominations for village office. No rule or amendment thereof\nshall be effective until the filing thereof in the office of the state\nboard of elections. Such rules shall continue to be the rules for the\ncommittee until they are amended or new rules adopted.\n  2. Rules may be amended or new rules adopted from time to time by a\nmajority vote of the members of the committee present at a meeting at\nwhich there is a quorum, provided a copy of the proposed amendment shall\nbe sent with the notice of the meeting at which such amendment is to be\nproposed, such notice to be mailed not less than five days before such\nmeeting to the post office address of each member of the committee.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>