<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-110"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_110">
        <num>2-110</num>
        <heading>Committees other than state and county; creation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-110. Committees other than state and county; creation. 1. All\ncommittees other than state and county committees shall be formed in the\nmanner provided for by the rules of the party.\n  2. In the city of New York there shall be the party positions of\nassembly district leaders or, if the rules of the county committee shall\nso provide, one assembly district leader and one associate assembly\ndistrict leader. Outside the city of New York there shall be such\npositions when the rules of the county committee shall so provide. Such\nleaders shall be elected at primary elections as herein provided, within\nevery county in such city for each assembly district, or for each part\nof an assembly district within such county as may be designated for the\npurpose in the rules of the county committee, and in every county of the\nstate outside of such city where the rules so provide, for such assembly\ndistrict or part thereof within such county as may be designated in such\nrules for the purpose. Such assembly district leaders or such assembly\ndistrict leader and associate assembly district leader shall be of\ndifferent genders, if the rules of the county committee shall so\nprovide, and shall be enrolled voters of the party residing within the\nassembly district and, if the rules of the county committee shall so\nprovide, within the part of the assembly district for which they are to\nbe elected, and shall be elected at the same primary election and for\nthe same term as members of the county committee. When any such rule\nprovides for representation by gender, the designating petitions and\nprimary ballots shall list candidates for such party positions\nseparately by gender marker. In providing for such representation, the\ncounty committee shall establish rules that provide for the ability of\nindividuals who do not exclusively identify as a binary gender to serve\nas district leader and which respect individuals' gender identity. Each\nshall perform such duties, powers and functions as the rules of the\ncounty committee may prescribe. Vacancies in such positions shall be\nfilled by the members of the county committee within the assembly\ndistrict or part thereof, as the case may be, until the first primary\nelection following the creation of such vacancy or vacancies for which\nthe period for circulating designating petitions ends at least seven\ndays after the creation of such vacancy or vacancies, at which time the\nsuccessor or successors shall be directly elected as herein provided.\nAssembly district leaders and associate assembly district leaders shall\nautomatically be members and shall have the right to participate and\nvote in meetings of the county committee or any subcommittee thereof.\nThe county committee may provide by its rules that the members of the\nstate committee, elected in accordance with the provisions of this\nchapter, shall possess the duties, powers and functions of an assembly\ndistrict leader or an associate assembly district leader. In such event\nthe provisions of this section shall not apply to the members of the\nstate committee but upon their election as a member of the state\ncommittee, such person shall be deemed to have also been elected as an\nassembly district leader or an associate assembly district leader.\n  3. To be eligible for election as assembly district leader or\nassociate assembly district leader at the first election next ensuing\nafter a readjustment or alteration of the units of representation\nbecomes effective, a candidate must only have been a resident of the\ncounty in which the unit, or any part thereof, is contained for the\ntwelve months immediately preceding the election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>