<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-124"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-124"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-124"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_124">
        <num>2-124</num>
        <heading>Party names and emblems; provision for</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-124. Party names and emblems; provision for. 1. The state\ncommittee of a party shall select a name and emblem to distinguish the\ncandidates of the party for public office in all districts of the state,\nand shall file in the office of the state board of elections, a\ncertificate executed by its chairman and secretary, setting forth the\nname and showing the emblem so selected.\n  2. The name of a party shall be in the English language and shall not\ninclude the words "American", "United States", "National", "New York\nState", "Independence" or "Independent", or "Empire State", or any\nabbreviation or plural thereof, nor the name or part of the name, or an\nabbreviation of the name, of an existing party. The emblem chosen may be\na star, an animal, an anchor, or any other proper symbol, but may not be\nthe same as or similar to any emblem, insignia, symbol or flag used by\nany political or governmental body, agency or entity nor any religious\nemblem, insignia, symbol or flag, nor the portrait of any person, nor\nthe representation of a coin or of the currency of the United States.\nThe name and emblem chosen shall not be similar to or likely to create\nconfusion with the name or emblem of any other existing party or\nindependent body.\n  3. If the name of any party shall contain more than fifteen letters,\nthe state committee shall similarly select and certify an abbreviated\nform thereof, containing not more than fifteen letters, to be used upon\nthe ballot whenever the necessities of space so require.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>