<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-122"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-122"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-122"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_122">
        <num>2-122</num>
        <heading>National party conventions; delegates, election</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-122. National party conventions; delegates, election. Delegates\nand alternates to a national convention of a party shall be elected from\ncongressional districts, or partly from the state at large and partly\nfrom congressional districts, as the rules of the state committee may\nprovide. Such delegates and alternates from the state at large shall be\nelected by the state committee or by a state convention of the party, as\nthe rules of the state committee shall prescribe. If the rules of a\nnational party provide for representation by gender among delegates\nelected from districts, such district delegates shall be elected\nseparately by gender. District delegates and alternates to national\nparty conventions and delegates, and alternates, if any, to such a state\nconvention shall be elected at a primary. All delegates and alternates\nto a national party convention shall be enrolled members of such party.\nWhen any such rule provides for representation by gender, the\ndesignating petitions and primary ballots shall list candidates for such\nparty positions separately by gender marker. In providing for such\nrepresentation, the party shall establish rules that provide for the\nability of individuals who do not exclusively identify as a binary\ngender to serve as delegates and which respect individuals' gender\nidentity.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>