<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-120"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-2-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_120">
        <num>2-120</num>
        <heading>Party positions; to be filled at primary election, time for filing statement as to</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-120. Party positions; to be filled at primary election, time for\nfiling statement as to.  1. The chairman of the county committee of each\nparty or such person as may be designated by the rules of the county\ncommittee shall file with the board of elections not later than two\nweeks before the first day on which designating petitions for a primary\nelection may be signed, a statement of the party positions to be filled\nby such party at such primary election, and the number of persons to be\nelected to each position; provided, however, that failure to file such\nstatement shall not be construed as a prerequisite to filing designating\npetitions for such position.\n  2. If the party positions to be filled are elected from a district\nwhich includes parts of two or more counties, the chairman of the state\ncommittee of each party or such person as may be designated by the rules\nof the state committee shall file such statement with the state board of\nelections and the board of elections for each county within such\ndistrict.\n  3. In each county within the city of New York, and in each county\noutside of such city where the rules of the county committee of a party\nprovide for the election of assembly district leaders, or one assembly\ndistrict leader and one associate assembly district leader from parts of\nan assembly district, the statement filed by such committee shall also\nset forth the election districts contained within each such part of such\nassembly district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>