<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-104-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-104-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-104-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-104-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-104-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-104-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-104-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_104_A">
        <num>3-104-A</num>
        <heading>Compliance unit; compliance procedures</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-104-a. Compliance unit; compliance procedures.  1. There shall be\na compliance unit within the board of elections. The compliance unit\nshall examine campaign finance statements required to be filed pursuant\nto article fourteen of this chapter. If such statements are found to be\ndeficient, the compliance unit shall notify the person required to file\nsuch statement of such deficiency. Such notice shall be in writing and\nmailed to the last known residence or business address of such person by\ncertified mail, return receipt requested, or mailed to such address by\nfirst class mail if an affidavit attesting to such mailing is created to\nevidence such mailing. If the person required to file such statement is\na treasurer who has stated that the committee has been authorized by one\nor more candidates, a copy of such notice shall be sent to each\ncandidate by first class mail.\n  2. Upon a failure to remedy the deficiencies identified by the\ncompliance unit within thirty days of the receipt of such notice the\nchief enforcement counsel may proceed pursuant to subdivision five of\nsection 3-104 of this title. If such notice is received within thirty\ndays of an election, failure to remedy the deficiencies identified\nwithin seven days of the receipt of such notice the chief enforcement\ncounsel may proceed pursuant to subdivision five of section 3-104 of\nthis title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>