<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-100"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_100">
        <num>3-100</num>
        <heading>New York state board of elections; membership; organization</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_100__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>appointing the individual\nso jointly recommended as a commissioner, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_100__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>jointly recommending\nanother individual for appointment by the governor according to the\nprocedure outlined in this subdivision.\n  2. The two commissioners of the board appointed upon the\nrecommendation of the legislative leaders shall be co-chairs of the\nstate board of elections.\n  3. The commissioners of the state board of elections shall have no\nother public employment. The commissioners shall receive an annual\nsalary of twenty-five thousand dollars, within the amounts made\navailable therefor by appropriation. The board shall, for the purposes\nof sections seventy-three and seventy-four of the public officers law,\nbe a "state agency", and such commissioners shall be "officers" of the\nstate board of elections for the purposes of such sections. Within the\namounts made available by appropriation therefor, the state board of\nelections shall appoint two co-executive directors, and such other staff\nmembers as are necessary in the exercise of its functions, and may fix\ntheir compensation. The commissioners or, in the case of a vacancy on\nthe board, the commissioner of each of the major political parties shall\nappoint one co-executive director. Each co-executive director shall\nserve a term of four years. Any vacancy in the office of co-executive\ndirector shall be filled by the commissioners or, in the case of a\nvacancy on the board, the commissioner of the same major political party\nas the vacating incumbent for the remaining period of the term of such\nvacating incumbent.\n  3-a. There is established within the state board of elections the\noffice of chief enforcement counsel to head the division of election law\nenforcement. Such counsel shall serve in said office for a fixed term of\nfive years commencing September first, two thousand fourteen, and may\nonly be removed by the governor for substantial neglect of duty, gross\nmisconduct in office, or the inability to discharge the powers or duties\nof office, upon notice with an opportunity to be he...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>