<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_103">
        <num>3-103</num>
        <heading>Computerized record keeping; sharing information in database</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-103. Computerized record keeping; sharing information in database.\n1. The state board of elections shall promulgate rules and regulations\nsetting minimum standards for computerized record keeping systems\nmaintained by county boards of elections. Such standards shall include,\nbut not be limited to system access and security, the format and content\nof the data to be recorded and stored on such systems, and the minimum\ntechnical specifications for computer programming. Such standards shall\nbe for the purpose of facilitating compatibility between the systems\nused by the several boards of elections.\n  2. The state board of elections, in accordance with subdivision four\nof section 3-100 of this title, shall enter into an agreement with the\ncommissioner of motor vehicles whereby the department of motor vehicles\nwill provide the state board of elections information to assist local\nboards of elections to verify a voter's identity pursuant to the federal\nHelp America Vote Act of 2002.\n  3. The commissioner of motor vehicles shall enter into an agreement\nwith the federal commissioner of social security whereby the social\nsecurity administration will provide the commissioner of motor vehicles\ninformation to allow local boards of elections to verify a voter's\nidentity pursuant to the federal Help America Vote Act of 2002.\n  4. In addition, the state board of elections, in accordance with\nsubdivision four of section 3-100 of this title, shall enter into an\nagreement with other agencies within the state that have information\nrelevant to the verification of a voter's identity whereby such agencies\nwill provide the state board of elections information to assist local\nboards of elections to verify a voter's identity pursuant to the federal\nHelp America Vote Act of 2002.\n  5. The information transmitted between the statewide voter\nregistration list and other databases, as provided for in this section,\nshall be limited to the information which is contained in a voter\nregistration application and is necessary to verify a voter's identity.\nThe information contained in the statewide voter registration list shall\nnot be used for non-election purposes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>