<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-106"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_106">
        <num>3-106</num>
        <heading>Fair campaign code</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-106. Fair campaign code. 1. In addition to the powers and duties\nelsewhere enumerated in this article, the state board of elections,\nafter public hearings, shall adopt a "fair campaign code" setting forth\nethical standards of conduct for persons, political parties and\ncommittees engaged in election campaigns including, but not limited to,\nspecific prohibitions against practices of political espionage and other\npolitical practices involving subversion of the political parties and\nprocess.\n  2. Copies of such code shall be sent to each candidate, political\nparty or political committee, upon request, by the board of elections\nwith which such candidate, party or committee is required to file\nstatements of campaign financial disclosure pursuant to article fourteen\nof this chapter.\n  3. The state board of elections, on its own initiative, or upon\ncomplaint or otherwise, may investigate any alleged violation of the\nfair campaign code and, in appropriate cases, may apply for an order, as\nprovided in this article.\n  4. In addition to any other civil or criminal penalty which may be\nprovided for by law, the state board may impose a civil penalty, not to\nexceed one thousand dollars, upon any person found by the board, after a\nhearing, to have violated any of the provisions of such code.\n  5. Any such finding by the board may only be had after a hearing\nconducted by it upon reasonable written notice, as the board may\ndetermine, to such person and affording such person a reasonable\nopportunity to be heard and present and examine witnesses thereat.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>