<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-112"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-112"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-112"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_112">
        <num>3-112</num>
        <heading>State board of elections; uniform standards for processing data requests and duty to send data and information to statewide database</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be consistent with any relevant standards, guidelines, or guidance\ndeveloped by the national institute of standards and technology, the\nelection assistance commission, or the cybersecurity and infrastructure\nsecurity agency; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>apply to every election authority in the state.\n  2. Upon the certification of election results and the completion of\nthe voter history file after every election, each election authority\nshall, by January first after such election, or within ten business\ndays, whichever is later, transmit to the state board of elections, if\nsuch election authority is able to maintain the record, copies of:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nelection results at the election district level for every statewide\nelection and every election in every political subdivision;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ncontemporaneous voter registration lists;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>voter history files;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nmaps or other documentation of the configuration of districts in any\nformat or formats as specified by the state board of elections;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ntabulations of the number of valid and invalid affidavit ballots, the\nreasons for which affidavit ballots were invalid, and the quantity and\ndisposition of affidavit ballots subject to the cure procedure\nprescribed by subdivision three of section 9-209 of this chapter;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ntabulations of the number of valid and invalid absentee ballots, the\nreasons for which absentee ballots were invalid and the quantity of\nabsentee ballots invalid for each such reason, and the quantity and\ndisposition of absentee ballots subject to the cure procedure prescribed\nby subdivision three of section 9-209 of this chapter;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lists of\nelection day poll sites and early voting sites and maps or other\ndocumentation of the configuration of districts in any format or formats\nas specified by the state board of elections of the election districts\nassigned to each election day poll site or early voting site;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nadopted districting or redistricting plans for every election in every\npolitical subdivision; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_112__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other publicly available data as\nrequested by the state board of elections. Nothing in this section shall\nbe construed to require an election authority to create or otherwise\nprovide a record it is not capable of collecting. Within sixty days of\nreceipt of records pursuant to this section, the New York voting and\nelections database shall post such records to its public facing website,\nprovided that individual voter registration records shall not be\npublished, but only made available to the public upon request pursuant\nto subdivision five of section 3-103 of the election law. No cost shall\nbe charged to access such records.\n  3. The state board of elections shall provide the attorney general\nwith access to copies of the non-confidential fields of the statewide\nvoter database or any similar successor statewide voter registration\ndatabase upon request, in a single tabular data file in a common,\nmachine readable format that can be readily accessed and analyzed.\n  4. Every six months, the state board of elections shall determine\nwhich election authorities have failed to transmit records to the state\nboard of elections pursuant to this section and shall publish a list of\nsuch election authorities. Upon publication of the list, an election\nauthority that failed to transmit records to the state board of\nelections pursuant to this section shall have a cure period of ten\nbusiness days to come into compliance or provide to the state board of\nelections an adequate reason the authority is not capable of\ntransmitting such records. The state board of elections may determine an\nadequate reason for non-compliance pursuant to its rules and\nregulations. If after ten business days, the election authority has\ntaken no action to cure its non-compliance the state board of elections\nor the attorney general may file an action against such election\nauthority to enforce compliance with the requirements of this section.\n  * NB Effective April 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>