<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-110"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_110">
        <num>3-110</num>
        <heading>Time allowed employees to vote</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-110. Time allowed employees to vote. 1. If a registered voter does\nnot have sufficient time outside of his or her scheduled working hours,\nwithin which to vote on any day at which he or she may vote, at any\nelection, he or she may, without loss of pay for up to two hours, take\noff so much working time as will, when added to his or her voting time\noutside his or her working hours, enable him or her to vote.\n  2. If an employee has four consecutive hours either between the\nopening of the polls and the beginning of his or her working shift, or\nbetween the end of his or her working shift and the closing of the\npolls, he or she shall be deemed to have sufficient time outside his or\nher working hours within which to vote. If he or she has less than four\nconsecutive hours he or she may take off so much working time as will,\nwhen added to his or her voting time outside his or her working hours\nenable him or her to vote, but not more than two hours of which shall be\nwithout loss of pay, provided that he or she shall be allowed time off\nfor voting only at the beginning or end of his or her working shift, as\nthe employer may designate, unless otherwise mutually agreed.\n  3. If the employee requires working time off to vote the employee\nshall notify his or her employer not more than ten nor less than two\nworking days before the day of the election that he or she requires time\noff to vote in accordance with the provisions of this section.\n  4. Not less than ten working days before every election, every\nemployer shall post conspicuously in the place of work where it can be\nseen as employees come or go to their place of work, a notice setting\nforth the provisions of this section. Such notice shall be kept posted\nuntil the close of the polls on election day.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>