<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-200"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_200">
        <num>3-200</num>
        <heading>Boards of elections; creation, qualifications of commissioners, removal</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-200. Boards of elections; creation, qualifications of\ncommissioners, removal. 1. There shall be a board of elections in each\ncounty of the state and in the city of New York for the five counties\nthereof.\n  2. Each board shall consist of two election commissioners, except that\nthe county legislative body of a county having a population of more than\none hundred and twenty thousand may, by local law, increase the number\nof commissioners to four, to be appointed as provided in this title.\nEach of the major political parties shall be eligible to recommend\nappointment of an equal number of commissioners.\n  3. In the city of New York the board shall consist of ten\ncommissioners of election who shall be registered voters in the county\nfor which they are appointed and they shall be appointed by the city\ncouncil of the city of New York. Not more than two commissioners shall\nbe registered voters of the same county.\n  4. No person shall be appointed as election commissioner or continue\nto hold office who is not a registered voter in the county and not an\nenrolled member of the party recommending his appointment, or who holds\nany other public office, except that of commissioner of deeds, notary\npublic, village officer, city or town justice, member of a community\nboard within the city of New York or trustee or officer of a school\ndistrict outside of a city.\n  6. An election commissioner shall not be a candidate for any elective\noffice which he would not be entitled to hold under the provisions of\nthis article, unless he has ceased by resignation or otherwise, to be\ncommissioner prior to his nomination or designation therefor. Otherwise\nsuch nomination or designation shall be null and void.\n  7. An election commissioner may be removed from office by the governor\nfor cause in the same manner as a sheriff. Any vacancy so resulting\nshall be filled in a manner prescribed by this article for filling\nvacancies.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>