<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-212"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-212"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-212"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_212">
        <num>3-212</num>
        <heading>Boards of elections; organization, proceedings, reports and records</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_212__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each board of elections shall make an annual report of its\naffairs and proceedings to its local legislative body once every twelve\nmonths and no later than the last day of January in any year. A copy of\nsaid annual report shall be filed with the state board of elections.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_212__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Said annual report, as required by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_212__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, shall include a detailed description of existing programs\ndesigned to enhance voter registration.  Such report shall include a\nvoter registration action plan which details the various activities and\nprograms of each board, including a description of those steps which\nshall be taken in the future to increase registration opportunities,\nespecially for those identifiable groups of persons historically\nunderrepresented on the rolls of registered voters; and coordinate voter\neducation programs with school districts, colleges and universities\nwithin the board's jurisdiction including voter registration of\nqualified applicants and instructional or extracurricular activities\npromoting participation in the electoral process.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_212__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each voter registration action plan shall provide for the\ndesignation by the board of a registration activities coordinator.  Such\ndesignee shall be responsible for initiating contact with each school\ndistrict, college and university within the area served by the board to\nrequest that such school district, college and university designate an\nadministrative liaison who, together with the registration activities\ncoordinator, shall plan, prepare and implement voter education and\nregistration programs to enhance electoral participation. The state\nboard of elections shall promulgate rules and regulations providing\nguidelines for county board of election assistance to school districts,\ncolleges and universities in the establishment of electoral\nparticipation programs.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_212__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each voter registration action plan shall set forth existing\nactivities and planned programs designed to insure compliance with the\nrequirements of subdivision two of section 5-210 of this chapter\nregarding the distribution of registration application forms.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_212__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The state board of elections shall review the voter registration\naction plan submitted by each board of elections and assist in the\ndevelopment and implementation of local registration outreach services\nand activities.\n  5. The board of elections of the city of New York, upon the\naffirmative vote of six commissioners, may adopt rules authorizing a\nnumber of commissioners less than the total membership of the board to\nact on behalf of the board on matters required to be performed by boards\nof election pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, provided that\nsuch number shall be comprised of commissioners representing equally the\ntwo political parties entitled to representation on the board.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>