<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-214"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-214"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-214"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_214">
        <num>3-214</num>
        <heading>Board of elections; general office and branches, hours</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-214. Board of elections; general office and branches, hours.  1.\nThe board of elections in the city of New York shall maintain an office\nin the borough of Manhattan, which shall be the headquarters of such\nboard, and an office in each borough of the city. Elsewhere, in each\ncounty, the county legislative body shall provide the board of elections\nfor such county with proper and suitable offices.\n  2. Any board of elections may establish as many fixed branch offices\nas it deems necessary.\n  3. Each office shall be open at least every business day during usual\nbusiness hours, except that each central board office shall be open for\nthe receipt of papers at least between the hours of nine A.M. and five\nP.M. on the last day on which a paper may be filed with it and on such\nother days and hours as may be required herein. In each of the two\ncalendar weeks before each general election, each office shall remain\nopen on at least two business days until at least seven P.M. and on\nSaturdays from not later than nine A.M. until at least noon. In the city\nof New York, each office shall also remain open on the Sunday before the\ngeneral election from not later than ten A.M. until at least one P.M.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>