<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-226"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-226"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-226"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_226">
        <num>3-226</num>
        <heading>Boards of elections; ownership, care, custody and control of voting machines</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-226. Boards of elections; ownership, care, custody and control of\nvoting machines. 1. Boards of elections shall direct the purchase,\nacquisition or lease of voting machines, of a kind authorized by law,\nwhich shall be selected by such board provided, however, nothing in this\nsection shall preclude the state board of elections from distributing\nvoting machines to boards of elections without charge. All voting\nmachines, and appliances and equipment relating to or used in the\nconduct of elections shall be in the care, custody and control of the\nboard of elections. Such board shall cause all necessary repairs and\nmaintenance to be made and employ such help as may be necessary in\nmaking such repairs and in moving, setting up and caring for all\nelection materials, equipment and appliances, including voting machines.\nAll supplies, equipment or election appliances to be used or furnished\nby such board shall be purchased by such board. All expenses of such\nboard of elections shall be certified, audited and paid as are other\nclaims against the county, or in the case of the city of New York, by\nsuch city, and all expenses connected with elections and matters\npreliminary relating thereto, including compensation of inspectors and\nclerks of election, shall be a county charge, except, at the option of\nthe county, all or any part of the type of expenses connected with\nelections and matters preliminary or relating thereto that were\npreviously incurred by towns and cities, may be apportioned pursuant to\nthis chapter to a city or town.\n  2. The board of elections shall publish or post, as the case may be,\nall notices, lists and other materials relating to elections to which\nthis section applies, and which are required by law to be published or\nposted in the county, or a political subdivision therein, except\npublications made by the state board of elections and village clerks.\n  3. Lists of persons recommended to serve as inspectors of election and\npoll clerks shall be filed by the chairperson of the county committees\nof the political parties entitled to representation on the board of\nelections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>