<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-302"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-302"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-302"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_302">
        <num>3-302</num>
        <heading>Voting machine technicians and custodians; appointment, duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-302. Voting machine technicians and custodians; appointment,\nduties.  1. The board of elections shall appoint as many voting machine\ntechnicians and voting machine custodians as shall be necessary for the\nproper preparation and repair of voting machines. Voting machine\ntechnicians may be full time employees of the board of elections and may\nalso serve as voting machine custodians as hereinafter provided. No\nperson shall be appointed as a voting machine technician or voting\nmachine custodian who is a candidate for any public office to be voted\nfor by the voters of the district in which he is to serve.\n  2. The voting machine technicians shall, under the direction of the\nboard of elections supervise the preparation of the voting machines.\nThey shall inspect voting machines to insure that they are in proper\nrepair and working order and shall notify the board of elections and the\nappropriate town or city clerk of the repairs found to be needed on any\nmachine. They shall have the authority to recommend the rejection of a\nmachine to the board of elections as not in suitable mechanical\ncondition for use in an election. They shall perform all other duties as\nrequired by the board of elections.\n  3. The board of elections shall, before the fifteenth day of January\nof each year, appoint as many custodians of voting machines as may be\nnecessary for the proper preparation of the machines. The custodian\nshall, under the direction of the board of elections, have charge of and\nrepresent the board of elections during the preparation of the voting\nmachines and serve at the pleasure of the board of elections.\n  4. The board of elections shall as often as necessary provide a course\nof training and education on the preparation, use, maintenance and\nrepair of the voting machine. Attendance at such course shall be\nrequired of all voting machine technicians who have not previously\ncompleted such a course satisfactorily.\n  5. Any person who fails to satisfactorily complete such a course shall\nnot be permitted to serve as a voting machine technician.\n  6. Voting machine custodians shall be paid for their services an\namount fixed by the board of elections, which amount shall, however, be\napproved by the legislative body of the county and shall be payable by\nthe county, or in the case of the city of New York, payable by such\ncity.\n  7. Salaries of voting machine technicians shall be fixed by the board\nof elections as provided herein and provided further that the salaries\nfor each technician may vary dependent on the number of machines to be\nserviced, other duties assigned and such other factors as the board may\nconsider relevant.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>