<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-404"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_404">
        <num>3-404</num>
        <heading>Election inspectors and poll clerks; designation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-404. Election inspectors and poll clerks; designation.  1. The\nboard of elections of each county shall on or before the fifteenth day\nof July of each year select and appoint election inspectors and poll\nclerks for each election district therein, and such number of election\ncoordinators as it determines to be necessary, and may thereafter select\nand designate election inspectors, poll clerks and election coordinators\nto fill any vacancy for an unexpired term.  The term of such designation\nshall be for a term ending on the fourteenth day of July of the\nfollowing year. If the election districts for a general or special\nvillage election conducted by the board of elections are coterminous\nwith the election districts established for general elections, such\nelection inspectors and poll clerks shall also serve at such village\nelections. If the election districts for such a village election are not\nso coterminous, the board of elections shall select the inspectors and\npoll clerks to serve in each such village election district from among\nthe inspectors and poll clerks appointed, pursuant to the provisions of\nthis section, for any election district wholly or partly in such\nvillage.\n  2. Each political party entitled to representation on any board of\nelections may, not later than the first day of May in each year, file\nwith the appropriate board of elections, an original list of persons\nrecommended to serve.  Supplemental lists may be filed at the same time\nand at any time before the designation is made and certified or when a\nvacancy exists. All designations shall be made first from those named in\nthe original list filed if those designated are found qualified.\n  3. Such lists shall be authenticated and filed by the chairman, or,\nunder his direction by the secretary, of the county committee of the\nparty, except that in cities other than the city of New York, if there\nis a general city committee of such party, such list shall be filed by\nthe chairman or secretary of such city committee.\n  4. Appointment of election inspectors, poll clerks and election\ncoordinators shall be made by boards of elections.\n  5. If a political party shall fail to submit a list or the list shall\nbe exhausted, the board of elections shall request from the appropriate\npolitical party an original or supplemental list. If after ten days no\nlist is filed by that party, the board of elections may appoint\nqualified persons, enrolled members of the political party in default,\nto act as election inspectors, poll clerks or election coordinators.\n  6. If election districts are altered or new districts created, the\nboard of elections shall have the power to transfer election inspectors\nand poll clerks in such districts; and if vacancies exist as a result of\nsuch action, those vacancies shall be filled in the manner provided by\nthis section.\n  7. Election officers shall be appointed from the lists submitted, by\nthose members of the board who represent the political party which\nsubmitted such lists. If such list is not furnished, the members of the\nboard who represent the political party in default, shall designate the\npersons to be appointed as election officers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>