<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-401"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-401"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-401"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-401/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-401/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-401/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-401/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_401">
        <num>3-401</num>
        <heading>Election coordinators; provision for</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-401. Election coordinators; provision for. 1. The board of\nelections of each county and in the city of New York, the board of\nelections of the city of New York, may, in its discretion, appoint\npersons to perform election day duties including directing voters to\ntheir proper polling place, assist election inspectors and poll clerks\nin the performance of their duties, and such other duties as may be\nassigned to them by the board of elections. Such persons shall be\ndesignated as election coordinators.\n  2. All election coordinators shall be trained in the manner prescribed\nby this article for election inspectors and poll clerks. Election\ncoordinators shall be appointed by the board of elections. The\nappointment of election coordinators shall be equally divided between\nthe two major political parties.\n  3. The board of elections of each county appointing election\ncoordinators and in the city of New York, the board of elections of the\ncity of New York, may, in its discretion, prescribe training in addition\nto that required by this article.\n  4. Any county board of elections appointing election coordinators and\nin the city of New York, the board of elections of the city of New York,\nshall prepare a report detailing assignments and duties to be delegated\nto election coordinators. Said report shall be filed with the state\nboard of elections no later than one month prior to the election at\nwhich election coordinators are to be assigned.\n  5. No person shall be certified or act as an election coordinator who\nis not a registered voter and a resident of the county in which he\nserves, or within the city of New York, of such city, who holds any\nelective public office, or who is a candidate for any public office to\nbe voted for by the voters of the district in which he is to serve, or\nwhich is not able to speak and read the English language and write it\nlegibly.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>