<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-402"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-402"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-402"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_402">
        <num>3-402</num>
        <heading>Election inspectors and poll clerks; authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-402. Election inspectors and poll clerks; authority. 1.  Election\ninspectors, in performing their duties, shall act as a board and a\nmajority vote thereof shall be required to decide all questions. If,\nhowever, any inspector or inspectors shall be temporarily absent for a\nportion of the meeting, the inspectors present shall have and may\nexercise any power or perform any duty conferred or imposed upon a board\nof inspectors, provided that they are not all members of the same\npolitical party.\n  2. Wherever an oath is provided for at any meeting of the board of\ninspectors, any inspector may administer it.\n  3. The board of inspectors, and each member thereof, shall preserve\ngood order within and around the polling place or place of registration,\nand shall keep access thereto unobstructed. The board of inspectors, or\nany member thereof, by order in writing may direct the arrest of any\nperson who refuses to obey the lawful commands of the inspectors or who\nis guilty of disorderly conduct disturbing their proceedings or\nviolating or attempting to violate any of the provisions of this\nchapter. Any peace officer, acting pursuant to his special duties, or\npolice officer shall, when requested by the board or a member thereof,\nexecute such order forthwith.\n  4. All election inspectors shall perform their duties as required by\nthe election law, and in accordance with the directions and instructions\ngiven them by the board of elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>