<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-406"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-406"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-406"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-406/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-406/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-406/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-406/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_406">
        <num>3-406</num>
        <heading>Election inspectors and poll clerks; additional</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-406. Election inspectors and poll clerks; additional. 1.  Each\nboard of elections shall establish a list of persons duly qualified to\nserve as election inspectors, which list shall be known as the\n"Additional Inspector List", in such number of persons as the board\nshall determine. Such a list shall be equally divided between the major\npolitical parties. Appointments under this section shall be made in the\nmanner provided for the appointment of regular election inspectors and\nfor a like term.\n  2. Any person serving as an additional inspector of elections may, at\nthe direction of the board of elections, be assigned to any election\ndistrict or transferred from one election district to another after he\nhas entered upon the performance of his duties on a day of registration\nor election.\n  3. Any person designated to the additional inspectors list shall meet\nthe requirements for regular election inspectors and may be removed in\nthe same manner as any election inspector.\n  4. If the board of elections shall determine that a vacancy exists\nupon any board of inspectors or that any election inspector or poll\nclerk is absent, and that no qualified voter has been appointed pursuant\nto this chapter to act in place of such election inspector or poll\nclerk, or to relieve any qualified voter who has been so appointed, it\nshall forthwith direct a person appointed pursuant to this section to\nact in place of the absent election inspector or poll clerk or qualified\nvoter so appointed until such absent election inspector or his appointed\nsuccessor shall appear; provided, however, that the additional election\ninspector so appointed shall be a designee of the same political party\nas the election inspector in whose place he shall act. The board of\nelections shall provide suitable identification for every additional\nelection inspector to present to the chairman of the board before\nentering upon the duties of such office.\n  5. Additional inspectors shall be paid by the county in which they\nserve in an amount fixed by the board of elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>