<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-418"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-418"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-418"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-418/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-418/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-418/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-418/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_418">
        <num>3-418</num>
        <heading>Election inspectors and poll clerks; emergency provisions for filling vacancies or absences</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-418. Election inspectors and poll clerks; emergency provisions for\nfilling vacancies or absences. 1. If, at the time of a meeting of the\ninspectors, there shall be a vacancy, or if any inspector shall be\nabsent, the inspector present who is the designee of the same party as\nthe absent inspector shall appoint a qualified voter of the same city or\ntown to act in place of the absent inspector. If, however, any\ninspectors shall be temporarily absent for a portion of the meeting, the\ninspectors present, provided that they are not all members of the same\npolitical party, shall have and may exercise any power or perform any\nduty conferred or imposed upon a board of inspectors.\n  2. If at the time of any such meeting two inspectors who are members\nof the same party shall be absent, or their places shall be vacant, the\npoll clerk or poll clerks present, if any, of the same party shall act\nas inspectors and shall appoint qualified voters of the same city or\ntown who are members of the same party as the absent inspectors, to act\nin place of such clerks.\n  3. If at the time of any such meeting two inspectors and the poll\nclerk or clerks, if any, who are members of the same party shall be\nabsent, or their places shall be vacant, the inspector or inspectors\npresent, or in their absence the poll clerk or clerks present, if any,\nshall appoint qualified voters of the same city or town, who are members\nof the same party as such absent inspectors, to act as such inspectors\nand clerks, until the inspectors or clerks duly appointed by the\noriginal appointing authority, shall appear.\n  4. If at the time of any such meeting, there shall be a vacancy in the\noffice of poll clerk, or if a poll clerk shall be absent, the inspectors\nwho are designees of the same party, or in their absence, any poll clerk\nof the same party who is present, shall appoint a qualified voter of the\nsame city or town who is a member of the same party, to act in place of\nthe absent poll clerk.\n  5. Every person so appointed or named shall take the oath of office,\nwhich shall be administered by any person authorized to administer oaths\nor by one of the inspectors.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>