<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-416"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-416"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-416"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-416/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-416/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-416/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-416/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_416">
        <num>3-416</num>
        <heading>Election inspectors, poll clerks and election coordinators; removal</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-416. Election inspectors, poll clerks and election coordinators;\nremoval. 1. Any election officer appointed pursuant to the provisions of\nthis chapter, may be removed for cause by the board making the\nappointment. Unless such removal is for improper conduct, while such\nofficer is actually on duty on the day of registration or election, it\nshall occur only after notice in writing to the officer to be removed.\nSuch notice shall set forth clearly the reasons for his removal.\nNeglect to attend to the duties of the office shall be a cause for the\nremoval of any such officer.\n  2. It shall be the duty of the board making the appointment of an\nelection officer, to remove forthwith such officer without preferring\nany charges and without notice to such officer, upon the written request\nof the official of the political party who certified the name of such\nelection officer, or his successor. All such vacancies so created shall\nbe filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made. Any\nelection officer who shall at any time be appointed to fill a vacancy,\nshall have that fact stated in his certificate of appointment and shall\nhold office only during the unexpired term of his predecessor.\n  3. Any election inspector, poll clerk or election coordinator who is\nremoved from office for cause shall forfeit the compensation earned up\nto the time of such removal.\n  4. An election inspector, poll clerk or election coordinator who is\nremoved for cause shall be ineligible to again serve in such capacity;\nprovided, however, that the board of elections may rehear the charges\nagainst such person at any time and it may determine that such person\nshall again be eligible for appointment if otherwise qualified.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>