<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-420"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-420"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-420"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-420/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-420/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-420/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-420/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_420">
        <num>3-420</num>
        <heading>Election inspectors, poll clerks and election coordinators; compensation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-420. Election inspectors, poll clerks and election coordinators;\ncompensation. 1. Election inspectors, poll clerks, election coordinators\nand qualified voters appointed to act in place of an absent inspector,\nclerk or coordinator shall be paid for their services on the days of\nregistration and election, by the county containing the election\ndistrict in which they serve, in an amount fixed by the county\nlegislative body, subject to such limitations as shall be prescribed or\nauthorized by statute, except that in the city of New York the amount of\nsuch compensation shall be payable by such city and shall be fixed by\nthe mayor at a daily rate which, in the case of election inspectors\nshall not be less than one hundred thirty dollars and in the case of\nelection coordinators not less than two hundred dollars. Such\ninspectors, poll clerks, election coordinators and qualified voters at a\ngeneral or special village election conducted by the board of elections\nshall be paid by such village in an amount fixed by the village board of\ntrustees subject to any such limitations.\n  2. An election inspector or poll clerk who attends a required training\nsession shall be paid not less than twenty-five dollars for each meeting\nplus, at the option of the county, transportation expenses not to exceed\nthe mileage allowance approved by the county legislative body for their\npermanent employees, payable by the county or in the case of the city of\nNew York, by such city. For administrative purposes, each county may\nestablish one or more categories for the mileage allowance, based on the\nrange of distance traveled, and pay the mileage allowance for that\ncategory.\n  3. The chairman of the board of inspectors of each election district\nshall, within twenty-four hours of any election or day of local\nregistration, furnish to the board appointing such officers, if required\nby such board to do so, a certificate stating the days and hours of\nactual service of each member of such board, the names of the persons,\nif any, who served as clerks on an election day, the hours of their\nservice, and the days on which the store, building or room hired for\nregistration and election purposes was actually used for such purposes.\n  4. If a person recommended and examined for appointment as election\nofficer in a city, or examined therefor without recommendation in the\nabsence of a party list, be found disqualified and be not appointed, as\ntherein provided, and such person shall serve in the same calendar year\nas inspector at a registration or election or as clerk at an election,\nunder a vacancy appointment, he shall receive no compensation for such\nservices.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>