<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-502"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-502"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-502"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-3-502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_502">
        <num>3-502</num>
        <heading>Nassau county; board of elections, special provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-502. Nassau county; board of elections, special provisions. 1. All\nthe provisions of this article, when not inconsistent with this section,\nshall apply to the county of Nassau.\n  2. At least thirty days before the first day of January of any year in\nwhich a commissioner of elections is to be appointed, or within thirty\ndays after a vacancy occurs in the office of commissioner of elections,\nthe chairman of the appropriate party county committee shall file with\nthe clerk of the county legislative body a certificate naming the person\nwhom he is recommending for appointment as such commissioner of\nelections. The certificate shall be in the form and contain the\ninformation prescribed by the state board of elections.\n  3. All petitions and certificates of nomination or designation, or of\ndeclination thereof, for an election to which this section applies, and\nall statements of receipts and expenditures relating to such an\nelection, required to be filed with any officer of Nassau county, or\npolitical subdivision therein shall be filed with the board of\nelections.\n  4. Inspectors of election shall be appointed for a term of two years,\nexcept that an inspector appointed to fill a vacancy, shall hold office\nonly for the unexpired term of his predecessor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>