<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-106"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_106">
        <num>4-106</num>
        <heading>Certification of offices to be filled at general or special elections; state board of elections, county, city, village and town clerks</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-106. Certification of offices to be filled at general or special\nelections; state board of elections, county, city, village and town\nclerks.\n  1. The state board of elections shall, by February first in the year\nof each general election, make and transmit to the board of elections of\neach county, a certificate stating each office, except county, city,\nvillage and town offices to be voted for at such election in such\ncounty.\n  2. Each county, city, village and town clerk, by February first in the\nyear of each general election, shall make and transmit to the board of\nelections a certificate stating each county, city, village or town\noffice, respectively to be voted for at each such election. Each village\nclerk, at least five months before each general village election\nconducted by the board of elections, shall make, and transmit to such\nboard, a certificate stating each village office to be filled at such\nelection.\n  3. If any such office is for an unexpired term, the certificate shall\nso state. The state board of elections shall forthwith, upon the filing\nof a governor's proclamation ordering a special election, transmit to\nthe board of elections in each county in which the special election is\nto be held, a notice of such proclamation and a certificate of the\noffices to be voted for at such special election.\n  4. Within three days after the occurrence of any vacancy in an office\nrequired to be filled at the next general election or a general or\nspecial village election or other special election conducted by the\nboard of elections, the state board of elections or the county, city,\ntown or village clerk as is appropriate, shall file with the county\nboard of elections, a certificate indicating the occurrence of the\nvacancy and the position which is to be filled.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>