<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-102"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_102">
        <num>4-102</num>
        <heading>Maps; congressional, senatorial, assembly and election districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-102. Maps; congressional, senatorial, assembly and election\ndistricts. 1. The state board of elections, at the expense of the state,\nshall publish maps showing the county or counties contained in each of\nthe congressional districts, senatorial districts and assembly districts\nof the state.\n  2. Where a portion of a county is contained in any congressional,\nsenatorial or assembly district, the state board shall publish a map\nshowing the portion of such county contained in each such respective\ndistrict. Such map or maps shall show the extreme boundaries of the\nportion of the county so contained, as described by the street boundary\nand shall have printed thereon the names of the streets or public ways\nbounding the district; provided however, that where the extreme boundary\nconsists of the boundary line of any city, town or village, it shall be\nsufficient to so indicate, without showing or naming individual streets\nor public ways.\n  3. The state board shall also publish three individual maps of each\nborough of the city of New York, which shall show all of the\ncongressional districts or parts thereof, all of the senatorial\ndistricts or parts thereof, and all of the assembly districts or parts\nthereof contained in such borough. Each such map shall show the extreme\nboundaries of the districts to which it refers, as described in the\nstreet boundary and shall have printed thereon the names of the streets\nor public ways bounding the district.\n  4. All such maps shall be to scale. Pertinent copies of such maps\nshall be filed and kept open to public inspection as follows: one in the\noffice of the town or city clerk, except in the city of New York; one in\nthe office of every board of elections, and each branch office, if any.\nSurplus copies if any, may be sold at cost and the proceeds remitted to\nthe state board of elections. Whenever the boundaries of any\ncongressional, senatorial, or assembly district are altered, the state\nboard of elections shall publish revised copies of those maps affected\nby such boundary alteration and make the distribution required in this\nsubdivision.\n  5. a. A map or separate maps of uniform scale of election districts\nwithin a town or ward, or, in the city of New York and the county of\nNassau, within an assembly district, wholly within such city or county\nor within that portion of any assembly district within such city or\ncounty, shall be made by the board or body creating or altering the\ndistricts so that the map or maps on file at any time will show the\nexisting election districts in such town, ward, assembly district, or\nthe appropriate portion of such assembly district.\n  b. In a city, street corner numbers of the block or blocks defining\nthe extreme boundaries of each election district shall be printed on the\nmap or maps, within or outside the block line or lines, so as to show\nplainly the highest and lowest street numbers within the election\ndistrict of every street bounding the district.\n  c. Copies of such maps or descriptions shall be filed and kept open to\npublic inspection as follows: one in the office of the town or city\nclerk, except in the city of New York; one in the office and each branch\noffice, if any, of the board of elections.\n  d. One copy of each map shall be delivered, upon request, to the state\nboard of elections and to a person or officer designated jointly by the\nspeaker of the assembly and the temporary president of the senate. Each\ntime an election district boundary is changed a copy of the new map\nshall be sent to each such board, person or officer who has requested\nsuch maps. Surplus copies of maps of election districts in a city or\ntown may be sold at cost and the proceeds paid to the county, city or\ntown which incurred the expense of preparing the maps.\n  e. Copies of such maps shall be posted on the board of elections'\nwebsite. In addition, each board of elections shall make such maps\navailable in downloadable digital file formats compatible with\ngeographic information system (GIS) software, such as shapefile,\ngeodatabase, KML, or other similar vector based GIS file types.\n  6. In a town, after the creation or alteration of any election\ndistrict therein, the board of elections shall furnish to the inspectors\nof election in each election district, on the first day of registration\nor election occurring after such change, a map or dsecription showing\nsuch election district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>