<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-104"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-104"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-104"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_104">
        <num>4-104</num>
        <heading>Registration and polling places; designation of</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_104__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the board of elections, after designating a polling place,\nand after sending written notice of such polling place to each\nregistered voter, designates an alternative polling place, it must, at\nleast five days before the next election or day for registration, send\nby mail a written notice to each registered voter notifying such voter\nof the changed location of such polling place. If such notice is not\npossible the board of elections must provide for an alternative form of\nnotice to be given to voters at the location of the previous polling\nplace.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_104__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a city with a population of one million or more, if the board\nof elections, after designating a polling place, is notified of the need\nto change the location of such polling place, such board of elections\nshall, within five days of receiving such notice, notify by mail:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_104__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the chairpersons of all state party committees;\n  (ii) the chairpersons of all county party committees in the county in\nwhich such polling place is located;\n  (iii) the member of the state assembly representing the district in\nwhich such polling place is located and any member of the state assembly\nwhose district includes any election district the residents of which are\nassigned to vote at such polling place;\n  (iv) the state senator representing the district in which such polling\nplace is located and any state senator whose district includes any\nelection district the residents of which are assigned to vote at such\npolling place;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_104__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the city councilmember representing the district in which such\npolling place is located and any city councilmember whose district\nincludes any election district the residents of which are assigned to\nvote at such polling place; and\n  (vi) in an assembly district in which assembly district leaders are\nelected to represent an entire assembly district, the assembly district\nleaders representing the district in which such polling place is located\nand any assembly district leader whose district includes any election\ndistrict the residents of which are assigned to vote at such polling\nplace, or, in an assembly district in which district leaders are elected\nin parts, the district leaders for the part in which the polling place\nis located and any assembly district leader whose part includes any\nelection district the residents of which are assigned to vote at such\npolling place.\n  3. A building exempt from taxation shall be used whenever possible as\na polling place if it is situated in the same or a contiguous election\ndistrict, and may contain as many distinctly separate polling places as\npublic convenience may require. The expense, if any, incidental to its\nuse, shall be paid like the expense of other places of registration and\nvoting. If a board or body empowered to designate polling places chooses\na public school building for such purpose, the board or agency which\ncontrols such building must make available a room or rooms in such\nbuilding which are suitable for registration and voting and which are as\nclose as possible to a convenient entrance to such building and must\nmake available any such room or rooms which the board or body\ndesignating such building determines are accessible to physically\ndisabled voters as provided in subdivision one-a. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of any general, special or local law, if a board or body\nempowered to designate polling places chooses a publicly owned or leased\nbuilding, other than a public school bui...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_104__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever the number of voters eligible to vote in an election\nin any election district is less than one hundred, the polling place\ndesignated for such district may be the polling place of any other\ndistrict which could properly be designated as the polling place of the\nfirst mentioned district pursuant to the provisions of this chapter,\nexcept that the polling place designated for any such district may be\nthe polling place of any other district in such city or town provided\nthat the distance from such first mentioned district to the polling\nplace for such other district is not unreasonable pursuant to rules or\nregulations prescribed by the state board of elections and provided that\nthe total number of persons eligible to vote in such other district in\nsuch election, including the persons eligible to vote in such first\nmentioned districts, is not more than five hundred. The inspectors of\nelection and poll clerks, if any, of such other election district shall\nalso act in all respects as the election officers for such first\nmentioned districts and no other inspectors shall be appointed to serve\nin or for such first mentioned districts. A separate poll ledger or\ncomputer generated registration list, separate voting machine or ballots\nand separate canvass of results shall be provided for such first\nmentioned districts, except that if the candidates and ballot proposals\nto be voted on by the voters of such districts are the same, the\nelection districts shall be combined and shall constitute a single\nelection district for that election. However, if the first mentioned\ndistrict contains fewer than ten voters eligible to vote in such\nelection, there shall be no limitation on the total number of persons\neligible to vote in such combined district. If the polling place for any\nelection district is moved for any election, pursuant to the provisions\nof this subdivision, the board of elections shall, not later than ten\nnor more than fifteen days before ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_104__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever the total number of voters eligible to vote in any\nprimary or special election, in any two election districts whose polling\nplaces are regularly located in the same building, is less than four\nhundred, the board of elections may assign the inspectors of election of\nthe election district which contains the greater number of such voters,\nto act also, in all respects, as the election officers of the other such\nelection district and no other election officers shall be appointed to\nserve in or for such other election district at such primary or special\nelection. A separate poll ledger or computer generated registration\nlist, separate voting machine or ballots and separate canvass of results\nshall be provided for each such election district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_104__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever all the candidates to be voted upon at a primary\nelection, except a primary election in the city of New York, or all the\ncandidates and ballot proposals to be voted upon at a special election,\nor at a school board election conducted by the board of elections, or at\na general election in the city of New York in a year in which there is\nno election for electors of president and vice-president of the United\nStates or governor of the state or mayor of such city, by the voters of\nany two or more election districts whose polling places are regularly\nlocated in the same building are identical, the board of elections may\ncombine such election districts for that election, provided that the\ntotal number of voters eligible to vote in any such combined election\ndistrict does not exceed one thousand two hundred in a primary election\nor does not exceed two thousand in a special election or a general\nelection in the city of New York.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_104__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, polling\nplaces designated for any one such election district that will be\nutilizing any voting machine or system certified for use in New York\nstate pursuant to chapter one hundred eighty-one of the laws of two\nthousand five, may be the polling place of any other contiguous district\nor districts, provided the voting system used in such polling place\nproduces separate and distinct vote totals for each election district\nvoting in such polling place on such voting machine or system.\n  5-a. Whenever a contiguous property of a college or university\ncontains three hundred or more registrants who are registered to vote at\nany address on such contiguous property, the polling place designated\nfor such registrants shall be on such contiguous property or at a nearby\nlocation recommended by the college or university and agreed to by the\nboard of elections.\n  6. Each polling place designated, whenever practicable, shall be\nsituated on the main or ground floor of the premises selected. It shall\nbe of sufficient area to admit and comfortably accommodate voters in\nnumbers consistent with the deployment of voting systems and privacy\nbooths, pursuant to 9 NYCRR 6210.19. Such deployment of voting systems,\nelection workers and election resources shall be in a sufficient number\nto accommodate the numbers of voters eligible to vote in such polling\nplace.\n  6-a. Each polling place designated, whenever practicable, shall be\nsituated directly on a public transportation route.\n  7. No polling place shall be located on premises owned or leased by a\nperson holding public office or who is a candidate for public office at\na primary or general election.\n  8. Whenever the board of elections shall determine that there is no\nbuilding within an election district available and suitable for the\nmeetings for the registration of voters or for any election, or that for\nreasons of efficiency or economy it is desirable to con...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>