<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-118"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-118"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-118"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_118">
        <num>4-118</num>
        <heading>Notice of primary election; publication of by board of elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-118. Notice of primary election; publication of by board of\nelections.  1. Each county board of elections shall publish in the week\nending on the Saturday preceding a primary election a notice specifying\nthe day of such primary election, the hours during which it will be held\nand the public offices for which nominations are to be made and the\nparty positions which are to be filled at such primary elections. Such\npublication shall be in two newspapers published within the county. If\nthe county contains a city or cities, at least one of such newspapers\nshall be published in the city, or the largest city, if there be more\nthan one.\n  2. The board of elections of every county containing a city, other\nthan the board of elections of the city of New York, shall publish on\nthe day of each primary election, in two newspapers within each city in\nsuch county, representing the major political parties, a list of the\npolling places designated within such city, referring to the election\ndistricts by their numbers and wards or assembly districts. Such list\nshall identify those polling places which do not provide access to\nhandicapped voters. If the newspaper is an evening newspaper, such\nnotice shall be published on the day prior to such primary election. If\nin an election district the primary of a party is uncontested, such\nnotice shall include, in a place where they clearly refer to the proper\ndistrict and polling place, the words "........................(insert\nname of party) primary uncontested."  If in an election district the\nprimaries of all parties are uncontested, such notice shall include, in\nlieu of the address of the polling place, the words "Polls not open. All\nprimaries uncontested." Such publication in such newspapers by the board\nof elections of the city of New York shall be at least one-half page in\nsize and in lieu of the information otherwise required by this\nsubdivision, shall set forth both in English and such other languages as\nsuch board deems appropriate the date of the election, the hours the\npolls are open and the phone number to call for information about\nlocation of polling places, their accessibility to the handicapped and\nany other subjects which such board deems appropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>