<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-112"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-112"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-03-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-112"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_112">
        <num>4-112</num>
        <heading>Certification of nominations; state board of elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-112. Certification of nominations; state board of elections. 1.\nThe state board of elections, not later than fifty-five days before a\ngeneral election, fifty-three days before a special election, or\ntwenty-four days before a special election held pursuant to paragraph b\nof subdivision three of section forty-two of the public officers law,\nshall certify to each county board of elections the name and residence\nof each candidate nominated in any valid certificate filed with it or by\nthe returns canvassed by it, the title of the office for which\nnominated; the name of the party or body specified of which he or she is\na candidate; and a notation as to whether or not any litigation is\npending concerning the candidacy. Upon the completion of any such\nlitigation, the state board of elections shall forthwith notify the\nappropriate county boards of elections of the results of such\nlitigation.\n  2. The state board of elections, not later than seven days before the\ngeneral election, shall certify to each county board of elections the\nname and residence of each write-in candidate for president and vice\npresident of the United States who has filed a valid certificate of\ncandidacy with it.\n  3. If a certificate of a nomination to fill a vacancy caused by death\nor disqualification is filed with the state board of elections, or a\ncourt order shall change a nomination, after the state board has made\nits certifications to the county boards of elections, the state board\nshall transmit forthwith a statement of such nomination to the\nappropriate boards of elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>