<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-116"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-116"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-11-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-116"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_116">
        <num>4-116</num>
        <heading>Constitutional amendments and questions; publication of by state board of elections and secretary of state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-116. Constitutional amendments and questions; publication of by\nstate board of elections and secretary of state. 1. The secretary of\nstate shall cause each concurrent resolution of the two houses of the\nlegislature agreeing to a proposed amendment to the constitution that\nhas been referred to the legislature to be chosen at the next general\nelection to be published at least once in each of the three months next\npreceding such election. Such publication shall include the information\nthat such amendment has been so referred.\n  2. The state board of elections shall publish once in the week\npreceding any election at which proposed constitutional amendments or\nother propositions or questions are to be submitted to the voters of the\nstate an abstract of such amendment or question, a brief statement of\nthe law or proceedings authorizing such submission, a statement that\nsuch submission will be made and the form in which it is to be\nsubmitted.\n  3. Publication required by subdivision two of this section shall be in\none newspaper of general circulation in each county.\n  4. No later than two months prior to the general election at which any\nstatewide ballot proposal is to be submitted to the people, the state\nboard of elections and all local boards of elections shall publish on\ntheir websites the information required to be published pursuant to\nsubdivision two of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>