<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-119"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-119"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-119"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_119">
        <num>4-119</num>
        <heading>Publication of list of places for registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-119. Publication of list of places for registration.  1. The board\nor body authorized to designate places for registration in any city,\nother than the city of New York, shall publish on each day of\nregistration a list of the places for registration designated within\nsuch city in two newspapers published in such city. The lists shall\nrefer to the election districts by their numbers and wards or assembly\ndistricts. Such lists shall identify those polling places which do not\nprovide access to handicapped voters. The board of elections of the city\nof New York shall publish in at least two newspapers in such city, a\nnotice, at least one-half page in size, in English and such other\nlanguages as such board deems appropriate which shall set forth the\ndates and hours of registration and the phone number to call for\ninformation about location of polling places, their accessibility to the\nhandicapped, applications for early mail and absentee ballots and any\nother subjects which such board deems appropriate. So far as is\nconsistent with the provisions of this section, one of such newspapers\nin each such city or, in each county of the city of New York, shall\nrepresent each of the major political parties and shall have a large\ncirculation affording wide publicity. If the newspaper is an evening\nnewspaper the notice shall be published on the last day, other than a\nSunday, prior to any such day of registration.\n  2. The board or body authorized to designate places for registration\nin any town may publish within one week next preceding the first day of\nregistration in a newspaper or newspapers designated by such board or\nbody, a list of places of registration within such town, a statement of\nthe days and hours of registration and a brief description of the\nboundaries of each election district in the town. Such lists shall\nidentify those polling places which do not provide access to handicapped\nvoters. The amount to be paid for any of such publications shall be at\nthe rate prescribed by section seventy-a of the public officers law. In\nno publication, however, shall any type smaller than agate be used. The\namount to be paid for all such publications shall be a town charge.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>