<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-120"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_120">
        <num>4-120</num>
        <heading>Notices of general, village and special elections; publication of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-120. Notices of general, village and special elections;\npublication of. 1. The board of elections shall publish once in each of\nthe two weeks preceding a general election, or a special or village\nelection conducted by the board of elections, a notice specifying the\nday of the election, and the public officers to be voted for within such\ncounty, or any part thereof at such election. The board of elections\nshall, as soon as practicable, but not less than two weeks prior to any\nspecial election, prominently display on its website the date and hours\nof the election, the offices to be voted on in the county, part of a\ncounty, or the city of New York, and a link to any poll site information\nor poll location tools, where available. Such information shall also be\nmade available to local governments, municipalities, and community\nboards for publication on any public-facing internet website, web\napplication, web domain or digital application, including a social\nnetwork or search engine, to the extent that such publication is\npracticable. If constitutional amendments, or questions are to be\nsubmitted to the voters of the state, the notice shall state that fact\nand that a copy of each such amendment or question may be obtained at\nthe board of elections, by any voter. Such publication shall be in two\nnewspapers published within the county. If the county contains a city or\ncities, at least one of such newspapers shall be published in the city,\nor the largest city, if there be more than one.\n  In the case of a village election, such publication shall be made in a\nnewspaper of general circulation in such village and shall include an\nabstract of any proposition to be voted upon at such election.\n  2. The board or body authorized to designate places for voting in any\ntown or in any city, except the city of New York, may publish on the\npublication day immediately preceding election day, in a newspaper or\nnewspapers designated by such board or body, a notice of the election,\nand the village clerk shall publish at least ten days prior to any\nvillage election conducted by the board of elections in a newspaper of\ngeneral circulation in such village a list of the polling places, the\ndate and hours of election and, at the discretion of such board or\nclerk, a brief description of the boundaries of each election district.\nSuch list shall identify those polling places which do not provide\naccess to handicapped voters. The amount to be paid for any of such\npublications shall be at the rate prescribed by section seventy-a of the\npublic officers law. In no publication, however, shall any type smaller\nthan agate be used. The amount to be paid for all such publications\nshall be a town, city or village charge.\n  3. The board of elections of the city of New York shall publish on the\neighth day before and the day before each general election, in at least\ntwo newspapers in such city, a notice, at least one-half page in size,\nin English and such other languages as such board deems appropriate,\nwhich sets forth the dates and hours of the election and the phone\nnumber to call for information about the location of polling places,\ntheir accessibility to the handicapped, applications for early mail and\nabsentee ballots and any other subjects which such board deems\nappropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>