<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-122"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-122"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-09-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-122"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_122">
        <num>4-122</num>
        <heading>Lists of nomination; publication of by board of elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-122. Lists of nomination; publication of by board of elections. 1.\nThe county board of elections shall publish, at least six days before an\nelection, a list containing the name of every candidate for public\noffice to be voted for within its jurisdiction at such election.\n  2. The candidates for the office of presidential electors shall, in\nthe list in subdivision one of this section, only be described as a\nspecific number of such electors, nominated to support the party\ncandidates, naming them, for the office of president and vice-president.\n  3. The list described in subdivision one of this section shall be\npublished at least once in not less than two nor more than four\nnewspapers in the county. In a county containing a city, at least one\nsuch publication shall be in a daily newspaper published in a city\ntherein, if there be such a newspaper. In the case of a village election\nheld at a time other than the time of a general election, such\npublication shall be in a newspaper having general circulation in such\nvillage. So far as is consistent with this section, one such newspaper\nshall represent each of the major political parties. Should the board of\nelections find it impossible to make such publication six days before\nelection it shall make it at the earliest possible day thereafter before\nthe election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>