<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-132"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-132"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-132"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-132/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-132/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-132/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-132/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_132">
        <num>4-132</num>
        <heading>Polling places; equipment for</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-132. Polling places; equipment for. The board of elections or the\ntown, city or village clerk, when a town, city or village holds an\nelection not conducted by the board of elections, shall provide in each\npolling place, as required, the following articles:\n  a. Material to define the voting area.\n  b. Separate boxes for the purposes of receiving ballots. Such boxes\nshall have an opening on the top, large enough to allow a single ballot\nto be passed easily through the opening, but no larger, and shall be\nsupplied with a protective lock or seal.\n  c. A booth or device in each election district for the use of voters\nmarking ballots. Such booth or device shall be so constructed as to\npermit the voter to mark his or her ballot in secrecy and shall be\nfurnished at all times with an appropriate marking device.\n  d. A sufficient number of maps, street finders or other descriptions\nof all of the polling places and election districts within the political\nsubdivision in which the polling place is located to enable the election\ninspectors and poll clerks to determine the correct election district\nand polling place for each street address within the political\nsubdivision in which the polling place is located.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>