<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-138"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-138"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-138"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-138/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-138/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-138/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-138/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_138">
        <num>4-138</num>
        <heading>Expenses of boards of elections outside New York City; apportionment of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-138. Expenses of boards of elections outside New York City;\napportionment of. The board of elections in each county, outside of the\ncity of New York, on or before the fifteenth day of December and not\nearlier than the first day of October, in each year, shall certify to\nthe clerk of the legislative body of the county, the total amount of the\nexpenses of such board of elections, including salaries for the\npreceding year, and, if the legislative body of any county shall so\ndirect, shall certify to such clerk the portions of such expenses which\nunder provisions of law are to be borne by any city or cities in said\ncounty and the portion thereof which is to be borne by the rest of such\ncounty. Whenever any additional expenses either for salaries or supplies\nin addition to the regular county-wide primary and election expenses are\nincurred by a board of elections incidental to any election in any city,\ntown or village, such board of elections shall certify to the county\nlegislative body a detailed statement of such expenses.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>