<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-136"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-136"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-136"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-136/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-136/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-136/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-136/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_136">
        <num>4-136</num>
        <heading>Election expenses; payment of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-136. Election expenses; payment of. 1. Except as provided for in\nsubdivision two of this section, the expenses of providing polling\nplaces, voting booths, supplies therefor, ballot boxes and other\nfurniture for the polling place for any election, including the storage,\ntransportation and maintenance of voting machines, appliances and\nequipment or ballot counting devices, and the compensation of the\nelection officers in each election district, shall be a charge upon the\ncounty in which such election district is situated, except in the city\nof New York where such expenses shall be a charge upon the city of New\nYork.\n  2. All expenses incurred under this chapter by the board of elections\nof a county outside of the city of New York shall be a charge against\nthe county and in the city of New York the expenses of the board of\nelections shall be a charge against such city. The expenses incurred by\nthe board of elections of a county outside the city of New York may,\npursuant to section 3-226 of this chapter, be apportioned among the\ncities and towns therein, or in the case of a village election held\nother than at the time of the fall primary or general election,\napportioned to such villages therein.\n  3. In the city of New York all leased or purchased equipment,\nsupplies, ballots, printing and publications, except newspaper notices\nand advertisements, to be used or furnished by such board, may be\nprocured for it by the purchasing department or agency of such city as\nif such board were an agency of such city. Such board shall comply with\nthe rules and regulations of the New York city procurement policy board\nand applicable state law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>