<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-130"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_130">
        <num>4-130</num>
        <heading>Supplies for registration; manner and time of delivery</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-130. Supplies for registration; manner and time of delivery.  1.\nBefore it is sent from the office or branch office of the board of\nelections, each ledger or binder of blank registration records shall be\nlocked in a distinctively numbered carrying case. Such board shall place\nthe key for such carrying case in a sealed envelope on which shall be\nwritten or printed the number of the carrying case.  No such case or key\nshall be delivered to any person who is not designated in this chapter\nas a person entitled to receive it. Any person to whom any such case or\nkey shall be delivered shall give a receipt therefor to the person\ndelivering it.  Such receipt shall recite the official title or capacity\nof the person receiving it and, in each instance, the distinctive number\nidentifying it.  After leaving the board of elections no such case shall\nbe unlocked except at the time and in the manner provided in this\nchapter.\n  2. a. Except in the cities of New York, Buffalo, and Rochester, the\nboard of elections shall deliver at its office to each town or city\nclerk in its county not more than five days before the beginning of\nlocal registration, the registration record forms, supplies and\nequipment required for local registration and such clerks shall deliver\nthe same to the several boards of inspectors within such town or city\napproximately one-half hour before the hour fixed for beginning such\nregistration.\n  b. In the cities of New York, Buffalo, and Rochester the board of\nelections shall deliver such material to the boards of inspectors at\nleast one-half hour before the hour fixed for beginning local\nregistration.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>