<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-134"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-134"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-134"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-134/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-134/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-134/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-4-134/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_134">
        <num>4-134</num>
        <heading>Preparation and delivery of ballots, supplies and equipment for use at elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4-134. Preparation and delivery of ballots, supplies and equipment\nfor use at elections. 1. The board of elections shall deliver, at its\noffice, to the clerk of each town or city in the county, except the\ncities of New York, Buffalo and Rochester and to the clerk of each\nvillage in the county in which elections are conducted by the board of\nelections, by the Saturday before the primary, general, village or other\nelection for which they are required: the official and sample ballots;\nledgers prepared for delivery in the manner provided in subdivision two\nof this section and containing the registration poll records of all\npersons entitled to vote at such election in such town, city or village,\nor computer generated registration lists containing the names of all\npersons entitled to vote at such election in such town, city or village;\nchallenge reports prepared as directed by this chapter; sufficient\napplications for registration by mail; sufficient ledger seals and other\nsupplies and equipment required by this article to be provided by the\nboard of elections for each polling place in such town, city or village.\nThe town, city or village clerk shall call at the office of such board\nof elections at such time and receive such ballots, supplies and\nequipment. In the cities of New York, Buffalo and Rochester the board of\nelections shall cause such ballots, supplies and equipment to be\ndelivered to the board of inspectors of each election district\napproximately one-half hour before the opening of the polls for voting,\nand shall take receipts therefor.\n  2. The board of elections shall provide for each election district a\nledger or ledgers containing the registration poll records or lists with\ncomputer generated facsimile signatures, of all persons entitled to vote\nin such election district at such election. Such ledgers shall be\nlabelled, sealed, locked and transported in locked carrying cases. After\nleaving the board of elections no such carrying case shall be unlocked\nexcept at the time and in the manner provided in this chapter.\n  3. Each kind of official ballot shall be arranged in a package in the\nconsecutive order of the numbers printed on the stubs thereof beginning\nwith number one. All official and sample ballots for each election\ndistrict shall be in separate sealed packages, clearly marked on the\noutside thereof, with the number and kind of ballots contained therein\nand indorsed with the designation of the election district for which\nthey were prepared. The other supplies provided for each election\ndistrict also shall be enclosed in a sealed package, or packages, with a\nlabel on the outside thereof showing the contents of each package.\n  4. All such packages so received and marked for any election district\nshall be delivered unopened and with the seals thereof unbroken to the\ninspectors of election of such election districts at least one hour\nbefore the opening of the polls of such election therein, who shall give\na receipt therefor specifying the number and kind of packages delivered.\n  5. Town, city and village clerks required to provide official and\nsample ballots, registration records, seals, supplies and equipment, as\ndescribed in this section, for town, city and village elections not\nconducted by the board of elections, shall in like manner, deliver them\nto the inspectors or presiding officers of the election at each polling\nplace at which such meetings and elections are held, respectively, in\nlike sealed packages marked on the outside in like manner, and shall\ntake receipts therefor in like manner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>