<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-05-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-106"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_106">
        <num>5-106</num>
        <heading>Qualifications of voters; reasons for exclusion</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-106. Qualifications of voters; reasons for exclusion.\n  1. No person who shall receive, accept, or offer to receive, or pay,\noffer or promise to pay, contribute, offer or promise to contribute to\nanother, to be paid or used, any money or any other valuable thing as a\ncompensation or reward for the giving or withholding a vote at an\nelection, or for registering or refraining from registering as a voter,\nor who shall make any promise to influence the giving or withholding of\nany such vote or registration, or who shall make or become directly or\nindirectly interested in any bet or wager depending upon the result of\nan election, shall vote at such election.\n  2. No person who has been convicted of a felony and sentenced to a\nperiod of imprisonment for such felony pursuant to the laws of this\nstate, shall have the right to register for or vote at any election\nwhile he or she is incarcerated for such felony.\n  3. No person who has been convicted in a federal court, of a felony,\nor a crime or offense which would constitute a felony under the laws of\nthis state, and sentenced to a period of imprisonment for such felony,\nshall have the right to register for or vote at any election while he or\nshe is incarcerated for such felony.\n  4. No person who has been convicted in another state for a crime or\noffense which would constitute a felony under the laws of this state and\nsentenced to a period of imprisonment for such felony, shall have the\nright to register for or vote at any election in this state while he or\nshe is incarcerated for such felony.\n  5. The provisions of subdivisions two, three and four of this section\nshall not apply if the person so convicted is not sentenced to either\ndeath or imprisonment, or if the execution of a sentence of imprisonment\nis suspended.\n  6. No person who has been adjudged incompetent by order of a court of\ncompetent judicial authority shall have the right to register for or\nvote at any election in this state unless thereafter he shall have been\nadjudged competent pursuant to law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>