<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-204"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_204">
        <num>5-204</num>
        <heading>Local registration; general provisions for the conduct of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-204. Local registration; general provisions for the conduct of.\n1. At the opening of each place of registration on each day of local\nregistration the board of inspectors shall:\n  a. See that the American flag is displayed.\n  b. Cause the election district map or maps, or certified description\nthereof, to be posted conspicuously in the registration place.\n  c. Check to see that all necessary supplies are available in order to\nproperly conduct registration.\n  d. Affix or attach to their clothing the proper identification,\nbuttons, badges or emblems issued by the board of elections pursuant to\nthe provisions of this chapter. They shall wear no other buttons, badges\nor emblems which are similar in design.\n  3. a. The inspectors of election in receiving registrations shall, by\nprinting in ink, fill out the registration poll record and the central\nfile registration record.\n  b. If the applicant's name does not appear on the list of registered\nvoters and if the applicant is not challenged, and he is found by the\ninspectors of election to be otherwise qualified, they shall complete\nhis registration as provided herein.\n  c. If the person's name appears on the list of registered voters and\nhe is residing at the same address as set forth therein, his\nregistration shall be refused as unnecessary.\n  d. If the applicant's name appears on the list of cancelled\nregistrations, the inspectors of election shall ascertain from such list\nthe reason for cancellation, and if satisfied that the reason for\ncancellation no longer exists shall register the applicant.\n  e. If the inspectors of election shall refuse to receive a\nregistration for any reason, they need not complete the registration\nrecords. They, however, shall enter the applicant's name and address on\nthe applicant's records, shall mark the word "Refused", and insert the\nreason for such refusal in the remarks section on each of such\nregistration records. In any such case, they shall inform the applicant\nof such reason, and advise the applicant of his right to appeal to the\nboard of elections for review of its decision.\n  f. If an applicant is challenged after the inspectors of election have\ncommenced to take his registration and if such applicant refuses to take\nthe challenge oath as prescribed by this article, or to answer a\nquestion appearing on the challenge affidavit, they shall not complete\nhis registration and shall insert in the remarks section of his\nregistration records the words "Challenge Oath Refused" or "Challenge\nQuestion Not Answered".\n  g. After completing the registration forms the inspectors of election\nshall require the applicant to sign the two registration records in the\nspaces provided for his signature at the time of registration.\n  h. After securing the voter's signatures, the two inspectors by whom\nthe registration is taken shall sign the records in the spaces provided.\n  k. If an applicant has removed from his residence but is still\neligible to vote from that address for a reason enumerated in this\nchapter, the inspectors shall require him to execute a statement of\ntemporary absence.\n  l. If an applicant for registration presents a court order directing\nthat he be registered, the board shall register him, enter the words\n"Court Order" in the remarks space on the face of each of his\nregistration records, write his new registration serial number on the\ntop of the first page of such order and return such order to the board\nof election with the executed certificates and forms.\n  4. The inspectors shall distribute to the voters applying for\nregistration copies of the ballot proposals to be submitted to the\nvoters at the ensuing election.\n  5. An inspector shall not remove or permit to be removed any\nregistration record or blank from the locked ledger in which it is filed\nor to insert or permit to be inserted any such record or blank in such\nledger. If a registration record blank is mutilated or voided or for any\nreason cannot be used, the board shall mark "Void" across the face of\nsuch blank and the blank of the same number in the other ledger of the\nsame set.\n  6. The map or maps furnished in cities shall be posted in the polling\nplace on the days of local registration.\n  7. There shall be no smoking in any place of registration in a church\nor school.\n  8. The inspectors shall act as a board and a majority of them shall\ndecide questions.\n  9. While the polls are open no person shall do any electioneering\nwithin the polling place, or within a one hundred foot radial measured\nfrom the entrances, designated by the inspectors of election, to a\nbuilding where the registration is being conducted. No political banner,\nposter or placard shall be allowed in or upon the place of registration\nduring any day of registration.  Where an oath is required or permitted\nby this article at any meeting for registration, any inspector may\nadminister it. The inspectors, and each of them, shall preserve good\norder within and around the place of registration and keep access\nthereto unobstructed. The board or any member thereof by order in\nwriting may direct the arrest of any person refusing to obey the lawful\ncommands of the inspectors, or guilty of disorderly conduct disturbing\ntheir proceedings, or violating, or attempting to violate, any of the\nprovisions of this chapter. Any police officer or peace officer, who is\nacting pursuant to his special duties, or any person designated by the\nboard shall execute the order.\n  10. Persons entitled to register who are on line, or in the polling\nplace, at or before the time fixed by law for closing of registration,\nshall be allowed to register.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>