<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-211"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_211">
        <num>5-211</num>
        <heading>Agency assisted registration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>seek to influence an applicant's political preference or party\ndesignation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>display any political preference or party allegiance;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make any statement to an applicant or take any action the purpose\nor effect of which is to discourage the applicant from registering to\nvote; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make any statement to an applicant or take any action the purpose\nor effect of which is to lead the applicant to believe that a decision\nto register or not to register has any bearing on the availability of\nservices or benefits.\n  6. The state board of elections shall coordinate and monitor the\ndistribution of voter registration forms by those state agencies,\ndepartments, divisions and offices selected to participate in the\nprogram to maximize the efficient and non partisan distribution of voter\nregistration information and forms. The board shall also adopt such\nrules and regulations as may be necessary to require county boards and\nparticipating agencies to provide the state board with such information\nand data as the board deems necessary to assess compliance with this\nsection and to compile such statistics as may be required by the federal\nelections commission.\n  7. Each participating agency, department, division and office that\nmakes available voter registration forms shall prominently display\npromotional materials designed and approved by the state board of\nelections, informing the public of the existence of voter registration\nservices.\n  8. Each participating agency, department, division or office that\nmakes available voter registration forms pursuant to this section shall\noffer with each application for the services or assistance of such\nagency, department, division or office and with each recertification,\nrenewal or change of address form relating to such service or\nassistance, a registration form together with instructions relating to\neligibility to register and for completing the form except that forms\nused by the department of social services for the initial application\nfor services, renewal or recertification for services and change of\naddress relating to such services shall physically incorporate a voter\nregistration application in a fashion that permits the voter\nregistration portion of the agency form to be detached theref...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the question, "If you are not registered to vote where you live\nnow, would you like to apply to register here today?"\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The statement, "applying to register or declining to register to\nvote will not affect the amount of assistance that you will be provided\nby this agency."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>boxes for the applicant to check to indicate whether the applicant\nwould like to register or decline to register to vote.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the statement in prominent type, "IF YOU DO NOT CHECK EITHER BOX,\nYOU WILL BE CONSIDERED TO HAVE DECIDED NOT TO REGISTER TO VOTE AT THIS\nTIME."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the statement, "If you would like help in filling out the voter\nregistration application form, we will help you. The decision whether to\nseek or accept help is yours. You may fill out the application form in\nprivate."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the statement, "If you believe that someone has interfered with\nyour right to register or decline to register to vote, your right to\nprivacy in deciding whether to register or in applying to register to\nvote, or your right to choose your own political party or other\npolitical preference, you may file a complaint with the state board of\nelections (address and toll free telephone number)."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a toll free number at the state board of elections that can be\ncalled for answers to registration questions.\n  9. Disclosure of voter registration information, including a\ndeclination to register, by a participating agency, its agents or\nemployees, for other than voter registration purposes, shall be deemed\nan unwarranted invasion of personal privacy pursuant to the provisions\nof subdivision two of section eighty-nine of the public officers law and\nshall constitute a violation of this chapter.\n  10. The form containing the declination to register to vote shall be\nretained by the recipient agency for the same period of time as such\nagency retains the accompanying application for services or for such\nshorter period of time as may be approved by the state board of\nelections.\n  11. The participating agency shall transmit the completed applications\nfor registration and change of address forms to the appropriate board of\nelections not later than ten days after receipt except that all such\ncompleted applications and forms received by the agency after the\ntwentieth day prior to an election and by the twelfth day before such\nelection shall be transmitted in such manner and at such time as to\nassure their receipt by such board of elections as soon as practicable\nand not later than the tenth day before such election.\n  12. Completed application forms, when received by a participating\nagency not later than the twelfth day before the next ensuing primary,\ngeneral or special election and transmitted by such agency to the\nappropriate board of elections so that they are received by such board\nnot later than the tenth day before such election shall entitle the\napplicant to vote in such election provided the board determines that\nthe applicant is otherwise qualified.\n  13. The state board of elections shall provide application forms for\nuse pursuant to this section except that any agency which uses a form\nother than such registration form shall be respon...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before January first, two thousand twenty, all\ninstitutions of the state university of New York and the city university\nof New York shall create and make available to all students a webpage\nfor voter education on each such institution's website, containing a\nlink to an application for voter registration, a link to an application\nfor an early mail ballot, contact information for the county board of\nelections, and the name and contact information for the administrator\nresponsible for voter registration assistance on each campus.\n  (ii) Each such institution shall, at the beginning of the school year,\nand again in January of a year in which the president of the United\nStates is to be elected, provide an application for voter registration\nand an application for an early mail ballot to each student in each such\ninstitution. Each institution shall be considered in compliance with the\nrequirements of this subparagraph for each student to whom the\ninstitution electronically transmits a message containing the link to\nthe webpage for voter education, the link to an application for voter\nregistration and the link to an application for an early mail ballot, if\nsuch information is in an electronic message devoted exclusively to\nvoter registration.\n  (iii) Each such institution shall provide the same degree of\nassistance as required of participating agencies.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state university of New York and the city university of New\nYork, on behalf of each institution within its system, shall on or\nbefore June first, two thousand twenty, and each subsequent year, submit\na report disaggregated according to each institution to the state board\nof elections that includes:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the efforts of the institution to register voters in the preceding\ncalendar year;\n  (ii) a date-stamped screen shot of the webpage for voter education\nthat contains the required information under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision;\n  (iii) the number of students who were registered for course work in\nthe preceding twelve months at such institution and the number of clicks\non the links to online voter registration and early mail ballot\napplications; and\n  (iv) any other efforts or recommendations the institution plans to\nimplement to improve access to voter registration and early mail ballot\nvoting for students at the institution.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state board of elections shall make the reports provided\npursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision publicly available on its\nwebsite.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>