<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-215"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-215"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-215"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-215/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-215/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-215/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-215/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_215">
        <num>5-215</num>
        <heading>Veterans' absentee registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-215. Veterans' absentee registration. 1. The board of elections in\nthe county in which a veterans' hospital is located shall appoint a\nboard of registration which shall attend each veterans' hospital between\nthe hours of nine o'clock in the morning and five o'clock in the evening\non the seventh Thursday before each general election and, in the event\nthat it be necessary for the completion of its duties, on the seventh\nFriday before such election except that if any of the religious holidays\nof Yom Kippur, Rosh Hashanah, Simchas Torah, Shmini Atzereth or Succoth\nshall fall on such days, such registration shall be held on the next\nregular business day which does not fall on any of such religious\nholidays, and shall receive from residents or patients therein, or their\nspouses, parents and children, the applications of such of them as\ndesire and are qualified to be registered by absentee registration.\n  2. After the applicant completes and signs the application, or has it\nsigned for him, it shall be deposited by or for him in an envelope and\nsealed. Before receiving the next application the board shall address\nthe envelope to the board of elections in the county where the applicant\nresides and note upon a form provided for such purpose the date of the\napplication, the name and residence address of the applicant and the\nname of the hospital at which the application was received.\n  3. At the end of each day each member of such board shall sign the\nform containing the list of applicants with their names and addresses\nand they shall, no later than the next day, return the list and the\nsealed envelopes to the board of elections in the county where such\nhospital is located.\n  4. The board of elections upon receipt of such applications shall\nimmediately mail those applications that are addressed to another board\nof elections and shall process those applications addressed to it.\n  5. If a veterans health administration hospital in which any veteran\nentitled to vote in this state is a resident or patient, is located\noutside the State of New York, an application for an early mail or\nabsentee ballot signed by such veteran or his or her spouse, parent or\nchild accompanying or being with him or her, if a qualified voter and a\nresident of the same election district, shall constitute permanent\npersonal registration.\n  6. All applications made and received pursuant to this section shall\nbe processed in the manner provided herein for personal registration by\nmail.\n  7. The cost incurred by the county in which such veterans' hospital is\nlocated, for the registration of voters as herein provided, may be\napportioned to the counties in which such voters reside in proportion to\nthe number of applicants for such registration residing in such\ncounties.\n  8. The board of elections shall not be required to send a board of\ncentral registration to each veterans' hospital in such county, pursuant\nto the provisions of this section, if, in lieu thereof, it shall provide\nsuch hospital with mail registration application forms in sufficient\nquantity so that each resident or patient of such hospital who wishes to\nregister will be able to do so. A complete application received from a\nresident or patient whose residence is in a county other than the county\nin which the hospital is located shall be immediately transmitted to the\nappropriate board of elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>