<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-216"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-216"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-216"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_216">
        <num>5-216</num>
        <heading>Registration; assistance to applicant</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-216. Registration; assistance to applicant. 1. If any person\nentitled to be registered shall declare to the board of inspectors that\nhe is unable to read or write by reason of illiteracy or disability, the\nboard shall provide assistance in registering. Such person shall, if\nunable to write, be excused from signing and the board shall enter the\nwords "unable to sign" in each space reserved for his signature. The\nboard shall also enter in the remarks space on the face of the\nregistration records the reason for his inability to write his name.\n  2. If the applicant be a person who does not speak the English\nlanguage, he may be assisted by a relative who can interpret for him. If\nthe applicant registers with this assistance the board shall put in the\nremarks space of the registration forms the name and address, and the\nrelationship, of the person so doing the interpreting and the\ninterpreter shall sign his name in the remarks space.\n  3. If the registrant needs assistance with registration, he may also\nhave the same assistance in order to mark the enrollment blank.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>