<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-213"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-213"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-213"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_213">
        <num>5-213</num>
        <heading>Inactive status</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-213. Inactive status. 1. When a voter is sent a confirmation\nnotice pursuant to the provisions of this article, the voter's name\nshall be placed in inactive status.\n  2. The registration poll records of all such voters shall be removed\nfrom the poll ledgers and maintained at the offices of the board of\nelections in a file arranged alphabetically by election district. If\nsuch board uses computer generated registration lists, the names of such\nvoters shall not be placed on such lists at subsequent elections other\nthan lists prepared pursuant to the provisions of section 5-612 of this\narticle but shall be kept as a computer record at the offices of such\nboard.\n  3. The board of elections shall restore the registration of any such\nvoter to active status if such voter notifies the board of elections\nthat they reside at the address from which they are registered, or the\nboard finds that such voter has validly signed a designating or\nnominating petition which states that they reside at such address, or if\nsuch voter casts a ballot in an affidavit envelope which states that\nthey reside at such address, or if the board receives notice that such\nvoter has voted in an election conducted with registration lists\nprepared pursuant to the provisions of section 5-612 of this article. If\nany such notification or information is received ten days or more before\na primary, special or general election, the voter's name must be\nrestored to active status for such election.\n  4. As soon as practicable, after it restores a voter's registration to\nactive status, the board of elections shall send the voter, by first\nclass forwardable mail, a notice advising him of the restoration in a\nform which is similar to the notice sent to new registrants pursuant to\nthe provisions of section 5-210 of this title and which has been\napproved by the state board of elections.\n  5. If the board of elections receives notice, which complies with the\nrequirements of this article, that a voter in inactive status is\nresiding at another address within the jurisdiction of such board, it\nshall transfer the registration and enrollment of such voter to such\nother address pursuant to the provisions of section 5-208 of this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>