<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-218"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-218"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-218"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_218">
        <num>5-218</num>
        <heading>Registration; challenges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-218. Registration; challenges. 1. Any person who applies for\nregistration may be challenged by any qualified voter, watcher, or\ninspector of election if such person has reason to suspect that the\napplicant is not qualified to be registered to vote.\n  2. When an applicant is challenged the person making the challenge\nmust first state the reason for the challenge and complete the\nchallenger's part of the challenge form. The board shall then administer\nto such applicant the following oath: "You do solemnly swear (or affirm)\nthat you will give true answers to the questions which may be put to you\nto establish your qualifications to register and vote". A member of such\nboard shall then read to the challenged person the questions printed\nupon the form of the challenge affidavit which relate to the reason\ngiven for the challenge, and such other questions on the form as in its\ndiscretion it may deem appropriate, and shall enter in ink, opposite\neach question, the answer thereto given by such applicant. After\nanswering, the applicant shall sign his name to such challenge\naffidavit. The inspector or member of such board who writes the answers\nshall enter in the place provided on the challenge affidavit,\ninformation identifying the person challenged and the name and address\nof the person challenging, and shall sign the certificate at the end\nthereof. The other inspectors present shall also sign such certificate\nat the end thereof.\n  3. The applicant shall be registered by the board if a majority of\nsuch board shall be satisfied with the answers of the registrant. If not\nsatisfied, they shall notify him of the qualifications which they\nbelieve he lacks as a voter, and shall furnish him a duplicate of the\nchallenge affidavit as completed. They shall also advise him of his\nright to apply to the board of elections for registration.\n  4. When a person who has been challenged is registered, the board\nshall enter in the remarks column the word "Challenged".\n  5. The state board of elections shall prescribe forms for challenge\naffidavits for use pursuant hereto, which forms shall elicit such\ninformation from the applicant as it deems appropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>