<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-224"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-224"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-224"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_224">
        <num>5-224</num>
        <heading>Registration of voters unlawfully denied the right to register</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-224. Registration of voters unlawfully denied the right to\nregister. 1. If any voter applies personally for registration and is\nunlawfully denied the right to register, the county board of elections\nmay, upon the application of the voter in person or by mail to such\nboard within two weeks after the last day of registration, or within\nfive days after the date of the voter's receipt of notice of the\nrejection of his application, upon proper proof, and upon such notice to\nthe chairman of the county committees of the several parties as the\nboard shall prescribe, direct that he be registered in the election\ndistrict in which he is a qualified voter. The directions of the county\nboard of elections shall be carried out by the board itself, by its\nclerks, or by the proper inspectors of elections, as the board may\nprescribe. The county board of elections shall make a final\ndetermination of such application not later than one week after the\napplication is made by the voter.\n  2. If the board of elections has reason to believe that any applicant\nhas been wrongfully denied the right to register, it shall notify him by\nmail and such person, upon application in person or by mail to the board\nof elections, within two weeks of the date of such notice, may be\nregistered by the board of elections.\n  3. The board of elections shall make a final determination on such\napplication not later than one week after it is made.\n  4. If any applicant is registered pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection, such registration shall be deemed effective as of the date of\nthe wrongful denial of the right to register.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>