<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-230"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-230"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-230"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-230/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-230/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-230/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-230/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_230">
        <num>5-230</num>
        <heading>Local registration; disposition of records and supplies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-230. Local registration; disposition of records and supplies. 1.\nAt the end of each day of registration, the chairman of each board of\ninspectors shall deliver the ledgers locked in the carrying case, if\nany, the flag and all other supplies to the police at the place of\nregistration, or, if directed, to the officer charged by this chapter\nwith the duty of delivering such articles to the board. The police or\nsuch other officer shall return all such articles on the next day of\nregistration to the chairman of such board at the place of registration\nimmediately prior to the opening hour for registration.\n  2. If allowed by the board of elections, at the end of each day of\nregistration, the chairman may, after locking and sealing the same,\nleave the registration poll records in the custody of a member of the\nboard of one political party and the corresponding central file\nregistration records with a member of the board of the opposite\npolitical party and himself retain custody of all other articles, or\nsecurely store such other articles in the place of registration if the\nsame be a public building.\n  3. If allowed by the board of elections, at the end of each day of\nregistration, the registration poll records and all other articles may\nbe securely stored in the place of registration if the same be a public\nbuilding.\n  4. At the close of the last day on which any board of inspectors is\nauthorized to take registrations such board shall seal the ledgers and\nlock them in the carrying case; enclose all keys in a sealed package and\nenclose all executed forms in a sealed package. The chairman of such\nboard shall deliver the sealed material, unused forms and all equipment\nand material furnished by the board of elections to a person designated\nby the board of elections to take custody of these items. The person\ndesignated shall deliver all such articles to the board of elections\nwithin twenty-four hours after the polls close.\n  5. The members of each board taking registrations shall sign all seals\nand shall affix their signatures to each in such a manner that the\narticle sealed cannot be opened without breaking their signatures.\n  6. Any person receiving such supplies from the board of inspectors\nshall give to the person delivering such supplies a receipt therefor,\nwhich, if a ledger carrying case is included, shall certify that such\ncase was locked at the time he received it.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>