<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-09-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-304"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_304">
        <num>5-304</num>
        <heading>Enrollment; change of enrollment or new enrollment by previously registered voters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-304. Enrollment; change of enrollment or new enrollment by\npreviously registered voters. 1. A registered voter may change his\nenrollment in the manner prescribed by this section.\n  2. The term "change of enrollment" shall apply to applications by a\nregistered voter already enrolled in one party to enroll in a different\nparty, or to delete his enrollment in any party, or an application by a\nregistered voter not enrolled in any party to enroll in a particular\nparty.\n  3. A change of enrollment received by the board of elections will take\neffect immediately, provided however, any change of enrollment received\nby the board of elections after February fourteenth and before or on\nseven days after the June primary shall take effect on the seventh day\nafter the June primary.\n  4. Registered voters may apply for change of enrollment personally by\nmail to or by appearing before a county board of elections or by\nappearing before a board of inspectors. If the applicant has appeared in\nperson and if the board finds that he or she is properly registered, it\nshall provide the applicant with an application form for voter\nregistration by mail which shall be treated as an application for change\nof enrollment filed pursuant to this section. If the voter has applied\npersonally by mail, the county board of elections shall mail him or her\nan application form for voter registration by mail as provided by this\nchapter. If a registered voter submits an application form for\nregistration or enrollment as provided by this chapter, from the\nresidence address from which he or she is then registered, and such form\nreflects a change of enrollment, the county board of elections shall\ntreat such form as an application for change of enrollment filed\npursuant to this section. If such application form also sets forth a new\naddress within the same city or county, the board of elections shall\nalso treat such form as an application for transfer of registration\npursuant to section 5-208 of this article. If a voter has cast a ballot\nin an affidavit ballot envelope on which such voter claims a party\nenrollment different from the enrollment in the records of the board of\nelections, such affidavit shall be treated as an application for change\nof enrollment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>