<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-402"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-402"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-402"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_402">
        <num>5-402</num>
        <heading>Cancellation of registration; generally, notice to voter</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_402__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section\n5-400 of this title or to cancel the registration of a voter who has\ndied. Together with such notice of cancellation, the board shall mail to\nsuch voter a postage paid return card in a form approved by the state\nboard of elections. Such card shall provide a place for the voter to set\nforth the reasons for his continued eligibility to vote in such county\nor city and to indicate his current address in the county or city and a\nstatement that failure to return the card will result in cancellation of\nregistration. The card shall also inform the voter of how to reregister\nif the voter has moved out of the county or city. If such registered\nvoter shall fail to appear or answer in writing within such time or if,\nafter he so appears or writes, the board is not satisfied that he is\nqualified to remain registered, the board shall cancel his registration.\n  3. The board of elections shall notify immediately every person whose\nregistration is cancelled after such person has responded, in person or\nby mail, to a notice sent pursuant to subdivision two of this section,\nof the action taken and the reason therefor, by written notice to the\naddress from which he was last registered. Such notice shall advise such\npersons either of their right to reregister or their right to apply to a\ncourt of law for reinstatement, whichever is appropriate.\n  4. Each board of elections shall, at least once a month, transmit to\nthe appropriate board of elections, a list of the names, old addresses\nand new addresses of every voter whose registration was cancelled\npursuant to the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_402__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsection 5-400 of this title because the voter moved to an address in the\njurisdiction of the board to which the list is sent, unless the board of\nelections sending the list has received notice that the voter has\nalready registered to vote from the new address.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>