<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-504"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-504"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-504"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-504/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-504/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-504/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-504/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_504">
        <num>5-504</num>
        <heading>Optional discontinuation of central file registration records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-504. Optional discontinuation of central file registration\nrecords.  1. Notwithstanding the provisions of this article to the\ncontrary, a board of elections may apply to the state board of elections\nfor permission to discontinue preparation, use and maintenance of\ncentral file registration records.\n  2. The state board of elections shall adopt regulations establishing\nthe requirements which must be met by a board of election seeking such\npermission.\n  3. Such requirements shall include, but not be limited to the\nfollowing:\n  a. The board of elections maintains a complete, current computer\nrecord of all registered voters.\n  b. At least one copy of such record is kept in a building other than\nthe one in which the offices of the board of elections are located.\n  c. The board of elections maintains, as a public record, at the\nappropriate office of the board, a complete and current alphabetized\nlist of all registered voters, including voters in inactive status,\nwhich contains next to each voter's name at least the following\ninformation: address, town or city, assembly district where appropriate,\nelection district, registration serial number, party enrollment, date of\nregistration, gender, date of birth and, if the voter is in inactive\nstatus, an indication of that fact.\n  d. A board of elections which has discontinued use of registration\npoll ledgers shall not be required to maintain such an alphabetized list\nof all registered voters if it has available for public use, a\nsufficient number of computer terminals from which such information can\nbe obtained. Such terminals must have the capacity to display a series\nof names arranged in such alphabetical order without an inquiry for each\nsuch name having to be entered into the computer separately.\n  4. After such inquiry as it deems appropriate, the state board of\nelections shall approve the applications of those boards of elections\nwhose systems meet the requirements established by this section and the\nregulations of the state board. Such boards may then discontinue\npreparation, use and maintenance of central file registration records.\n  5. If the state board of elections amends its regulations, a board of\nelections whose system was previously approved by the state board shall\nhave a reasonable time to conform to the new regulation.\n  6. If the state board of elections determines on its own initiative,\nor upon investigation of a complaint, that the system being used by a\nboard of elections is not in compliance with the requirements of this\nsection and the regulations of the state board, it shall order such\nboard of elections to comply forthwith.\n  7. If such a board of elections does not comply with the provisions of\nsubdivision six of this section, the state board shall issue an order\nwithdrawing permission to discontinue use of central file registration\nrecords and such board of elections shall be required to reinstitute use\nof such records on the first day of December following issuance of such\nan order.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>