<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-502"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-502"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-502"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_502">
        <num>5-502</num>
        <heading>Registration records; supplies and equipment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-502. Registration records; supplies and equipment.  1. The board\nof elections shall furnish in time for use by the boards of inspectors\nof election, the registration records, an American flag, a map or\ncertified description of the election district, and the adjoining\nelection districts, challenge affidavits, early mail ballot\napplications, absentee voting applications, a list of voters who are\ncurrently registered in the election district, a list of those voters\nwho have been cancelled in the last year with the reason for such\ncancellations, forms for statements of temporary absence, a sufficient\nnumber of copies of the ballot proposals to be submitted to the voters\nat the ensuing election, at least one copy of the instruction booklet\nfor inspectors and all other forms and supplies required for the\nadministration of the registration system as provided by this article.\n  2. The board of elections shall also maintain in its custody and\ncontrol:\n  a. At the headquarters of the board, filing cabinets and ledgers\nsufficient in number and form to accommodate the records required by\nthis article to be kept at such headquarters or office.\n  b. Carrying cases sufficient to carry to and from the registration\nplaces the ledgers, if any, and forms required by this chapter to be\navailable for use at such places.\n  3. Each ledger and cabinet shall be equipped with a lock of such a\nnature that when the ledger or cabinet is locked it shall not be\npossible to remove any record or form which has been filed therein, or\nto file in it any other record or form. Each carrying case shall be\nequipped with a lock. Each carrying case lock and its key shall bear an\nidentical distinctive identifying number.\n  4. Subject to the requirements of this article, the state board of\nelections shall prescribe the number of and the form, content, color and\nspecifications of such registration records, lists, and check cards. It\nmay require such other forms, supplies and equipment as it deems\nnecessary to be furnished by the boards of elections and any other\nofficer charged with equipping the places for taking registrations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>