<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-604"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_604">
        <num>5-604</num>
        <heading>Enrollment lists; publication of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-604. Enrollment lists; publication of. 1. The board of elections\nshall also cause to be published for each election district a complete\nlist of the registered voters of each election district. Such list\nshall, in addition to the information required for registration lists,\ninclude the party enrollment of each voter. At least as many copies of\nsuch list shall be prepared as the required minimum number of\nregistration lists.\n  Lists for all the election districts in a ward or assembly district\nmay be bound together in one volume. The board of elections shall also\ncause to be published a complete list of names and residence addresses\nof the registered voters, including the party enrollment of each voter,\nfor each town and city over which the board has jurisdiction. The names\nfor each town and city may be arranged according to street and number or\nalphabetically. Such lists shall be published before the twenty-first\nday of February. The board shall keep at least five copies for public\ninspection at each main office or branch office of the board. Surplus\ncopies of the lists shall be sold at a charge not exceeding the cost of\npublication.\n  2. Immediately after the publication of such lists the board shall\nsend at least one true copy, duly certified, of each such list to the\nstate board of elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>