<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-600"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-600"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-600"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-600/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-600/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-600/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-600/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_600">
        <num>5-600</num>
        <heading>Registration records; filing of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-600. Registration records; filing of. 1. The board of elections\nshall keep all registration records, when not in use at the polls for an\nelection, at its main office, or a branch office designated by it. Such\nrecords shall be kept in locked ledgers or locked filing cabinets and\nshall not be removed from the office or branch office of the board of\nelections, except that the registration poll records of all voters\nentitled to vote at an election shall be delivered as provided in this\nchapter to the appropriate election district polling places for use at\nsuch election.\n  2. The central file registration records shall be filed for the entire\ncounty using a system permitting location by name. Cancelled\nregistration records shall be filed separately and shall be arranged in\nthe same manner as current registration records.\n  3. The registration poll records shall be classified by election\ndistricts, the records for each election district being filed according\nto street, by number, and alphabetically within any address or in the\ndiscretion of the board of elections they may be filed alphabetically by\nname of voter.\n  4. Any registration record not completed because of the refusal of a\nboard of inspectors to register an applicant shall be filed by the board\nof elections with the cancelled registration records as if the person\naffected had registered and his registration had been cancelled.\n  5. After receipt thereof from a board of inspectors at the close of a\nperiod of local registration, the board of elections, before removing\nany records or blank forms from any ledger containing registration\nrecords of voters registered during such period, shall compare such\nrecords and blanks with the certificate filed by such board of\ninspectors. It shall investigate any discrepancy between such returned\nmaterial and the information contained on such certificate and if such\ndiscrepancy is not satisfactorily resolved, it shall, at the request of\nany commissioner, make a written report thereof in triplicate and send\none copy of such report to the district attorney and one to the state\nboard of elections and keep the third copy on file at its office as a\npublic record. The board of elections shall then remove the records and\nblanks from the ledgers and shall file them as provided herein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>