<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-602"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-602"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-602"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_602">
        <num>5-602</num>
        <heading>Lists of registered voters; publication of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-602. Lists of registered voters; publication of. 1. After the last\nday of local registration and before the fifth day before the next\nensuing general election in each year, the board of elections shall\ncause to be published a complete list of names and residence addresses\nof the registered voters for each election district over which the board\nhas jurisdiction. The names for each election district may be arranged\naccording to street and number or alphabetically. Each list shall be\nprepared in such a manner as to indicate the registrants whose names did\nnot appear on the list of registered voters last published pursuant to\nthe provisions of this section and the registrants who are in inactive\nstatus. The board of elections, in its discretion, may publish the names\nof the registrants in inactive status as a separate list. In lieu of\npublishing such a registration list, such board of elections may publish\na complete list of the names and residence addresses of all registered\nvoters whose names do not appear in the annual enrollment lists\npublished in such year by such board, in the same form as such\nenrollment lists, and a list of the registered voters whose names appear\nin such annual enrollment lists but who have been placed in inactive\nstatus or whose registrations have been cancelled since the publication\nof such annual enrollment lists. Lists for all election districts in a\nward or assembly district may be bound together in one volume.\n  2. The board of elections shall cause a list to be published for each\nelection district over which it has jurisdiction.\n  3. The board of elections shall prepare such number of copies of such\nlists as it determines will be sufficient to meet the demand for such\nlists and shall send at least one copy of each such list to the state\nboard of elections, and shall keep at least five copies for public\ninspection at each main office or branch of the board. Other copies\nshall be sold at a charge not exceeding the cost of publication.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>