<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-608"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-608"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-608"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_608">
        <num>5-608</num>
        <heading>Replacement of registration and enrollment records; damaged, unusable or lost</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-608. Replacement of registration and enrollment records; damaged,\nunusable or lost. 1. If the registration or enrollment records of any\nvoter shall be lost, mutilated, defaced or destroyed, the board of\nelections shall, except as provided in subdivision two hereof, require\nhim to reregister or reenroll.  Such reregistration or reenrollment\nshall be deemed to have taken effect as of the date of the original\nregistration or enrollment.\n  2. If one or both of the registration records of the voter are still\nin the possession of the board of elections and it is possible therefrom\nto duplicate the lost or damaged record, the board of elections shall\nprepare a new record containing all the information required, using the\noriginal serial number, and shall paste photostatic copies of the\nvoter's signature in each space on the new record where his signature\nwas placed on the original record.\n  3. When the spaces for signature or for other entries, on a\nregistration poll record are filled so as to render a record no longer\nusable, the board of elections shall prepare a second poll record. All\npertinent information shall be copied from the original poll record on\nto the second poll record. The registration signature on the original\npoll record shall be photostated and pasted on the back in the space for\nthe registration signature on the second poll record.  Within the space\nreserved for remarks shall be imprinted "Record Continued--2nd Poll\nRecord", or "3rd Poll Record", as appropriate.\n  4. The active but unusable poll record shall be kept in a special file\nfor active continued registrations until such time as the next poll\nrecord may be cancelled, at which time the poll records are stamped\n"cancelled" and fastened together when placed in the cancellation file.\n  5. All mutilated or defaced registration records which are replaced by\nnew records under the provisions of this section shall be stamped across\nthe face with the words "Record Replaced", without obliterating any of\nthe entries thereon and shall be kept on file by the board of elections.\n  6. If the records of an entire election district or a large segment\nthereof are lost, mutilated, defaced or destroyed, or are determined by\nthe board of elections to be so inaccurate or incomplete as to be\nunusable, such board may, upon due notice, require re-registration of\nall qualified voters resident within such district.  In such event, the\nboard shall fix and determine additional days of local registration for\nsuch re-registration.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>