<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-614"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-614"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-614"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-614/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-614/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-614/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-614/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_614">
        <num>5-614</num>
        <heading>Statewide voter registration list</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_614__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the list of persons who have\ndied maintained by the New York city department of health and the state\ndepartment of health, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_614__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the list of persons subject to forfeiture\nof the right to vote pursuant to section 5-106 of this article\nmaintained by the office of court administration or by a court having\nmade such determination.\n  6. Each local board of elections shall, within twenty-five days after\nreceiving such list of decedents or list of persons subject to\nforfeiture of the right to vote pursuant to section 5-106 of this\narticle, use such lists to identify and remove decedents and persons\nsubject to forfeiture of the right to vote pursuant to section 5-106 of\nthis article from the list of eligible voters.\n  7. The local board of elections shall electronically file with the\nstate board of elections a cancellation and removal report indicating\nall cancellations and removal actions taken by the local board of\nelections from the list of eligible voters. Such report shall be filed\nin a format and at such intervals as directed by the state board of\nelections.\n  8. If the information received by the board of elections through the\nstatewide voter registration list indicates that a voter is currently\nregistered to vote more than once, the local board of elections\ncontaining the registration record of the earlier dated registration\nrecord shall send such voter the confirmation notice prescribed by\nsection 5-712 of this article and place such voter in inactive status\npursuant to section 5-213 of this article.\n  9. The state board of elections shall, in accordance with subdivision\nfour of section 3-100 of this chapter, promulgate rules and regulations\nto ensure compliance with the adding, changing, canceling or removing of\nvoters from the single, official, statewide voter registration list.\n  10. Any person may bring a challenge pursuant to this chapter against\nany board of elections to compel the removal of an ineligible voter from\nthe list of eligible voters or to compel the correction of a\nregistration record in the case of a voter wrongfully canceled or\nremoved from ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_614__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name of each registered voter appears in the statewide voter\nregistration list;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_614__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>only names of persons who are not registered or who are not\neligible to vote are removed from such list; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_614__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the prior registrations of duplicate names are removed from such\nlist.\n  13. The state board of elections shall provide adequate technological\nsecurity measures to prevent the unauthorized access to or disruption of\nthe statewide voter registration list established pursuant to this\nsection and any voter registration records electronically transmitted\nbetween local boards of elections and the state board of elections as\nprovided for in subdivision two of this section. A copy of such list\nshall be stored at least twenty-five miles away from the place where the\noriginal is housed.\n  14. The statewide voter registration list system shall ensure that\nvoter registration records in the state are accurate and are updated\nregularly, including a system of file maintenance that makes a\nreasonable effort to remove registrants who are ineligible to vote from\nthe official list of eligible voters, as provided for by this chapter.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>