<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-708"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-708"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-708"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-708/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-708/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-708/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-708/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_708">
        <num>5-708</num>
        <heading>Change of voter status; reports of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-708. Change of voter status; reports of. 1. It shall be the duty\nof the state health department and the department of health of the city\nof New York to deliver to the state board of elections, at least\nmonthly, records, in a format as mutually determined by both agencies,\nof the names of all persons of voting age for whom death certificates\nwere issued. Such records shall be arranged by county of residence and\nshall include the name, residence address and birth date of each such\nperson.\n  2. It shall be the duty of every court having jurisdiction over such\nmatters, or the office of court administration, to transmit to the\nappropriate board of elections or, in the discretion of the office of\ncourt administration, to the state board of elections, at least\nquarterly, the names, residence addresses and birthdates of all persons\nfor whom convictions or revocations of probation or conditional\ndischarge result in loss of voting privileges pursuant to the provisions\nof section 5-106 of this article. Such transmittals shall be in a format\nas mutually determined by such agencies and the state board of\nelections.\n  3. It shall be the duty of every court having jurisdiction over such\nmatters or the office of court administration to transmit to the\nappropriate board of elections or, in the discretion of the office of\ncourt administration, to the state board of elections, at least\nquarterly, of the name, residence address and birthdate of any person of\nvoting age who has been adjudicated as incompetent.\n  4. a. If a board of elections receives any notices pursuant to the\nprovisions of subdivisions two and three of this section which set forth\na residence address outside of the city or county of such board's\njurisdiction, it shall, at least once a month, transmit such notices to\nthe appropriate board of elections, or, if such address is outside the\nstate, to the state board of elections.\n  b. The state board shall arrange such notices and the names received\npursuant to the other provisions of this section by county of residence\nand transmit such notices and any notices of conviction for a felony\nreceived from a United States attorney to the appropriate board of\nelections.\n  c. If any such notices, or names received pursuant to the other\nprovisions of this section, set forth a residence address outside New\nYork state, the state board shall transmit such notices to the chief\nstate election official of such state at such times and in such manner\nas it deems appropriate.\n  5. a. At least once each year during the month of February, each board\nof elections shall obtain through the National Change of Address System,\nthe forwarding address for every voter registered with such board of\nelections for whom the United States Postal Service has such a\nforwarding address together with the name of each such voter whom the\nPostal Service records indicate has moved from the address at which he\nis registered without leaving a forwarding address.\n  b. The state board of elections shall obtain such information for\nthose boards of elections which request it do so. Such a request must be\nmade not later than April first. Each board which makes such a request\nshall supply the list of voters registered with such board in a format\nprescribed by the state board. Each such board shall reimburse the state\nboard for the fees it disburses to obtain such information if such fee\nexceeds two hundred fifty dollars.\n  c. If the information received through the National Change of Address\nSystem indicates that a voter has moved to an address outside such\ncounty or city, or has moved without leaving a forwarding address, the\nboard of elections shall, not later than June first, send such voter the\nconfirmation notice prescribed by section 5-712 of this title and place\nsuch voter in inactive status pursuant to section 5-213 of this article.\n  d. If the information received through the National Change of Address\nSystem indicates that a voter has moved to another address in such\ncounty or city, the board of elections shall transfer the registration\nof such voter to such new address pursuant to the provisions of section\n5-208 of this article and send such voter the notice prescribed by such\nsection 5-208.\n  6. It shall be the duty of the appropriate officers of a city, town or\nvillage to notify the appropriate board of elections of any action by\nsuch city, town or village which shall affect or change the name or\nstreet numbers of any street located within such city, town or village.\nUpon receipt of such information the board of elections shall make the\nnecessary changes in the addresses of the voters registered from\naddresses wherein such change of street name or street numbers was\neffected.\n  7. The real property assessment bureau of the department of finance of\nthe city of New York shall notify the board of elections in the city of\nNew York of each residence which, because of abandonment, demolition or\nvacancy, no longer contains a potential voter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>