<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-712"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-712"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-712"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-712/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-712/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-712/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-712/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_712">
        <num>5-712</num>
        <heading>Confirmation notices</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_712__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of elections shall also send a confirmation notice to\nevery registered voter for whom it receives a notice of change of\naddress to an address not in such city or county which is not signed by\nthe voter.  Such change of address notices shall include, but not be\nlimited to, notices of change of address received pursuant to\nsubdivision eleven of section 5-211 and subdivision six of section 5-212\nof this article, notice of change of address from the United States\nPostal Service through the National Change of Address System or from any\nother agency of the federal government or any agency of any state or\nlocal government and notice of a forwarding address on mail sent to a\nvoter by the board of elections and returned by the postal service. Such\nconfirmation notices shall be sent to such new address.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_712__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a notice sent pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_712__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision to\nthe voter at the new address is returned as undeliverable, the board of\nelections shall send another such notice to the address at which the\nvoter was originally registered.\n  3. Such notices shall be in a form prescribed by the state board of\nelections and shall include a postage-paid return card on which the\nvoter may confirm the fact that he still resides at the address to which\nthe notice was sent, or notify the board of any change of address. Such\nnotices shall request all voters who receive the notice to reply with\ntheir current addresses. Such notices shall request all voters who\nreceive the notice to reply with their current addresses and shall state\nthat voters who have not moved or who have moved within the county or\ncity and who do not respond may be required to vote by affidavit ballot\nand that if they do not vote in any election up to and including the\nsecond federal election after such notice, their registrations may be\ncancelled.  Such notices sent to addresses in New York state shall also\ninclude a mail registration form and information on how voters who have\nmoved to a different city or county may reregister.\n  4. No such confirmation notices shall be sent between June first in\nany year and the date of the general election in such year or in the\nninety days before a spring primary election except that such notices\nshall be sent forthwith to persons for whom an acknowledgment of\nacceptance of registration sent pursuant to subdivision nine of section\n5-210 of this article is returned to the board of elections as\nundeliverable and to every registered voter for whom the board of\nelections receives a notice of change of address described in paragraph\na of subdivision two of this section to an address not in such city or\ncounty.\n  5. All voters or applicants to whom a confirmation notice is sent,\npursuant to the provisions of this section, shall forthwith be placed in\ninactive status.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>