<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-710"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-710"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-710"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-710/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-710/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-710/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-710/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_710">
        <num>5-710</num>
        <heading>Check of registrants; personal</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-710. Check of registrants; personal. 1. A special door to door\ncheck of all the registered voters in any or all of the election\ndistricts including election districts previously checked shall be\nconducted in any year upon the written filed request of any one member\nof the board of elections. The board of elections shall employ a\nsufficient number of employees for the purpose of conducting such\nchecks.\n  2. The board shall supply such employees with copies of the most\nrecent registration list prepared for such election district under check\nas corrected by the board to reflect new registrations and cancellations\noccurring since the publication thereof. Such check shall be performed\nby two employees of the board representing the major political parties\nand they shall submit to the board of elections on or before a date\nfixed by the board, a report signed by each of them. Such signed report\nshall be accepted for all purposes as the equivalent of an affidavit,\nand if it contains any material false statement, shall subject the\npersons who sign the report to the same penalties as if each had been\nduly sworn and such provision shall be printed in bold type directly\nabove the signature lines on such report. At the end of the ensuing\nperiod of local registration in such years, the board of elections shall\nforthwith prepare a supplementary list of all voters registered for the\nfirst time during such period of local registration in the election\ndistricts so canvassed and shall direct the conduct of a similar check\nof all such voters.\n  3. Whenever it appears from the report that a registered voter is no\nlonger qualified the board shall proceed in the manner prescribed by\nsection 5-402 of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>