<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-802"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-802"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-802"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_802">
        <num>5-802</num>
        <heading>Online voter registration application</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_802__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>completes an electronic voter registration application promulgated\nby the state board of elections which shall include all of the voter\nregistration information required by section 5-210 of this article; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_802__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>affirms, subject to penalty of perjury, by means of electronic or\nmanual signature, that the information contained in the voter\nregistration application is true and that the applicant meets all of the\nqualifications to become a registered voter; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_802__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>consents to the use of an electronic copy of the individual's\nmanual signature that is in the custody of the department of motor\nvehicles, the state board of elections, or other agency designated by\nsections 5-211 or 5-212 of this article, as the individual's voter\nregistration exemplar signature, or provides such a signature by direct\nupload in a manner that complies with the New York state electronic\nsignature and records act and the rules and regulations promulgated by\nthe state board of elections.\n  2. The board of elections shall provide the personal online voter\nregistration application in any language required by the federal Voting\nRights Act of 1965 (52 U.S.C. Sec. 10503) in any county in the state.\n  3. The online voter registration application process shall provide\nreasonable accommodations to improve accessibility for persons with\ndisabilities, and shall be compatible for use with standard online\naccessibility assistance tools for persons with visual, physical or\nperceptive disabilities.\n  4. The state board of elections shall promulgate rules and regulations\nfor the creation and administration of an online voter registration\nsystem pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>