<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-804"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-804"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-804"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_804">
        <num>5-804</num>
        <heading>Failure to provide exemplar signature not to prevent registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-804. Failure to provide exemplar signature not to prevent\nregistration. 1. If a voter registration exemplar signature is not\nprovided by an applicant who submits a voter registration application\npursuant to this title, the local board shall seek to obtain such\nexemplar signature from the statewide voter registration database, the\nstate board of elections, or a state or local agency designated by\nsection 5-211 or 5-212 of this article.\n  2. If such exemplar signature is not available from the statewide\nvoter registration database, the state board of elections, or a state or\nlocal agency designated by section 5-211 or 5-212 of this article, the\nlocal board of elections shall, absent another reason to reject the\napplication, proceed to register and, as applicable, enroll the\napplicant. Within ten days of such action, the board of elections shall\nsend a standard form promulgated by the state board of elections to the\nvoter whose record lacks an exemplar signature, requiring such voter to\nsubmit a signature for identification purposes. The voter shall submit\nto the board of elections a voter registration exemplar signature by any\none of the following methods: in person, by mail with return postage\npaid provided by the board of elections, by electronic mail, or by\nelectronic upload to the board of elections through the electronic voter\nregistration transmittal system. If such voter does not provide the\nrequired exemplar signature, when the voter appears to vote the voter\nshall be entitled to vote by affidavit ballot.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>