<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-800"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-800"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-800"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-800/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-800/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-800/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-800/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_800">
        <num>5-800</num>
        <heading>Electronic voter registration transmittal system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-800. Electronic voter registration transmittal system. In addition\nto any other means of voter registration provided for by this chapter,\nthe state board of elections shall establish and maintain an electronic\nvoter registration transmittal system through which applicants may apply\nto register to vote online. The state board of elections shall\nelectronically transmit such applications to the applicable board of\nelections of each county or the city of New York for filing, processing\nand verification consistent with this chapter. In accordance with\ntechnical specifications provided by the state board of elections, each\nboard of elections shall maintain a voter registration system capable of\nreceiving and processing voter registration application information,\nincluding electronic signatures, from the electronic voter registration\ntransmittal system established by the state board of elections.\nNotwithstanding any other inconsistent provision of this chapter,\napplications filed using such system shall be considered filed with the\napplicable board of elections on the calendar date the application is\ninitially transmitted by the voter through the electronic voter\nregistration transmittal system.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>