<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-900"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-900"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-900"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-900/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-900/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-900/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-5-900/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_900">
        <num>5-900</num>
        <heading>Integrated personal voter registration application required</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>include a statement of the eligibility requirements for voter\nregistration and shall require the applicant to attest by the\napplicant's signature that the applicant meets those requirements under\npenalty of perjury and is applying to register or pre-register to vote\nunless such applicant declines such registration;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>inform the applicant, in print identical to that used in the\nattestation section of the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>voter eligibility requirements;\n  (ii) penalties for submission of a false registration application;\n  (iii) that the office where the applicant applies for registration\nshall remain confidential and the voter registration information shall\nbe used only for voter registration purposes;\n  (iv) that if the applicant applies to register to vote electronically,\nsuch applicant thereby consents to the use of an electronic copy of the\nindividual's manual signature that is in the custody of the department\nof motor vehicles, the state board of elections, or other agency\ndesignated by this section, as the individual's voter registration\nexemplar signature if the individual voter's exemplar signature is not\nprovided with the voter registration application;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the applicant signs the application and does not check the box\ndeclining to register to vote, such applicant thereby consents to the\nuse of any information required to complete the voter registration\napplication;\n  (vi) if the applicant declines to register, such applicant's\ndeclination shall remain confidential and be used only for voter\nregistration purposes; and\n  (vii) that applying to register or declining to register to vote will\nnot affect the amount of assistance that the applicant will be provided\nby this agency;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>include a box for the applicant to check to indicate whether the\napplicant would like to decline to register to vote along with the\nfollowing statement in prominent type, "IF YOU DO NOT CHECK THIS BOX,\nAND YOU PROVIDE YOUR SIGNATURE ON THE SPACE BELOW, YOU WILL HAVE APPLIED\nTO REGISTER OR PRE-REGISTER TO VOTE, AND YOU WILL HAVE ATTESTED TO YOUR\nELIGIBILITY TO REGISTER OR PRE-REGISTER TO VOTE."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>include the following warning statement in prominent type, "IF YOU\nARE NOT A CITIZEN OF THE UNITED STATES, YOU MUST CHECK THE BOX BELOW.\nNON-CITIZENS WHO REGISTER OR PRE-REGISTER TO VOTE MAY BE SUBJECT TO\nCRIMINAL PENALTIES AND SUCH VOTER REGISTRATION OR PRE-REGISTRATION MAY\nRESULT IN DEPORTATION OR REMOVAL, EXCLUSION FROM ADMISSION TO THE UNITED\nSTATES, OR DENIAL OF NATURALIZATION.";\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>include a space for the applicant to indicate the applicant's\nchoice of party enrollment, with a clear alternative provided for the\napplicant to decline to affiliate with any party and the following\nstatement in prominent type " ONLY ENROLLED MEMBERS OF A POLITICAL PARTY\nMAY VOTE IN THAT PARTY'S PRIMARIES".\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>include a statement that if an applicant is a victim of domestic\nviolence or stalking, the applicant may contact the state board of\nelections before or after registering or pre-registering to vote in\norder to receive information regarding the address confidentiality\nprogram for victims of domestic violence under section 5-508 of this\narticle.\n  7. Information from the voter relevant to both voter registration and\nthe agency application shall be entered by the voter only once upon an\nelectronic application.\n  8. The agency shall redact or remove from the completed integrated\napplication to be transmitted to the state board of elections any\ninformation solely applicable to the agency application.\n  9. Information concerning the citizenship status of individuals, when\ncollected and transmitted pursuant to subdivision one of this section,\nshall not be retained, used or shared for any other purpose except as\nmay be required by law.\n  10. A voter shall be able to decline to register to vote using an\nintegrated application by selecting a single check box, or equivalent,\nwhich shall include the following statement: "I DECLINE USE OF THIS FORM\nFOR VOTER REGISTRATION AND PRE-REGISTRATION PURPOSES. DO NOT FORWARD MY\nINFORMATION TO THE BOARD OF ELECTIONS."\n  11. The voter shall be able to sign the voter registration application\nand the agency application by means of a single manual or electronic\nsignature unless the agency requires more than one signature for other\nagency purposes.\n  12. No application for voter registration shall be submitted if the\napplicant declines registration or fails to sign the integrated\napplication, whether on paper or online.\n  13. Beginning January first, two thousand twenty-three, designated\nagencies for purposes of this section shall include the department of\nmotor vehicles. Beginning January first, two thousand twenty-four,\ndesignated agencies for the purposes of this section shall also include\nthe department of he...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ntwo years after designation by the governor, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_900__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>five days after the\ndate of certification by the state board of elections that the\ninformation technology infrastructure to substantially implement the\nprovisions of this section at the agency is functional.\n  15. The state board of elections shall promulgate rules and\nregulations for the creation and administration of an integrated\nelectronic voter registration process as provided for by this section.\n  16. Each participating agency shall provide an opportunity through\nrulemaking for public notice and comment regarding the plans for\nimplementation in the agency. Such opportunity must be provided\nsufficiently in advance of implementation to allow for adjustment of\nagency plans to take public comment into account. Agency plans for\nimplementation shall provide for sufficient testing of the process in\nthe agency prior to implementation in order to ensure the technology is\nfunctioning properly, the process is usable and understandable for\napplicants and agency employees, and reasonable precautions have been\nput in place to minimize error or the possibility of discouraging\napplications for services, assistance, or registration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>