<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-108"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_108">
        <num>6-108</num>
        <heading>Party nominations; towns</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-108. Party nominations; towns. 1. In any town in a county having a\npopulation of over seven hundred fifty thousand inhabitants, as shown by\nthe latest federal decennial or special population census, party\nnominations of candidates for town offices shall be made at the primary\npreceding the election. In any other town, nominations of candidates for\ntown offices shall be made by caucus or primary election as the rules of\nthe county committee shall provide, except that the members of the\ncounty committee from a town may adopt by a two-thirds vote, a rule\nproviding that the party candidates for town offices shall be nominated\nat the primary election. If a rule adopted by the county committee of a\npolitical party or by the members of the county committee from a town,\nprovides that party candidates for town offices, shall be nominated at a\nprimary election, such rule shall not apply to nor affect a primary held\nless than four months after a certified copy of the rule shall have been\nfiled with the board of elections. After the filing of such a rule, the\nrule shall continue in force until a certified copy of a rule revoking\nthe same shall have been filed with such board at least four months\nbefore a subsequent primary. Such a caucus shall be held no earlier than\nthe first day on which designating petitions for the primary election\nmay be signed.\n  2. In the event that there is no town committee with a chairman, the\nchairman of the county committee or such other person or body as the\nrules of such committee may provide, shall designate an enrolled member\nof the party who is a qualified voter of such town as the town caucus\nchairman to convene such caucus and give notice thereof.\n  3. A notice of any party caucus held for making party nominations of\ncandidates for town offices shall be given by proper party authorities\nby posting such notice in the public areas at the offices of the town\nclerk and the board of elections and filing a copy of such notice with\nsuch clerk and such board at least ten days preceding the day of the\ncaucus and, either by newspaper publication thereof once within the town\nat least one week and not more than two weeks preceding the caucus, or\nby posting in ten public places in the town at least ten days preceding\nthe day of the caucus. The notice shall specify the time and place or\nplaces, and the purpose of the caucus. There shall be a chairman and\nsecretary, and there may be tellers, for each such caucus, and they\nshall take the constitutional oath of office before acting. No person\nshall participate in such a caucus for the nomination of candidates for\ntown offices, unless he shall appear as an enrolled party voter on the\ntranscript of enrollments from the registration poll ledger. Town\ncaucuses described in this section shall be held at the expense of the\nparty. Subject to the foregoing provisions, the county committee of the\ncounty containing a town may prescribe rules governing the conduct of\nparty caucuses described in this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>