<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-03-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-120"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_120">
        <num>6-120</num>
        <heading>Designation and nomination; restrictions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-120. Designation and nomination; restrictions. 1. A petition,\nexcept as otherwise herein provided, for the purpose of designating any\nperson as a candidate for party nomination at a primary election shall\nbe valid only if the person so designated is an enrolled member of the\nparty referred to in said designating petition at the time of the filing\nof the petition.\n  2. Except as provided in subdivisions three and four of this section,\nno party designation or nomination shall be valid unless the person so\ndesignated or nominated shall be an enrolled member of the political\nparty referred to in the certificate of designation or nomination at the\ntime of filing of such certificate.\n  3. The members of the party committee representing the political\nsubdivision of the office for which a designation or nomination is to be\nmade, unless the rules of the party provide for another committee, in\nwhich case the members of such other committee, and except as\nhereinafter in this subdivision provided with respect to certain offices\nin the city of New York, may, by a majority vote of those present at\nsuch meeting provided a quorum is present, authorize the designation or\nnomination of a person as candidate for any office who is not enrolled\nas a member of such party as provided in this section. In the event that\nsuch designation or nomination is for an office to be filled by all the\nvoters of the city of New York, such authorization must be by a majority\nvote of those present at a joint meeting of the executive committees of\neach of the county committees of the party within the city of New York,\nprovided a quorum is present at such meeting. The certificate of\nauthorization shall be filed not later than four days after the last day\nto file the designating petition, certificate of nomination or\ncertificate of substitution to which such authorization relates,\nprovided, however, such certificate shall be filed not later than nine\ndays following the issuance of a proclamation of a special election held\npursuant to paragraph b of subdivision three of section forty-two of the\npublic officers law. The certificate of authorization shall be signed\nand acknowledged by the presiding officer and the secretary of the\nmeeting at which such authorization was given.\n  4. This section shall not apply to a political party designating or\nnominating candidates for the first time, to candidates nominated by\nparty caucus, nor to candidates for judicial offices.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>