<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-126"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-126"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-126"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-126/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-126/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-126/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-126/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_126">
        <num>6-126</num>
        <heading>Conventions; rules for holding</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-126. Conventions; rules for holding. 1. The time and place of\nmeeting of a convention shall be fixed, within the times prescribed\nherein, by a committee appointed pursuant to the rules of the state\ncommittee. The room designated for the meeting place of a convention\nshall have ample seating capacity for all delegates and alternates.\nEvery convention shall be called to order by the chairman of the\ncommittee from which the call originates or by a person designated in\nwriting for that purpose by such chairman, or, if he fails to make such\ndesignation, then, by a person designated in such manner as the rules of\nthe party shall prescribe. Such chairman or person designated shall have\nthe custody of the roll of the convention until it shall have been\norganized.  No such convention shall proceed to the election of a\ntemporary chairman or transact any business until the time fixed for the\nopening thereof nor until a majority of the delegates or respective\nalternates named in the official roll shall be present. The roll call\nupon the election of a temporary chairman shall not be delayed more than\none hour after the time specified in the call for the opening of the\nconvention, provided a majority of delegates, including alternates\nsufficient to make up such majority by substitution, are present. The\nperson who calls the convention to order shall exercise no other\nfunction than that of calling the official roll of the delegates upon\nthe vote for temporary chairman and declaring the result thereof.\n  2. The temporary chairman shall be chosen upon a call of the official\nroll.  The committees of the convention shall be appointed by the\nconvention, or by the temporary chairman, as the convention may order.\nWhere only one candidate is placed in nomination for any office, the\nvote may be taken viva voce. When more than one candidate is placed in\nnomination for an office the roll of the delegates shall be called and\neach delegate when his name is called shall arise in his place and\nannounce his choice, except that the chairman of a delegation from any\nunit of representation provided for by party rules, unless a member of\nsuch delegation objects, may announce the vote of such delegation.  The\nconvention may appoint a committee to nominate candidates to fill\nvacancies in nominations made by the convention and caused by the death,\ndeclination or disqualification of a candidate. The permanent officer\nshall keep the records of the convention.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>