<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-147"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-147"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-147"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-147/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-147/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-147/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-147/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_147">
        <num>6-147</num>
        <heading>Multiple designations of a candidate for a party position</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-147. Multiple designations of a candidate for a party position. 1.\nThe name of a person designated on more than one petition as a candidate\nfor a party position to be filled by two or more persons shall be\nprinted on the ballot with the group of candidates designated by the\npetition first filed unless such person, in a certificate duly\nacknowledged by him or her and filed with the board of elections not\nlater than the tenth Tuesday preceding the primary election or five days\nafter the board of elections mails such person notice of his or her\ndesignation in more than one group, whichever is later, specifies\nanother group in which his or her name shall be printed.\n  2. A person designated as a candidate for the position of member of\nthe county committee in more than one election district shall be deemed\nto have been designated in the lowest numbered election district unless\nsuch person, in a certificate duly acknowledged by him or her, and filed\nwith the board of elections not later than the tenth Tuesday preceding\nthe primary election or five days after the board of elections mails\nsuch person notice of his or her designation in more than one election\ndistrict whichever is later, specifies that he or she wishes to be\ndeemed designated in a different election district.\n  3. The board of elections shall forthwith notify each person\ndesignated more than once for the same party position in one or more\ndistricts of the fact of such designations and of his right to file a\ncertificate pursuant to the provisions of this section, specifying the\ngroup or district in which he wishes to be deemed a candidate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>