<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-144"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-144"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-144"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-144/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-144/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-144/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-144/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_144">
        <num>6-144</num>
        <heading>Nominating and designating petitions and certificates; place for filing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-144. Nominating and designating petitions and certificates; place\nfor filing.  Petitions, certificates and minutes specified in this\narticle shall be filed in the office of the Board of Elections of the\ncounty, except as follows:  for an office or position to be voted for\nwholly within the city of New York, in the office of the Board of\nElections of that city; for an office or position to be voted for in a\ndistrict greater than one county, or portions of two or more counties,\nin the office of the state board of elections; for a village office to\nbe filled in a village election not conducted by the board of elections,\nin the office of the village clerk. All such petitions and certificates\nshall at the time of filing thereof be endorsed by such officer or board\nwith the day, hour and minute of such filing. Such officer or board\nshall keep a book, which shall be open to public inspection in which\nshall be entered the times of filing all such petitions and\ncertificates; the names and residences of all candidates named therein;\nthe names and residences of all candidates certified to such officer or\nboard; the title of the office or party position; the name of the party\nor independent body to which the petition or certificate relates and a\nmemorandum of any objections to such petition or certificate. Forthwith\nupon the filing of a petition or certificate designating or nominating a\nperson or persons for public office, such officer or board shall mail\nnotice thereof to each such person. Such notice shall also state the\nlast day to decline such designation or nomination, and include a\nstatement that the candidate's name shall appear on the ballot as it\nappears in such notice.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>