<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-164"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-164"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-10-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-164"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-164/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-164/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-164/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-164/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_164">
        <num>6-164</num>
        <heading>Primary, uncontested; opportunity to ballot</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-164. Primary, uncontested; opportunity to ballot. Enrolled members\nof a party entitled to vote in the nomination of a candidate for public\noffice or the election of a candidate for party position in a primary\nelection of such party, and equal in number to at least the number of\nsigners required to designate a candidate for such office or position\nmay file with the officer or board with whom or which are filed\ndesignating petitions for such office or position a petition requesting\nan opportunity to write in the name of a candidate or candidates\nenrolled in such party, who need not be specified, for such office or\nposition. Upon the receipt of such a petition, such office or position\nshall be deemed contested and the primary ballots of the party shall\nafford an opportunity to vote thereon. Requests for an opportunity to\nwrite in the names of candidates for two or more offices or positions\nmay be included in the same petition. Such petitions shall be subject to\nobjections and court determination thereof in the same manner as\ndesignating petitions so far as the provisions therefor are applicable.\nAll required notices shall be served on the members of the committee\nnamed in the petition, and such committee shall have capacity to bring a\nproceeding under this chapter as if such committee was a candidate named\non a petition. A signature to a petition for an opportunity to ballot in\nprimary elections made earlier than sixteen days before the last day to\nfile designating petitions for the primary election shall not be\ncounted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>