<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-168"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-168"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-168"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-168/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-168/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-168/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-168/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_168">
        <num>6-168</num>
        <heading>Designating petitions; candidates for the office of judge of the civil court of the city of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-168. Designating petitions; candidates for the office of judge of\nthe civil court of the city of New York. 1. The board of elections of\nthe city of New York, not later than fourteen days before the first day\nto circulate designating petitions for a primary election, or the day\nafter a vacancy occurs, whichever is later, shall promulgate and have\navailable for public inspection at its main office, a list of all\nvacancies in the office of judge of the civil court of the city of New\nYork for which nominations will be made at such primary election. Such\nlist shall include the borough and district, if any, in which each such\nvacancy exists, the name of the judge who was last elected to such seat\nand a number assigned to each such vacancy by the board of elections.\n  2. A designating petition for any candidate for any such office shall\ninclude in the title of the office for which a designation is being\nmade, the number assigned by the board of elections to the vacancy for\nwhich such candidate is designated.\n  3. If, at any primary election in which more than one nomination is to\nbe made for the office of judge of the civil court of the city of New\nYork in any borough of such city or in any civil court district within\nany such borough, only one candidate is designated for any such vacancy,\nsuch candidate shall be deemed nominated and his name shall not appear\nupon the primary ballot unless a petition for opportunity to ballot for\nsuch vacancy is filed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.\n  4. If more than one person is designated for one or more such\nvacancies, all such persons shall be listed on the primary ballot as\ncandidates for such office without reference to the seat for which they\nwere designated and those persons, equal to the number of such\nvacancies, who receive the highest number of votes shall be nominated as\ncandidates for such office.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>