<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-202"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_202">
        <num>6-202</num>
        <heading>Party nominations; villages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-202. Party nominations; villages. 1. Party nominations of\ncandidates for village offices in any county shall be made at a party\ncaucus or at a primary election, as the rules of the county committee,\nheretofore or hereafter adopted consistent with the provisions of this\nchapter shall provide. If the rules of the county committee of any\npolitical party provide that party nominations for village offices of\nthat party in any or all villages in the county shall be made at a\nvillage primary election, such primary election shall be held forty-nine\ndays prior to the date of the village election. In the event there is no\nvillage committee with a chairman, the chairman of the county committee,\nor such other person or body as the rules of such committee may provide,\nshall designate an enrolled member of the party who is a qualified voter\nof the village as the village election chairman. The chairman of the\ncounty committee of each party in which nominations in any village are\nmade at a primary election shall file with the board of elections, at\nleast one week before the first day to file designating petitions for\nsuch primary elections, a list of the name and address of the chairman\nof the village committee or the village election chairman in each such\nvillage. Such village chairman shall have general party responsibility\nfor the conduct of the village caucus or primary election. Such\nnominations shall be made not more than fifty-six, nor less than\nforty-nine days prior to the date of the village election.\n  2. A notice of any village primary held for making party nominations\nof candidates for village offices to be filled at a village election\nshall be given by the proper party authorities by publication at least\nonce in each of the two weeks preceding the primary in at least one\nnewspaper of general circulation within the village.\n  3. A notice of any party caucus held for making party nominations for\nvillage offices for village elections shall be given by the proper party\nauthorities by posting such notice in the public areas at the offices of\nthe village clerk and the board of elections and by filing such notice\nwith such clerk and such board at least ten days preceding the day of\nthe caucus and, either by newspaper publication thereof once within the\nvillage at least one week and not more than two weeks preceding the\ncaucus, or by posting such notice in six public places in the village at\nleast ten days preceding the day of the caucus.\n  4. The notice shall specify the time and place or places, and the\npurpose of such caucus or primary, including the offices for which\ncandidates will be nominated thereat.  There shall be a chairman and a\nsecretary and tellers for each such village primary or caucus, who shall\nbe appointed by the appropriate party officials. No person shall\nparticipate in such primary or caucus who is not a resident of the\nvillage and an enrolled voter of the party conducting the primary or\ncaucus. At any primary or caucus in which nominees are chosen by vote of\nthe people in attendance, the person eligible and receiving the highest\nnumber of votes for an office shall be deemed nominated. Such village\nprimary or caucus shall not be conducted at public expense. The board of\nelections shall furnish a list of enrolled voters to the chairman of the\nvillage caucus or primary.\n  5. Any party nomination made at any such caucus or village primary\nshall be evidenced by the filing of a certificate of nomination with the\nboard of elections. There shall be filed, together with such\ncertificate, or within five days after the board of elections sends the\nnotice of failure to file prescribed by this subdivision, a list of\nenrolled members of the party who have participated in such caucus or\nprimary. If such list is not filed with such certificate, the board of\nelections shall forthwith send notice of the failure to file such list\nto the persons who signed such certificate, by first class mail,\ntogether with a notice that such list must be filed within five days\nafter such notice was mailed. Such list shall be certified by the\npresiding officer or secretary of such caucus or primary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>