<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-11-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-206"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_206">
        <num>6-206</num>
        <heading>Independent nominations; petition, form</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-206. Independent nominations; petition, form.  1. Independent\nnominations for elective village offices shall be made by a petition\ncontaining the signatures in ink of residents of the village who are\nregistered with the appropriate county board of elections at the time of\nsigning. The sheets of such a petition shall be numbered. A signer need\nnot himself or herself fill in the date or residence. Each sheet of such\npetition must be in substantially the following form and shall contain\nall the information required therein:\n                 VILLAGE INDEPENDENT NOMINATING PETITION\n  I, the undersigned, do hereby state that I am a registered voter of\nthe Village of......., that my present place of residence is truly\nstated opposite my signature, and I do hereby nominate the following\nnamed person (or persons) as a candidate (or as candidates) for election\nto public office (or public offices) to be voted for at the election to\nbe held on the.....day of........, 20....., and that I select the\nname........... (fill in name) as the name of the independent body\nmaking the nomination (or nominations) and.....(fill in emblem) as the\nemblem of such body.\n     Name of\n    Candidate           Public Office           Term        Residence\n                        (include district\n                        number, if applicable)\n   .............      ....................      ....      ...............\n   .............      ....................      ....      ...............\n  I do hereby appoint (insert names and addresses of at least three\npersons, all of whom shall be registered voters within such village) as\na committee to fill vacancies in accordance with the provisions of the\nelection law.\n  In witness whereof, I have signed this petition on the day and year\nstated before my signature.\n    Date          Signature           Residence\n  ..........    .................   ...................\n  ..........    .................   ...................\n                          STATEMENT OF WITNESS\n  I, ..................... state that I am a duly qualified voter of the\nState of New York. I now reside at ................ (residence address).\nEach of the voters whose names are subscribed to this petition sheet\ncontaining ................ (fill in number) signatures, subscribed his\nor her name in my presence.\n  I understand that this statement will be accepted for all purposes as\nthe equivalent of an affidavit and, if it contains a material false\nstatement, shall subject me to the same penalties as if I had been duly\nsworn.\n .......................           ..............................\n    Date                               Signature of witness\n  2. In lieu of the signed statement of a witness who is a duly\nqualified voter of the state qualified to sign the petition, the\nfollowing statement signed by a notary public shall be accepted:\n  On the dates above indicated before me personally came each of the\nvoters whose signatures appear on this petition sheet\ncontaining ............. (fill in number) signatures, who signed same in\nmy presence and who, being by me duly sworn, each for himself or\nherself, said that the foregoing statement made and subscribed by him or\nher, was true.\nDate:..................\n                      ...............................\n                      (Signature and official title\n                       of officer administering oath)\n    Page No........\n  3. The name selected for the independent body making the nomination\nshall be in the English language and shall not include the name or part\nof the name, or an abbreviation of the name or of part of the name, of a\nthen existing party. The name and emblem shown upon such petition shall\nconform to the requirements of this chapter, relating to party names and\nparty emblems. If such a petition shall not show an emblem, or the\npetition shall fail to select a name for such independent body, the\nboard of elections shall select an emblem or name, or both to\ndistinguish the candidates nominated thereby.\n  4. An independent nominating petition for a village office must be\nsigned by at least one hundred voters in villages containing a\npopulation of five thousand or more; by at least seventy-five voters in\nvillages containing a population of three thousand and less than five\nthousand; and by at least fifty voters in villages containing a\npopulation of one thousand and less than three thousand; and in villages\ncontaining a population of less than one thousand by voters numbering at\nleast five per centum of the number of voters at the last regular\nvillage election. For the purposes of this section, the population of a\nvillage shall be determined by the last federal decennial or local\nspecial population census federally supervised pursuant to section\ntwenty of the general municipal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>