<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-11-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-204"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_204">
        <num>6-204</num>
        <heading>Designating petition; form</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-204. Designating petition; form.  1. Party designations for\nelective village offices shall be made on a designating petition\ncontaining the signatures in ink of residents of the village who are\nregistered to vote with the appropriate county board of elections at the\ntime of signing and who are enrolled in such political party. The sheets\nof such a petition shall be numbered. A signer need not himself or\nherself fill in the date or residence. Each sheet of such petition must\nbe in substantially the following form and shall contain all the\ninformation required therein:\n                       PARTY DESIGNATING PETITION\n  I, the undersigned do hereby state that I am a registered voter of the\nVillage of ............. and a duly enrolled voter of the .............\nparty and entitled to vote at the next primary election of such party,\nthat my place of residence is truly stated opposite my signature hereto,\nand I hereby designate the following named person (or persons) as a\ncandidate or (candidates) for nomination of such party for the public\noffice or (public offices) to be voted for at the primary election to be\nheld on the ...... day of ............ 20.... as hereinafter specified.\n                          Public Office\n                          (include district\n                          number,\n    Name of Candidate     if applicable)      Term          Residence\n  ....................  .................   ..........    ............\n  ....................  .................   ..........    ............\n  I do hereby appoint (insert names and addresses of at least three\npersons, all of whom shall be enrolled voters of said party) as a\ncommittee to fill vacancies in accordance with the provisions of the\nelection law.\n  In witness whereof, I have hereunto set my hand, the day and year\nplaced opposite my signature.\n    Date             Name            Residence\n   .............   .............   ...............\n   .............   .............   ...............\n                          STATEMENT OF WITNESS\n  I ............... (name of witness) state: I am a duly qualified voter\nof the State of New York; and an enrolled voter of the .........  party.\nI now reside at ..... (residence address). Each of the persons whose\nnames are subscribed to this petition sheet containing .........\nsignatures, subscribed his or her name in my presence.\n  I understand that this statement will be accepted for all purposes as\nthe equivalent of an affidavit and, if it contains a material false\nstatement, shall subject me to the same penalties as if I had been duly\nsworn.\n   ........................        .................................\n      Date:                                 Signature of witness\n  In lieu of the signed statement of a witness who is a duly qualified\nvoter of the state qualified to sign the petition, the following\nstatement signed by a notary public shall be accepted:\n  On the dates above indicated before me personally came each of the\nvoters whose signatures appear on this petition sheet containing\n.............. (fill in number) signatures, who signed same in my\npresence and who, being by me duly sworn, each for himself or herself,\nsaid that the foregoing statement made and subscribed by him or her, was\ntrue.\nDate..................\n                     ...............................\n                     (Signature and official title\n                     of officer administering oath)\n    Page No........\n  2. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the number of\nsignatures required on a designating petition shall be five percent of\nthe number of enrolled voters of the party residing in the village.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>