<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-210"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-6-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_210">
        <num>6-210</num>
        <heading>Petitions and certificates; place and times for filing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-210. Petitions and certificates; place and times for filing. 1.\nPetitions and certificates specified in this title shall be filed with\nthe county board of elections.\n  2. a. A certificate of party nomination for an office to be filled at\nthe time of a general or special village election for offices shall be\nfiled not earlier than fifty-four days nor later than forty-seven days\npreceding the election.\n  b. A certificate of acceptance or declination of a party nomination\nfor an office to be filled at the time of a general or special village\nelection shall be filed not later than forty-four days prior to such\nelection.\n  c. A certificate to fill a vacancy caused by declination of a party\nnomination for an office to be filled at the time of a general or\nspecial village election shall be filed not later than forty-one days\nprior to such election.\n  d. Party designating petitions for a village primary election shall be\nfiled not earlier than twenty-two days nor later than fifteen days prior\nto the primary election.  Upon such a filing, the board of elections\nshall immediately notify the village election chairman of such party and\nthe person or persons designated in such petition of the fact of such\nfiling and that such petition may be inspected in its office.\n  e. A written declination of a party designation must be filed within\nthree days of the date of the filing of the designating petition. Upon\nthe filing of such declination, the board of elections shall, within one\nday notify the committee to fill vacancies named in the petition. A\ncertificate to fill the vacancy caused by a declination or any other\nreason must be filed within three days after the date of the notice to\nthe committee to fill vacancies and shall have appended thereto the\nwritten consent of the person or persons designated.\n  3. a. An independent nominating petition for an office to be filled at\nthe time of a general or special village election shall be filed not\nearlier than forty-two days nor later than thirty-five days preceding\nthe election.\n  b. A certificate of acceptance or declination of an independent\nnomination for an office to be filled at the time of a general or\nspecial village election shall be filed not later than three days after\nthe last day to file the petition which made such independent\nnomination.\n  c. A certificate to fill a vacancy caused by a declination of an\nindependent nomination for an office to be filled at the time of a\ngeneral or special village election for offices shall be filed not later\nthan three days after the last day to file the certificate of\ndeclination, and shall have appended thereto the written consent of the\nperson or persons nominated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>