<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-114"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-114"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-114"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_114">
        <num>7-114</num>
        <heading>Ballots; form for primary election; additional requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_114__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On the face of the official ballot for a primary election\ncontests and candidates for nomination for public office shall appear\nfirst, followed by contests and candidates for party positions. When\nnecessary, a part may be divided into two or more columns or rows, but\nthe names of all persons designated for the same office or party\nposition shall be in the same column or row.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_114__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a candidate for nomination for the same public office or for\nelection to the same party position is designated by two or more\npetitions, his or her name shall be placed upon the ballot for the\nprimary election but once as such a candidate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_114__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The ballot shall not contain a space for voting for candidates for\nuncontested offices and positions, and no ballot shall be printed for a\nparty for which there is no contested office or position unless a\npetition for opportunity to ballot has been filed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_114__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the offices of governor and lieutenant governor, ballots shall\nbe printed with the names of the candidates for both offices who were\ndesignated jointly. The names shall appear in the same row or column,\nwith the name of the candidate for governor appearing first. The ballot\nshall have one designating letter or number to reflect the offices are\nvoted for jointly.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_114__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on the official primary election ballot, the ballot endorsement\nshall include the name of the party for which such ballot is valid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_114__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>where two or more candidates are to be elected to a party\nposition, the names of candidates designated by each petition shall be\ngrouped together, and may be referred to collectively on the ballot as a\ngroup.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>