<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-118"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-118"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-01-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-118"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_118">
        <num>7-118</num>
        <heading>Ballots; facsimile and sample</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-118. Ballots; facsimile and sample. 1. The board of elections\nshall provide facsimile and sample ballots which shall be arranged in\nthe form of a diagram showing such part of the face of the voting\nmachine or ballots as shall be in use at that election. Such facsimile\nand sample ballots shall be distinguishable from the official ballot by\nsize, color, or other means and shall contain suitable illustrated\ndirections for voting on the voting machine or ballot.\n  2. Such facsimile ballots shall be mounted and displayed for public\ninspection at each polling place during election day.\n  3. Sample ballots may be mailed by the board of elections to each\neligible voter at least three days before the election, or in lieu\nthereof, a copy of such sample ballot may be published at least once\nwithin one week preceding the election in newspapers or on a website\nmaintained by the board of elections. Each county board of elections\nshall transmit electronically in a format to be determined by the state\nboard of elections, as it is available, a copy of the candidate and\ncontest information contained on each of its ballot styles to the state\nboard of elections. The state board shall create a system to allow such\ninformation to be made publicly available via its website, as well as\nthe website of any county board of elections, and in such a way as to be\naccessible with a computer screen-reading program.\n  4. One copy of such facsimile shall be sent to each school in the\ncounty, providing the ninth through the twelfth years of compulsory\neducation, and in the city of New York to each such school in the city\nof New York, at least one week before each general election for posting\nat a convenient place in such school. The board of elections shall also\nsend a facsimile ballot to any other school requesting such a ballot. In\nthe alternative, the requirements of this subdivision may be fully\nsatisfied by publishing such facsimile on a website maintained by the\nboard of elections and notifying each such school of such publication.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>