<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-119"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-119"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-119"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_119">
        <num>7-119</num>
        <heading>Ballots; early mail voters</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_119__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Ballots for early mail\nvoters shall be, as nearly as practicable, in the same form as those to\nbe voted in the district on election day, except that such ballots need\nnot have a stub, and shall have the words "Early Mail Ballot", endorsed\nthereon.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_119__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All provisions of this chapter not inconsistent with this\nsubdivision shall be applicable to early mail ballots prepared for\ncounting by a ballot scanner or by hand. The instructions for marking an\nearly mail ballot shall be provided and shall be substantially as\nfollows, so that they accurately reflect the ballot layout:\nINSTRUCTIONS\nMark the (insert "oval" or "square") to the left of the name of your\nchoice. (Provide illustration of correctly-marked voting position here.)\nTo vote for a candidate whose name is not printed on the ballot, (insert\n"mark the oval (or square) to the left of 'write-in' and print the name\nclearly" or "print the name clearly in the box labeled 'write-in'"),\nstaying within the box. Any mark or writing outside the spaces provided\nfor voting may void the entire ballot. You have a right to a replacement\nballot. If you make a mistake or want to change your vote, call the\nboard of elections at (insert phone number here) for instructions on how\nto obtain a new ballot. The number of choices is listed for each\ncontest. Do not mark the ballot for more candidates than allowed. If you\ndo, your vote in that contest will not count.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_119__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a question or proposal is included on the ballot,\ninstructions substantially similar to those provided in subdivision\nfifteen of section 7-104 of this article shall be included.\n  2. The determination of the appropriate county board of elections as\nto the candidates duly designated or nominated for public office or\nparty position whose name shall appear on the early mail ballot and as\nto ballot proposals to be voted on shall be made no later than the day\nafter the state board of elections issues its certification of those\ncandidates to be voted for at the general, special or primary election.\nThe determinations of the state board of elections and the respective\ncounty boards of elections shall be final and conclusive with respect to\nsuch offices for which petitions or certificates are required to be\nfiled with such boards, as the case may be but nothing contained in this\nsection shall prevent a board of elections, or a court of competent\njurisdiction from determining at a later date that any such\ncertification, designation or nomination is invalid and, in the event of\nsuch later determination, no vote cast for any such nominee by any voter\nshall be counted at the election.\n  3. There shall be three envelopes for each early mail ballot issued by\nmail: the inner affirmation envelope into which a voter places their\nvoted ballot, the outer envelope which shall be addressed to the early\nmail voter, and the mailing envelope which is addressed to the county\nboard of elections. The board of elections shall furnish with each early\nmail ballot an inner affirmation envelope. On one side of the envelope\nshall be printed:\n                       OFFICIAL EARLY MAIL BALLOT\n                                   for\n                GENERAL (OR PRIMARY OR SPECIAL) ELECTION,\n ..........., 20.......\nName of voter ..................\nResidence (street and number if any) ..............\nCity/or town of (village, if any) .................\nCounty of ...........</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>