<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-125"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-125"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-125"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_125">
        <num>7-125</num>
        <heading>Ballots; special presidential voters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-125. Ballots; special presidential voters. 1. The ballots for\nspecial presidential voters shall provide for voting for presidential\nand vice presidential electors only and shall be in the form prescribed\nfor absentee ballots, except that either on the front or the back they\nshall be endorsed with the words printed or stamped, "Official\nBallot-Special Presidential Voter" and "Presidential Electors".\n  2. There shall be three envelopes for each special presidential\nabsentee ballot issued by mail: the inner affirmation envelope into\nwhich a voter places his or her voted ballot, the outer envelope which\nshall be addressed to the absentee voter, and the mailing envelope which\nis addressed to the county board of elections. The board of elections\nshall furnish with each special presidential ballot an envelope. On one\nside of the envelope shall be printed:\n              OFFICIAL BALLOT, SPECIAL PRESIDENTIAL VOTERS,\n                          FOR GENERAL ELECTION,\n                         NOVEMBER......., 20....\nName of voter ..........................................................\nResidence from which vote is being cast:\nStreet and number ......................................................\nCity or town ...........................................................\nCounty .................................................................\nAssembly District or Ward ..............................................\nElection District ......................................................\n  The date of the election and name of the county shall be printed, and\nthe name of the voter, residence, name of the city or town, number of\nward or assembly district, if any, and election district shall be\nprinted, written or stamped in by the board.\n  3.  On the reverse side of such envelope shall be printed the\nfollowing statement:\n                 STATEMENT OF SPECIAL PRESIDENTIAL VOTER\n  I do declare I am a qualified special presidential voter of said\ndistrict; that I am not qualified and am not able to qualify to vote\nelsewhere than as set forth on the reverse side of this envelope; that I\nam a citizen of the United States; that on the date of the election for\nwhich this ballot is voted, I will be at least eighteen years of age;\nand that I have not committed any act, nor am I under any impediment,\nwhich denies me the right to vote.\n  I hereby declare that the foregoing is a true statement to the best of\nmy knowledge and belief, and I understand that if I make any material\nfalse statement in the foregoing statement, I shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor.\nDate.................20.....       .....................................\n                                   Signature or mark of voter\n                                   .....................................\n                                   Signature of Witness (required only\n                                   if voter does not sign his or her own\n                                   name)\n                                   .....................................\n                                   Address of Witness\n  4. The envelope shall be gummed, ready for sealing, and shall have\nprinted thereon, on the side opposite the statement, instructions as to\nthe duties of the voter after the marking of the ballot, which\ninstructions shall include a specific direction stating that the\nenvelope must be delivered or mailed to the appropriate board of\nelections and a specific direction stating when such envelope must be\ndelivered or postmarked and when such envelope, if so mailed, must reach\nsuch board of elections in order to be canvassed.\n  5. Each ballot envelope shall be enclosed in a second envelope\naddressed to the board of elections and bearing a specific direction\nthat if an application for special presidential ballot is received with\nthe ballot, such application must be completed by the voter and returned\nin such envelope together with the envelope containing the special\npresidential ballot. Such second envelope shall be enclosed in a third\nenvelope addressed to the special presidential voter. The second and\nthird envelopes shall have printed on the face thereof the words\n"Election Material--Please Expedite".\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>