<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-120"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_120">
        <num>7-120</num>
        <heading>Ballots; emergency use, to be furnished</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-120. Ballots; emergency use, to be furnished.  1. If any voting\nmachine or voting system for use in any election shall become out of\norder during an election it shall, if possible, be repaired or another\nmachine or voting system substituted as promptly as possible. In case\nsuch repair or substitution cannot be made, emergency ballots, printed\nor written, and of any suitable form, shall be provided by the board of\nelections and may be used for the casting of votes.\n  2. If the official ballots for an election district shall not be\ndelivered within the time necessary to open the polls, or shall be lost,\ndestroyed or stolen, or if the supply of official ballots shall be\nexhausted before the polls are closed, the board of elections, or at its\ndirection, the town or city clerk, or the election inspectors of such\ndistrict, shall cause emergency ballots to be prepared, printed or\nwritten, as nearly in the form of the official ballots as practicable.\nThe inspectors shall use the ballots so substituted in the same manner,\nas near as may be, as the official ballots.\n  3. It shall be the duty of each board of elections to cause a\nsufficient number of emergency ballots to be placed at each polling\nplace in which voting machines or voting systems are used, to be\nemployed in the event the voting machines or voting systems break down.\nAt any time during the hour succeeding a breakdown, the inspectors of\nelection may use such emergency ballots, and if such breakdown lasts\nmore than one hour, such emergency ballots must be used. The sample\nballots may be used for this purpose in full or reduced size.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>