<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-204"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_204">
        <num>7-204</num>
        <heading>Contracts for purchase of voting machines or systems</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-204. Contracts for purchase of voting machines or systems. 1. All\ncontracts for purchase of voting machines or systems of types approved\nby the state board of elections shall include, but not be limited to,\nrequirements that the vendors provide assistance in training board of\nelections personnel in the operation of such machines or systems and any\nancillary equipment, assistance in the conduct of all elections\nconducted during the first year in which each such machine or system is\nused and at least five years of service for all such machines or systems\nand ancillary equipment.\n  2. All such contracts shall also require the vendor to guarantee in\nwriting to keep such machines and systems in good working order for at\nleast five years without additional cost and to perform satisfactorily\nits training and service obligations under the contract and to give a\nsufficient bond conditioned to that effect.\n  3. The state board of elections, in consultation with the office of\ngeneral services, shall issue regulations specifying the manner in which\ncontracts must be drawn in order to comply with the provisions of this\nsection.\n  4. Purchase contracts for purchase of voting machines or systems of\ntypes approved by the state board of elections may not become effective\nuntil a date at least ten days after copies of such contracts are\nreceived by the state board of elections unless, within such ten day\nperiod, such board of elections notifies the local board of elections\nwhich submitted such contract that such contract does not meet\nrequirements of this chapter or the regulations of the state board of\nelections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>