<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-203"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_203">
        <num>7-203</num>
        <heading>Voting machines; requirement of use</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-203. Voting machines; requirement of use. 1. The board of\nelections shall provide a sufficient number of voting machines to fully\nequip all election districts within its jurisdiction. Such voting\nmachines shall be used at all general, special and primary elections\nconducted pursuant to this chapter.\n  2. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the state\nboard of elections shall establish, in accordance with subdivision four\nof section 3-100 of this chapter, for each election, the minimum number\nof voting machines required in each polling place and the maximum number\nof voters that can vote on one voting machine. Such minimum number of\nvoting machines shall be based on the voting machine in use, taking into\naccount machine functionality and capability, including the ability to\ntabulate multiple official ballots and the need for efficient and\norderly elections and, in the case of a general or special election, the\nnumber of registered voters, excluding voters in inactive status, in the\nelection district or, in the case of a primary election, the number of\nenrolled voters, excluding voters in inactive status, therein.\n  3. In the event that the board of elections shall not agree upon, or\nthe county shall not execute a contract or contracts for the purchase\nof, the necessary voting machines, such contract or contracts shall be\nawarded, made and executed by the state board of elections, in\naccordance with subdivision four of section 3-100 of this chapter, on\napproval of the attorney general as to form. The expense of making and\nentering into such contracts, including the preparation and printing of\nspecifications, and also all payments for voting machines to be made\nthereunder, shall be chargeable to the county, except in the city of New\nYork where such expense shall be chargeable to such city, and it shall\nbe the duty of the comptroller or other chief fiscal officer of the\ncounty or city, as the case may be, to pay the same upon the certificate\nof the officer making such contract, or upon the certificate of the\nstate board of elections in the event that such contract be made by it.\nNo provision of any charter or other law or ordinance governing the\npurchase of patented articles shall be deemed to apply to the purchase\nof voting machines pursuant to the provisions of this section. Nothing\nin this section shall be construed to prevent the state board of\nelections from distributing voting machines to boards of elections\npursuant to other provisions of this chapter without charge.\n  4. The board of elections may purchase voting machines for use in\ndemonstration and as extra machines within the county.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>