<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-201"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_201">
        <num>7-201</num>
        <heading>Voting machines and systems; examination of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-201. Voting machines and systems; examination of. 1. Any person or\ncorporation owning or being interested in any voting machine or system\nmay apply to have the state board of elections examine such machine or\nsystem. Such applicant shall pay to the board before the examination a\nfee equal to the cost of such examination. The state board of elections\nshall cause the machine or system to be examined and a report of the\nexamination to be made and filed in the office of the state board. Such\nexamination shall include a determination as to whether the machine or\nsystem meets the requirements of section 7-202 of this title and a\nthorough review and testing of any electronic or computerized features\nof the machine or system. Such report shall state an opinion as to\nwhether the kind of machine or system so examined can safely and\nproperly be used by voters and local boards of elections at elections,\nunder the conditions prescribed in this article and the requirements of\nthe federal Help America Vote Act. If the report states that the machine\nor system can be so used, and the board after its own examination so\ndetermines, in accordance with subdivision four of section 3-100 of this\nchapter, the machine or system shall be deemed approved, and machines or\nsystems of its kind may be adopted for use at elections as herein\nprovided. The voting machine or system shall be examined by examiners or\ntesting laboratories to be selected for such purpose by the state board.\nEach examiner or laboratory shall receive compensation and expenses for\nmaking an examination and report as to each voting machine or system\nexamined by him or it. Neither any member of the state board of\nelections nor any examiner or owner or employee of any testing\nlaboratory, shall have any pecuniary interest in any voting machine or\nsystem. Any form of voting machine or system not so approved, cannot be\nused at any election.\n  2. When any change is made in the operation or material of any feature\nor component of any machine or system which has been approved pursuant\nto the provisions of this section, such machine or system must be\nsubmitted for such re-examination and reapproval pursuant to the\nprovisions of subdivision one of this section as the state board of\nelections deems necessary.\n  3. If at any time after any machine or system has been approved\npursuant to the provisions of subdivision one or two of this section,\nthe state board of elections has any reason to believe that such machine\nor system does not meet all the requirements for voting machines or\nsystems set forth in this article, it shall forthwith cause such machine\nor system to be examined again in the manner prescribed by subdivision\none of this section. If the opinions in the report of such examinations\ndo not state that such machine or system can safely and properly be used\nby voters at elections under the conditions prescribed by this article,\nthe state board of elections shall forthwith rescind its approval of\nsuch machine or system. After the date on which the approval of any\nmachine or system is rescinded, no machines or systems of such type may\nbe purchased for use in this state. The state board of elections shall\nexamine all machines or systems of such type which were previously\npurchased, to determine if they may continue to be used in elections in\nthis state.\n  4. The state board of elections may authorize, for use on an\nexperimental basis, one or more types of voting machine, system or\nequipment not previously approved by such board pursuant to the\nprovisions of this section and may authorize a local board of elections\nto rent or borrow a limited number of one such type of machine, system\nor equipment for use in a primary, special, general or village election.\nAuthorization for such use of such a machine, system or equipment may be\ngiven for all or part of any city, town or village for any such\nelection.\n  5. The board shall deposit all fees collected pursuant to the\nprovisions of subdivision one of this section to the credit of the\nvoting machine and system examination fund established pursuant to\nsection ninety-two-p of the state finance law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>