<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-200"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_200">
        <num>7-200</num>
        <heading>Adoption and use of voting machine or system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-200. Adoption and use of voting machine or system. 1. The board of\nelections of the city of New York and other county boards of elections\nmay adopt any kind of voting machine or system approved by the state\nboard of elections, or the use of which has been specifically authorized\nby law; and thereupon such voting machine or system may be used at any\nor all elections and shall be used at all general or special elections\nheld by such boards in such city, town or village and in every contested\nprimary election in the city of New York and in every contested primary\nelection outside the city of New York in which there are one thousand or\nmore enrolled voters qualified to vote. No more than two types of voting\nmachines or systems may be used by any local board of elections at a\nsingle election. Notwithstanding the other provisions of this\nsubdivision, any local board of elections may borrow or lease for use on\nan experimental basis for a period of not more than one year each,\nvoting machines or systems of any type approved by the state board of\nelections.\n  2. For five years after any voting machine or system of a type\napproved by the state board of elections pursuant to the election reform\nand modernization act of 2005 is first used in any election district,\nthe local board of elections which owns such machine or system shall\nprovide a model or diagram of such voting machine or system for each\npolling place in which any such election district is located. Such\nmodels or diagrams shall meet the standards set forth in regulations\npromulgated by the state board of elections.\n  3. Whenever there are more offices to be elected than can be\naccommodated on the voting machine or system or more candidates have\nbeen nominated for an office than can be accommodated on the voting\nmachine or system, the local board of elections may provide for the use\nof separate paper ballots for such offices, when other offices are voted\nfor on voting machines or systems by voters of the same election\ndistrict.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>