<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-202"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-7-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_202">
        <num>7-202</num>
        <heading>Voting machine or system; requirements of</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_202__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>being capable of conducting both pre-election and post-election\ntesting of the logic and accuracy of the machine or system that\ndemonstrates an accurate tally when a known quantity of votes is entered\ninto each machine; and\n  (ii) providing a means by which a malfunctioning voting machine or\nsystem shall secure any votes already cast on such machine or system;\n  s. permit alternative language accessibility pursuant to the\nrequirements of section 203 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (42 U.S.C.\n1973aa-1a) such that it must have the capacity to display the full\nballot in the alternative languages required by the federal Voting\nRights Act if such voting machine or system is to be used where such\nalternative languages are required or where the local board deems such\nfeature necessary; and\n  t. not include any device or functionality potentially capable of\nexternally transmitting or receiving data via the internet or via radio\nwaves or via other wireless means.\n  2. The state board of elections shall approve, for use at each polling\nplace at least one voting machine or system at such polling place which,\nin addition to meeting the requirements in subdivision one of this\nsection, shall:\n  a. be equipped with a voting device with tactile discernible controls\ndesigned to meet the needs of voters with limited reach and limited hand\ndexterity;\n  b. be equipped with an audio voting feature that communicates the\ncomplete content of the ballot in a voice which permits a voter who is\nblind or visually impaired to cast a secret ballot using voice-only or\ntactile discernible controls; and\n  c. be capable of being equipped with a pneumatic switch voting\nattachment which can be operated orally by gentle pressure or the\ncreation of a vacuum through the inhalation or exhalation of air by the\nvoter including, but not limited to, a sip-and-puff switch voting\nattachment.\n  3. The state board of elections may, in accordance with subdivision\nfour of section 3...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>