<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-104"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-104"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-104"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_104">
        <num>8-104</num>
        <heading>Polls</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the sample ballot and instructions for the use\nof ballot scanners and ballot marking devices required pursuant to\nsection 7-118 of this chapter;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement that "today is election\nday" and the hours during which polling places will be open;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ninstructions on how to cast an affidavit ballot and a concise statement\nof a voter's right to such a ballot;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>instructions relating to\nrequirements for voting on ballot scanners by those registrants who must\nprovide identification pursuant to the federal Help America Vote Act of\n2002;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>instructions for first-time voters;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a voter's bill of\nrights describing voter's rights under applicable federal and state law,\nincluding the right of accessibility and alternate language\naccessibility;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>information pertaining to voting by election day\npaper ballot, including information about the consequence of casting an\novervote, steps to prevent unintentional undervoting and spoiled\nballots;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>instructions on how to contact the appropriate officials if\na voter's right to vote or right to otherwise participate in the\nelectoral process has been violated; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_104__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>general information on\nfederal and state laws regarding prohibitions on acts of fraud and\nmisrepresentation. The state board of elections shall prescribe the form\nand content of the voter information posting, which may be comprised of\none or more pages, provided each page shall be posted separately. The\nstate board of elections shall prescribe an official version of such\nvoter information posting for every language which appears on any\ngeneral, primary or special election ballot in any election district in\nthe state and for such other languages as such board, in its opinion,\ndetermines is appropriate. Such posting shall be used in all\njurisdictions, and a separate posting shall be made by election\ninspectors for each language appearing on the ballot and for such\nadditional languages as the board of elections may require. A board of\nelections may modify or supplement the voter information posting used in\nits jurisdiction to provide additional or local information; provided,\nhowever, any such modification or supplementation shall be submitted to\nthe state board of elections for prior approval.\n  2. The ballot boxes, other secure storage containers and all official\nballots shall be kept within the guard-rail, and at least six feet\ntherefrom, from the opening of the polls until the announcement of the\nresult of the canvass and the signing of the inspectors' returns\nthereof. No person shall be admitted within the guard-rail during such\nperiod except the election officers, authorized watchers, persons\nadmitted by the inspectors to preserve order or enforce the law, voters\nduly admitted for the purpose of voting and children under the age of\nsixteen accompanying their voting parents or guardians; provided,\nhowever, that candidates voted for at the polling place may be within\nthe guard-rail during the canvass.\n  3. The provisions of this chapter concerning the preservation of order\nand apprehension for crime on a day of registration, shall apply...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>