<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-100"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_100">
        <num>8-100</num>
        <heading>Elections; dates of and hours for voting</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_100__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A primary\nelection shall be held on the fourth Tuesday in June before every\ngeneral election unless otherwise changed by an act of the legislature.\nMembers of the state and county committees and assembly district leaders\nand associate district leaders and all other party positions to be\nelected shall be elected at such primary and all nominations for public\noffice required to be made at a primary election in such year shall be\nmade at such primary. In each year in which electors of president and\nvice president of the United States are to be elected an additional\nprimary election, to be known as the spring primary, shall be held on\nthe first Tuesday in February unless otherwise changed by an act of the\nlegislature, for the purpose of electing delegates to the national\nconvention.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_100__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event a run-off primary election is required in the city of\nNew York, it shall be held on the fourth Tuesday next succeeding the\ndate on which the initial primary election was held.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_100__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The general election shall be held annually on the Tuesday next\nsucceeding the first Monday in November.\n  2. Polls shall be open for voting during the following hours: a\nprimary election from six o'clock in the morning until nine o'clock in\nthe evening; the general election from six o'clock in the morning until\nnine o'clock in the evening; a special election called by the governor\npursuant to the public officers law, and, except as otherwise provided\nby law, every other election, from six o'clock in the morning until nine\no'clock in the evening; early voting hours shall be as provided in title\nsix of this article. Early voting times shall be as provided in section\n8-600 of this article.\n  3. In any election district in which a primary of any party is\nuncontested, no primary of such party shall be held. In any election\ndistrict in which the primaries of all parties are uncontested on the\nday of any primary election, no primaries shall be held on such day and\nthe polling place shall not be opened for voting.\n  4. No primary, special or general election for any state or local\noffice or for the election of officers of any corporation which is\nfunded in whole or in part by federal, state or municipal moneys shall\nbe held on a Saturday or Sunday.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>