<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-202"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_202">
        <num>8-202</num>
        <heading>Board of inspectors; conduct of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8-202. Board of inspectors; conduct of. 1. The chair of the board of\ninspectors theretofore appointed shall continue to act as such, and the\ninspectors shall act as a board, and a majority thereof shall decide\nquestions. Two inspectors who are not of the same political faith shall\nhave charge of the registration poll ledgers or computer generated\nregistration lists, subject to inspection thereof by any inspector and\nhis or her participation in the decision of any question. Of the\ninspectors in charge of the registration poll ledgers or computer\ngenerated registration lists, one shall be assigned to the duty of\ncomparing the signatures of voters. Inspectors shall be assigned to the\nforegoing duties by majority vote of the board of inspectors, before the\nopening of the polls. Such assignments shall be by lot if a majority\ncannot agree. The duties of an inspector or clerk may be changed during\nthe day. If there be clerks, the board of inspectors may direct a clerk,\nwho is not otherwise engaged, to perform any duty of an inspector of the\nsame party, except to vote upon a question to be decided by such board.\nWhere an oath is required or permitted by this article at any election,\nany inspector may administer it. Where ballot scanners, ballot marking\ndevices, privacy booths, ballot boxes or other secure storage containers\nare used, clerks or inspectors shall attend such ballot scanners, ballot\nmarking devices, privacy booths, boxes or containers.\n  2. The exterior of any ballot scanner, ballot marking device and\nprivacy booth and every part of the polling place shall be in plain view\nof the election inspectors and watchers. The ballot scanners, ballot\nmarking devices, and privacy booths shall be placed at least four feet\nfrom the table used by the inspectors in charge of the poll ledger or\ncomputer generated registration list. The guard-rail shall be at least\nthree feet from the machine and the table used by the inspectors. The\nelection inspectors shall not themselves be, or allow any other person\nto be, in any position or near any position, that will permit one to see\nor ascertain how a voter votes, or how he or she has voted nor shall\nthey permit any other person to be less than three feet from the ballot\nscanner, ballot marking device, or privacy booth while occupied. The\nelection inspectors or clerks attending the ballot scanner, ballot\nmarking device, or privacy booth shall regularly inspect the face of the\nballot scanner, ballot marking device, or the interior of the privacy\nbooth to see that the ballot scanner, ballot marking device, or privacy\nbooth has not been damaged or tampered with. During elections the door\nor other covering of the counter compartment of the machine shall not be\nunlocked or opened except by a member of the board of elections, a\nvoting machine custodian or any other person upon the specific\ninstructions of the board of elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>