<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-406"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-406"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-406"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-406/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-406/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-406/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-406/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_406">
        <num>8-406</num>
        <heading>Absentee ballots, delivery of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8-406. Absentee ballots, delivery of. 1. If the board shall find\nthat the applicant is a qualified voter of the election district\ncontaining his residence as stated in his statement and that his\nstatement is sufficient, it shall, as soon as practicable after it shall\nhave determined his right thereto, mail to him at an address designated\nby him, or deliver to him, or to any person designated for such purpose\nin writing by him, at the office of the board, such an absentee voter's\nballot or set of ballots and an envelope therefor. If the ballot or\nballots are to be sent outside of the United States to a country other\nthan Canada or Mexico, such ballot or ballots shall be sent by air mail.\nHowever, if an applicant who is eligible for an absentee ballot is a\nresident of a facility operated or licensed by, or under the\njurisdiction of, the department of mental hygiene, or a resident of a\nfacility defined as a nursing home or residential health care facility\npursuant to subdivisions two and three of section two thousand eight\nhundred one of the public health law, or a resident of a hospital or\nother facility operated by the Veteran's Administration of the United\nStates, such absentee ballot need not be so mailed or delivered to any\nsuch applicant but, may be delivered to the voter in the manner\nprescribed by section 8-407 of this chapter if such facility is located\nin the county or city in which such voter is eligible to vote.\n  2. When mailing an absentee ballot to a voter the board of elections\nshall provide a domestic postage paid return envelope. When providing an\nabsentee ballot to a voter in-person, the board of elections shall offer\nthe voter a domestic postage paid return envelope and provide one if\nrequested.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>