<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-10-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-404"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_404">
        <num>8-404</num>
        <heading>Absentee voting; hospitalized veterans, special provisions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_404__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any voter who is duly registered and whose registration records\nare marked "Hospitalized Veteran" or "Hospitalized Veteran's Relative"\nneed not thereafter make application for an absentee ballot. Sixty days\nbefore each election, the board of elections shall compile and send a\nlist to each veterans health administration hospital of all residents\nand patients of veterans health administration hospitals who appear by\nthe records of such board to be "hospitalized veterans" entitled to\nreceive absentee ballots at each such hospital pursuant to the\nprovisions of this section. Each veterans health administration hospital\nshall no later than fifteen days following the receipt of such list,\nreturn it with notations made thereon showing whether the resident or\npatient continues to be confined therein or has been discharged\ntherefrom. Upon the receipt of such returned list from each veterans\nhealth administration hospital with the proper notations showing that a\n"hospitalized veteran" continues to be confined in such hospital, the\nboard of elections, by mail addressed to such "hospitalized veteran" at\nhis or her last known hospital address and by mail addressed to such\n"hospitalized veteran's relative" at his or her last known address shall\nsend an absentee ballot for the ensuing election to such "hospitalized\nveteran" and such "hospitalized veteran's relative" an absentee ballot\nin the same manner as provided in this section for a qualified voter\nentitled to an absentee ballot because of permanent disability. The\nboard shall record on the back of his or her registration poll record in\nthe space reserved for his or her signature at such election, the fact\nthat such ballot has been sent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_404__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the returned list from a veterans' administration hospital\ncontains a notation showing that a "hospitalized veteran" is no longer a\nresident or patient at the veterans health administration hospital where\nhe or she is recorded as staying, or if such letter containing an\nabsentee voter's ballot for a "hospitalized veteran" or a "hospitalized\nveteran's relative" is returned by the post office as undeliverable, the\nboard of elections shall ascertain whether the "hospitalized veteran" or\n"hospitalized veteran's relative" is residing at the address given on\nhis or her registration records as his or her permanent address. If he\nor she is residing there, the board shall not send him or her any\nfurther absentee ballots unless he or she applies therefor in the\nregular way. If he or she is not residing at the place of residence\ngiven on his or her registration records but the board ascertains that\nhe or she has been transferred to another veterans health administration\nhospital, the board shall cause a central board of registration to make\nthe necessary changes of temporary address on his or her registration\nrecords and shall continue sending him or her absentee ballots at the\nveterans health administration hospital where he or she is staying. If\nhe or she is not residing at the place of residence given on his or her\nregistration records and the board cannot ascertain that he or she has\nbeen transferred to another veterans health administration hospital, the\nboard shall cancel his or her registration. Whenever a registration is\ncancelled pursuant to this paragraph notice shall be mailed to the\nveteran or his or her relative at his or her permanent residence address\nand last temporary address.\n  2. The board of elections shall furnish to each party county chairman\nin such county a list of the names and residence addresses of the\nhospitalized veterans and hospitalized veterans' relatives to whom\nabsentee ballots have been sent.\n  3. Such ballots ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>