<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-410"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-410"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-03-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-410"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_410">
        <num>8-410</num>
        <heading>Absentee voting; method of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8-410. Absentee voting; method of. The absentee voter shall mark an\nabsentee ballot as provided for paper ballots or ballots prepared for\ncounting by ballot counting machines. Such absentee voter shall make no\nmark or writing whatsoever upon the ballot, except as above prescribed,\nand shall see that it bears no such mark or writing. Such absentee voter\nshall make no mark or writing whatsoever on the outside of the ballot.\nIn cases where the express intent of the voter is unambiguous, any stray\nmarks or writing shall not be a basis for voiding a ballot. After\nmarking the ballot or ballots such absentee voter shall fold each such\nballot and enclose them in the envelope and seal the envelope. Such\nabsentee voter shall then take and subscribe the oath on the envelope,\nwith blanks properly filled in. The envelope, containing the ballot or\nballots, shall then be mailed or delivered to the board of elections of\nthe county or city of such absentee voter's residence or deposited in a\nballot drop box established by the board of elections of the county or\ncity of the voter's residence.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>