<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-412"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-412"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-03-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-412"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_412">
        <num>8-412</num>
        <heading>Absentee ballots; deadline for receipt, and delivery to polling place</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8-412. Absentee ballots; deadline for receipt, and delivery to\npolling place. 1. The board of elections shall cause all absentee\nballots received by it before the close of the polls on election day and\nall ballots contained in envelopes showing a cancellation mark of the\nUnited States postal service or a foreign country's postal service, or\nshowing a dated endorsement of receipt by another agency of the United\nStates government, with a date which is ascertained to be not later than\nthe day of the election and received by such board of elections not\nlater than seven days following the day of election to be cast and\ncounted except that the absentee ballot of a voter who requested such\nballot by letter, rather than application, shall not be counted unless a\nvalid application form, signed by such voter, is received by the board\nof elections with such ballot. For purposes of this section, any\nabsentee ballot received by the board of elections by mail that does not\nbear or display a dated postmark shall be presumed to have been timely\nmailed or delivered if such ballot bears a time stamp of the receiving\nboard of elections indicating receipt by such board on the day after the\nelection. For the purposes of this section, an absentee ballot shall be\ndeemed to be received by the board of elections before the close of the\npolls on election day if it is deposited in a ballot drop box before the\nclose of polls on election day. Ballots received in accordance with this\nsection shall be deemed timely and the failure of a board of elections\nto time stamp such ballots received in this manner on or before election\nday shall not prohibit the canvassing of such ballots. At the close of\nthe polls on election day, the board of elections shall close every\nballot drop box and collect ballots deposited in such ballot drop box.\n  2. Absentee ballots received by the board of elections shall be\nretained at the board of elections and cast and canvassed pursuant to\nthe provisions of section 9-209 of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>