<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-510"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-510"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-510"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-510/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-510/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-510/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-510/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_510">
        <num>8-510</num>
        <heading>Challenge report; completion of and procedure after</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8-510. Challenge report; completion of and procedure after. 1.\nImmediately after the close of the polls the board of inspectors of\nelection shall verify the entries which it has made on the challenge\nreport or in the spaces provided in the computer generated registration\nlist by comparing such entries with the information appearing on the\nregistration poll records of the affected voters or the information\nappearing in the spaces provided in the computer generated registration\nlist. If it has made no entries in section two, three or four of such\nreport it shall write across or note in such section the words "No\nchallenges", "No assistance" or "None", as the case may be, as directed\nin this chapter.\n  2. After completing such report the inspectors shall sign a\ncertificate in the spaces provided by the county board of elections for\nsuch report.\n  3. The inspectors shall place such completed report, and each court\norder, if any, directing that a person be permitted to vote, in the\nsecure container provided by the county board of elections for such\nledger of registration records or computer generated registration lists\nand then shall close and seal each ledger of registration records or\ncomputer generated registration lists, lock such ledger in the carrying\ncase furnished for that purpose and enclose the keys in a sealed package\nor seal such list in the envelope provided for that purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>