<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-604"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_604">
        <num>8-604</num>
        <heading>Registration during early voting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8-604. Registration during early voting. 1. In addition to other\nmethods of voter registration provided under this chapter, a person who\nis not registered to vote in the state but is otherwise qualified to\nregister to vote and to cast a ballot may register to vote and enroll in\na political party at an early voting polling location, provided such\nregistration is in accordance with the voter registration deadline set\nforth in subdivision three of section 5-210 of this chapter.\n  2. A qualified person who is not registered to vote in the state who\nappears at an early voting polling place shall be offered the\nopportunity to register to vote and enroll in a political party and\nshall be given an affidavit ballot, provided such registration is in\naccordance with the voter registration deadline set forth in subdivision\nthree of section 5-210 of this chapter.\n  3. If such registration is deemed effective, the board of elections\nshall add the person's voter registration information to the statewide\nelectronic voter file and include the corresponding affidavit ballot in\nthe official canvass, if otherwise valid.\n  4. The board of elections shall conduct the receipt and handling of\neach voter registration and corresponding ballot in a manner that\nprotects the secrecy of the ballot and allows the elections official to\nprocess the registration and include the corresponding ballot in the\nofficial canvass, if otherwise valid.\n  5. The board of elections shall advise a person completing such voter\nregistration of the procedures for determining the validity of such\nvoter registration.\n  6. The state board of elections shall promulgate rules and regulations\nto implement this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>