<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-702"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-702"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-702"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_702">
        <num>8-702</num>
        <heading>Early voting by mail; review of application by board of elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8-702. Early voting by mail; review of application by board of\nelections. 1. Upon receipt of an application to vote early by mail the\nboard of elections shall determine whether the applicant is a registered\nvoter of the county or city at the address listed in the application and\nis eligible to vote in the election or elections for which the\napplication is filed. An application to vote early by mail filed or\nreceived simultaneously with or on the same day as a valid registration\napplication from the applicant shall be considered valid.\n  2. If the board of elections determines that the applicant is not a\nregistered voter of the county or city at the address listed in the\napplication pursuant to subdivision one of this section or the applicant\nis not eligible to vote in all of the elections for which the\napplication is filed, the board of elections shall immediately notify\nthe applicant of the rejection of the application to vote early by mail\nand provide the reason for such rejection.\n  3. In the case of a primary election, the board of elections shall\ndeliver only the ballot of the party in which the records of the board\nof elections show the applicant to be enrolled. In the event a primary\nelection is uncontested in the applicant's election district for all\noffices or positions except the party position of member of the ward,\ntown, city or county committee, no ballot shall be delivered to such\napplicant for such election; and the applicant shall be advised why they\nare not being sent a ballot.\n  4. The board shall keep a record of applications to vote early by mail\nas they are received, showing the names and residences of the\napplicants, and their party enrollment in the case of primary elections,\nand, as soon as practicable shall, when requested, give to the chairman\nof each political party or independent body in the county, and shall\nmake available for inspection to any other registered voter upon\nrequest, a complete list of all applicants to whom early mail ballots\nhave been delivered or mailed, containing their names and places of\nresidence as they appear on the registration record, including the\nelection district and ward, if any, and in the city of New York and the\ncounty of Nassau, the assembly district, and their party enrollment in\nthe case of primary elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>