<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-710"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-710"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-03-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-710"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-710/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-710/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-710/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-8-710/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_710">
        <num>8-710</num>
        <heading>Early mail ballots; deadline for receipt, and delivery to polling place</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8-710. Early mail ballots; deadline for receipt, and delivery to\npolling place. 1. The board of elections shall cause all early mail\nballots received by it before the close of the polls on election day and\nall ballots contained in envelopes showing a cancellation mark of the\nUnited States postal service or a foreign country's postal service, or\nshowing a dated endorsement of receipt by another agency of the United\nStates government, with a date which is ascertained to be not later than\nthe day of the election and received by such board of elections not\nlater than seven days following the day of election to be cast and\ncounted. For purposes of this section, any early mail ballot received by\nthe board of elections by mail that does not bear or display a dated\npostmark shall be presumed to have been timely mailed or delivered if\nsuch ballot bears a time stamp of the receiving board of elections\nindicating receipt by such board on the day after the election. For the\npurposes of this section, an early mail ballot shall be deemed to be\nreceived by the board of elections before the close of the polls on\nelection day if it is deposited in a ballot drop box before the close of\npolls on election day. Ballots received in accordance with this section\nshall be deemed timely and the failure of a board of elections to time\nstamp such ballots received in this manner on or before election day\nshall not prohibit the canvassing of such ballots. At the close of the\npolls on election day, the board of elections shall close every ballot\ndrop box and collect ballots deposited in such ballot drop box.\n  2. Early mail ballots received by the board of elections shall be\nretained at the board of elections and cast and canvassed pursuant to\nthe provisions of section 9-209 of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>