<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-112"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-112"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-11-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-112"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_112">
        <num>9-112</num>
        <heading>Canvass ballots; validity of ballot</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_112__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>does any act extrinsic to the ballot such as\nenclosing any paper or other article in the folded ballot or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_112__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>defaces\nor tears the ballot except that a ballot card which is in perforated\nsections shall not be void because it has been separated into sections\nor</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_112__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>makes any erasure thereon or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_112__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>makes any mark thereon other\nthan a cross X mark or a check V mark in a voting square, or filling in\nthe voting square, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_112__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>writes, other than in the space provided, a\nname for the purpose of voting; except that an erasure or a mark other\nthan a valid mark made in a voting square shall not make the ballot\nvoid, but shall render it blank as to the office, party position or\nballot proposal in connection with which it is made. No ballot shall be\ndeclared void or partially blank because a mark thereon is irregular in\nform. The term "voting square" shall include the voting space provided\nfor a voter to mark his or her vote for a candidate or ballot proposal.\n  2. A cross X mark or a check V mark, made by the voter, in a voting\nsquare at the left of a candidate's name, or the voter's filling in such\nvoting square, shall be counted as a vote for such candidate.\n  3. A vote shall be counted for a person whose name is written in under\nthe title of an office or party position only if such name is written by\nthe voter upon the ballot in the proper space provided therefor and only\nif such name is not printed under the title of such office or position.\nA voting mark before or after such written in name shall not invalidate\nthe vote.\n  4. If, in the case of a candidate whose name appears on the ballot\nmore than once for the same office, the voter shall make a cross X mark\nor a check V mark in each of two or more voting squares before the\ncandidate's name, or fill in two or more such voting squares only the\nfirst vote shall be counted for such candidate. If such vote was cast\nfor the office of governor, such vote shall not be recorded in the tally\nsheet or returns in a separate place on the tally sheet as a vote not\nfor any particular party or independent body.\n  5. If a voter makes a cross X mark or a check V mark in a voting\nsquare following the word "Yes" or the word "No", before a ballot\nproposal, or fills in such square, such mark shall be counted in the\naffirmative or negative, as so indicated.\n  6. If the voter marks more names than there are persons to be elected\no...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>