<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-116"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-116"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-116"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_116">
        <num>9-116</num>
        <heading>Tallying ballots; generally</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-116. Tallying ballots; generally. 1. As each vote for any office\nor position, or upon any ballot proposal, is announced, a clerk, or, if\nthere be no clerks, an inspector, under the scrutiny of a clerk or\ninspector of opposite political party immediately shall tally it in ink,\nwith a downward stroke from right to left upon the official tally sheet.\nEach such clerk or inspector, as he or she tallies a vote, shall\nannounce clearly the name of the person for whom he or she tallies it,\nor that he or she tallies the vote blank or void as the case may be, or,\nin the case of a ballot proposal, that he or she tallies the vote "yes"\nor "no". When the name of a person voted for is not printed on the tally\nsheet, such clerks or inspectors shall write it in full thereon in ink\nin the place provided therefor.\n  2. When all the votes upon the same office, position or ballot\nproposal shall have been canvassed the tally thereof shall be verified\nby adding together all the votes tallied thereupon. Whenever the total\nnumber of votes tallied (including blank and void votes) for any office\nor party position, divided by the number of persons to be nominated or\nelected thereto, or tallied for any ballot proposal, does not exactly\nequal the number of ballots cast (including blank and void ballots), a\nrecanvass must be made immediately in order to correct the error.\n  In applying this section to a primary election the term "ballots"\nmeans the ballots of the party whose tallied votes for an office or\nparty position are counted as above provided. Upon a recanvass the\nclerks or inspectors must keep the tally in ink from left to right\nacross the previous tally marks.\n  3. When the errors if any have been corrected such clerks or\ninspectors shall indicate the last tally opposite each name by forthwith\ndrawing in ink a long horizontal line immediately after the last tally\nmark opposite such name. Such tally sheets having thus been prepared,\nverified and closed, such clerks or inspectors shall sign their initials\non each sheet, in any blank space thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>