<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-114"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-114"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-11-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-114"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_114">
        <num>9-114</num>
        <heading>Counting ballots; objections to</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-114. Counting ballots; objections to. 1. If objection be made to\nthe counting of any ballot or as to any section of any such ballot, the\nboard of inspectors shall forthwith and before canvassing any other\nballot or section thereof, rule upon the objection. If the objection be\ncontinued after this ruling, the chair or an inspector under the\nscrutiny of an inspector of the opposite party shall write in ink upon\nthe back of the ballot a memorandum of the ruling and objection. The\nmemorandum of the ruling shall be in the words "Counted void", or\n"Counted blank", or "Counted for (naming the candidate or candidates or\nthe presidential ticket)", or, in the case of a ballot proposal "Counted\nfor Proposal No.......," or "Counted against Proposal No........", as\nthe case may be. The memorandum of the objection shall be in the words\n"Objected to", followed by a brief statement of the nature of the\nobjection, the name and address of the challenger and the signature of\nthe chair or inspector.\n  2. Any ballot to which objection is not taken but which is wholly\nblank or is void shall be indorsed in ink by the chair of the board of\ninspectors or an inspector under the scrutiny of an inspector of the\nopposite party with the words "Wholly blank" or "Void", as the case may\nbe, and signed by the chair or inspector.\n  3. When all the ballots of any one kind shall have been canvassed, the\ninspectors shall ascertain the total number of all such ballots and the\nnumber of ballots to which any objection was taken and shall enter such\nnumbers in the place provided therefor in the inspectors' returns of\nsuch canvass.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>