<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-110"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_110">
        <num>9-110</num>
        <heading>Canvass; election day paper ballots that have not been scanned; method of</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-110. Canvass; election day paper ballots that have not been\nscanned; method of. 1. Election day paper ballots that have not been\nscanned because a ballot scanner was not available or because the ballot\nhas been abandoned by a voter at the ballot scanner shall be canvassed\nas follows: a bipartisan team of inspectors shall cast such ballots on a\nballot scanner, if one is available, at the close of the polls before\nthe tabulated results tape is printed. If a ballot does not scan because\nof an overvote or blank ballot warning on the ballot scanner screen, the\ninspectors shall cause the ballot scanner to eject such ballot to be\nhand counted pursuant to subdivision two of this section.\n  2. Election day paper ballots that cannot be scanned, as provided in\nsubdivision one of section 9-102 of this title as applicable and\nsubdivision one of this section shall be canvassed as follows: The\ninspectors shall unfold each ballot of the kind then to be canvassed and\nshall place all such ballots upon the table in one pile face down. The\nchair shall take up each ballot in order, turn it face up and announce\nloudly and distinctly the vote registered on each section, in the order\nof the sections upon the ballot, or that the ballot is void or the\nsection blank, as the case may be. If more than one person is to be\nelected to the same office or party position the chair, if the ballot is\nvoid or the ballot or section is wholly blank, shall announce as many\nvoid or blank votes as there are persons to be elected to the office or\nparty position. On a primary ballot a "section," as the term is used\nabove, shall mean the space occupied by the title of an office or party\nposition, names of candidates therefor and the voting squares therewith.\nThe canvass of each ballot must be completed before the next ballot is\ntaken up. When the tallies of the votes of all such ballots are proven,\nand the results announced, the inspectors shall affix tally sheets to or\nrecord the results from same on the return of canvass.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require or permit\nabsentee or affidavit ballots to be canvassed at the poll site on\nelection day. Such ballots shall be canvassed pursuant to section 9-209\nof this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>