<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-124"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-124"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-124"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_124">
        <num>9-124</num>
        <heading>Returns of canvass, procedure after</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_124__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of\nsection 9-102 of this title, and any early mail, absentee, military,\nspecial federal, or special presidential ballots which may have been\ndelivered to the poll site during election day, and securely lock and\nseal such boxes or containers.  Notwithstanding the preceding sentence,\nsuch portable memory device from each ballot scanner with the\ncorresponding results tape may be enclosed in a sealed container and\ntransported prior to and separately from other materials referenced in\nthis section for the purpose of using such device to provide an\nunofficial tally of results as required by section 9-126 of this title.\n  2. Each box, envelope, or container containing the ballots and stubs,\nif any, and all items described in subdivision one of this section shall\nbe deposited by an inspector designated for that purpose with the\nofficer or board from whom or which the board of inspectors received it.\nIn the city of New York, every such box, envelope, or container shall be\ndelivered at the polling place to police or peace officers designated by\nthe police commissioner of such city, who shall deposit them with the\nboard of elections.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_124__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except in the city of New York, the registration poll records\nor computer generated registration lists, the returns of canvass with\nresults tapes and tally sheets, if any, annexed, the voted ballots,\nstubs, opened packages of unused ballots and ballot envelopes, any early\nmail, absentee, military, special federal, or special presidential\nballots which may have been delivered to the poll site during election\nday, the challenge report records, keys and the package of protested and\nvoid ballots shall be filed with the board of elections.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_124__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Records and supplies to be filed with a city, town or village\nclerk shall be so filed or delivered immediately after the completion of\nthe returns of the canvass, by an inspector designated by the board of\ninspectors. Returns, papers and registration poll records or computer\ngenerated registration lists to be filed with the board of elections\nshall be so filed by the chairman of the board of inspectors within\ntwenty-four hours after the completion of such returns. The person\nreceiving such returns in the board of elections shall give to the\nperson delivering the returns a receipt stating therein the date and\nhour of delivery, the name of the person making the delivery, and to\nwhom said returns were delivered and shall keep a duplicate of said\nreceipt on file in the office of the board of elections.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_124__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the city of New York, the board of inspectors shall deliver to\npolice or peace officers designated by the police commissioner of such\ncity, at the polling place the registration poll records or computer\ngenerated registration lists, challenge report, records, keys, other\nelection supplies, including two copies of the returns of the canvass\nand any early mail, absentee, military, special federal, or special\npresidential ballots which may have been delivered to the poll site\nduring election day, voted ballots, stubs, open packages of unused\nballots and ballot envelopes. Such police or peace officers shall file\nthe returns, the package of void and protested ballots, if any, and the\nearly mail, absentee, military, special federal, or special presidential\nballots which may have been delivered to the poll site during election\nday; and emergency ballots, stubs and ballot envelopes, if any, within\ntwenty-four hours after the close of the polls, in the office of the\nboard of elections or its branch office within the borough, as the case\nmay be.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>