<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-120"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_120">
        <num>9-120</num>
        <heading>Returns of canvass; generally</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_120__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and the tally sheet</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_120__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for any office, party position or ballot\nproposal, if separate from such form, shall be securely attached by the\nchair or an inspector under the scrutiny of an inspector of the opposite\nparty to such form returns and it shall not be necessary to transcribe\ninformation provided by such results tapes onto such form. Results\ntape</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_120__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or a tally sheet</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_120__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, when so annexed, or forming part of the\nsame paper as the return, shall be treated as part of the return. The\ninspectors, and clerks, if any, shall subscribe in ink the certificate\nat the end of the set of returns. Each set of returns shall be securely\nsealed in an envelope properly endorsed on the outside by the\ninspectors. At an election at which voting machines are not used, the\nballot boxes, if any, supplied by the board of elections, may when\nsecurely locked be used instead of sealed envelopes.\n  2. The form for the return or returns of the canvass shall be printed\nin a format approved by the state board of elections. The form of such\nreturn of canvass shall provide for the total number of votes for each\ncandidate in each contest, or upon each ballot proposal, including the\ntotal number of unscanned voted ballots canvassed in accordance with\nsection 9-110 of this title.\n  3. In the event that there is more than one election district at a\npolling place, the board of elections may authorize the use of one or\nmore returns of canvass that consolidate the report of the number of\nvotes for each candidate, or upon each ballot proposal, for more than\none election district or more than one ballot scanner, provided that\nsuch consolidated returns of canvass have attached to them the results\ntape</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_120__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>produced by the ballot scanner</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_120__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that identify the number of\nvotes for each candidate, or upon each ballot proposal, within each such\nelection district and each such ballot scanner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>