<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-200"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_200">
        <num>9-200</num>
        <heading>Canvass of primary returns by board of elections; notices to delegates; certificates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-200. Canvass of primary returns by board of elections; notices to\ndelegates; certificates. 1. The board of elections shall canvass the\nreturns of primary elections filed with it. It shall canvass first the\nvotes of the delegates and alternates to judicial district conventions\nand complete such canvass at the earliest time possible. It shall\ncomplete the canvass otherwise within thirteen days from the day upon\nwhich the primary election is held. Upon the completion of the canvass\nthe board shall make and file in its office tabulated statements, signed\nby the members of such board or a majority thereof, of the number of\nvotes cast for all the candidates for nomination to each public office\nor for election to each party position, and the number of votes cast for\neach such candidate. The candidate receiving the highest number of votes\nfor nomination for a public office or for election to a party position\nvoted for wholly within the political unit for which such board is\nacting, shall be the nominee of his party for such office or elected to\nsuch party position and the board, if requested by a candidate elected\nto a party position, shall furnish to him a certificate of election.\n  2. The board forthwith upon the completion of the canvass for members\nof a state committee and delegates and alternates to a national, state\nor judicial district convention, shall transmit to the state board of\nelections a certificate stating the name and residence of each member of\na state committee and delegate and alternate elected from a district\nwholly within the jurisdiction of such board, except that, in respect to\na judicial district convention in the first, second, eleventh, twelfth\nand thirteenth judicial districts, the board of elections, instead of\ntransmitting such certificate, shall compile the roll of the convention\nand transmit it to the chairman or secretary of the committee which, by\nparty rules, is empowered to fix the time and place of the convention.\nThe board of elections shall send by mail to each delegate and alternate\nelected a notice of his election. The certificate or roll of the\nconvention shall list the delegates and alternates elected at a primary\nin the order of the votes received by each delegate or alternate, with\nthe delegate or alternate receiving the highest number of votes listed\nfirst. Tie votes shall be indicated in a manner prescribed by the state\nboard of elections. If there shall have been no contested election for\nalternates, the names of the alternates shall appear on the certificate\nor roll in the order in which their names appeared on the petition which\ndesignated them.\n  3. The board forthwith, upon the completion of the canvass, shall file\nwith the state board of elections a certified copy of its tabulated\nstatement of the votes cast for each nomination or party position in a\ndistrict extending beyond the political unit for which the board is\nacting.\n  4. The state board of elections, upon the request of the chairman of\nthe state committee of any political party, shall furnish to him a list\nof the duly elected members of the state committee of such party.\n  5. There shall be included in the official compilation of the canvass\nof the returns, the names of the persons who shall have been nominated\nfor public office or elected to party position without balloting, and in\neach such case the word "uncontested" shall be placed in such\ncompilation wherever the vote cast for such a candidate is required to\nbe stated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>