<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-06-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-202"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_202">
        <num>9-202</num>
        <heading>Canvass of primary returns by state board of elections; convention rolls</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-202. Canvass of primary returns by state board of elections;\nconvention rolls. The state board of elections upon receipt by it from\nboards of elections of the tabulated statements of votes at a primary\nelection required to be filed with it shall proceed forthwith to canvass\nsuch statements. Upon the completion of the canvass it shall make,\ncertify and file in its office tabulated statements of the number of\nvotes cast for all the candidates for nomination to each public office\nor for election to each party position, and the number of votes cast for\neach such candidate. The candidate receiving the highest number of votes\nshall be the nominee of his party for such office or shall be elected to\nsuch party position, as the case may be, and the board, if requested,\nshall furnish to the elected candidates a certificate of election. From\nsuch certified statements of the votes for delegates and alternates\nelected to a state or judicial district convention of any party, other\nthan a judicial district convention in the first, second, eleventh,\ntwelfth and thirteenth judicial districts, the state board shall\nforthwith compile the roll of each such convention in duplicate and\ntransmit it, if for a state convention, to the chairman and secretary of\nthe state committee of the party, and if for a judicial district\nconvention, to the chairman and secretary of the committee which, by\nparty rules, is empowered to fix the time and place of the convention.\nThe roll of the convention shall list the candidates elected at a\nprimary in the order of the votes received by each candidate together\nwith the number of votes received by each such candidate. If there shall\nhave been no contested election for alternates, the names of the\nalternates shall appear on the roll in the order in which their names\nappear on the petition which designated them. The state board of\nelections shall transmit copies of the certified statements of the votes\nfor delegates and alternates to a national convention of a party to the\nchairman and secretary of the state committee of such party.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>