<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-206"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_206">
        <num>9-206</num>
        <heading>Canvass of election district returns of general and special elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-206. Canvass of election district returns of general and special\nelections. The canvassing board shall canvass the votes cast within the\ncounty for state, county, city and town offices; also the vote cast on\nany ballot proposal.  The canvass by the county board of canvassers\nrelating to the offices of president and vice president of the United\nStates, governor, lieutenant-governor, state comptroller,\nattorney-general, United States senator, member of the house of\nrepresentatives, member of the state senate, member of the assembly and\nany ballot proposal shall show in each election district the total\nnumber of persons voting at such election, the number of votes cast for\neach candidate, the number of unrecorded or blank votes for each of the\nabove-mentioned offices and each ballot proposal. Write-in votes cast\nfor president or vice president for persons who were not certified by\nthe state board of elections as write-in candidates for such offices\nshall not be canvassed for such candidates but such votes shall be\ncanvassed as void votes. If, during the canvass, there shall clearly\nappear to be any omission or clerical mistake in the return for any\ndistrict filed with the board of elections, the canvassing board may\nsummon the election officers before the board, and such officers shall\nmeet forthwith and make any necessary correction, in order that their\ncanvass may be correctly stated, but they shall not alter any decision\ntheretofore made by them.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>