<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-212"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-212"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-212"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_212">
        <num>9-212</num>
        <heading>Determinations by county canvassing boards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-212. Determinations by county canvassing boards. 1. The canvassing\nboard shall determine each person elected by the greatest number of\nvotes to each county office, and each person elected by the greatest\nnumber of votes to each city, town or village office of a city, town or\nvillage of which it is the board of canvassers. The canvassing board\nshall also determine whether any ballot proposal submitted only to the\nvoters of the county, or only to the voters of a city, town or village\nof which it is the board of canvassers, as the case may be, has by the\ngreater number of votes been adopted or rejected.\n  2. All such determinations shall be in writing and signed by the\nmembers of the canvassing board or a majority of them and filed and\nrecorded in the office of the board of elections. Except in the city of\nNew York and in the counties of Nassau, Orange and Westchester, the\nboard of elections shall cause a copy of such determinations, and of the\nstatements filed in its office upon which such determinations were\nbased, to be published once in each of the newspapers designated to\npublish election notices and the official canvass. The statement of\ncanvass to be published, however, shall not give the vote by election\ndistricts but shall contain only the total vote for a person, or the\ntotal vote for and the total vote against a ballot proposal, cast within\nthe county, or within the portion thereof, if any, in which an office is\nfilled or ballot proposal is decided by the voters if the canvass of the\nvote thereon devolves upon the county board of canvassers. Such totals\nshall be expressed in arabic numerals.\n  3. The board of elections shall prepare and forthwith transmit to each\nperson determined by the canvassing board to have been elected a\ncertified statement, naming the office to which such canvassing board\nhas declared him elected.\n  4. The appropriate state or local election official shall establish a\nfree access system (such as a toll-free telephone number or an internet\nwebsite) that any individual who casts an affidavit ballot may access to\ndiscover whether the vote of that individual was counted, and, if the\nvote was not counted, the reason that the vote was not counted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>