<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-218"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-218"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-218"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_218">
        <num>9-218</num>
        <heading>Proceedings by boards of canvassers to carry into effect a court order</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-218. Proceedings by boards of canvassers to carry into effect a\ncourt order. 1. Upon the re-convening of the state board of canvassers\nor any county board of canvassers, or of the board of elections of the\ncity of New York as a county or city board of canvassers, by order of a\ncourt of competent jurisdiction, for the purpose of correcting an error\nor of performing a duty imposed by law or by an order of the court\ngranted pursuant to law, the meeting for that purpose shall be deemed a\ncontinuance of its regular session, and any new or corrected statement,\ndetermination or certificate which is made to give effect to the order\nshall stand in lieu of the original statement, determination or\ncertificate.\n  2. When a new or corrected statement or certificate, to give effect to\nan order of the court, shall vary from the original statement or\ncertificate respecting the votes cast for an office for which the state\nboard of canvassers is required to canvass statements made by county\nboards, the board of elections forthwith shall transmit certified copies\nof the new or corrected statement or certificates to the state board of\nelections. The state board of canvassers shall meet within five days\nafter such a certified copy has been received by the state board of\nelections.  From such certified copy, such board shall make a new\nstatement as to the votes for such office cast in the state or political\nsubdivision in which such office is filled, and shall determine and\ndeclare what person or persons whose votes are affected by such new or\ncorrected statement have been, by the greatest number of votes, duly\nelected to the office or offices. The state board of canvassers and the\nstate board of elections shall, respectively, have the same powers and\nduties in respect to new or corrected statements that they have in\nrespect to original statements.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>