<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-210"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_210">
        <num>9-210</num>
        <heading>Statements of canvass by canvassing boards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-210. Statements of canvass by canvassing boards. Upon the\ncompletion of the canvass the canvassing board shall make statements\nthereof, showing separately the result for each office and ballot\nproposal. Each such statement shall set forth, in words written out at\nlength, all votes cast for all candidates for each office; the name of\neach candidate; the number of votes so cast for each, and, in the case\nof a candidate who was nominated by two or more parties or independent\nbodies, the number, separately stated, of votes cast for him as the\ncandidate of each party or independent body by which he was nominated;\nand all votes so cast upon any ballot proposal, and all the votes so\ncast in favor of and against the same respectively. Such statements\nshall show the total number of unrecorded or blank votes and the total\nnumber of votes cast for each office and each ballot proposal.\n  Such statements shall be certified as correct over the signatures of\nthe members of the board, or a majority of them, and such statements\ntogether with any tabulation sheets showing the vote by election\ndistricts from which such statements were made, shall be filed in the\noffice of the board of elections. The separate statement relating to\nelectors of president and vice-president shall be so filed immediately\nupon the making, signing and certification thereof. To facilitate its\nwork, the board of elections may cause copies of such tabulation sheets\nto be printed in pamphlet form.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>