<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-214"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-214"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-214"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_214">
        <num>9-214</num>
        <heading>Transmission of statements of canvassing boards to state board of elections and secretary of state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-214. Transmission of statements of canvassing boards to state\nboard of elections and secretary of state. The board of elections shall\ntransmit by mail or cause to be delivered personally to the state board\nof elections, a certified copy of the statement of the canvassing board\nrelating to the offices of electors of president and vice-president of\nthe United States, United States senator, representatives in congress\nand state offices, including members of the state senate and assembly,\nand to the votes cast on any ballot proposal submitted to all the voters\nof the state, within twenty-five days after the election. If any\ncertified copy shall not be received by the state board on or before the\ntwenty-fifth day following a general election, or a special election, it\nshall dispatch a special messenger to obtain such certified copy, and\nthe board of elections, immediately upon demand of such messenger at its\noffice, shall make and deliver a certified copy to such messenger who\nshall deliver it forthwith to the state board.\n  The board of elections shall transmit to the secretary of state within\ntwenty-five days after a general election, and within twenty days after\na special election, a list of the names and residences of all persons\ndetermined by the canvassing board to be elected to any county office.\n  The board of elections shall transmit to the state board, on or before\nthe tenth day of December following an election for governor, a\ncertified tabulated statement, by election districts, of the official\ncanvass of the votes cast for candidates for governor, to include, in\nthe case of a candidate who was nominated by two or more parties or\nindependent bodies, a separate statement of the number of votes cast for\nhim as the candidate of each party or independent body by which he was\nnominated and if the county contains more than one assembly district or\nparts of more than one assembly district, a statement of the number of\nvotes cast for governor by assembly district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>