<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ELN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-216"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-216"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-216"/>
          <FRBRname value="ELN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/eln/section-9-216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_216">
        <num>9-216</num>
        <heading>Canvass of statements of general and special elections by state board of canvassers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-216. Canvass of statements of general and special elections by\nstate board of canvassers. 1. The state board of elections shall be the\nstate board of canvassers. The records of the state board of canvassers\nshall be kept in the custody of the state board of elections, which\nshall assign a deputy or other assistant to act as the clerk of said\nboard of canvassers.\n  2. The state board of canvassers shall canvass the certified copies of\nthe statements of the county board of canvassers of each county. They\nshall canvass first the statements, if any, for the offices of president\nand vice-president and next the statements, if any, for the office of\nmember of the state senate, and next the statements, if any, for the\noffice of member of the state assembly.  Three members of the board\nshall constitute a quorum. The state board of canvassers shall meet on\nor before the fifteenth day, or, in a year when electors of president\nand vice-president are chosen on or before the first Monday after the\nfirst Wednesday, of December next after each general election, and\nwithin forty days after each special election, to canvass such\nstatements. The board may adjourn from day to day, not exceeding a term\nof five days. If any member of the board shall dissent from a decision\nof the board or shall protest against any of the proceedings of the\nboard as irregular, he shall state such dissent or protest in a writing\nsigned by him setting forth his reasons and file it in the office of the\nstate board of elections.\n  3. Upon the completion of the canvass the board shall make separate\ntabulated statements, signed by the members of the board or a majority\nthereof, of the number of votes cast for all the candidates for each\noffice voted for, the number of votes cast for each of such candidates,\nthe number of votes cast in each county for each of them and if the\nvoters of any one district of the state voted for any such candidate,\nthe name and number of such district, the determination of the board as\nto the persons elected to each office, the number of votes cast upon\neach ballot proposal, the number of votes cast in favor of and against\neach respectively, and the determination of the board as to whether it\nwas adopted or rejected.\n  4. Such tabulated statements shall be filed and recorded in the office\nof the state board of elections. Thereupon, the state board of elections\nshall transmit a certified copy of each such statement of votes cast for\ncandidates for any office to the person shown thereby to have been\nelected to such office.  The state board of elections shall prepare a\ngeneral certificate under the seal of the state and attested by the\nmembers of the state board of elections, addressed to the house of\nrepresentatives of the United States, of the due election of all persons\nchosen at that election as representatives of this state in congress,\nand shall transmit the same to the house of representatives. If any\nperson so chosen at such election shall have been elected to fill a\nvacancy in the office of representative in congress, the statement of\nthe state board of elections shall so specify.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>