<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-108"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-108"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="108"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-108/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-108/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_108">
        <num>108</num>
        <heading>Payments into fund; returns; recoupment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_108__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three\nthousand four hundred twenty of the insurance law relating to every\npolicy providing comprehensive personal liability insurance on a one,\ntwo, three or four family owner-occupied dwelling.\n  4. The superintendent shall adopt a recoupment rate which shall enable\neach carrier to recoup over a reasonable length of time a sum reasonably\ncalculated to recover the payments by the carrier under this section by\nway of a surcharge on premiums charged for insurance policies to which\nthis section applies. Amounts recouped shall not be considered taxable\nfor the purposes of article thirty-three of the tax law.\n  5. The amount of any surcharge on premiums pursuant to subdivison two\nof this section shall be separately stated on either a billing or policy\ndeclaration sent to an insured. The superintendent shall determine the\nrate of the surcharge and the collection period and these shall be\nmandatory for all carriers. Carriers who collect surcharges in excess of\npayments made pursuant to this section shall remit the excess to the\nsuperintendent within one hundred twenty days after the end of the\ncollection period determined by the superintendent. The excess shall\nfirst be applied to reimburse, on an equitable basis, those carriers who\nare unable to collect surcharges equal to their paid assessments, and\nany excess thereafter shall be retained by the fund to reduce future\nassessments.\n  6. The statement of the amount of surcharge required to be provided by\nsubdivision five of this section shall include a description of, and\npurpose for, the New York Workers' Compensation Security Fund, as\nfollows:\n  "Companies writing workers' compensation insurance business in New\nYork are required to participate in the New York Workers' Compensation\nSecurity Fund. If a company becomes insolvent, the security fund settles\nunpaid claims and assesses each insurance company for its fair share.\n  New York law requires all companies to surcharge policies t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>