<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="109-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_109_E">
        <num>109-E</num>
        <heading>Rights and duties of superintendent of financial services as administrator of the fund</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 109-e. Rights and duties of superintendent of financial services as\nadministrator of the fund. The superintendent of financial services may\ndesignate or appoint a duly authorized representative or representatives\nto appear and defend an insured against a liability claim under the\nemployer's liability portion of the standard New York workers'\ncompensation and employer's liability insurance policy, and to appear\nand defend before the board any or all claims for compensation or\nbenefits against an employer insured by an insolvent carrier or against\nsuch insolvent carrier. The superintendent of financial services shall\nhave, as of the date of the insolvency of any carrier, only all the\nrights and duties which the insurance carrier would have had with\nrespect to awards made or claims for compensation or benefits filed or\npending, or pending liability claims, if it had not become insolvent.\nFor the purposes of this article the superintendent shall have power to\nemploy such counsel, clerks and assistants as may by him be deemed\nnecessary, and to give each of such persons such powers to assist him as\nhe may consider wise.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>