<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="109-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-109-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_109_B">
        <num>109-B</num>
        <heading>Custody and investment of fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_109_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the\nsuperintendent of financial services shall annually no later than\nNovember first in each year, submit to the director of the budget a\nrequest for an appropriation of sixty-seven million dollars. The\ngovernor shall include such amount in a budget bill for the next state\nfiscal year. The state comptroller shall encumber the amount so\nappropriated before the end of the fiscal year for which any such\nappropriation is made. If for any fiscal year commencing on or after\nApril first, nineteen hundred eighty-three, the governor fails to submit\na budget bill containing an appropriation in the amount requested by the\nsuperintendent of financial services or the legislature fails to\nappropriate the amount in a budget bill submitted by the governor for\nsuch fiscal year, the amount appropriated for and encumbered during the\npreceding fiscal year shall be payable forthwith to the fund on the\nfirst day of July of such year in the manner prescribed by law,\nprovided, however, that such amount shall not exceed the amount of\nmoneys transferred to the general fund from the fund pursuant to the\nprovisions of chapter fifty-five of the laws of nineteen hundred\neighty-two.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It is hereby found and declared that any appropriation made as\nprovided for in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall be deemed an\nasset of the fund, and that any transfer of moneys from such fund to the\ngeneral fund in accordance with the provisions of chapter fifty-five of\nthe laws of nineteen hundred eighty-two is deemed a proper and prudent\nlegal undertaking for any state officer with the responsibility for the\ncustody or the investment of the assets of the fund, notwithstanding any\nother provision of law to the contrary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>