<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11">
        <num>11</num>
        <heading>Alternative remedy</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>securing the\npayment of workers' compensation in accordance with article six-F of the\nexecutive law to black car operators, as defined in such article, whose\ninjury arose out of and in the course of providing services for a\ncentral dispatch facility, as defined in such article, that is a\nregistered member of such fund, and (ii) any statutory penalty resulting\nfrom the failure to secure such payment. The liability under this\nchapter of a central dispatch facility, as defined in article six-F of\nthe executive law, that is a registered member of the New York black car\noperators' injury compensation fund, inc. that shall be limited to\nremaining a registered member in good standing of such fund and any\nstatutory penalty, including loss of immunity provided by this section,\nresulting from the failure to become or remain a registered member in\ngood standing of such fund, except, however, that such central dispatch\nfacility shall be subject to the provisions of section one hundred\nthirty-one of this chapter and shall be liable for any payments for\nwhich it may become responsible pursuant to such section or pursuant to\nsection fourteen-a of this article.\n  The liability under this chapter of the New York independent livery\ndriver benefit fund, inc. shall be limited to:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>securing the payment\nof workers' compensation coverage to cover those matters required by\narticle six-G of the executive law for independent livery drivers, as\ndefined in such article, whose injury arose out of and in the course of\nproviding covered services for a livery base, as defined in such\narticle, that is a registered member of such fund, and (ii) any\nstatutory penalty resulting from the failure to secure such payment.\n  2. Determination by the board shall not be given collateral estoppel\neffect in any other action or proceeding arising out of the same\noccurrence, other than the determination of the existence of an employer\nemployee relationship.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>