<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-121-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-121-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="121-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-121-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-121-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-121-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-121-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_121_A">
        <num>121-A</num>
        <heading>Proof of dependency in foreign countries</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 121-a. Proof of dependency in foreign countries. In cases involving\nthe dependency of noncitizens residing in foreign countries, transcripts\nof birth or marriage certificates, also documents and affidavits,\ncertified by a local official or local magistrate and authenticated as\nto such official or magistrate by the secretary of state or other\nofficial having charge of foreign affairs, or a United States consul, in\nsaid foreign country, may be received in evidence, but in all such cases\nproof of present existence and of dependency may be made by the personal\nappearance of each and all persons claiming relationship to or\ndependence upon a deceased worker under the provisions of sections\nsixteen and seventeen of this chapter, before a diplomatic or consular\nofficer of the United States, and statements made to or evidence\npresented before such diplomatic or consular officer under oath may be\nreceived in evidence in whole or in part by the board upon any such\nclaim. Questions regarding admissibility and adequacy of evidence\narising in connection with proceedings before the consul shall be\ndetermined by the board. The board may by rule prescribe the conditions\nunder which proofs other than personal appearance before a diplomatic or\nconsular officer of the United States may be accepted as proof of the\nfacts of existence, relationship and dependency.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>