<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-125"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-125"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="125"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_125">
        <num>125</num>
        <heading>Job discrimination prohibited based on prior receipt of benefits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 125. Job discrimination prohibited based on prior receipt of\nbenefits.  1. It shall be unlawful for any employer to inquire into, or\nto consider for the purpose of assessing fitness or capability for\nemployment, whether a job applicant has filed for or received benefits\nunder this chapter, or to discriminate against a job applicant with\nregard to employment on the basis of that claimant having filed for or\nreceived benefits under this chapter, or because the claimant is an\ninjured veteran. An individual aggrieved under this subdivision may\ninitiate proceedings in a court of competent jurisdiction seeking\ndamages, including reasonable attorney fees, for violation of this\nsubdivision.\n  2. An employer who violates the provisions of subdivision one of this\nsection shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction shall be\npunished, except as in this chapter or in the penal law otherwise\nprovided, by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars, and subject\nto the debarment provisions of section one hundred forty-one-b of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>