<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_E">
        <num>13-E</num>
        <heading>Revocation of licenses of compensation medical bureaus and laboratories</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 13-e. Revocation of licenses of compensation medical bureaus and\nlaboratories. The chairman may revoke the license of any compensation\nmedical bureau or laboratory upon a finding certified to him by the\nmedical society of the county in which such bureau or laboratory is\nlocated, or by a board designated by such medical society or otherwise,\nas provided under section thirteen-b, or by the medical appeals unit,\nthat such bureau or laboratory has been guilty of professional or other\nmisconduct, or of violation of the provisions of this chapter, or that\nthe personnel of such bureau is not properly qualified under this\nchapter, or that the equipment of such bureau or laboratory is\ninadequate for the proper rendering of medical care.\n  The medical appeals unit may review the determination of such medical\nsociety or board, and on application of the compensation medical bureau\nor laboratory accused must do so, and may reopen the matter and receive\nfurther evidence. The decision and recommendation of the medical appeals\nunit shall be advisory to the chairman, and shall not be binding or\nconclusive upon him.\n  The medical appeals unit shall prescribe the rules of procedure\ngoverning the investigation, hearing and determination of all charges of\nprofessional or other misconduct under this section.\n  Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting in any respect\nthe power or duty of the chairman to investigate instances of\nmisconduct, or violations of the provisions of this chapter, or\nviolations of rules promulgated by the chairman under the provisions of\nthis chapter, or failure to submit full and truthful medical reports\ndirectly to the chairman within the time limits provided under\nsubdivision four of section thirteen-a of this chapter, either before or\nafter investigation or hearing by a medical society or board, or review\nby the medical appeals unit as herein provided, and to temporarily\nsuspend the license of any laboratory or medical bureau, or after a\nhearing to revoke the same.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>