<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_F">
        <num>13-F</num>
        <heading>Payment of medical fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 13-f. Payment of medical fees. (1) Fees for medical services shall\nbe payable only to a physician or other qualified person permitted by\nsections thirteen-b, thirteen-k, thirteen-l and thirteen-m of this\nchapter or other authorized provider of health care under the education\nlaw or the public health law permitted to render medical care or\ntreatment under this chapter, or to the agent, executor or administrator\nof the estate of such physician or such other qualified person.  Except\nas provided in section thirteen-d of this chapter, no provider of health\ncare rendering medical care or treatment to a compensation claimant,\nshall collect or receive a fee from such claimant within this state, but\nshall have recourse for payment of services rendered only to the\nemployer under the provisions of this chapter. Any compensation claimant\nwho pays a fee to a provider of health care for medical care or\ntreatment under this chapter shall have a cause of action against such\nprovider of health care for the recovery of the money paid, which cause\nof action may be assigned to the chair in trust for the assigning\nclaimant. All such assignments shall run to the chair. The chair may sue\nthe physician, or other authorized provider of health care as herein\ndescribed on the assigned cause of action with the benefits and subject\nto the provisions of existing law applying to such actions by the\nclaimant himself or herself. Hospitals shall not be entitled to receive\nthe remuneration paid to physicians on their staff for medical and\nsurgical services.\n  (2) Whenever his attendance at a hearing is required, the physician of\nthe injured employee shall be entitled to receive a fee from the\nemployer, or carrier, in an amount to be fixed by the board in addition\nto any fee payable under section eight thousand one of the civil\npractice law and rules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>