<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-13-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_N">
        <num>13-N</num>
        <heading>Mandatory registration of entities which derive income from independent medical examinations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 13-n. Mandatory registration of entities which derive income from\nindependent medical examinations. 1. Any entity which derives income\nfrom independent medical examinations performed in accordance with\nsubdivision four of section thirteen-a, subdivision three of section\nthirteen-k, subdivision three of section thirteen-1 and subdivision four\nof section thirteen-m of this article, whether by employing or\ncontracting with independent examiners to conduct such independent\nmedical examinations or by acting as a referral service or otherwise\nfacilitating such examinations, shall register with the chair by filing\na statement of registration containing such information prescribed by\nthe chair in regulation. A fee may be imposed in accordance with\nregulations promulgated by the chair. Any such fees collected shall be\nused for the purpose of administering this section.\n  2. The chair shall assign a registration number to the entity upon\nregistration. If an entity operates under more than one name, or in more\nthan one location, the chair may assign a series of registration numbers\nwhich would differentiate each such sub-entity. In order to qualify as\nadmissible medical evidence, for purposes of adjudicating any claim\nunder this chapter, any report submitted to the board by an independent\nmedical examiner who is employed by, or has contracted with, an entity\nas described in subdivision one of this section for the purpose of\nperforming independent medical examinations, must include the\nregistration number of such entity.\n  3. The chair, upon finding that an entity that derives income from\nindependent medical examinations has materially altered an independent\nmedical examination report, or caused such a report to be materially\naltered, may revoke the registration of such entity, impose a penalty\nnot exceeding ten thousand dollars and refer the matter to the attorney\ngeneral for prosecution.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>