<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-134"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-134"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="134"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-134/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-134/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-134/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-134/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_134">
        <num>134</num>
        <heading>Workplace safety and loss prevention program; certification of safety and loss management specialists</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_134__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>receive and review\napplications from applicants for certification as safety and loss\nmanagement specialists; and (ii) certify persons as safety and loss\nmanagement specialists; and (iii) revoke certification of safety and\nloss management specialists for just cause.\n  9. The commissioner of labor shall monitor all safety incentive plans\nimplemented by employers. As part of this responsibility, the board\nshall insure that employee representatives are involved in the\ndevelopment of such plans through meetings and discussions with the\nrespective certified safety and loss management specialist.\n  10. The commissioner of labor, in consultation with the superintendent\nof financial services, shall promulgate rules and regulations for the\ncertification of safety and loss management specialists. Such rules and\nregulations shall include provisions that outline the minimum\nqualifications for safety and loss management specialists, procedures\nfor certification, causes for revocation or suspension of certification\nand appropriate administrative and judicial review procedures, and\nviolations and penalties for misuse of certification by certified safety\nand loss management specialists.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>