<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-14-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-14-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-04-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-14-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-14-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-14-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-14-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_A">
        <num>14-A</num>
        <heading>Double compensation and death benefits when minors illegally employed</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-a. Double compensation and death benefits when minors illegally\nemployed. 1. Compensation, death benefits, and awards to the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance in accordance with subdivision nine\nof section fifteen and section twenty-five-a, as provided in this\narticle, shall be double the amount otherwise payable if the injured\nemployee at the time of the accident is a minor employed, permitted or\nsuffered to work in violation of any provision of the labor law or in\nviolation of any rule heretofore or hereafter adopted by the board of\nstandards and appeals pursuant to subdivision four of section one\nhundred thirty-three of said law.\n  An employer who knowingly permits or suffers a newspaper carrier to\nwork in violation of section thirty-two hundred twenty-eight of the\neducation law, shall be liable for the increased awards provided by this\nsection.\n  2. The employer alone and not the insurance carrier shall be liable\nfor the increased compensation, increased death benefits, or awards to\nthe commissioner of taxation and finance provided for by this section.\nAny provision in an insurance policy undertaking to relieve an employer\nfrom such increased liability shall be void.\n  3. A person over eighteen years of age may apply for a certificate of\nage to the superintendent of schools or to an employment certificating\nofficer. Upon such application a certificate of age, signed by the\nofficer issuing it and containing the name, date of birth, address and\nsignature of the applicant shall be issued to him if he furnishes\nevidence that he is over eighteen years of age such as is required for\nthe issuance of an employment certificate. Such a certificate of age\nshall be conclusive evidence for an employer that the person has reached\nthe age certified to therein, and the provisions of this section shall\nnot apply to the employer of such person while the person is engaged in\nemployment lawful for the age and sex as certified to in the certificate\nof age.\n  4. With respect to a jockey, apprentice jockey or exercise person\nlicensed under article two or four of the racing, pari-mutuel wagering\nand breeding law, and at the election of the New York Jockey Injury\nCompensation Fund, Inc., with the approval of the New York state gaming\ncommission, an employee of a licensed trainer or owner, who, pursuant to\nsection two of this chapter, is an employee of all owners and trainers\nlicensed or required to be licensed under article two or four of the\nracing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law and The New York Jockey\nInjury Compensation Fund, Inc., the owner or trainer for whom such\njockey, apprentice jockey, exercise person or, if approved by the New\nYork state gaming commission, employee of a licensed trainer or owner\nwas performing services at the time of the accident shall be solely\nresponsible for the double payments described in subdivision one of this\nsection, to the extent that such payments exceed any amounts otherwise\npayable with respect to such jockey, apprentice jockey, exercise person\nor, if approved by the New York state gaming commission, employee of a\nlicensed trainer or owner under any other section of this chapter, and\nthe New York Jockey Injury Compensation Fund, Inc. shall have no\nresponsibility for such excess payments, unless there shall be a failure\nof the responsible owner or trainer to pay such award within the time\nprovided under this chapter. In the event of such failure to pay and the\nboard requires the fund to pay the award on behalf of such owner or\ntrainer who has been found to have violated this section, the fund shall\nbe entitled to an award against such owner or trainer for the amount so\npaid which shall be collected in the same manner as an award of\ncompensation.\n  5. With respect to a black car operator who, pursuant to section two\nof this chapter, is an employee of the New York black car operators'\ninjury compensation fund, inc., the central dispatch facility for which\nthe black car operator was performing services at the time of the\naccident shall be solely responsible for the double payments described\nin subdivision one of this section, to the extent that such payments\nexceed any amounts otherwise payable with respect to such black car\noperator under any other section of this chapter, and the New York black\ncar operators' injury compensation fund, inc. shall have no\nresponsibility for such excess payments, unless there shall be a failure\nof the responsible central dispatch facility to pay such award within\nthe time provided under this chapter. In the event of such failure to\npay, the board may require the fund to pay the award on behalf of the\ncentral dispatch facility that is found to have violated this section.\nIn such a case, the fund shall be entitled to an award against the\ncentral dispatch facility for the excess amount paid by the fund, which\nshall be collected in the same manner as an award of compensation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>