<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-140"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-140"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-02-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="140"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-140/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-140/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-140/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-140/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_140">
        <num>140</num>
        <heading>Workers' compensation board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 140. Workers' compensation board. The workers' compensation board in\nthe department of labor is hereby continued. Such board shall consist of\nthirteen members, at least four of whom shall be attorneys and\ncounsellors-at-law duly admitted to practice in this state. The members\nof the board shall be appointed by the governor, by and with the advice\nand consent of the senate. The members of the board in office, together\nwith the additional members and the members appointed to fill vacancies,\nif any, at the time this section takes effect, shall continue,\nnotwithstanding the appointment of any of the members for a term\nexpiring on a different date, to hold office for terms to be assigned by\nthe governor by and with the advice and consent of the senate; two such\nterms to expire on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty; two to\nexpire on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-one; two to\nexpire on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-two; two to\nexpire on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-three; two to\nexpire on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-four; two to\nexpire on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-five; and one to\nexpire on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-six. The members\nnext appointed, except to fill a vacancy created otherwise than by\nexpiration of term, shall be appointed for terms of seven years. The\ngovernor shall designate one of the members of the board as chairman and\nanother as vice-chairman.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>