<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-148"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-148"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="148"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-148/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-148/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-148/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-148/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_148">
        <num>148</num>
        <heading>Salaries and expenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 148. Salaries and expenses. 1. The chairman and members of the board\nshall devote their entire time to the duties of their office and shall\nnot practice in their respective professions or callings. The reasonable\nand necessary expenses of the board and the reasonable and necessary\ntraveling and other expenses of the chairman and members of the board,\nthe secretary and other officers and employees of the board, while\nactually engaged in the performance of their duties, outside of the city\nof Albany, or if any such officer or employee be in charge of or\nactually employed at an office of the board outside of the city of\nAlbany, the reasonable and necessary traveling and other expenses\noutside of the place in which such office is located, shall be paid from\nthe state treasury upon the audit and warrant of the comptroller, upon\nvouchers approved by the chairman or vice-chairman or secretary of the\nboard.\n  2. For the purpose of extending the benefits of workmen's compensation\nand improving administration and expediting the adjudication of claims,\nthe chairman is hereby authorized, within the limits of the\nappropriation available therefor, to initiate studies and surveys, to\nobserve operations in other states, to conduct research, and to make\ninvestigations in the entire field of workmen's compensation, within and\nwithout the state of New York. The chairman is also hereby authorized to\naccept a gift, grant, or contribution of funds to be used in his\ndiscretion to carry out the purposes of this subdivision and shall in\nthe annual report of the board set forth the progress of the same.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>