<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-09-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15">
        <num>15</num>
        <heading>Schedule in case of disability</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>five hundred twenty-five weeks in cases in which the loss of\nwage-earning capacity is greater than ninety-five percent; (ii) five\nhundred weeks in cases in which the loss of wage-earning capacity is\ngreater than ninety percent but not more than ninety-five percent; (iii)\nfour hundred seventy-five weeks in cases in which the loss of\nwage-earning capacity is greater than eighty-five percent but not more\nthan ninety percent; (iv) four hundred fifty weeks in cases in which the\nloss of wage-earning capacity is greater than eighty percent but not\nmore than eighty-five percent;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>four hundred twenty-five weeks in\ncases in which the loss of wage-earning capacity is greater than\nseventy-five percent but not more than eighty percent; (vi) four hundred\nweeks in cases in which the loss of wage-earning capacity is greater\nthan seventy percent but not more than seventy-five percent; (vii) three\nhundred seventy-five weeks in cases in which the loss of wage-earning\ncapacity is greater than sixty percent but not more than seventy\npercent; (viii) three hundred fifty weeks in cases in which the loss of\nwage-earning capacity is greater than fifty percent but not more than\nsixty percent; (ix) three hundred weeks in cases in which the loss of\nwage-earning capacity is greater than forty percent but not more than\nfifty percent;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two hundred seventy-five weeks in cases in which the\nloss of wage-earning capacity is greater than thirty percent but not\nmore than forty percent; (xi) two hundred fifty weeks in cases in which\nthe loss of wage-earning capacity is greater than fifteen percent but\nnot more than thirty percent; and (xii) two hundred twenty-five weeks in\ncases in which the loss of wage-earning capacity is fifteen percent or\nless. For a claimant with a date of accident or disablement after the\neffective date of the chapter of the laws of two thousand seventeen that\namended this subdivision, where the carrier or employer has provided\ncompensation pursuant to subdivision five of this section beyond one\nhundred thirty weeks from the date of accident or disablement, all\nsubsequent weeks in which compensation was paid shall be considered to\nbe benefit weeks for purposes of this section, with the carrier or\nemployer receiving credit for all such subsequent weeks against the\namount of maximum benefit weeks when permanent partial disability under\nthis section is determined. In the event of payment for intermittent\ntemporary partial disability paid after one hundred thirty weeks from\nthe date of accident or disablement, such time shall be reduced to a\nnumber of weeks, for which the carrier will receive a credit against the\nmaximum benefit weeks. For a claimant with a date of accident or\ndisablement after the effective date of the chapter of the laws of two\nthousand seventeen that amended this subdivision, when permanency is at\nissue, and a claimant has submitted medical evidence that he or she is\nnot at maximum medical improvement, and the carrier has produced or has\nhad a reasonable opportunity to produce an independent medical\nexamination concerning maximum medical improvement, and the board has\ndetermined that the claimant is not yet at maximum medical improvement,\nthe carrier shall not receive a credit for benefit weeks prior to a\nfinding that the claimant has rea...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_x__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There will be a presumption that medical services shall continue\nnotwithstanding the completion of the time period for compensation set\nforth in this section and the burden of going forward and the burden of\nproof will lie with the carrier, self-insured employer or state\ninsurance fund in any application before the board to discontinue or\nsuspend such services. Medical services will continue during the\npendency of any such application and any appeals thereto.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_x__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board is directed to promulgate regulations that establish an\nindependent review and appeal by an outside agent or entity of the\nboard's choosing of any administrative law judge's determination to\ndiscontinue or suspend medical services before a final determination of\nthe board.\n  x. Impairment guidelines. The chair shall consult with representatives\nof labor, business, medical providers, insurance carriers, and\nself-insured employers regarding revisions to permanency impairment\nguidelines, including permitting review and comment by such\nrepresentatives' chosen medical advisors, and after consultation shall,\nin accordance with the state administrative procedure act, propose for\npublic comment revised permanency guidelines concerning medical\nevaluation of impairment and the determination of permanency as set\nforth in paragraphs a through v of this subdivision by September first,\ntwo thousand seventeen, with such guidelines to be adopted by the chair\nby January first, ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation\nfor permanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs,</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on\nor after January first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, shall not exceed\none hundred twenty-five dollars per week, that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after\nJuly first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, shall not exceed one hundred\neighty dollars per week, that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after January first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-nine, shall not exceed two hundred fifteen\ndollars per week, that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, nineteen\nhundred eighty-three, shall not exceed two hundred fifty-five dollars\nper week, that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, nineteen hundred\neighty-four, shall not exceed two hundred seventy-five dollars per week,\nthat occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, nineteen hundred eighty-five,\nshall not exceed three hundred dollars per week, that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred ninety, shall not exceed three\nhundred forty dollars per week; and in the case of temporary total\ndisability shall not be less than thirty dollars per week and in the\ncase of permanent total disability shall not be less than twenty dollars\nper week except that if the employee's wages at the time of injury are\nless than thirty or twenty dollars per week respectively, he or she\nshall receive his or her full weekly wages.  Compensation for permanent\nor temporary partial disability due to an accident or disablement\nresulting from an occupational disease that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, shall not exceed one\nhundred five dollars per week, that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-three, shall not exceed one hundred twenty-five\ndollars per week, that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, nineteen\nhundred eighty-four, shall not exceed one hundred thirty-five dollars\nper week, that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, nineteen hundred\neighty-five, shall not exceed one hundred fifty dollars per week, that\noccurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, nineteen hundred ninety, shall not\nexceed two hundred eighty dollars per week; nor be less than twenty\ndollars per week; except that if the employee's wages at the time of\ninjury are less than twenty dollars per week, he or she shall receive\nhis or her full weekly wages. In no event shall compensation when\ncombined with decreased earnings or earning capacity exceed the amount\nof wages which the employee was receiving at the time the injury\noccurred. Compensation for permanent or temporary partial disability, or\nfor permanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred ninety-one and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-two, shall not exceed three hundred fifty\ndollars per week;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, nineteen hundred\nninety-two, shall not exceed four hundred dollars per week; nor be less\nthan forty dollars per week except that if the employee's wages at the\ntime of injury are less than forty dollars per week, the employee shall\nreceive his or her full wages. Compensation for permanent or temporary\npartial disability, or for permanent or temporary total disability due\nto an accident or disablement resulting from an occupational disease\nthat occurs</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, two thousand seven shall not\nexceed five hundred dollars per week,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, two\nthousand eight shall not exceed five hundred fifty dollars per week,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\non or after July first, two thousand nine shall not exceed six hundred\ndollars per week, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>on or after July first, two thousand ten, and\non or after July first of each succeeding year, shall not exceed\ntwo-thirds of the New York state average weekly wage for the year in\nwhich it is reported. Compensation for permanent or temporary partial\ndisability, or for permanent or temporary total disability due to an\naccident or disablement resulting from an occupational disease that\noccurs on or after July first, two thousand seven shall not be less than\none hundred dollars per week except that if the employee's wages at the\ntime of injury are less than one hundred dollars per week, the employee\nshall receive his or her full wages.  Compensation for permanent or\ntemporary partial disability, or for permanent or temporary total\ndisability due to an accident or disablement resulting from an\noccupational disease that occurs on or after May first, two thousand\nthirteen shall not be less than one hundred fifty dollars per week\nexcept that if the employee's wages at the time o...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred seventy-four, and prior to July\nfirst, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, shall not exceed one hundred\ntwenty-five dollars per week nor be less than thirty dollars per week;\nexcept that if the employee's wages at the time of injury are less than\nthirty dollars per week, he shall receive his full weekly wages.\nCompensation for permanent total disability or for permanent or\ntemporary partial disability due to an accident or disablement resulting\nfrom an occupational disease that occurs on or after July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-four, and prior to January first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-eight, shall not exceed ninety-five dollars per week;\nnor be less than twenty dollars per week; except that if the employee's\nwages at the time of injury are less than twenty dollars per week, he\nshall receive his full weekly wages. In no event shall compensation when\ncombined with decreased earnings or earning capacity exceed the amount\nof wages which the employee was receiving at the time the injury\noccurred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred seventy and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-four, shall not exceed ninety-five dollars per\nweek nor be less than thirty dollars per week; except that if the\nemployee's wages at the time of injury are less than thirty dollars per\nweek, he shall receive his full weekly wages. Compensation for permanent\ntotal disability or for permanent or temporary partial disability due to\nan accident or disablement resulting from an occupational disease that\noccurs on or after July first, nineteen hundred seventy and prior to\nJuly first, nineteen hundred seventy-four, shall not exceed eighty\ndollars per week; nor be less than twenty dollars per week; except that\nif the employee's wages at the time of injury are less than twenty\ndollars per week, he shall receive his full weekly wages. In no event\nshall compensation when combined with decreased earnings or earning\ncapacity exceed the amount of wages which the employee was receiving at\nthe time the injury occurred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy, shall not exceed eighty-five dollars per week\nnor be less than thirty dollars per week; except that if the employee's\nwages at the time of injury are less than thirty dollars per week, he\nshall receive his full weekly wages. Compensation for permanent total\ndisability or for permanent or temporary partial disability due to an\naccident or disablement resulting from an occupational disease that\noccurs on or after July first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, and prior\nto July first, nineteen hundred seventy, shall not exceed seventy\ndollars per week; nor be less than twenty dollars per week; except that\nif the employee's wages at the time of injury are less than twenty\ndollars per week, he shall receive his full weekly wages. In no event\nshall compensation when combined with decreased earnings or earning\ncapacity exceed the amount of wages which the employee was receiving at\nthe time the injury occurred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for permanent or temporary partial disability, or for\npermanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred sixty-five, and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-eight, shall not exceed sixty dollars per week;\nnor be less than twenty dollars per week; except that if the employee's\nwages at the time of injury are less than twenty dollars per week, he\nshall receive his full weekly wages. In no event shall compensation when\ncombined with decreased earnings or earning capacity exceed the amount\nof wages which the employee was receiving at the time the injury\noccurred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for permanent or temporary partial disability, or for\npermanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred sixty-two and prior to July first\nnineteen hundred sixty-five, shall not exceed fifty-five dollars per\nweek; nor be less than twenty dollars per week; except that if the\nemployee's wages at the time of injury are less than twenty dollars per\nweek, he shall receive his full weekly wages. In no event shall\ncompensation when combined with decreased earnings or earning capacity\nexceed the amount of wages which the employee was receiving at the time\nthe injury occurred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for permanent or temporary partial disability, or for\npermanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred sixty and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-two, shall not exceed fifty dollars per week; nor\nbe less than twenty dollars per week, except that if the employee's\nwages at the time of injury are less than twenty dollars per week, he\nshall receive his full weekly wages. In no event shall compensation when\ncombined with decreased earnings or earning capacity exceed the amount\nof wages which the employee was receiving at the time the injury\noccurred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for permanent or temporary partial disability, or for\npermanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred fifty-eight and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred sixty, shall not exceed forty-five dollars per week;\nnor, except in cases of permanent total disability, be less than twenty\ndollars per week; except that if the employee's wages at the time of\ninjury are less than twenty dollars per week, he shall receive his full\nweekly wages; further provided, that in each case of permanent total\ndisability minimum compensation shall not be less than twenty dollars\nper week, except that where the employee's wages at the time of injury\nare less than twenty dollars per week he shall receive his full weekly\nwages. In no event shall compensation when combined with decreased\nearnings or earning capacity exceed the amount of wages which the\nemployee was receiving at the time the injury occurred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for permanent or temporary partial disability, or for\npermanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred fifty-four and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred fifty-eight, shall not exceed thirty-six dollars per\nweek; nor, except in cases of permanent total disability, be less than\ntwelve dollars per week; except that if the employee's wages at the time\nof injury are less than twelve dollars per week, he shall receive his\nfull weekly wages; further provided, that in each case of permanent\ntotal disability minimum compensation shall not be less than fifteen\ndollars per week, except that where the employee's wages at the time of\ninjury are less than fifteen dollars per week he shall receive his full\nweekly wages. In no event shall compensation when combined with\ndecreased earnings or earning capacity exceed the amount of wages which\nthe employee was receiving at the time the injury occurred.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation for permanent or temporary partial disability, or for\npermanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter July first, nineteen hundred forty-eight and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred fifty-four, shall not exceed thirty-two dollars per\nweek and compensation for permanent or temporary partial disability, or\nfor permanent or temporary total disability due to an accident or\ndisablement resulting from an occupational disease that occurs on or\nafter June first, nineteen hundred forty-six, and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred forty-eight, shall not exceed twenty-eight dollars per\nweek; nor, except in cases of permanent total disability, be less than\ntwelve dollars per week; except that if the employee's wages at the time\nof injury are less than twelve dollars per week, he shall receive his\nfull weekly wages; further provided, that in each case of permanent\ntotal disability minimum compensation shall not be less than fifteen\ndollars per week, except that where the employee's wages at the time of\ninjury are less than fifteen dollars per week, he shall receive his full\nweekly wages but in no event shall compensation when combined with\ndecreased earnings or earning capacity exceed the amount of wages which\nthe employee was receiving at the time the injury occurred; further\nprovided, that compensation may be in excess of twenty-five dollars but\nshall not exceed twenty-eight dollars per week for permanent or\ntemporary total disability due to an accident or disablement resulting\nfrom an occupational disease that occurred on or after June first,\nnineteen hundred forty-four, and prior to July first, nineteen hundred\nforty-eight, and in each case of temporary total disability minimum\ncompensation shall not be less than twelve dollars per week, except that\nwhere the employee's wages at the time of injury are less than twelve\ndollars per week, he sha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nDeclaration of policy and legislative intent. As a guide to the\ninterpretation and application of this subdivision, the policy and\nintent of this legislature is declared to be as follows:\n  First: That every person in this state who works for a living is\nentitled to reasonable opportunity to maintain his independence and\nself-respect through self-support even after he/she has been physically\nhandicapped by injury or disease;\n  Second: That any plan which will reasonably, equitably and practically\noperate to break down hindrances and remove obstacles to the employment\nof partially disabled persons who</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are honorably discharged from our\narmed forces, or (ii) have a qualifying condition, as defined in section\none of the veterans' services law, and received a discharge other than\nbad conduct or dishonorable from such service, or (iii) are discharged\nLGBT veterans, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law,\nand received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from\nsuch service, or any other physically handicapped persons, is of vital\nimportance to the state and its people and is of concern to this\nlegislature;\n  Third: That it is the considered judgment of this legislature that the\nsystem embodied in this subdivision, which makes a logical and equitable\nadjustment of the liability under the workers' compensation law which an\nemployer must assume in hiring employees, constitutes a practical and\nreasonable approach to a solution of the problem for the employment of\nphysically handicapped persons.\n  Moreover, because of the insidious nature of slowly developing\ndiseases such as silicosis and other dust diseases and because of the\nreluctance on the part of employers to employ persons previously exposed\nto silica or other harmful dust, means should also be provided whereby\nemployers will be encouraged to employ and to continue the employment of\nsuch persons, by apportioning liability fairly between the employer and\nindustry as a whole without at the same time removing any incentive for\nthe prevention of harmful dust diseases.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Definition. As used in this subdivision, "permanent physical\nimpairment" means any permanent condition due to previous accident or\ndisease or any congenital condition which is or is likely to be a\nhindrance or obstacle to employment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Permanent total disability after permanent partial disability.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, if\nan employee who has previously incurred permanent partial disability\nthrough the loss of one hand, one arm, one foot, one leg, or one eye,\nincurs permanent total disability through the loss of another member or\norgan, he/she shall be paid, in addition to the compensation for\npermanent partial disability provided in this section and after the\ncessation of the payments for the prescribed period of weeks special\nadditional compensation during the continuance of such total disability\nto the amount of sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of the average\nweekly wage earned by him/her at the time the total permanent disability\nwas incurred. If such employee shall establish an earning capacity by\nemployment he shall be paid during the period of such employment,\ninstead of the additional compensation above provided, two-thirds of the\ndifference between his average weekly wages at the time the total\ndisability was incurred and his wage earning capacity as determined by\nhis actual earnings in such employment, subject to the limitations in\nsubdivision six of this section. Such additional compensation, and\nexpense as in this subdivision provided, shall be paid out of the\nspecial disability fund and in the manner as hereinafter in this\nsubdivision provided.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If an employee of an employer who has secured the payment of\ncompensation as required under the provisions of section fifty of this\nchapter, who had a total or partial loss or loss of use of one hand, one\narm, one foot, one leg or one eye, or who has other permanent physical\nimpairment incurs a subsequent disability by accident arising out of and\nin the course of his employment or an occupational disease arising\ntherefrom, resulting in a permanent disability caused by both conditions\nthat is materially and substantially greater than that which would have\nresulted from the subsequent injury or occupational disease alone, the\nemployer or his insurance carrier shall in the first instance pay all\nawards of compensation and all medical expense provided by this chapter,\nbut such employer or his insurance carrier, except as specifically\nprovided in paragraph (ee) of this subdivision, shall be reimbursed from\nthe special disability fund created by this subdivision for all\ncompensation and medical benefits subsequent to those payable for the\nfirst one hundred four weeks of disability for claims where the date of\naccident or date of disablement occurred prior to August first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-four, and two hundred sixty weeks of disability for\nclaims where the date of accident or date of disablement occurred on or\nafter August first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, regardless of\nknowledge on the part of the employer as to the existence of such\npre-existing permanent physical impairment.\n  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this chapter, there may be\napportionment of liability for the special disability fund under this\nsubdivision within a single claim by disposition between the fund,\ncarriers, self-insurers or employers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the subsequent injury of such an employee resulting from an\naccident arising out of and in the course of his employment or an\noccupational disease resulting therefrom, as set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision, shall result in the death of the employee and it\nshall be determined that either the injury or death would not have\noccurred except for such pre-existing permanent physical impairment, the\nemployer or his insurance carrier shall in the first instance pay the\nfuneral expenses and the death benefits prescribed by this chapter, but\nhe or his insurance carrier, except as specifically provided in\nparagraph (ee) of this subdivision, shall be reimbursed from the special\ndisability fund created by this subdivision for all death benefits\npayable in excess of one hundred four weeks of disability for claims\nwhere the date of accident or date of disablement occurred prior to\nAugust first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, and two hundred sixty weeks\nof disability for claims where the date of accident or date of\ndisablement occurred on or after August first, nineteen hundred\nninety-four, regardless of knowledge on the part of the employer as to\nthe existence of such pre-existing permanent physical impairment.\n  (ee) If an employee of an employer who has secured the payment of\ncompensation as required under the provisions of section fifty of this\nchapter is disabled from silicosis or other dust disease, or in the\nevent of death, death was due to silicosis or other dust disease, and if\nsuch an employee has been subject to an injurious exposure in an\nemployment defined under paragraph twenty-nine of subdivision two of\nsection three of this chapter, the provisions of this subdivision shall\napply except as hereinafter stated; and it shall not be required that\nthe employee had, either at the time of hiring or during the employment,\nany previous physical condition or disability which may result in such\ndisability or death. In all such cases the employer or his insurance\ncarrier shall in the first instance pay all awards of compensation and\nall medical expense provided by this chapter; and in the event of death,\nthe employer or his insuranc...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision be reimbursed from the special disability fund created by\nthis subdivision for all compensation and medical benefits subsequent to\nthose payable for the first one hundred four weeks of disability for\nclaims where the date of accident or date of disablement occurred prior\nto August first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, and two hundred sixty\nweeks of disability for claims where the date of accident or date of\ndisablement occurred on or after August first, nineteen hundred\nninety-four, and, in the event of death, the employer or his insurance\ncarrier shall be reimbursed from the special disability fund created by\nthis subdivision for all death benefits payable in excess of one hundred\nfour weeks for claims where the date of accident or date of disablement\noccurred prior to August first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, and two\nhundred sixty weeks for claims where the date of accident or date of\ndisablement occurred on or after August first, nineteen hundred\nninety-four; provided, however, that when total disability or death\noccurred after July first, nineteen hundred forty-seven, and prior to\nJuly first, nineteen hundred seventy-four, the employer or his insurance\ncarrier shall be reimbursed from the special disability fund created by\nthis subdivision for all compensation and medical benefits including\nfuneral expenses and death benefits subsequent to those payable for the\nfirst two hundred sixty weeks of disability and death benefits combined;\nand further provided, however, that in the event of death due to\nsilicosis or other dust disease on or after July first, nineteen hundred\nforty-seven, of such an employee who shall have been totally disabled\nfrom silicosis or other dust disease prior to such date, the employer or\nhis insurance carrier shall be reimbursed from the special disability\nfund created by this subdivision for death benefits subsequent to those\npayable for the first one hundred four weeks.\n  The compensation o...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any award under this subdivision shall be made against the\nemployer or his or her insurance carrier, but if such employer or\ninsurance carrier be entitled to reimbursement as provided in this\nsubdivision, notice or claim of the right to such reimbursement shall be\nfiled with the board in writing prior to the final determination that\nthe resulting disability is permanent, but in no case more than one\nhundred four weeks after the date of disability or death or fifty-two\nweeks after the date that a claim for compensation is filed with the\nchair, whichever is later, or in the event of the reopening of a case\ntheretofore closed, no later than the determination of permanency upon\nsuch reopening. In no event shall such a notice of claim be filed beyond\nthe dates set forth in subparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision.\n  The employer or his or her insurance carrier shall in the first\ninstance make the payments of compensation and medical expenses provided\nby this subdivision. Whenever for any reason payments are not made by\nthe employer or his or her insurance carrier at any time after the\npayments have been made for the first one hundred four weeks for claims\nwhere the date of accident or date of disablement occurred prior to\nAugust first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, and two hundred sixty weeks\nfor claims where the date of accident or date of disablement occurred on\nor after August first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, the payments of\nsubsequent compensation and medical expenses shall be made out of the\nspecial disability fund by the commissioner of taxation and finance upon\nvouchers approved by the chair of the workers' compensation board. In\ncase any payments prior to the expiration of the first one hundred four\nweeks for claims where the date of accident or date of disablement\noccurred prior to August first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, and two\nhundred sixty weeks for claims where the date of accident or date of\ndisablement occurred on or after August first, nineteen hundred\nninety-four are not made by the employer or his or her insurance carrier\nby reason of the insolvency of such carrier, the payments until the\nexpiration of one hundred four weeks for claims where the date of\naccident or date of disablement occurred prior to August first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-four, and two hundred sixty weeks for claims where the\ndate of accident or date of disablement occurred on or after August\nfirst, nineteen hundred ninety-four shall be made out of the stock\nworkers' compensation security fund created by the provisions of section\none hundred seven of this chapter if the insolvent carrier be a stock\ncompany, or out of the mutual workers' compensation security fund\ncreated under the provisions of section one hundred nine-d of this\ncha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the making of a determination that an employer or insurance\ncarrier is entitled to reimbursement from the special disability fund in\nany case where the employer or insurance carrier has made payment into\nthe aggregate trust fund, as provided in section twenty-seven of this\nchapter, or where payment of compensation has been commuted into one or\nmore lump sum payments, the employer or insurance carrier shall be\nreimbursed forthwith for the sums paid in excess of those payable for\none hundred four weeks for claims where the date of accident or date of\ndisablement occurred prior to August first, nineteen hundred\nninety-four, two hundred sixty weeks for claims where the date of\naccident or date of disablement occurred on or after August first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-four or two hundred sixty weeks in a silicosis\nor other dust disease case as otherwise provided in paragraph (ee) of\nthis subdivision, exclusive of administrative and loading charges paid\npursuant to section twenty-seven, in accordance with the decision and\norder of the board. In all other cases such employer or insurance\ncarrier shall, periodically every six months from the decision and order\nof the board, be reimbursed from such special disability fund for all\ncompensation and medical expense in accordance with the provisions of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Special disability fund.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_h__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fund heretofore maintained and\nprovided for by and pursuant to former subdivision eight of this\nsection, is hereby continued and shall retain the liabilities heretofore\ncharged or chargeable thereto under the provisions of such former\nsubdivision eight of this section as it existed immediately prior to the\ntime this subdivision, as hereby added, takes effect, and the\nliabilities chargeable thereto under the provisions of former\nsubdivision eight-a of this section as added by chapter seven hundred\nforty-nine of the laws of nineteen hundred forty-four and repealed at\nthe same time this subdivision, as heretofore added, takes effect, and\npayments therefrom on account of such liabilities shall continue to be\nmade as provided herein. The said fund shall be known as the special\ndisability fund and shall be available only for the purposes stated in\nthis subdivision, and the assets thereof shall not at any time be\nappropriated or diverted to any other use or purpose.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_h__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A) No carrier or employer, or the state insurance fund, may file\na claim for reimbursement from the special disability fund, for an\ninjury or illness with a date of accident or date of disablement on or\nafter July first, two thousand seven. No carrier or employer, or the\nstate insurance fund, may file a claim for reimbursement from the\nspecial disability fund after July first, two thousand ten, and no\nwritten submissions or evidence in support of such a claim may be\nsubmitted after that date.\n  (B) All requests for reimbursement from the special disability fund\nwith a date of injury or date of disablement prior to July first, two\nthousand seven as to which the board has determined that the special\ndisability fund is liable must be submitted to the special disability\nfund by the later of</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one year after the expense has been paid, or\n(ii) one year from the effective date of this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Effective the first day of January, two thousand fourteen, and\nannually thereafter, the chair of the board shall collect from all\naffected employers (A) a sum equal to one hundred fifty per centum of\nthe total expected disbursements made from the special disability fund\nduring the year (not including any disbursements made on account of\nanticipated liabilities or waiver agreements funded by bond proceeds and\nrelated earnings), less the estimated amount of the net assets in such\nfund expected as of December thirty-first and (B) a sum sufficient to\ncover debt service, and associated costs (the "debt service assessment")\nto be paid during the calendar year by the dormitory authority, as\ncalculated in accordance with subparagraph four of this paragraph. Such\nassessments shall be included in the assessment rate established\npursuant to subdivision two of section one hundred fifty-one of this\nchapter. Such assessments shall be deposited with the commissioner of\ntaxation and fina...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The chair and the commissioner of taxation and finance are\nauthorized and directed to enter into a financing agreement with the\ndormitory authority, to be known as the "special disability fund\nfinancing agreement." Such agreement shall set forth the process for\ncalculating the annual debt service of the bonds issued by the dormitory\nauthority and any other associated costs. For purposes of this section,\n"associated costs" may include a coverage factor, reserve fund\nrequirements, all costs of any nature incurred by the dormitory\nauthority in connection with the special disability fund financing\nagreement or pursuant thereto, the operating costs of the waiver\nagreement management office, the costs of any independent audits\nundertaken under this section, and any other costs for the\nimplementation of this subparagraph and the issuance of bonds by the\ndormitory authority, including interest rate exchange payments, rebate\npayments, liquidity fees, credit provider fees, fiduciar...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner of taxation and finance is hereby authorized to\nreceive and credit to such special disability fund any sum or sums that\nmay at any time be contributed to the state by the United States of\nAmerica under any act of congress, or otherwise, to which the state may\nbe or become entitled by reason of any payments made out of such fund.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_15__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner of taxation and finance shall be the custodian of\nsaid fund and, unless otherwise provided for in the special disability\nfund financing agreement, shall invest any surplus or reserve moneys\nthereof in securities which constitute legal investments for savings\nbanks under the laws of this state and in interest bearing certificates\nof deposit of a bank or trust company located and authorized to do\nbusiness in this state or of a national bank located in this state\nsecured by a pledge of direct obligations of the United States or of the\nstate of New York in an amount equal to the amount of such certificates\nof deposit, and may sell any of the securities or certificates of\ndeposit in which such fund is invested if necessary for the proper\nadministration or in the best interest of such fund. Disbursements from\nsuch fund as provided by this subdivision shall be made by the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance upon vouchers signed by the chair\nof the board unless ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pledged assessment\nrevenue and securitization coverage, (ii) debt service maturities, (iii)\ninterest rate exchange or similar agreements, and (iv) financing and\nissuance costs.\n  The commissioner of taxation and finance may establish within the\nspecial disability fund such accounts and sub-accounts as he or she\ndeems useful for the operation of the fund, or as necessary to segregate\nmoneys within the fund, subject to the provisions of the financing\nagreement. The waiver agreement management office, as defined in section\nthirty-two of this article, shall make application to the chair on a\nquarterly basis for any administrative costs incurred by the office.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When an application for apportionment of compensation is made\nunder this subdivision, the chair of the workers' compensation board\nshall appoint an attorney to represent and defend such fund in such\nproceedings. Such attorney shall thereafter be given notice of all\nproceedings involving the rights or obligations of such fund. Such\nattorney may apply to the chair of the board for authority to hire such\nmedical and other experts and to defray the expense thereof and of such\nwitnesses as may be necessary to a proper defense of any claim, within\nan amount in the discretion of the chair and, if authorized, such amount\nshall be a charge against such special disability fund.\n  The provisions of this chapter with respect to procedure, except as\nmay be otherwise provided in this subdivision, and the right of appeal\nshall be preserved to the claimant and to the employer or his insurance\ncarrier and to such fund through its attorney as herein provided.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this subdivision, except as herein otherwise\nprovided, shall not be applicable to any case where the accident causing\nthe subsequent injury or death or the disablement or death from a\nsubsequent occupational disease shall have occurred prior to the time\nthis subdivision, as hereby added, takes effect, provided, however, that\nany rights that have accrued under former subdivision eight or eight-a\nof this section prior to the time this subdivision, as hereby added,\ntakes effect shall continue to inure to the benefit of any persons\naffected thereby as though such subdivisions had not been repealed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The additional compensation required to be paid by an employer in\nthe case of the injury of a minor illegally employed, in accordance with\nthe provisions of subdivisions one and two of section fourteen-a of this\nchapter, shall not be reimbursable under the provisions of this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_15__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this subdivision, when\nan employer or carrier shall have paid additional benefits to an\nemployee pursuant to subdivision six of section fourteen of this article\nas a result of the employee's increased average weekly wages from wages\nearned in concurrent employment, reimbursement for all such additional\nbenefits shall be made to the employer or carrier from the special\ndisability fund created by this subdivision. It shall not be required\nthat the employee had, either at the time of hiring or during the\nemployment, any previous physical condition or disability, nor shall it\nbe required that the employee's disability be permanent in nature.\nNotice of the right to reimbursement shall be filed with the board in\nwriting prior to the decision making an award, and reimbursement shall\nbe made periodically, every six months from the decision of the board.\n  9. Expenses for rehabilitating injured employees. An employee, who as\na result of injury is or may be expected to be totally or partially\nincapacitated for a remunerative occupation and who, under the direction\nof the state education department is being rendered fit to engage in a\nremunerative occupation, may receive additional compensation necessary\nfor his rehabilitation, not more than thirty dollars per week of which\nmay be expended for maintenance. Such expense and such of the\nadministrative expenses of the state education department as are\nproperly assignable to the expenses of rehabilitating employees entitled\nto compensation as a result of injuries under this chapter, shall be\npaid out of a special fund created in the following manner: The\nemployer, or if insured, his insurance carrier, shall pay into the\nvocational rehabilitation fund for every case of injury causing death,\nin which there are no persons entitled to compensation, the sum of five\nhundred dollars where such injury occurred prior to July first, nineteen\nhundred sixty-three and the ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>