<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-16"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-16"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-16/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-16/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-16/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-16/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16">
        <num>16</num>
        <heading>Death benefits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 16. Death benefits. If the injury causes death, the compensation\nshall be known as a death benefit and shall be payable in the amount and\nto or for the benefit of the persons following:\n  1. Funeral expenses. The chair shall prepare and establish a schedule\nfor the state or schedules limited to defined localities of maximum\ncharges and fees for such funeral expenses, to be determined in\naccordance with, and to be subject to change pursuant to, rules\npromulgated by the chair. Before preparing such schedule for the state\nor schedules for limited localities, the chair shall request the\npresident of the New York state funeral directors' association to submit\nto the chair a report on the amount of remuneration deemed by such\nassociation to be fair and adequate for the types of funeral services\nrendered under this chapter, but consideration shall also be given to\nthe views of other interested parties. The amounts payable by the\nemployer for such services shall be the actual fees and charges up to\nthe maximum established by such schedule. Provided, however, no such\nschedule of charges and fees shall apply where a firefighter dies from\ninjuries received in the line of duty as a direct result of firefighting\nor where a police officer dies from injuries received in the line of\nduty as a direct result of law enforcement activities, where such\nfuneral expenses are reasonable. If such funeral expenses shall have\nbeen paid by the claimants entitled to compensation under this section\nor by others, the funeral expenses awarded shall be made payable to such\nclaimants or others, otherwise they shall be made payable to the\nundertaker who shall have provided burial. Funeral expenses shall be\nawarded in case of all injuries causing death including cases in which\nthere are no persons entitled to other compensation under this chapter.\n  1-a. For the purpose of this section, (1) the term dependent blind or\nphysically disabled as used herein in relation to dependent children\nshall be deemed to mean totally blind or physically disabled children\nwhose disablement is total and permanent, (2) the term surviving spouse\nshall be deemed to mean the legal spouse but shall not include a spouse\nwho has abandoned the deceased, and (3) the term abandoned shall be\ndeemed to mean such an abandonment as would be sufficient under section\ntwo hundred of the domestic relations law to sustain a judgment of\nseparation on that ground.\n  1-b. If there be a surviving spouse and no child of the deceased under\nthe age of eighteen years and no child of any age dependent blind or\nphysically disabled, and the death occurs on or after July first,\nnineteen hundred forty-eight, and prior to January first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-eight, to such spouse forty per centum of the average\nwages of the deceased during widowhood or widowerhood with two years'\ncompensation in one sum, upon remarriage; and where the death occurred\nprior to July first, nineteen hundred forty-eight, to such wife (or\ndependent husband) thirty per centum of such wages during widowhood (or\ndependent widowerhood) with two years' compensation in one sum, upon\nremarriage.\n  1-c. If there be a surviving spouse and no child of the deceased under\nthe age of eighteen years or under the age of twenty-three years if\nenrolled and attending as a full time student in an accredited\neducational institution and such enrollment and full time attendance is\ncertified by such institution and no child of any age dependent blind or\nphysically disabled, and the death occurs on or after January first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-eight, to such spouse sixty-six and two-thirds\nper centum of the average wages of the deceased during widowhood or\nwidowerhood with two years' compensation, in one sum, upon remarriage.\nWhere the death occurs on or after January first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-eight, and the spouse is receiving the survivors insurance\nbenefits under the social security act, the death benefit payable under\nthis section shall be reduced in accordance with the provisions of table\nNo. 1 below by five per centum of the spouse's share of the survivor's\ninsurance benefits under the social security act for each ten dollars of\ndeceased's average weekly wage in excess of one hundred dollars provided\nthat in no case shall such reduction exceed fifty per centum of said\nspouse's share of the survivors insurance benefits under the social\nsecurity act.\n                               TABLE No. I\n             Offset provisions applicable in death benefits\n                 where there is a sole surviving spouse\nAVERAGE WEEKLY WAGE                               PERCENTAGE OF SPOUSE'S\n                                                      SHARE OF SURVIVORS\n                                                      INSURANCE BENEFITS\nover $100 up to and including $110 ................................... 5\nover $110 up to and including $120 .................................. 10\nover $120 up to and including $130 .................................. 15\nover $130 up to and including $140 .................................. 20\nover $140 up to and including $150 .................................. 25\nover $150 up to and including $160 .................................. 30\nover $160 up to and including $170 .................................. 35\nover $170 up to and including $180 .................................. 40\nover $180 up to and including $190 .................................. 45\nover $190 up to and including $200 .................................. 50\nover $200 ........................................................... 50\n  1-d. If there be a surviving spouse of an employee of a private\nvoluntary hospital killed in a World Trade Center rescue, who passed a\nphysical examination upon employment as a rescue worker that failed to\nreveal evidence of a condition that was the proximate cause of death,\nand no child of the deceased under the age of eighteen years, or under\nthe age of twenty-three years if enrolled and attending as a full-time\nstudent in an accredited educational institution and such enrollment and\nfull-time attendance is certified by such institution, and no child of\nany age dependent blind or physically disabled, to such spouse\nseventy-five per centum of the average wages of the deceased during\nwidowhood or widowerhood, with two years' compensation, in one sum, upon\nremarriage. Where such death occurs, and the spouse is receiving the\nsurvivors insurance benefits under the social security act, the death\nbenefit payable under this section shall be reduced in accordance with\nthe provisions of table No. I in subdivision one-c of this section by\nfive per centum of the spouse's share of the survivor's insurance\nbenefits under the social security act for each ten dollars of\ndeceased's average weekly wage in excess of one hundred dollars;\nprovided that in no case shall such reduction exceed fifty per centum of\nsuch spouse's share of the survivors insurance benefits under the social\nsecurity act.\n  2. If there be a surviving spouse and a surviving child or children of\nthe deceased under the age of eighteen years or a surviving child or\nchildren of any age dependent blind or physically disabled, and the\ndeath occurs on or after July first, nineteen hundred forty-eight, and\nprior to January first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, to such spouse\nthirty per centum of the average wages of the deceased during widowhood\nor widowerhood with two years' compensation in one sum, upon remarriage;\nand the additional amount of twenty per centum of such wages for each\nsuch child until the age of eighteen years or until the removal of the\ndependency of the blind or physically disabled child or children; in\ncase of the subsequent death or remarriage of such surviving spouse any\nsurviving child of the deceased employee, at the time under eighteen\nyears of age or dependent through mental or physical infirmity, shall\nhave his compensation increased to thirty per centum of such wages, and\nthe same shall be payable until he shall reach the age of eighteen years\nor until such dependent blind or physically disabled condition shall\nhave been removed; provided that the total amount payable shall in no\ncase exceed sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of such wages. Upon\nstatutory termination of compensation payments to all such children, the\ncompensation of the surviving spouse shall be increased to forty per\ncentum of such wages with two years' compensation, at such rate, in one\nsum, upon remarriage.\n  If there be a surviving wife (or dependent husband) and any of the\naforementioned surviving children, and the death occurred prior to July\nfirst, nineteen hundred forty-eight, to such wife (or dependent husband)\nthirty per centum of the average wages of the deceased during widowhood\n(or dependent widowerhood) with two years' compensation in one sum, upon\nremarriage; and the additional amount of ten per centum of such wages\nfor each such child until eighteen years of age or until the removal of\nthe dependency of the blind or physically disabled child or children; in\ncase of the subsequent death or remarriage of such surviving wife (or\ndependent husband) any surviving child of the deceased shall have his\ncompensation increased to fifteen per centum of such wages until he\nshall reach the age of eighteen years or until such dependent blind or\nphysically disabled condition shall have been removed; provided that the\ntotal amount payable shall in no case exceed sixty-six and two-thirds\nper centum of such wages.\n  The board may in its discretion require the appointment of a guardian\nfor the purpose of receiving the compensation of a minor child or a\ndependent blind or physically disabled child. In the absence of such a\nrequirement by the board the appointment of a guardian for such purposes\nshall not be necessary.\n  2-a. If there</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>