<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-168"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-168"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-09-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="168"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-168/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-168/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-168/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-168/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_168">
        <num>168</num>
        <heading>Additional period for filing certain claims</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 168. Additional period for filing certain claims. 1. A claim by a\nparticipant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup\noperations whose disablement occurred between September eleventh, two\nthousand three, and September eleventh, two thousand eight, shall not be\ndisallowed as barred by section eighteen or section twenty-eight of this\nchapter if such claim is filed on or before September eleven, two\nthousand ten. Any such claim by a participant in the World Trade Center\nrescue, recovery or cleanup operations whose disablement occurred\nbetween September eleventh, two thousand three, and September eleventh,\ntwo thousand eight, and was disallowed by section eighteen or\ntwenty-eight of this chapter shall be reconsidered by the board.\n  2. A claim by a participant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery\nor cleanup operations whose disablement occurred between September\ntwelfth, two thousand eight, and September eleventh, two thousand\ntwelve, shall not be disallowed as barred by section eighteen or section\ntwenty-eight of this chapter if such claim is filed on or before\nSeptember eleventh, two thousand fourteen. Any such claim by a\nparticipant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup\noperations whose disablement occurred between September eleventh, two\nthousand eight, and September eleventh, two thousand twelve, and was\ndisallowed by section eighteen or twenty-eight of this chapter shall be\nreconsidered by the board.\n  3. A claim by a participant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery\nor cleanup operations whose disablement occurred between September\neleventh, two thousand twelve, and September eleventh, two thousand\nfifteen, shall not be disallowed as barred by section eighteen or\nsection twenty-eight of this chapter if such claim is filed on or before\nSeptember eleventh, two thousand eighteen. Any such claim by a\nparticipant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup\noperations whose disablement occurred between September eleventh, two\nthousand twelve, and September eleventh, two thousand fifteen, and was\ndisallowed by section eighteen or twenty-eight of this chapter shall be\nreconsidered by the board.\n  4. A claim by a participant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery\nor cleanup operations whose disablement occurred between September\neleventh, two thousand fifteen, and September eleventh, two thousand\nseventeen, shall not be disallowed as barred by section eighteen or\nsection twenty-eight of this chapter if such claim is filed on or before\nSeptember eleventh, two thousand twenty-two. Any such claim by a\nparticipant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup\noperations whose disablement occurred between September eleventh, two\nthousand fifteen, and September eleventh, two thousand seventeen, and\nwas disallowed by section eighteen or twenty-eight of this chapter shall\nbe reconsidered by the board.\n  5. A claim by a participant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery\nor cleanup operations whose disablement occurred between September\neleventh, two thousand seventeen, and September eleventh, two thousand\ntwenty-one, shall not be disallowed as barred by section eighteen or\nsection twenty-eight of this chapter if such claim is filed on or before\nSeptember eleventh, two thousand twenty-six. Any such claim by a\nparticipant in the World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup\noperations whose disablement occurred between September eleventh, two\nthousand seventeen, and September eleventh, two thousand twenty-one, and\nwas disallowed by section eighteen or twenty-eight of this chapter shall\nbe reconsidered by the board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>