<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-18-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-18-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-04-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="18-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-18-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-18-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-18-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-18-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_18_A">
        <num>18-A</num>
        <heading>Notice: The New York Jockey Injury Compensation Fund, Inc</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 18-a. Notice: The New York Jockey Injury Compensation Fund, Inc.\nWherever in this chapter it shall be required that notice be given to an\nemployer, except for claims involving section fourteen-a of the workers'\ncompensation law such notice requirement shall be deemed satisfied by\ngiving notice to the New York Jockey Injury Compensation Fund, Inc., in\nconnection with an injury to a jockey, apprentice jockey or exercise\nperson licensed under article two or four of the racing, pari-mutuel\nwagering and breeding law, and at the election of the New York Jockey\nInjury Compensation Fund, Inc., with the approval of the New York state\ngaming commission, an employee of a licensed trainer or owner, who,\npursuant to section two of this chapter, is an employee of all owners\nand trainers licensed or required to be licensed under article two or\nfour of the racing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law and of the\nfund. In a claim involving section fourteen-a of the workers'\ncompensation law such required notice shall be given to the employing\nowner and/or trainer of the fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>