<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_A">
        <num>19-A</num>
        <heading>Physicians not to accept fees from carriers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 19-a. Physicians not to accept fees from carriers. No physician or\nsurgeon in the employ of the board for the purpose of making the\nexaminations required by section nineteen of this chapter, shall, during\nsuch employment, be employed by or accept or participate in any fee from\nany insurance company authorized to write workmen's compensation\ninsurance in this state or from any self-insurer, if such employment or\nfee relates to a workmen's compensation claim or otherwise except as\nherein provided. Any physician or surgeon so employed by the board who\nviolates the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor.\n  The foregoing provisions of this section limiting and restricting the\nemployment of physicians or surgeons in the employ of the board and\ntheir acceptance or participation in fees shall not be applicable to\nmedical treatment rendered to their patients who are or may be claimants\nunder article nine of this chapter, provided, however, that any such\nphysician or surgeon shall be disqualified from testifying as a witness\nin any proceeding before the board or its referees in connection with\nsuch claims.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>