<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-19-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_B">
        <num>19-B</num>
        <heading>Treatment by physicians in employ of board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 19-b. Treatment by physicians in employ of board. No doctor,\nphysician or surgeon in the employ of the board shall solicit or treat\nany claimant under this chapter, or own or operate any clinic, giving\nbaking and massage, physio-therapy, or other treatment to such\nclaimants. Such doctors, physicians and surgeons shall not recommend\nthat a claimant be treated by any particular physician or surgeon, or\nreceive baking and massage, physio-therapy or other treatment from any\nparticular person, clinic or hospital. Any such physician or surgeon may\nrecommend the necessary treatment needed and the board shall direct the\nemployer or carrier to provide such treatment, but the board shall not\ndesignate a particular physician, surgeon, clinic or hospital to provide\nthe treatment. The employer or carrier shall furnish the prescribed\ntreatment and upon their failure so to do within five days after the\ndirection is made, the claimant may secure the same at the expense of\nthe employer or carrier. Any physician or surgeon so employed by the\nboard who violates the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor.\n  The foregoing provisions of this section prohibiting physicians or\nsurgeons in the employ of the board from recommending that a claimant be\ntreated by any particular physician or surgeon shall not be applicable\nto recommendations for specialist care of their patients who are or may\nbe claimants under article nine of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>