<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-208"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-208"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="208"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Payment of disability and family leave benefits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 208. Payment of disability and family leave benefits. 1. Benefits\nprovided under this article shall be paid periodically and promptly and,\nexcept as to a contested period of disability or family leave, without\nany decision by the board, or designee of the chair pursuant to section\ntwo hundred twenty-one of this article. The first payment of benefits\nshall be due on the fourteenth day of disability or family leave and\nbenefits for that period shall be paid directly to the employee within\nfour business days thereafter or within four business days after the\nfiling of required proof of claim, whichever is the later. If the\nemployer or carrier rejects an initial claim for family leave benefits,\nthe employer or carrier must notify the employee in a manner prescribed\nby the chair within eighteen days of filing of the proof of claim.\nFailure to timely reject shall constitute a waiver of objection to the\nfamily leave claim. Thereafter benefits shall be due and payable\nbi-weekly in like manner. The chair or chair's designee, pursuant to\nsection two hundred twenty-one of this article, may determine that\nbenefits may be paid monthly or semi-monthly if wages were so paid, and\nmay authorize deviation from the foregoing requirements to facilitate\nprompt payment of benefits. Any inquiry which requires the employee's\nresponse in order to continue benefits uninterrupted or unmodified shall\nprovide a reasonable time period in which to respond and include a clear\nand prominent statement of the deadline for responding and consequences\nof failing to respond.\n  2. The chair and superintendent of financial services may, whenever\nsuch information is deemed necessary, require any carrier to file in\nform prescribed by the chair a report or reports as to any claim or\nclaims, including (but without limitation) dates of commencement and\ntermination of benefit payments and amount of benefits paid under this\narticle. The chair and superintendent of financial services may also\nrequire annually information in respect to the aggregate of benefits\npaid, the number of claims allowed and disallowed, the average benefits\nand duration of benefit periods, the amount of payrolls covered and such\nother information as the chair may deem necessary for the purposes of\nadministering this article. If the carrier is providing benefits in\nrespect to more than one employer, the chair and superintendent of\nfinancial services may require that such information be shown separately\nas to those employers who are providing only benefits that are\nsubstantially the same as the benefits required in this article. The\nchair and superintendent of financial services may prescribe the format\nof such report and may promulgate regulations to effectuate this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>