<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-213"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-213"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="213"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_213">
        <num>213</num>
        <heading>Non-compliance or default</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_213__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the payment of benefits to an employee\nif the policy of the employer's carrier is subject to the protection\nafforded by any guaranty fund pursuant to the insurance law; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_213__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nreimbursement to the fund, created under section two hundred fourteen of\nthis article, by an employer whose carrier has failed to pay benefits.\n  3. The provisions of section one hundred forty-one-b of this chapter\nshall not apply to violations of this section after January first, two\nthousand eighteen and before January first, two thousand twenty.\nThereafter, in the event an employer is subject to debarment solely due\nto a penalty for violation of this section, the chair may, in the\ninterests of justice, restore the employer's eligibility to submit a bid\non or be awarded any public work contract or subcontract. The chair may\nexercise this authority only if it is the employer's first time\nviolation of section one hundred forty-one-b of this chapter; the\nemployer is not liable for any outstanding workers' compensation,\ndisability or family leave claims as a result of the lack of coverage;\nand the employer has paid all fines, assessments, and penalties\nassociated with the lack of coverage.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>