<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-214"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-214"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="214"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_214">
        <num>214</num>
        <heading>Special fund for disability benefits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 214. Special fund for disability benefits. There is hereby created a\nfund which shall be known as the special fund for disability benefits to\nprovide for the payment of disability benefits under sections two\nhundred seven, two hundred thirteen and attendance fees under section\ntwo hundred thirty-two of this article.\n  1. As promptly as practicable after April first, in each year, the\nchairman shall ascertain the condition of the fund, and if as of any\nsuch date the net assets of the fund shall be one million dollars or\nmore below the sum of twelve million dollars, the chairman shall assess\nand collect an amount sufficient to restore the fund to an amount equal\nto twelve million dollars.. Such assessment shall be included in the\nassessment rate established pursuant to subdivision two of section one\nhundred fifty-one of this chapter. Such assessments shall be deposited\nwith the commissioner of taxation and finance and transferred to the\nbenefit of such fund upon payment of debt service, if any, pursuant to\nsection one hundred fifty-one of this chapter.\n  2. Whenever the net assets of the fund shall be less than three\nmillion dollars and the disability claims currently being paid shall\nindicate the necessity of supplementing the assets of the fund the\nchairman may transfer from monies collected pursuant to subdivision two\nof section one hundred fifty-one of this chapter an amount sufficient in\nthe discretion of the chairman for the needs of the fund, but not in\nexcess of an amount sufficient to restore the fund to twelve million\ndollars.\n  3. All contributions and assessments received by the chairman under\nthe provisions of this section shall be credited to the fund herein\nestablished and deposited by the chairman to the credit of the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance for the benefit of the fund. The\nsuperintendent of financial services may examine into the condition of\nthe fund at any time on his own initiative or upon the request of the\nchairman.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>