<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-223"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-223"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="223"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-223/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-223/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-223/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-223/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_223">
        <num>223</num>
        <heading>Modification of board decisions or orders</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 223. Modification of board decisions or orders. Upon its own motion\nor upon the application of any party in interest, the board may at any\ntime review any decision or order regarding disability benefits and, on\nsuch review, may make a decision ending, diminishing or increasing the\ndisability benefits previously ordered, and shall state the reason\ntherefor. Upon the filing of such decision regarding disability\nbenefits, the chair shall send to each of the parties a copy thereof. No\nsuch review shall affect any previous decision as regards any moneys\nregarding disability benefits already paid, except that a decision\nincreasing the disability benefit rate may be made effective from date\nof commencement of disability, and except that, if any part of the\ndisability benefits due is unpaid, a decision decreasing the disability\nbenefit rate may be made effective from the commencement of disability,\nand any payments made prior thereto in excess of such decreased rate\nshall be deducted from future disability benefits in such manner and by\nsuch method as may be determined by the board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>