<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-226"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-226"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="226"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_226">
        <num>226</num>
        <heading>The insurance contract</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_226__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any insurance carrier or the state insurance fund who issues,\nreinstates, amends or endorses any contract of insurance or rider\nthereto providing the benefits required to be paid under this article\nshall file notification in the office of the chair within thirty days\nafter such issuance, reinstatement, amendment or endorsement of the\ncontract. Such notice shall be filed in the manner and form prescribed\nby the chair.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_226__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event notice required under this subdivision or subdivision\nfive of this section is not filed with the chair within the thirty-day\ntime period, the chair may impose a penalty of up to one hundred dollars\nfor each ten-day period the insurance carrier or state insurance fund\nfailed to file the notification. All penalties collected pursuant to\nthis subdivision shall be deposited in the uninsured employers' fund.\n  7. The chair may require by regulation that every policy of family\nleave insurance contain a provision requiring that all disputes be\nresolved by designated alternative dispute resolution process in\naccordance with such regulations.\n  8. Premiums for policies providing disability or family leave benefits\nin accordance with this article shall be calculated in accordance with\napplicable provisions of the insurance law, including subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_226__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection four thousand two hundred thirty-five of such law.\n  9. Except as set forth in subdivision eight of section two hundred\neleven of this article, every policy of insurance issued pursuant to\nthis article must offer coverage for both disability and family leave\nbenefits.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>