<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-229"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-229"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="229"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-229/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-229/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-229/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-229/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_229">
        <num>229</num>
        <heading>Posting of notice and providing of notice of rights</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 229. Posting of notice and providing of notice of rights. 1. Each\ncovered employer shall post and maintain in a conspicuous place or\nplaces in and about the employer's place or places of business\ntypewritten or printed notices in form prescribed by the chair, stating\nthat the employer has provided for the payment of disability and family\nleave benefits as required by this article. The chair may require any\ncovered employer to furnish a written statement at any time showing the\ncarrier insuring the payment of benefits under this article or the\nmanner in which such employer has complied with section two hundred\neleven of this article or any other provision of this article. Failure\nfor a period of ten days to furnish such written statement shall\nconstitute presumptive evidence that such employer has neglected or\nfailed in respect of any of the matters so required.\n  2. Whenever an employee of a covered employer who is eligible for\nbenefits under section two hundred four of this article shall be absent\nfrom work due to a disability or to provide family leave as defined in\nsubdivision nine and subdivision fifteen respectively, of section two\nhundred one of this article for more than seven consecutive days, the\nemployer shall provide the employee with a written statement of the\nemployee's rights under this article in a form prescribed by the chair.\nThe statement shall be provided to the employee within five business\ndays after the employee's seventh consecutive day of absence due to\ndisability or family leave or within five business days after the\nemployer has received notice that the employee's absence is due to\ndisability or family leave, whichever is later.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>