<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-27-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-27-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-27-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-27-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-27-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-27-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_A">
        <num>27-A</num>
        <heading>Investments in obligations of designated public benefit corporations; indemnifications</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to\nborrow an amount not exceeding the obligation incurred by the aggregate\ntrust fund pursuant to this section, and to pledge as collateral\ntherefor such assets as they may deem advisable, (ii) to sell any fund\nassets under an agreement or option for the repurchase thereof from\nmonies or assets in the fund or (iii) to sell fund assets on such terms\nand conditions as are found to be fair and reasonable by the state\nsuperintendent of financial services.\n  3. It is hereby found and declared that any and all obligations of the\nstate of New York, the New York state housing finance agency, the New\nYork state medical care facilities finance agency, the dormitory\nauthority and the New York state environmental facilities corporation,\nare reasonable, prudent, proper and legal investments for the aggregate\ntrust fund and for all state officers with responsibility for the\ncustody or investment of such fund or of its assets.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no state officer with\nresponsibility for the custody or investment of the aggregate trust fund\nor of its assets, or for the approval of the sale or investment of such\nassets, nor any investment advisor, attorney, accountant or actuary who\nshall have been employed by or shall have advised such officer, shall\nincur or suffer any liability whatsoever to any person by reason of\nactions taken pursuant to the authorization and direction of subdivision\none or two of this section. Any action which could have been brought\nagainst any aforementioned state officer, investment advisor, attorney,\naccountant or actuary, except for the provisions of this subdivision,\nmay be brought against the aggregate trust fund.\n  5. a. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the\nprovisions of section seventeen of the public officers law, the\naggregate trust fund and the state, jointly and severally, shall save\nharmless and indemnify each and every state officer with responsibility\nfor the custo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>