<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3">
        <num>3</num>
        <heading>Application</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section 65.10 of the penal law in\nfulfillment of a sentence of probation or of conditional discharge and\nof persons performing such services pursuant to the provisions of\nsection 170.55 or 170.56 of the criminal procedure law, and such persons\nshall for the purposes of this chapter be deemed to be employees for the\npublic or not-for-profit corporation, association, institution or\nagency. Said employer may elect to bring such employees within the\ncoverage of this chapter by securing compensation in accordance with the\nterms of section fifty of this chapter.\n  Group 20. In a city having a population of one million or more,\nteachers, regular or substitute, of shop work, manual training,\nindustrial or trade subjects, mechanic arts, textiles, machine shop\nassistants, laboratory assistants, laboratory specialists, laboratory\ntechnicians, and teachers of any subject, trade, or employment\nrequiring, for instruction purposes, use of tools or machinery for which\nprotective, guarding or safety devices are required by the labor law,\nmay elect to receive the benefits prescribed by this chapter provided\nthey are not qualified to receive benefits even if eligible to apply for\nretirement under the teachers' retirement system in said city.  An\nelection to come within this chapter shall constitute a waiver of any\nright to receive absence refunds from the board of education of said\ncity. But a teacher shall, if incapacitated to teach by reason of his\ninjuries, be entitled to the refund of his accumulated deductions in the\nteachers' retirement system or in lieu thereof he may elect to receive\nan annuity which shall be the actuarial equivalent of said accumulated\ndeductions. Any election or choice provided for herein may be made for\nthe teacher by one acting in the teacher's behalf if said teacher is\nincapacitated to act for himself.\n  Group 20-a. For the purposes of this chapter, the work of any person\nemployed as a school aide by scho...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>