<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-316"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-316"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="316"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-316/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-316/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-316/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-316/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_316">
        <num>316</num>
        <heading>Record of enrollment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 316. Record of enrollment. Each local director of civil defense\nshall maintain a record of enrollment of civil defense volunteers who\nare personnel of the volunteer agencies sponsored by his local office.\nEach record shall contain the name and address of the volunteer, the\nname of his employer, date of enrollment and authorized classification\nor assignment to duty, including the times of his assigned duty, as well\nas changes in or termination of enrollment. Such record shall be\nmaintained in duplicate and the duplicate records shall be filed in\nseparate places for greater security in the event of attack.\n  Records of enrollment shall be open for inspection during usual\nbusiness hours by the chairman or by an officer or employee of the board\ndesignated by the chairman. The local director shall furnish to the\nchairman on request such information in the record of enrollment as is\nrequired for administration of this article.\n  In the event of attack, actual or imminent, for which volunteers in\nany part of the area under the jurisdiction of a local director are\nmobilized, the local director shall forthwith deliver to the chairman\none of such duplicate records of enrollment.\n  If the civil defense volunteers enrolled by a local office shall, in\naccordance with a mutual aid agreement approved by the New York state\ncivil defense commission, respond to a request for assistance from any\nplace, either within or without the state, which has suffered attack,\nand shall perform therein authorized civil defense duties, the local\ndirector shall forthwith deliver to the chairman one of such duplicate\nrecords of enrollment.\n  The information contained in such record of enrollment delivered to\nthe chairman shall be prima facie evidence of information on which the\nchairman may rely in paying claims of civil defense volunteers or their\ndependents under this article; and if such record is not delivered to\nthe chairman as required by this section, the burden of proving his\nright to compensation under this article in the case of civil defense\nvolunteers of the local office shall rest on the claimant.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>