<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-325"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-325"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="325"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-325/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-325/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-325/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-325/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_325">
        <num>325</num>
        <heading>Administration expenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 325. Administration expenses. The entire expense of administering\nthis article shall be paid out of the special fund and charged thereto.\n  At least thirty days prior to the first days of April and October in\neach year, the chairman shall submit to the director of the budget for\nhis approval an estimated budget of expenditures for the succeeding six\nmonths. In the event of attack within the state for which civil defense\nvolunteers are mobilized or outside the state if, in accordance with a\nmutual aid agreement approved by the New York state civil defense\ncommission, civil defense volunteers of any local office respond to a\nrequest for assistance, the chairman shall prepare and submit to the\ndirector of the budget for his approval an estimated budget of\nexpenditures for funds to be allocated to the board during the period of\nemergency. There may not be expended for purposes of such administration\nmore than the amounts specified in such budget for each item of\nexpenditure, except as authorized by the director of the budget. The\nfunds so allocated by the director of the budget shall be available to\nthe workmen's compensation board for services and expenses, including\ntravel outside the state, to carry out the provisions of this article\nand shall be paid from the treasury on audit and warrant of the\ncomptroller on vouchers approved by the chairman, vice chairman or\nsecretary of the board. If there be officers or employees of the board\nwhose duties relate partly to the general work of the board and partly\nto such administration, and in case there is other expense which is\nincurred jointly on behalf of the general work of the board and to such\nadministration, an equitable apportionment of the expense shall be made\nand the part thereof which is applicable to administration as provided\nin this article shall be chargeable thereto.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>