<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-47"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-47"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="47"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-47/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-47/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-47/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-47/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47">
        <num>47</num>
        <heading>Presumption as to the cause of disease</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 47. Presumption as to the cause of disease. If the employee, at or\nimmediately before the date of disablement, was employed in any process\nmentioned in the second column of the schedule of diseases in\nsubdivision two of section three of this chapter, and his or her disease\nis the disease in the first column of such schedule set opposite the\ndescription of the process, the disease presumptively shall be deemed to\nhave been due to the nature of that employment. Any exposure to the\nhazards of compressed air after July first, nineteen hundred forty-six\nshall be presumed, in the absence of substantial evidence to the\ncontrary, to be injurious exposure. Any exposure to the hazards of\nharmful dust in this state for a period of sixty days after September\nfirst, nineteen hundred thirty-five, shall be presumed, in the absence\nof substantial evidence to the contrary, to be an injurious exposure.\nWith respect to any state or local correction officer as defined in\nsubdivision twenty-five of section 2.10 of the criminal procedure law,\nsafety and security officer employed by the office of mental health,\nsecurity hospital treatment assistant employed by the office of mental\nhealth, any uniformed court officer or court clerk of the unified court\nsystem having the powers of peace officer, the court reporter or the\ncourt interpreter, an exposure to the blood or bodily fluid of an\nindividual, incarcerated, confined or otherwise, during the course of\nhis or her employment that is reported in writing to such correction\nofficer's, safety and security officer's, security hospital treatment\nassistant's, uniformed court officer's, court clerk's, court reporter's\nor court interpreter's employer within twenty-four hours of such\nexposure, shall be presumed, in the absence of substantial evidence to\nthe contrary, to be an injurious exposure if, subsequent to such\nexposure, such correction officer, safety and security officer, security\nhospital treatment assistant, uniformed court officer, court clerk,\ncourt reporter or court interpreter is diagnosed with a blood-borne\ndisease, including, but not limited to hepatitis C.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>