<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-50-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-50-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-50-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-50-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-50-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-50-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_B">
        <num>50-B</num>
        <heading>Task force on group self-insurance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-b. Task force on group self-insurance. There is established the\ntask force on group self-insurance whose membership shall consist of the\nchair or his or her designee, the superintendent of financial services\nor his or her designee, the commissioner of labor or his or her\ndesignee, and twelve members to be appointed by the governor as follows:\ntwo upon nomination of the speaker of the assembly, two upon nomination\nof the temporary president of the senate, one upon nomination by the\npresident of the New York state American federation of labor-congress of\nindustrial organizations, one upon the nomination of the business\ncouncil of New York state, one who is a representative of an individual\nself-insurer or representative of an organization that represents\nindividual self-insurers, one who is a trustee or administrator of a\ngroup self-insurer or representative of an organization that represents\ngroup self-insurers, one who is a representative of an organization that\nrepresents workers' compensation claimants, and three others without\nlimitation. The governor shall appoint the chair of the task force. The\ntask force shall report to the governor, the speaker of the assembly and\nthe temporary president of the senate on or before February first, two\nthousand nine making recommendations concerning:\n  1. the prevention of future defaults by group self-insurers;\n  2. regulation of group self-insurers and its impact and effectiveness;\n  3. payment of claims insured by defaulted group self-insurers;\n  4. the long term viability of group self-insurers; and\n  5. such other topics related to group self-insurance as the task force\nmay deem necessary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>