<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-51"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-51"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="51"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_51">
        <num>51</num>
        <heading>Posting of notice regarding compensation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 51. Posting of notice regarding compensation. Every employer who has\ncomplied with section fifty of this article shall post and maintain in a\nconspicuous place or places in and about his place or places of business\ntypewritten or printed in English and Spanish notices in form prescribed\nby the chairman, stating the fact that he has complied with all the\nrules and regulations of the chairman and the board and that he has\nsecured the payment of compensation to his employees and their\ndependents in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, but\nfailure to post such notice as herein provided shall not in any way\naffect the exclusiveness of the remedy provided for by section eleven of\nthis chapter. Every employer who owns or operates automotive or\nhorse-drawn vehicles and has no minimum staff of regular employees\nrequired to report for work at an established place of business\nmaintained by such employer and every employer who is engaged in the\nbusiness of moving household goods or furniture shall post such notices\nin each and every vehicle owned or operated by him. Failure to post or\nmaintain such notice in any of said vehicles shall constitute\npresumptive evidence that such employer has failed to secure the payment\nof compensation. The chairman may require any employer to furnish a\nwritten statement at any time showing the stock corporation, mutual\ncorporation or reciprocal insurer in which such employer is insured or\nthe manner in which such employer has complied with any provision of\nthis chapter. Failure for a period of ten days to furnish such written\nstatement shall constitute presumptive evidence that such employer has\nneglected or failed in respect of any of the matters so required. Any\nemployer who fails to comply with the provisions of this section shall\nbe required to pay to the board a fine of five hundred dollars for each\nviolation, in addition to any other penalties imposed by law to be\ndeposited into the uninsured employers' fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>