<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-58"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-58"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="58"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-58/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-58/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-58/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-58/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_58">
        <num>58</num>
        <heading>Payment of compensation to persons providing housekeeping or nursing services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 58. Payment of compensation to persons providing housekeeping or\nnursing services. An employer under the workmen's compensation law, or\nthe insurance carrier under the policy of workmen's compensation\ninsurance covering such employer, or any other person or organization\nincluding the state, a municipal corporation or other political\nsubdivision of the state which provides housekeeping, or nursing\nservices to an injured employee or recipient of social services\nassistance or which arranges for such services by authorizing the hiring\nof an employee for such purposes and which supplies funds for the\npayment of such employee's wages, notwithstanding any general or special\nstatute requiring or authorizing such housekeeping or nursing services,\nshall be liable for the payment of compensation to the person performing\nsuch housekeeping or nursing services as provided by this chapter.\nNothing in this section shall create an employer-employee relationship\nwhen such relationship does not otherwise exist.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>