<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-61"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-61"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="61"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-61/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-61/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-61/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-61/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_61">
        <num>61</num>
        <heading>Continuance of existing plans; establishment of new plans</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 61. Continuance of existing plans; establishment of new plans. 1.\nPlans of mutual self-insurance heretofore adopted by boards of\nsupervisors of counties pursuant to former subdivision three-a of\nsection fifty of this chapter, are hereby continued; provided, however,\nthat the board of supervisors of a county must provide by local law for\nthe continuation of the plan and for the administration thereof pursuant\nto this article on or before July thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nfifty-six, or such plan shall be deemed abandoned as of October\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-six, subject to the provisions of\nsubdivision two of section seventy-five of this chapter. All such plans\nnot so abandoned shall be operated pursuant to the provisions of this\narticle and local laws adopted pursuant thereto.\n  2. The board of supervisors of a county may by local law establish the\nplan of self-insurance provided for in this article.\n  3. A local law establishing a plan pursuant to this article may,\nnotwithstanding the provisions of paragraph f of subdivision one of\nsection eleven of the municipal home rule law, provide that the\nprovisions of subdivision three of section sixty-three of this article,\nas amended from time to time, shall not be applicable to the plan in\nthat county and, if such plan is established, the term "liability", as\nused in this article, shall not include any compensation, assessments or\nother obligations under the volunteer firefighters' benefit law and the\nprovisions of subdivision three of section sixty-three of this article,\nas amended from time to time, shall not be applicable in relation to\nsuch plan.\n  4. If a plan has been continued pursuant to this article, the board of\nsupervisors may, notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph f of\nsubdivision one of section eleven of the municipal home rule law, adopt\na local law on or before the first day of August in any year to provide\nthat the provisions of subdivision three of section sixty-three of this\narticle, as amended from time to time, shall not be applicable to the\nplan in that county after the thirty-first day of December in such year,\nexcept as to liabilities existing on such latter date, and, if such a\nlocal law is adopted, the term "liability", as used in this article,\nshall not include any compensation, assessments or other obligations\nunder the volunteer firefighters' benefit law, and the provisions of\nsubdivision three of section sixty-three of this article shall not be\napplicable in relation to such plan, after the thirty-first day of\nDecember in such year, except as to, and in connection with, liabilities\nexisting on such thirty-first day of December.\n  5. If a local law has been adopted pursuant to either subdivision\nthree or subdivision four of this section, the board of supervisors may,\nnotwithstanding the provisions of paragraph f of subdivision one of\nsection eleven of the municipal home rule law, adopt a local law on or\nbefore the first day of August in any year to provide that the\nprovisions of subdivision three of section sixty-three of this chapter,\nas amended from time to time, shall be applicable to the plan in that\ncounty after the thirty-first day of December in such year, and, if such\na local law is adopted, the term "liability", as used in this article\nshall include any compensation, assessments, or other obligations under\nthe volunteer firefighters' benefit law, the volunteer ambulance\nworkers' benefit law, and the provisions of subdivision three of section\nsixty-three of this chapter shall be applicable in relation to such\nplan, after the thirty-first day of December in such year, and, further,\nthe provisions of section sixty-seven of this chapter shall be\napplicable on and after the first day of August in such year in relation\nto such plan.\n  6. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph f of subdivision one of\nsection eleven of the municipal home rule law, the board of supervisors\nof a county may by local law amend the definition of "liability", as\ndefined in subdivision seven of section sixty of this article, to\nexclude any liability under paragraph m of subdivision one of section\nfive of the volunteer firefighters' benefit law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>