<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-63"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-63"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="63"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-63/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-63/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-63/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-63/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_63">
        <num>63</num>
        <heading>Liability of county</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the liability of participants\narising on and after January first, nineteen hundred fifty-seven, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_63__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the joint liability of the participants imposed pursuant to such\nformer subdivision three-a of section fifty of this chapter, shall be\nmade by the county.\n  2. When a plan is established pursuant to this article, payments with\nrespect to the liability of participants arising on and after the\neffective date of the plan shall be made by the county.\n  3. Where a town participates in a plan, in addition to payments with\nrespect to the liability of the town, the county shall make payments\nwith respect to that portion of the liability of all villages, fire\ndistricts, fire protection districts and fire alarm districts within\nsuch town and all territory within such town outside cities, villages,\nfire districts, fire protection districts and fire alarm districts\narising out of the death of or injury to volunteer firefighters;\nprovided, however, that the county shall not be obligated to make such\npayments in the case of a village, fire district, fire protection\ndistrict or fire alarm district, located in more than one town unless\nthe town board of each town containing part of the village or district\nby resolution elects to become a participant in the plan.  Participation\nin a plan by a village or fire district shall make the county liable for\nsuch payments where the town or towns in which such village or fire\ndistrict is located are not participants in the plan. The term "injury",\nas used in this subdivision, means "injury" as defined in subdivision\nfour of section three of the volunteer firefighters' benefit law, as\namended from time to time. If a county has elected to establish a\nself-insurance plan for itself, it may elect to extend coverage under\nsuch plan to voluntary ambulance companies upon the same terms and\nconditions as such coverage applies to volunteer firefighters.\n  4. The expenditure of county funds for payments authorized or required\nby this article is hereby declared to be for a county purpose.\n  5. For the purposes of this articl...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>elect not to provide such coverage,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>elect to provide such coverage in a manner provided in section fifty\nof this chapter other than under article five thereof,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>elect to\nrevoke an election made under either "</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>" or "</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>" above and adopt the\nother of such elections, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>elect to revoke an election made under\neither "</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>" "</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>" or "</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_63__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>" above and have such coverage provided under\nthe plan as if no election had been made hereunder.  Any such election\nshall become effective when adopted if it is filed with the chairman of\nthe workmen's compensation board and with the committee or administrator\nof the plan within ten days after adoption, otherwise it shall become\neffective when filed with both the chairman of the workmen's\ncompensation board and the committee or administrator of the plan. The\nchairman of the workmen's compensation board may prescribe the form or\nforms of any such election. Notwithstanding the provisions of section\nthree, subdivision one, group nineteen, of this chapter, if the county\nelects to exclude one or more groups of such civil defense volunteers of\nthe county's office of civil defense, then the plan shall not be liable\nfor coverage under this chapter for such civil defense volunteers so\nexcluded, but this shall not preclude a town or a village in such county\nor a city participating...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>