<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-64"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-64"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="64"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_64">
        <num>64</num>
        <heading>Administration of plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 64. Administration of plan. 1. The board of supervisors shall by\nlocal law provide for the administration of the plan, such plan to be\nadministered by either a committee or an administrator. Any county\nofficer or employee or other person may be appointed to such committee\nor act as administrator, or be appointed or employed by such committee\nor administrator. The committee or administrator may employ, subject to\nthe approval of the board of supervisors, such persons as may be deemed\nnecessary for the operation of the plan, and may contract for necessary\nactuarial, or other expert or professional services. Members of the\ncommittee or the administrator, and all other officers and employees of\nthe plan, shall receive such salary or other remuneration, payable from\nmoneys of the plan, as shall be fixed by the board of supervisors.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of any other law, a county officer or\nemployee, other than a member of the board of supervisors, in addition\nto his salary as such officer or employee, may be compensated as a\nmember of such committee, as such administrator, or as an officer or\nemployee of the plan.\n  2. The county treasurer shall be the custodian of all moneys of the\nplan. Such moneys shall be accounted for as a separate fund to be known\nas the county self-insurance fund, and shall be deposited in a bank or\ntrust company designated in the manner provided by law as a depositary\nof moneys of the county. Disbursements of such moneys, except for\npayment of fixed salaries, shall be made only upon order of the\ncommittee or administrator, as the case may be. Compensation may be paid\nupon such order to persons entitled thereto in the manner provided in\nsection twenty-five of this chapter. The amount of compensation payable\nprior to an award pursuant to such order shall constitute a settled\nclaim within the meaning of the local finance law. Books, records and\npapers of the plan shall be subject to examination and audit as provided\nin section two hundred ten of the county law.\n  3. The county attorney shall be legal advisor to the plan and it shall\nbe his duty to represent the plan in all controversies. In addition, the\ncounty attorney may engage subject to the approval of the board of\nsupervisors, counsel in respect to any particular subject matter,\nproceeding or litigation, in which event the expense of engaging such\nspecial counsel shall be charged as an administrative expense of the\nplan.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>