<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-73"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-73"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="73"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-73/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-73/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-73/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-73/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_73">
        <num>73</num>
        <heading>Abandonment of plan</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection one thousand one hundred thirteen of the insurance law and\ncovered by the workers' compensation security fund as created and\ngoverned by article six-A of this chapter. It shall only be issued for a\nsingle complete premium payment in advance by the county, city, village,\ntown, school district, fire district or other political subdivision of\nstate and in an amount deemed acceptable by the chair and the\nsuperintendent of financial services. In lieu of the applicable premium\ncharge ordinarily required to be imposed by a carrier, said premium\nshall include a surcharge in an amount to be determined by the chair to\nsatisfy all assessment liability due and owing to the board and/or the\nchair under this chapter. Said surcharge shall be payable to the board\nsimultaneous to the execution of the assumption of workers' compensation\nliability insurance policy. However, the payment of said surcharge does\nnot relieve the carrier from any other liability, including liability\nowed to the superintendent of financial services pursuant to article\nsix-A of this chapter. When issued such policy shall be non-cancellable\nwithout recourse for any cause during the continuance of the liability\nsecured and so covered.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>