<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-76"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-76"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="76"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-76/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-76/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-76/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-76/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_76">
        <num>76</num>
        <heading>Creation of state fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_76__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reimbursement of all losses\nand loss adjustment expenses under such policies; and (ii) fees and\nother costs, including but not limited to those for claims services,\nrelating to such agreements. An agreement under this subdivision shall\nnot include the provision of claims services for any claim under this\nchapter.\n  b. For a policyholder to be eligible for insurance in states other\nthan New York provided through agreements entered into under this\nsubdivision, either:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_76__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the policyholder's workers' compensation\npremiums with the state insurance fund covering its employees under this\nchapter must be greater than the premiums charged to cover the\npolicyholder's obligations to pay workers' compensation benefits in all\nstates, in the aggregate, other than New York when covered under such\nagreements; or (ii) the payroll for the policyholder's operations in New\nYork must be greater than the policyholder's payroll in all states, in\nthe aggregate, other than New York when covered under such agreements\nfor the prior policy period. For determining eligibility, "premiums"\nmean estimated premiums as determined by the state insurance fund at the\nbeginning of the policy period. In addition, for a policyholder to be\neligible for insurance in states other than New York through the state\ninsurance fund, the policyholder must meet the state insurance fund's\nunderwriting criteria for other states coverage as specified by rules of\nthe commissioners.\n  2. The purposes of the state insurance fund herein created are hereby\nenlarged to provide insurance for the payment of the benefits required\nby section two hundred four of this chapter including benefits for\nfamily leave. A separate fund is hereby created within the state\ninsurance fund, which shall be known as the "disability benefits fund",\nand which shall consist of all premiums received and paid into said fund\non account of such insurance, all securities acquired by and through the\nuse of moneys belonging to said fund and of interest earned upon moneys\nbelonging to said fund and deposited or invested as herein provided.\nSaid disability benefits fund shall be applicable to the payment of\nbenefits, expenses and assessments on account of insurance written\npursuant to article nine of this chapter. Premiums for policies\nproviding disability and family leave benefits in accordance with this\narticle shall be calculated in accordance with applicable provisions of\nthe insurance law...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_76__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section four thousand two\nhundred thirty-five of such law. The state insurance fund shall have\nauthority to discount or surcharge on established premium rates based on\nsound actuarial principles.\n  2-b. The purposes of the state insurance fund created in this section\nare hereby enlarged to provide for the insurance by the state insurance\nfund of the payment of the benefits required by section one hundred\nsixty-ddd of the executive law.\n  3. The respective assets and liabilities of the workers' compensation\nand disability benefits funds provided in this section shall be and\nremain separate except that advances may be made from either fund for\nthe payment of benefits and for administrative expenses, subject to\nannual reimbursement.\n  Whenever used in this article the terms "state insurance fund", "state\nfund" and "fund" shall be deemed to include both the workers'\ncompensation fund and the disability benefits fund unless the context\notherwise indicates.\n  4. The purposes of such state insurance fund are hereby further\nenlarged to permit it to furnish to self-insurers, as defined in\nsubdivision three of section fifty of this chapter, representation and\nservices of the nature specified in paragraph five of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_76__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection one thousand six hundred one of the insurance law and\nsubdivision three-d of section fifty of this chapter.\n  5. No monies of the state insurance fund shall be transferred to any\nother fund, nor shall any such monies be applied to the making of any\npayment for any purpose other than the purposes set forth in this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>