<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-83"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-83"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="83"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-83/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-83/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-83/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-83/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_83">
        <num>83</num>
        <heading>Rules</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 83. Rules. The commissioner shall adopt rules for the conduct of the\nbusiness of the state fund, and may from time to time alter, amend or\nrepeal any rule therefore adopted. At least six affirmative votes shall\nbe required for the adoption of any rule, or the amendment or repeal of\nany rule. No rule, and no resolution proposing to alter, amend or repeal\nany rule, shall be effective unless approved by the commissioner of\nlabor. If the commissioner of labor fails to act upon any such rule or\nresolution within thirty days after it is communicated to him or her,\nsuch rule or resolution shall be deemed to have been approved.\n  The rules of the commissioners shall provide for the conduct of the\nbusiness of the state insurance fund, including the issuance of policies\nand their terms and conditions, the fixing of premium rates, the keeping\nof records, auditing of payrolls, and the billing and collection of\npremiums therefor, the inspection of risks and the setting of the\nstandards of safety, the adjustment and payment of claims and awards,\nand the investigation of all matters relating thereto, the medical\nexamination of persons claiming compensation and the furnishing and\nsupervision of medical and surgical treatment to persons injured as set\nforth in this chapter, the conduct of the legal business of the fund and\nthe enforcement of the subrogated rights of the fund against third\nparties, the investment of the surplus and reserves of the fund, and the\ncollection and analysis of statistics of payrolls, premiums, losses and\nexpenses and the actuarial consideration thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>