<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-86"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-86"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="86"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-86/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-86/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-86/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-86/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_86">
        <num>86</num>
        <heading>Catastrophe surplus and reserves for workers' compensation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 86. Catastrophe surplus and reserves for workers' compensation. Ten\nper centum of the premiums collected from employers insured in the fund\nfor workers' compensation shall be set aside for the creation of a\nsurplus until such surplus shall amount to the sum of one hundred\nthousand dollars, and thereafter five per centum of such premiums, until\nsuch time as in the judgment of the commissioners such surplus shall be\nsufficiently large to cover the catastrophe hazard. Thereafter the\ncontribution to such surplus may be reduced or discontinued conditional\nupon constant maintenance of a sufficient surplus to cover the\ncatastrophe hazard. Reserves shall be set up and maintained adequate to\nmeet anticipated losses and carry all claims and policies to maturity,\nwhich reserves shall be computed to reflect the present values, at five\npercent interest per annum, of the determined and estimated unpaid\nlosses, and other requirements computed in accordance with such rules as\nshall be approved by the superintendent of financial services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>