<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-87-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-87-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="87-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-87-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-87-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-87-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-87-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_87_F">
        <num>87-F</num>
        <heading>Appropriations to the state insurance fund</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 87-f. Appropriations to the state insurance fund. 1.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the state insurance fund,\nhereinafter referred to as the fund, and all state officers with\nresponsibility for the custody or investment of such fund or of its\nassets, shall annually, no later than November first in each year,\nsubmit to the director of the budget the fund's request for an\nappropriation of one billion sixty-five million dollars. The governor\nshall include such amount in a budget bill for the next state fiscal\nyear. The state comptroller shall encumber the amount so appropriated\nbefore the end of the fiscal year for which any such appropriation is\nmade. If for any fiscal year commencing on or after April first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-three, the governor fails to submit a budget\nbill containing an appropriation in the amount requested by the fund or\nthe legislature fails to appropriate the amount in a budget bill\nsubmitted by the governor for such fiscal year, the amount appropriated\nfor and encumbered during the preceding fiscal year shall be payable\nforthwith to the fund on the first day of July of such year in the\nmanner prescribed by law, provided, however, that such amount shall not\nexceed the amount of moneys transferred to the general fund, the note\nrepayment account or the capital projects fund by the fund pursuant to\nthe provisions of chapter fifty-five of the laws of nineteen hundred\neighty-two, chapter twenty-eight of the laws of nineteen hundred\neighty-six, chapter forty-seven of the laws of nineteen hundred\neighty-seven and chapter seven of the laws of nineteen hundred\neighty-nine.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the fund and all state\nofficers with responsibility for the custody or investment of such fund\nor of its assets shall annually, no later than November first in each\nyear, submit to the director of the budget the fund's additional request\nfor an appropriation of two hundred thirty million dollars and the\ngovernor shall include such additional amount in a budget bill for the\nnext state fiscal year. The state comptroller shall encumber the amount\nso appropriated before the end of the fiscal year for which any such\nappropriation is made. If for any fiscal year commencing on or after\nApril first, nineteen hundred ninety the governor fails to submit a\nbudget bill containing an appropriation in the amount requested by the\nfund or the legislature fails to appropriate the amount in a budget bill\nsubmitted by the governor for such fiscal year, the amount appropriated\nfor and encumbered during the preceding fiscal year shall be payable\nforthwith to the fund on the first day of July of such year in the\nmanner prescribed by law, provided, however, that such amount shall not\nexceed the amount of moneys transferred to the general fund or the note\nrepayment account by the fund pursuant to the provisions of a chapter of\nthe laws of nineteen hundred ninety entitled "AN ACT to authorize and\ndirect the transfer of hazardous waste remedial fund industry fee\ntransfer account balances and receipts to the general fund; to amend the\nstate finance law, in relation to industry fee surcharges and the\ncalculations relating thereto, to authorize the transfer of state\ninsurance fund balances to the general fund; to amend the workers'\ncompensation law, in relation to the provision of appropriations by the\nstate for the maintenance of reserves of the state insurance fund; and\nmaking appropriations relating thereto".\n  3. It is hereby found and declared that any appropriations made as\nprovided for in subdivision one or two of this section shall be deemed\nadmitted assets of the state insurance fund, and that any transfer of\nmoneys by the fund to the general fund, the note repayment account or\nthe capital projects fund in accordance with the provisions of chapter\nfifty-five of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-two, chapter\ntwenty-eight of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-six, chapter\nforty-seven of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-seven, chapter seven\nof the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-nine or a chapter of the laws of\nnineteen hundred ninety entitled "AN ACT to authorize and direct the\ntransfer of hazardous waste remedial fund industry fee transfer account\nbalances and receipts to the general fund; to amend the state finance\nlaw, in relation to industry fee surcharges and the calculations\nrelating thereto, to authorize the transfer of state insurance fund\nbalances to the general fund; to amend the workers' compensation law, in\nrelation to the provision of appropriations by the state for the\nmaintenance of reserves of the state insurance fund; and making\nappropriations relating thereto" is deemed a proper and prudent legal\nundertaking for any state officer with the responsibility for the\ncustody or the investment of the assets of the fund, notwithstanding any\nother provision of law to the contrary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>