<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="88*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_88*2">
        <num>88*2</num>
        <heading>Administration expenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 88. Administration expenses. The entire expense of administering\nthe state insurance fund shall be paid out of such fund which shall not\nbe considered an agency or a fund of the state for the purposes of\nsection four of the state finance law. The portion of such expenses\napplicable and chargeable to the disability benefits fund shall be\ndetermined on an equitable basis with due allowance for the division of\noverhead expenses. There shall be submitted to the director of the\nbudget quarterly financial statements on a calendar year basis. In no\ncase shall the amount of administrative expenditures so authorized for\nan entire year from the workers' compensation fund exceed twenty-five\nper centum of the earned premiums for such insurance for that year. In\nno case shall the amount of administrative expenditures authorized for\nthe disability benefits fund for an entire year exceed twenty-five per\ncentum of the premiums earned by that fund for such insurance for that\nyear. No payment, expenditure or refund out of the state insurance fund\nshall be subject to pre-audit by the department of audit and control as\nprovided by section one hundred eleven of the state finance law. All\nappointments to positions in the state insurance fund shall be made\nsubject to civil service requirements.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 88\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>