<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="88-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-88-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_88_C">
        <num>88-C</num>
        <heading>Coverage of state employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 88-c. Coverage of state employees. Notwithstanding any other\nprovisions of law to the contrary and except as set forth in section two\nhundred and twelve-a of this chapter, the liability of the state for the\npayment of compensation under this chapter heretofore existing or\nhereinafter arising shall be secured by an insuring agreement to be\nentered into between the department of civil service and the state\ninsurance fund wherein the state, from moneys appropriated therefor,\nshall pay in advance to the fund on a periodic basis the actual costs to\nthe fund for the meeting and paying, as the same become due and payable,\nall obligations incurred under this chapter by the state as an employer.\nNotwithstanding any law to the contrary, the fund may on an actuarially\nsound basis provide to the state insurance for any portion of the\nobligations of the state as employer under this chapter with respect to\ninjuries or deaths resulting from accidents arising out of and in the\ncourse of employment on or after April first, nineteen hundred\neighty-one. All such payments made by the state and paid into the state\nfund shall constitute a separate account in the fund to be used solely\nfor the purpose of discharging all compensation obligations of the state\npursuant to the provisions of this chapter and in accordance with the\ninsuring agreement as provided in this section. Any portion of the\naccount may be invested in the same manner as the assets of the fund as\nprovided in section eighty-seven of this article. The liability of the\nfund for the payment of any claims or the meeting of any obligations of\nthe state as an employer as provided in this chapter shall not exceed\nthe moneys paid into such separate account and any increments or\ndiminutions thereof. The agreement shall further provide that the fund\nshall render all services and make all reasonable expenditures necessary\nor required for the processing, defense and payment of all claims under\nthis chapter, including the protection of liens, subrogation, credit and\nother rights of the state as an employer or the fund as an insurer, in\nsituations where the employees' injuries or deaths were caused by\nculpability of third parties. Except to the extent that the state\nobtains insurance on an actuarially sound basis pursuant to the\nprovisions of this section, the provisions of section eighty-six of this\nchapter with respect to the maintenance of reserves for the purpose of\nmeeting anticipated compensation losses, shall not in any manner be\napplicable to claims of employees of the state with respect to injuries\nor deaths resulting from accidents arising out of and in the course of\nemployment prior to April first, nineteen hundred eighty-one, or to an\ninsuring agreement entered into between the state insurance fund and the\ndepartment of civil service in accordance with the provisions of this\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>