<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="WKC">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-92"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-92"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="92"/>
          <FRBRname value="WKC"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-92/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-92/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-92/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/wkc/section-92/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_92">
        <num>92</num>
        <heading>Payment of premiums</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 92. Payment of premiums. 1. Workers' compensation insurance premiums\nfor any policy period shall be paid into the state insurance fund at the\nbeginning of the period when the amount of such premium is less than one\nthousand dollars according to the estimated expenditure of wages for the\nperiod except to the extent that rules of the commissioners permit such\namount to be paid by installments. For all other policyholders, workers'\ncompensation insurance premiums for any policy period based on an\nestimated expenditure of wages for the period may, at the policyholders'\noption, be paid into the state insurance fund by installments in\naccordance with rules promulgated by the commissioners.\n  2. Disability benefits insurance premiums for any period shall be paid\ninto the state insurance fund at the beginning of the period according\nto the estimated expenditure of wages for the period except to the\nextent that rules of the commissioners permit such amount to be paid by\ninstallments.\n  3. At the end of the period an adjustment of the premium shall be made\naccording to the actual expenditure of wages. If such adjusted premium\nis more than the premium paid at the beginning of the period, the\npolicyholder shall pay the difference immediately upon notification of\nthe amount due except to the extent that rules promulgated by the\ncommissioners permit such amount to be paid by installments. If such\nadjusted premium is less than the premium paid in advance, the state\ninsurance fund shall, at the policyholder's option, either refund the\ndifference or credit the amount thereof to the policyholder's account\nwith the state insurance fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>