<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-24"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-24"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="24"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-24/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-24/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_24">
        <num>24</num>
        <heading>Public holidays; half-holidays</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 24. Public holidays; half-holidays. The term public holiday includes\nthe following days in each year: the first day of January, known as New\nYear's day; the third Monday of January, known as Dr. Martin Luther\nKing, Jr. day; the twelfth day of February, known as Lincoln's birthday;\nthe third Monday in February, known as Washington's birthday; the last\nMonday in May, known as Memorial day; the second Sunday in June, known\nas Flag day; the nineteenth day of June, known as Juneteenth; the fourth\nday of July, known as Independence day; the first Monday in September,\nknown as Labor day; the second Monday in October, known as Columbus day;\nthe eleventh day of November, known as Veterans' day; the fourth\nThursday in November, known as Thanksgiving day; and the twenty-fifth\nday of December, known as Christmas day, and if any of such days except\nFlag day is Sunday, the next day thereafter; each general election day,\nand each day appointed by the president of the United States or by the\ngovernor of this state as a day of general thanksgiving, general fasting\nand prayer, or other general religious observances. The term\nhalf-holiday includes the period from noon to midnight of each Saturday\nwhich is not a public holiday.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>