<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-25"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-25"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="25"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_25">
        <num>25</num>
        <heading>Public holiday, Saturday or Sunday in contractual obligations; extension of time where performance of act authorized or required by contr...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 25. Public holiday, Saturday or Sunday in contractual obligations;\nextension of time where performance of act authorized or required by\ncontract is due on Saturday, Sunday or public holiday. 1. Where a\ncontract by its terms authorizes or requires the payment of money or the\nperformance of a condition on a Saturday, Sunday or a public holiday, or\nauthorizes or requires the payment of money or the performance of a\ncondition within or before or after a period of time computed from a\ncertain day, and such period of time ends on a Saturday, Sunday or a\npublic holiday, unless the contract expressly or impliedly indicates a\ndifferent intent, such payment may be made or condition performed on the\nnext succeeding business day, and if the period ends at a specified\nhour, such payment may be made or condition performed, at or before the\nsame hour of such next succeeding business day, with the same force and\neffect as if made or performed in accordance with the terms of the\ncontract.\n  2. Where time is extended by virtue of the provisions of this section,\nsuch extended time shall not be included in the computation of interest\nunless the contract so provides, except that when the period is\nspecified as a number of months, such extended time shall be included in\nthe computation of interest unless the contract otherwise provides.\n  3. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all time deposits and\ncertificates of deposit of banking organizations that mature on a\nSaturday, Sunday or bank holiday shall continue to accrue interest at\nthe same rate fixed for the term of the deposit or certificate until the\nfirst banking day next succeeding the date of maturity, at which the\nprincipal and all accrued interest may be withdrawn, unless sooner\nwithdrawn by the depositor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>