<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="60"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gcn/section-60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_60">
        <num>60</num>
        <heading>Newspapers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 60. Newspapers. a. In any case in which notice of any fact is\nrequired by law to be published or advertised in a newspaper, the term\n"newspaper" shall mean a paper of general circulation which is printed\nand distributed ordinarily not less frequently than once a week, and has\nbeen so for at least one year immediately preceding such publication or\nadvertisement, and which contains news, articles of opinion (as\neditorials), features, advertising, or other matter regarded as of\ncurrent interest, has a paid circulation and (except for such a paper\nwhich has been printed and distributed not less frequently than once a\nweek for a period of ten years prior to January one, nineteen hundred\nseventy-five) has been entered at United States post-office as\nsecond-class matter. A publication which is distributed or made\navailable primarily for advertising purposes to the public generally\nwithout consideration being paid therefor shall not be deemed to be a\n"newspaper" for the purpose of publication or advertisement of such\nnotice required by law. Notwithstanding any provision of this\nsubdivision to the contrary, a publication which was designated and\npublishing notice as an official newspaper prior to the year nineteen\nhundred forty and continued to be so designated and publishing for at\nleast thirty years after such year shall be deemed to be a newspaper\nwithin the meaning of this subdivision.\n  b. The terms "daily newspaper" and "newspaper published each business\nday" in a statute, contract, or any public or private instrument, mean,\nrespectively, a newspaper customarily published on each business day of\nthe year, whether or not such newspaper is published on any other day.\nThe term "business day" when used herein does not include Saturdays,\nSundays or legal holidays.\n  c. The term "newspaper of a county, city, town or village" when used\nin a statute shall mean a newspaper published, circulated, printed or\ndistributed in the county, city, town or village.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>