<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1103"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1103">
        <num>1103</num>
        <heading>Public officers and employees to obey title; exceptions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nThe provisions of this title applicable to the drivers of vehicles upon\nthe highways shall apply to drivers of all vehicles owned or operated by\nthe United States, this state, or any county, city, town, district, or\nany other political subdivision of the state, except as provided in this\nsection and subject to such specific exceptions as are set forth in this\ntitle with reference to authorized emergency vehicles.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless specifically made applicable, the provisions of this title,\nexcept the provisions of sections eleven hundred ninety-two through\neleven hundred ninety-six of this chapter, shall not apply to persons,\nteams, motor vehicles, and other equipment while actually engaged in\nwork on a highway nor shall the provisions of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\ntwelve hundred two apply to hazard vehicles while actually engaged in\nhazardous operation on or adjacent to a highway but shall apply to such\npersons and vehicles when traveling to or from such hazardous operation.\nThe foregoing provisions of this subdivision shall not relieve any\nperson, or team or any operator of a motor vehicle or other equipment\nwhile actually engaged in work on a highway from the duty to proceed at\nall times during all phases of such work with due regard for the safety\nof all persons nor shall the foregoing provisions protect such persons\nor teams or such operators of motor vehicles or other equipment from the\nconsequences of their reckless disregard for the safety of others.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>