<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1104"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1104"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1104"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1104">
        <num>1104</num>
        <heading>Authorized emergency vehicles</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The driver of an authorized\nemergency vehicle, when involved in an emergency operation, may exercise\nthe privileges set forth in this section, but subject to the conditions\nherein stated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The driver of an authorized emergency vehicle may:\n  1. Stop, stand or park irrespective of the provisions of this title;\n  2. Proceed past a steady red signal, a flashing red signal or a stop\nsign, but only after slowing down as may be necessary for safe\noperation;\n  3. Exceed the maximum speed limits so long as he does not endanger\nlife or property;\n  4. Disregard regulations governing directions of movement or turning\nin specified directions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except for an authorized emergency vehicle operated as a police\nvehicle or bicycle, the exemptions herein granted to an authorized\nemergency vehicle shall apply only when audible signals are sounded from\nany said vehicle while in motion by bell, horn, siren, electronic device\nor exhaust whistle as may be reasonably necessary, and when the vehicle\nis equipped with at least one lighted lamp so that from any direction,\nunder normal atmospheric conditions from a distance of five hundred feet\nfrom such vehicle, at least one red light will be displayed and visible.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authorized emergency vehicle operated as a police, sheriff or\ndeputy sheriff vehicle may exceed the maximum speed limits for the\npurpose of calibrating such vehicles' speedometer. Notwithstanding any\nother law, rule or regulation to the contrary, a police, sheriff or\ndeputy sheriff bicycle operated as an authorized emergency vehicle shall\nnot be prohibited from using any sidewalk, highway, street or roadway\nduring an emergency operation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The foregoing provisions shall not relieve the driver of an\nauthorized emergency vehicle from the duty to drive with due regard for\nthe safety of all persons, nor shall such provisions protect the driver\nfrom the consequences of his reckless disregard for the safety of\nothers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1104__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other law, rule or regulation to the contrary,\nan ambulance operated in the course of an emergency shall not be\nprohibited from using any highway, street or roadway; provided, however,\nthat an authority having jurisdiction over any such highway, street or\nroadway may specifically prohibit travel thereon by ambulances if such\nauthority shall deem such travel to be extremely hazardous and would\nendanger patients being transported thereby.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>