<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1111"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1111">
        <num>1111</num>
        <heading>Traffic-control signal indications</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1111__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Green indications:\n  1. Traffic, except pedestrians, facing a steady circular green signal\nmay proceed straight through or turn right or left unless a sign at such\nplace prohibits either such turn. Such traffic, including when turning\nright or left, shall yield the right of way to other traffic lawfully\nwithin the intersection or an adjacent crosswalk at the time such signal\nis exhibited.\n  2. Traffic, except pedestrians, facing a steady green arrow signal may\ncautiously enter the intersection only to make the movement indicated by\nsuch arrow, or such other movement as is permitted by other indications\nshown at the same time, except that a U-Turn may be made by traffic\nfacing a left green arrow signal unless a sign prohibits such U-Turn or\nsuch U-Turn is in violation of any other provision of law. Such traffic\nshall yield the right of way to other traffic lawfully within the\nintersection or an adjacent cross walk at the time such signal is\nexhibited.\n  3. Unless otherwise directed by a pedestrian-control signal as\nprovided in section eleven hundred twelve, pedestrians facing any steady\ngreen signal, except when the sole green signal is a turn arrow, may\nproceed across the roadway within any marked or unmarked crosswalk.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1111__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Yellow indications:\n  1. Traffic, except pedestrians, facing a steady circular yellow signal\nmay enter the intersection; however, said traffic is thereby warned that\nthe related green movement is being terminated or that a red indication\nwill be exhibited immediately thereafter.\n  2. Traffic, except pedestrians, facing a steady yellow arrow signal\nmay cautiously enter the intersection only to complete the movement\nindicated by such arrow or make such other movement as is permitted by\nother indications shown at the same time; however, said traffic is\nthereby warned that the related green arrow movement is being terminated\nor that a red indication will be exhibited immediately thereafter.\n  3. Unless otherwise directed by a pedestrian-control signal as\nprovided in section eleven hundred twelve, pedestrians facing any steady\nyellow signal are thereby advised that there is insufficient time to\ncross the roadway before a red indication is shown and no pedestrian\nshall then start to cross the roadway.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1111__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Red indications:\n  1. Traffic, except pedestrians, facing a steady circular red signal,\nunless to make such other movement as is permitted by other indications\nshown at the same time, shall stop at a clearly marked stop line, but if\nnone, then shall stop before entering the crosswalk on the near side of\nthe intersection, or in the event there is no crosswalk, at the point\nnearest the intersecting roadway where the driver has a view of the\napproaching traffic on the intersecting roadway before entering the\nintersection and shall remain standing until an indication to proceed is\nshown except as provided in paragraph two of this subdivision.\n  2. Except in a city having a population of one million or more, unless\na sign is in place prohibiting such turn:\n  a. Traffic facing a steady circular red signal may cautiously enter\nthe intersection to make a right turn after stopping as required by\nparagraph one of this subdivision, except that right turning traffic is\nnot required to stop when a steady right green arrow signal is shown at\nthe same time. Such traffic shall yield the right-of-way to pedestrians\nwithin a marked or unmarked crosswalk at the intersection and to other\ntraffic lawfully using the intersection;\n  b. Traffic, while on a one-way roadway, facing a steady red signal may\ncautiously enter the intersection to make a left turn onto a one-way\nroadway after stopping as required by paragraph one of this subdivision.\nSuch traffic shall yield the right-of-way to pedestrians within a marked\nor unmarked crosswalk at the intersection and to other traffic lawfully\nusing the intersection.\n  c. On or after the effective date of this subparagraph, the sign which\nprohibits such turn shall be prominently displayed from all newly\ninstalled traffic signals where possible.\n  Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any city having a\npopulation of one million or more, is hereby authorized and empowered to\nadopt a local law authorizing subparagra...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1111__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Traffic shall obey signs requiring obedience to traffic-control\nsignals at intersections other than those at which such signals are\nlocated. No intersection not controlled by such signs prior to the\neffective date of this section shall hereafter be made subject to such\nmethod of control and no ordinance, order, rule or regulation requiring\nsuch obedience shall hereafter be adopted.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1111__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event an official traffic-control signal is erected and\nmaintained at a place other than an intersection, the provisions of this\nsection shall be applicable except as to those provisions which by their\nnature can have no application. Any stop required shall be made at a\nsign or marking on the pavement indicating where the stop shall be made,\nbut in the absence of any such sign or marking the stop shall be made at\nthe signal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>