<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1120"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1120">
        <num>1120</num>
        <heading>Drive on right side of roadway; exceptions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1120__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon all\nroadways of sufficient width a vehicle shall be driven upon the right\nhalf of the roadway, except as follows:\n  1. When overtaking and passing another vehicle proceeding in the same\ndirection under the rules governing such movement;\n  2. When overtaking or passing bicyclists, pedestrians, animals or\nobstructions on the right half of the roadway;\n  3. When an obstruction exists making it necessary to drive to the left\nof the center of the highway; provided, any person so doing shall yield\nthe right of way to all vehicles traveling in the proper direction upon\nthe unobstructed portion of the highway within such distance as to\nconstitute an immediate hazard;\n  4. Where travel on the shoulder or slope is permitted by section\neleven hundred thirty-one of this article;\n  5. Upon a roadway divided into three marked lanes for traffic under\nthe rules applicable thereon; or\n  6. Upon a roadway restricted to one-way traffic.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1120__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition, upon all roadways, any vehicle proceeding at less\nthan the normal speed of traffic at the time and place and under the\nconditions then existing shall be driven in the right-hand lane then\navailable for traffic, or as close as practicable to the right-hand curb\nor edge of the roadway, except when overtaking and passing another\nvehicle proceeding in the same direction or when preparing for a left\nturn at an intersection or into a private road or driveway.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1120__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon any roadway having four or more lanes for moving traffic and\nproviding for two way movement of traffic, no vehicle shall be driven to\nthe left of the center line of the roadway, except when authorized by\nsigns or markings designating certain lanes to the left side of the\ncenter of the roadway for use by traffic not otherwise permitted to use\nsuch lanes, or except as permitted under subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1120__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1120__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>hereof.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>