<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1160"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1160"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1160"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1160">
        <num>1160</num>
        <heading>Required position and method of turning at intersections</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Right turns. Both the approach for a right turn and a right turn\nshall be made as close as practicable to the right hand curb or edge of\nthe roadway or, where travel on the shoulder or slope has been\nauthorized, from the shoulder or slope.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Left turns on two-way roadways. At any intersection where traffic\nis permitted to move in both directions on each roadway entering the\nintersection, an approach for a left turn shall be made in that portion\nof the right half of the roadway nearest the center line thereof and by\npassing to the right of such center line where it enters the\nintersection and after entering the intersection the left turn shall be\nmade so as to leave the intersection to the right of the center line of\nthe roadway being entered. Whenever practicable the left turn shall be\nmade in that portion of the intersection to the left of the center of\nthe intersection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Left turns on other than two-way roadways. At any intersection\nwhere traffic is restricted to one direction on one or more of the\nroadways, the driver of a vehicle intending to turn left at any such\nintersection shall approach the intersection in the extreme left-hand\nlane of the roadway lawfully available to traffic moving in the\ndirection of travel of such vehicle or, where travel on the shoulder or\nslope has been authorized, from the shoulder or slope, and after\nentering the intersection the left turn shall be made so as to leave the\nintersection, as nearly as practicable, in the left-hand lane lawfully\navailable to traffic moving in such direction upon the roadway being\nentered.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When markers, buttons, signs, or other markings are placed within\nor adjacent to intersections and thereby require and direct that a\ndifferent course from that specified in this section be traveled by\nvehicles turning at an intersection, no driver of a vehicle shall turn a\nvehicle at an intersection other than as directed and required by such\nmarkers, buttons, signs, or other markings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1160__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>U-turns. U-turns shall be made from and to that portion of the\nhighway nearest the marked center line. Where more than one lane of a\nhighway has been designated for left turns, U-turns shall be made only\nfrom the lane so designated that is adjacent to the marked center line.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>