<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1161"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1161"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-02-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1161"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1161/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1161/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1161/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1161/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1161">
        <num>1161</num>
        <heading>U turns in certain areas prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1161. U turns in certain areas prohibited. a. No motor vehicle shall\nmake a U turn upon any curve, or upon the approach to, or near the crest\nof a grade, where such motor vehicle cannot be seen by the driver of any\nother motor vehicle approaching from either direction within five\nhundred feet.\n  b. No motor vehicle shall make a U turn within a school zone. For the\npurposes of this subdivision, the term "school zone" shall mean the\ndistance along a highway passing a school building, entrance or exit of\na school abutting on the highway for which a school sign (S1-1) has been\nposted pursuant to this chapter and in compliance with the manual on\nuniform traffic control devices maintained pursuant to section sixteen\nhundred eighty of this chapter.\n  c. No altered motor vehicle commonly referred to as a "stretch\nlimousine" having a seating capacity of nine or more passengers\nincluding the driver shall make a U-turn upon any public highway or\nprivate road open to public motor vehicle traffic. Every person\nconvicted of a violation of this subdivision shall: for a first\nconviction thereof, be punished by a fine of not less than two hundred\nfifty dollars nor more than four hundred dollars or by imprisonment for\nnot more than fifteen days or by both such fine and imprisonment; for a\nconviction of a second or subsequent violation, both of which were\ncommitted within a period of eighteen months, such person shall be\npunished by a fine of not less than six hundred dollars nor more than\nseven hundred fifty dollars or by imprisonment for not more than\nforty-five days or by both such fine and imprisonment. A violation of\nthis subdivision wherein the violator is operating such altered motor\nvehicle and such altered motor vehicle is carrying at least one\npassenger other than the driver shall be punishable by a fine of not\nless than seven hundred fifty dollars nor more than one thousand dollars\nor by imprisonment for not more than one hundred eighty days or by both\nsuch fine and imprisonment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>