<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1182-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1182_A">
        <num>1182-A</num>
        <heading>Multi-jurisdictional speed contests, races and similar special events</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1182-a. Multi-jurisdictional speed contests, races and similar\nspecial events. 1. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the\ncontrary, the department of transportation may, by order, rule or\nregulation, prohibit or regulate races, speed contests, exhibitions of\nspeed or other similar special events which are held on public highways\nin more than one county. Participants in an approved race, contest, or\nexhibition are exempted from compliance with any traffic laws otherwise\napplicable thereto, but shall exercise reasonable care. Such rules and\nregulations shall include, among other things, provision for adequate\ninsurance coverage; provision for approval by the municipalities\ninvolved; provision for payment or reimbursement of all the costs and\nexpenses of the state which are incurred in connection with such an\nevent; provision for assumption of risk for damages or claims by the\norganizer, sponsor, driver, rider or participant in such event;\nprovision for the closure of or restriction on public use and travel\nupon highways or parts thereof for a certain period of time whenever the\nstate or local police determine such is necessary to protect the public\nsafety, security, or convenience.  Prior to the scheduled date of a\nproposed multi-jurisdictional race, speed contest, exhibition of speed\nor other similar special event, the sponsor or organizer shall apply, in\nwriting, to the department of transportation for consideration of and\nauthorization to conduct such an event. Such application shall be\nreviewed by the commissioner of transportation, the commissioner of\neconomic development and the superintendent of state police, or their\ndesignees. Only if such persons unanimously agree that the proposed\nevent should take place, the department of transportation shall continue\nthe review process and shall establish such reasonable requirements as\nare necessary to protect the public safety.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, no\nperson or entity shall have the right to bring an action against the\nstate or municipality or any person employed by the state or\nmunicipality who was acting within the scope of his authority for\ndamages resulting from or in connection with any such race, contest or\nexhibition. In the event of any such claim being brought against any\nsuch individual employed by the state, the provisions of section\nseventeen of the public officers law shall apply.\n  3. The division of state police and the department of commerce are\nhereby authorized to provide necessary support and assistance to the\ndepartment of transportation in connection with its power to prohibit or\nregulate races, speed contests, exhibitions of speed or other similar\nspecial events pursuant to this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>