<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1182-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1182-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1182_B">
        <num>1182-B</num>
        <heading>Filming of movies, commercials and similar events</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1182-b. Filming of movies, commercials and similar events. 1.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\ndepartment of transportation may, by order, rule or regulation, prohibit\nor regulate the filming of movies, commercials and similar events on\nstate highways. Such rules and regulations shall include, among other\nthings, provision for adequate insurance coverage; provision for\nconsultation by the production company of any movie, commercial or\nsimilar events with the municipality involved; provision for payment or\nreimbursement of all of the costs and expenses of the state which are\nincurred in connection with such an event; provision for assumption of\nrisk for damages or claims by the production company, its employees and\nparticipants in such event; provision for the closure of or restriction\non public use and travel upon highways or parts thereof for a certain\nperiod of time whenever the state police determine such is necessary to\nprotect the public safety, security, or convenience. Prior to the\nscheduled date of the filming of a movie, commercial or other similar\nevents, the production company shall apply, in writing, to the\ndepartment of transportation for consideration of and authorization to\nfilm such an event. Such application shall be reviewed by the\ncommissioner of transportation, or his designee, the commissioner of\ncommerce, or his designee, and the superintendent of state police, or\nhis designee.  Only if such persons unanimously agree that the proposed\nfilming should take place, the department of transportation shall\ncontinue the review process and shall establish such reasonable\nrequirements as are necessary to protect the public safety.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, no\nperson or entity shall have the right to bring an action against the\nstate or municipality or any person employed by the state or\nmunicipality who was acting within the scope of his authority for\ndamages resulting from or in connection with the filming of a movie,\ncommercial or similar events. In the event of any such claim being\nbrought against any such individual employed by the state, the\nprovisions of section seventeen of the public officers law shall apply.\n  3. The division of state police and department of commerce are hereby\nauthorized to provide necessary support and assistance to the department\nof transportation in connection with its power to prohibit or regulate\nthe filming of movies, commercials or other similar events pursuant to\nthis section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>