<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1196"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1196"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1196"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1196/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1196/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1196/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1196/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1196">
        <num>1196</num>
        <heading>Alcohol and drug rehabilitation program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section eleven hundred ninety-three\nor in subparagraph three of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section\neleven hundred ninety-four of this article, upon successful completion\nof a course in such program as certified by its administrator, a\nparticipant may apply to the commissioner on a form provided for that\npurpose, for the termination of the suspension or revocation order\nissued as a result of the participant's conviction which caused the\nparticipation in such course. In the exercise of discretion, upon\nreceipt of such application, and upon payment of any civil penalties for\nwhich the applicant may be liable, the commissioner is authorized to\nterminate such order or orders and return the participant's license or\nreinstate the privilege of operating a motor vehicle in this state.\nHowever, the commissioner shall not issue any new license nor restore\nany license where said issuance of restoral is prohibited by subdivision\ntwo of section eleven hundred ninety-three of this article.\n  6. Fees. The commissioner shall establish a schedule of fees to be\npaid by or on behalf of each participant in the program, and may, from\ntime to time, modify same. Such fees shall defray the ongoing expenses\nof the program. Provided, however, that pursuant to an agreement with\nthe department a municipality, department thereof, or other agency may\nconduct a course in such program with all or part of the expense of such\ncourse and program being borne by such municipality, department or\nagency. In no event shall such fee be refundable, either for reasons of\nthe participant's withdrawal or expulsion from such program or\notherwise.\n  7. Conditional license.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision\nof this chapter, participants in the program, except those penalized\nunder paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section eleven hundred\nninety-three of this article for any violation of subdivision two,\nthree, or four of section eleven hundred ninety-two of this article,\nmay, in the commissioner's discretion, be issued a conditional driver's\nlicense, or if the holder of a license issued by another jurisdiction\nvalid for operation in this state, a conditional privilege of operating\na motor vehicle in this state. Such a conditional license or privilege\nshall be valid only for use, by the holder thereof,</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>enroute to and\nfrom the holder's place of employment,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if the holder's employment\nrequires the operation of a motor vehicle then during the hours thereof,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>enroute to and from a class or an activity which is an authorized\npart of the alcohol and drug rehabilitation program and at which his\nattendance is required,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>enroute to and from a class or course at an\naccredited school, college or university or at a state approved\ninstitution of vocational or technical training,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to or from court\nordered probation activities,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to and from a motor vehicle office for\nthe transaction of business relating to such license or program,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for\na three hour consecutive daytime period, chosen by the administrators of\nthe program, on a day during which the participant is not engaged in\nusual employment or vocation,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>enroute to and from a medical\nexamination or treatment as part of a necessary medical treatment for\nsuch participant or member of the participant's household, as evidenced\nby a written statement to that effect from a licensed medical\npractitioner, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1196__subsec_d__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>enroute to and from a place, including a school,\nat which a child or children of the holder are cared for on a regular\nbasis and which is necessary for the holder to maintain such holder's\nemployment or enrollment at an accredited school, college or university\nor at a state approved institution of vocational or technical training.\nSuch license or privilege shall remain in effect during the term of the\nsuspension or revocation of the participant's license or privilege\nunless earlier revoked by the commissioner.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The conditional license or privilege described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision shall be in a form prescribed by the commissioner, and\nshall have indicated thereon the conditions imposed by such paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receipt of a conditional license issued pursuant to this\nsection, any order issued by a judge, justice or magistrate pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section eleven hundred ninety-three\nof this article shall be surrendered to the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall require applicants for a conditional\nlicense to pay a fee of seventy-five dollars for processing costs. Such\nfees assessed under this subdivision shall be paid to the commissioner\nfor deposit to the general fund and shall be in addition to any fees\nestablished by the commissioner pursuant to subdivision six of this\nsection to defray the costs of the alcohol and drug rehabilitation\nprogram.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The conditional license or privileges described in this\nsubdivision may be revoked by the commissioner, for sufficient cause\nincluding, but not limited to, failure to register in the program,\nfailure to attend or satisfactorily participate in the sessions,\nconviction of any traffic infraction other than one involving parking,\nstopping or standing or conviction of any alcohol or drug-related\ntraffic offense, misdemeanor or felony. In addition, the commissioner\nshall have the right, after a hearing, to revoke the conditional license\nor privilege upon receiving notification or evidence that the offender\nis not attempting in good faith to accept rehabilitation. In the event\nof such revocation, the fee described in subdivision six of this section\nshall not be refunded.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be a traffic infraction for the holder of a conditional\nlicense or privilege to operate a motor vehicle upon a public highway\nfor any use other than those authorized pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision. When a person is convicted of this offense, the\nsentence of the court must be a fine of not less than two hundred\ndollars nor more than five hundred dollars or a term of imprisonment of\nnot more than fifteen days or both such fine and imprisonment.\nAdditionally, the conditional license or privileges described in this\nsubdivision shall be revoked by the commissioner upon receiving\nnotification from the court that the holder thereof has been convicted\nof this offense.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained in a\ncertificate of relief from disabilities or a certificate of good conduct\nissued pursuant to article twenty-three of the correction law, any\nconditional license or privilege issued to a person convicted of a\nviolation of any subdivision of section eleven hundred ninety-two of\nthis article shall not be valid for the operation of any commercial\nmotor vehicle. In addition, no such conditional license or privilege\nshall be valid for the operation of a taxicab as defined in this\nchapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this chapter, the\nconditional license described in this subdivision may, pursuant to\nregulations established by the commissioner, be issued to a person whose\nlicense has been suspended pending prosecution pursuant to subparagraph\nseven of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1196__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section eleven hundred\nninety-three of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>