<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1203-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1203_B">
        <num>1203-B</num>
        <heading>Parking spaces; handicapped</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1203-b. Parking spaces; handicapped. 1. Parking spaces for the\nhandicapped as provided for in sections one thousand two hundred three-a\nand one thousand two hundred three-c of this chapter shall also be\nextended to a motor vehicle registered in accordance with section four\nhundred four-a of this chapter. A handicapped permit issued in\naccordance with the provisions of section one thousand two hundred\nthree-a of this chapter shall entitle the driver to park in such parking\nspaces. Parking spaces for the handicapped shall be those parking spaces\naccorded to a holder of a handicapped parking permit provided in\naccordance with section one thousand two hundred three-a or as provided\nin section four hundred four-a of this chapter.\n  2. It shall be a violation for any person to stop, stand or park a\nvehicle in any area designated as a place for handicapped parking unless\nthe vehicle bears a permit issued under section one thousand two hundred\nthree-a or a registration issued under section four hundred four-a of\nthis chapter and such vehicle is being used for the transportation of a\nseverely disabled or handicapped person. This subdivision shall not\napply to a violation of section twelve hundred three-c of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>