<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1203-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1203-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1203_H">
        <num>1203-H</num>
        <heading>Metered parking waiver for certain disabilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section sixteen hundred forty of\nthis chapter or imposed by such town pursuant to paragraph nine of\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section sixteen hundred sixty of this chapter.\nProvided, however, that such permit shall not waive any time limit at a\nmetered parking space imposed pursuant to paragraph nine of subdivision\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section sixteen hundred forty of this chapter or paragraph nine\nof subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section sixteen hundred sixty of this chapter that\nis applicable to a motor vehicle parking in such metered parking space\nwithout such permit.\n  2. The application, permit design, period of validity, and procedures\nfor reissuance of such waiver permits shall be as determined by the\ncommissioner.\n  3. Such waiver permits shall be issued by issuing agents appointed\npursuant to subdivision one of section twelve hundred three-a of this\narticle by governing bodies of cities, villages and towns having a\npopulation of less than one million to persons with disabilities who:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are residents of New York state; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are residents of the city, town or village in which such issuing\nagent is located, except that, an issuing agent, in his or her\ndiscretion, may issue a permit to a severely disabled person who is not\na resident of the city, town, or village in which such issuing agent is\nlocated where such person resides in a city, town, or village in which\nthe governing body has not appointed an issuing agent; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hold a valid driver's license issued by New York state; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are severely disabled persons, as defined in subdivision four of\nsection four hundred four-a of this chapter, whose severe disability, as\ncertified by a licensed physician, limits one or more of the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fine motor control in both hands;\n  (ii) ability to reach or access a parking meter due to use of a\nwheelchair or other ambulatory device; or\n  (iii) ability to reach a height of forty-two inches from the ground\ndue to the lack of finger, hand or upper extremity strength or mobility.\n  4. For the purposes of this section, such waiver permit shall be for\nuse exclusively in a vehicle when the person to whom it has been issued\nis driving and unaccompanied by a person able to put payment into a\nparking meter. Such permit shall not be transferable and shall be\nforfeited if used by any other person. Any abuse by any person to whom\nsuch waiver permit has been issued shall be sufficient cause for\nrevocation of said permit.\n  5. The special metered parking waiver permit issued by the\ncommissioner shall be recognized statewide and is the only valid permit,\nother than a special vehicle identification parking permit issued by\ncities having a population of one million or more pursuant to paragraph\nfifteen of subdivision a of section twenty-nine hundred three of the New\nYork city charter, for the waiver of metered parking fees for certain\nseverely disabled drivers.\n  6. A person who knowingly and willfully, with the intent to deceive,\nmakes a false statement or gives information which such individual knows\nto be false to a public official to obtain a metered parking waiver\npermit in addition to any other penalty provided by law, shall be\nsubject to a civil penalty of not less than two hundred fifty dollars\nnor more than one thousand dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>