<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1220"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1220">
        <num>1220</num>
        <heading>Throwing refuse on highways and adjacent lands prohibited</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1220__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nNo person shall throw, dump, deposit or place, or cause to be thrown,\ndumped, deposited or placed upon any highway, or within the limits of\nthe right of way of such highway, or upon private lands adjacent\nthereto, any refuse, trash, garbage, rubbish, litter or any nauseous or\noffensive matter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1220__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing herein contained shall be construed as prohibiting the use\nin a reasonable manner of ashes, sand, salt or other material for the\npurpose of reducing the hazard of, or providing traction on snow, ice or\nsleet.\n  (b-1) Nothing herein contained shall be construed as prohibiting the\nuse of any highway or private lands adjacent thereto for the transport\nor transit of agricultural trucks, machines or implements or dairy or\ndomestic animals or agricultural stock with any accompanying reasonable\nor unavoidable deposit of nauseous or offensive matter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1220__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A violation of the provisions of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1220__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section\nshall be punishable by a fine not to exceed three hundred fifty dollars\nand/or a requirement to perform services for a public or not-for-profit\ncorporation, association, institution or agency not to exceed ten hours\nand for any second or subsequent violation by a fine not to exceed seven\nhundred dollars and/or a requirement to perform services for a public or\nnot-for-profit corporation, association, institution or agency not to\nexceed fifteen hours.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>