<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1234"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1234"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1234"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1234">
        <num>1234</num>
        <heading>Riding on roadways, shoulders, bicycle or in-line skate lanes and bicycle or in-line skate paths</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1234__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon all roadways, any bicycle\nor in-line skate shall be driven either on a usable bicycle or in-line\nskate lane or, if a usable bicycle or in-line skate lane has not been\nprovided, near the right-hand curb or edge of the roadway or upon a\nusable right-hand shoulder in such a manner as to prevent undue\ninterference with the flow of traffic except when preparing for a left\nturn or when reasonably necessary to avoid conditions that would make it\nunsafe to continue along near the right-hand curb or edge. Conditions to\nbe taken into consideration include, but are not limited to, fixed or\nmoving objects, vehicles, bicycles, in-line skates, pedestrians,\nanimals, surface hazards or traffic lanes too narrow for a bicycle or\nperson on in-line skates and a vehicle to travel safely side-by-side\nwithin the lane.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1234__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Persons riding bicycles or skating or gliding on in-line skates\nupon a roadway shall not ride more than two abreast. Persons riding\nbicycles or skating or gliding on in-line skates upon a shoulder,\nbicycle or in-line skate lane, or bicycle or in-line skates path,\nintended for the use of bicycles or in-line skates may ride two or more\nabreast if sufficient space is available, except that when passing a\nvehicle, bicycle or person on in-line skates, or pedestrian, standing or\nproceeding along such shoulder, lane or path, persons riding bicycles or\nskating or gliding on in-line skates shall ride, skate, or glide single\nfile. Persons riding bicycles or skating or gliding on in-line skates\nupon a roadway shall ride, skate, or glide single file when being\novertaken by a vehicle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1234__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person operating a bicycle or skating or gliding on in-line\nskates who is entering the roadway from a private road, driveway, alley\nor over a curb shall come to a full stop before entering the roadway.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>