<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1238"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1238"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1238"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1238/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1238/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1238/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1238/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1238">
        <num>1238</num>
        <heading>Passengers on bicycles under one year of age prohibited; passengers and operators under fourteen years of age to wear protective headgear...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such passenger is wearing a helmet meeting standards established\nby the commissioner. For the purposes of this subdivision wearing a\nhelmet means having a helmet of good fit fastened securely upon the head\nwith the helmet straps; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such passenger is placed in a separate seat attached to the\nbicycle and such seat shall have adequate provision for retaining the\npassenger in place and for protecting the passenger from the moving\nparts of the bicycle.\n  2-a. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations\nestablishing standards for helmets required to be worn while bicycling,\nin-line skating, or operating a skate board. Such standards, to the\nextent practicable, shall reflect the standards recommended by the Snell\nMemorial Foundation, Safety Equipment Institute, or United States\nConsumer Product Safety Commission.\n  3. Any person who violates the provisions of subdivision two of this\nsection shall pay a civil fine not to exceed fifty dollars.\n  4. The court shall waive any fine for which a person who violates the\nprovisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section would be\nliable if such person supplies the court with proof that between the\ndate of violation and the appearance date for such violation such person\npurchased or rented a helmet, which meets the requirements of paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section. Further, the court shall waive\nany fine for which a person who violates the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision two of this section would be liable if such person\nsupplies the court with proof that between the date of violation and the\nappearance date for such violation such person purchased or rented a\nseat which meets the requirements of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of\nthis section. The court may waive any fine for which a person who\nviolates the provisions of subdivision two of this section would be\nliable if the court finds that due to reasons of economic hardship such\nperson was unable to purchase a helmet or seat. Such waiver of fine\nshall not apply to a second or subsequent conviction under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nor</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section.\n  5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person operating a bicycle shall allow a person five or more\nyears of age and less than fourteen years of age to ride as a passenger\non a bicycle unless such passenger is wearing a helmet meeting standards\nestablished by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person, one or more years of age and less than fourteen years\nof age, shall operate a bicycle unless such person is wearing a helmet\nmeeting standards established by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this subdivision wearing a helmet means having\na helmet of good fit fastened securely upon the head with the helmet\nstraps.\n  5-a. No person, one or more years of age and less than fourteen years\nof age, shall skate or glide on in-line skates or a skate board unless\nsuch person is wearing a helmet meeting standards established by the\ncommissioner. For the purposes of this subdivision, wearing a helmet\nmeans having a helmet of good fit fastened securely on the head of such\nwearer with the helmet straps securely fastened.\n  5-b. No person less than fourteen years of age shall ride upon, propel\nor otherwise operate a two-wheeled vehicle commonly called a scooter\nunless such person is wearing a helmet meeting standards established by\nthe commissioner. As used in this subdivision, wearing a helmet means\nhaving a properly fitting helmet fixed securely on the head of such\nwearer with the helmet straps securely fastened.\n  5-c. No person shall ride upon, propel or otherwise operate a class\nthree bicycle with electric assist unless such person is wearing a\nhelmet meeting standards established by the commissioner. For the\npurposes of this subdivision, wearing a helmet means having a properly\nfitting helmet fixed securely on the head of such wearer with the helmet\nstraps securely fastened.\n  6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who violates the provisions of subdivision five,\nfive-a, five-b or five-c of this section shall pay a civil fine not to\nexceed fifty dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall waive any fine for which a person who violates the\nprovisions of subdivision five or subdivision five-c of this section\nwould be liable if such person supplies the court with proof that\nbetween the date of violation and the appearance date for such violation\nsuch person purchased or rented a helmet.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may waive any fine for which a person who violates the\nprovisions of subdivision five, five-a, five-b, or five-c of this\nsection would be liable if the court finds that due to reasons of\neconomic hardship such person was unable to purchase a helmet or due to\nsuch economic hardship such person was unable to obtain a helmet from\nthe statewide in-line skate and bicycle helmet distribution program, as\nestablished in section two hundred six of the public health law, or a\nlocal distribution program. Such waiver of a fine shall not apply to a\nsecond or subsequent violation of subdivision five-c of this section.\n  7. The failure of any person to comply with the provisions of this\nsection shall not constitute contributory negligence or assumption of\nrisk, and shall not in any way bar, preclude or foreclose an action for\npersonal injury or wrongful death by or on behalf of such person, nor in\nany way diminish or reduce the damages recoverable in any such action.\n  8.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A police officer shall only issue a summons for a violation of\nsubdivision two, five, or five-a of this section by a person less than\nfourteen years of age to the parent or guardian of such person if the\nviolation by such person occurs in the presence of such person's parent\nor guardian and where such parent or guardian is eighteen years of age\nor more. Such summons shall only be issued to such parent or guardian,\nand shall not be issued to the person less than fourteen years of age.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1238__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A police officer shall only issue a summons for a violation of\nsubdivision five-c of this section by a person less than sixteen years\nof age to the parent or guardian of such person if the violation by such\nperson occurs in the presence of such person's parent or guardian and\nwhere such parent or guardian is eighteen years of age or more. Such\nsummons shall only be issued to such parent or guardian, and shall not\nbe issued to the person less than sixteen years of age.\n  9. Subdivisions five, five-a, five-b, and six of this section shall\nnot be applicable to any county, city, town or village that has enacted\na local law or ordinance prior to the effective date of this subdivision\nthat prohibits a person who is one or more years of age and less than\nfourteen years of age from operating a bicycle or skating or gliding on\nin-line skates or a skate board without wearing a bicycle helmet meeting\nthe standards of the American National Standards Institute (Ansi Z 90.4\nbicycle helmet standards), the Snell Memorial Foundation's Standards for\nProtective Headgear for use in Bicycling, or the American Society of\nTesting and Materials (ASTM) bike helmet standards, or that prohibits a\nperson operating a bicycle from allowing a person five or more years of\nage and less than fourteen years of age to ride as a passenger on a\nbicycle unless such passenger is wearing a bicycle helmet that meets\nsuch standards. The failure of any person to comply with any such local\nlaw or ordinance shall not constitute contributory negligence or\nassumption of risk, and shall not in any way bar, preclude or foreclose\nan action for personal injury or wrongful death by or on behalf of such\nperson, nor in any way diminish or reduce the damages recoverable in any\nsuch action. The legislative body of a county, city, town or village may\nenact a local law or ordinance that prohibits a person who is fourteen\nor more years of age from skating or gliding on in-line skates,\noperating a ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>