<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1241"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1241"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1241"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1241/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1241/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1241/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1241/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1241">
        <num>1241</num>
        <heading>Leaving the scene of an incident involving a wheeled non-motorized means of conveyance without reporting in the first degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1241. Leaving the scene of an incident involving a wheeled\nnon-motorized means of conveyance without reporting in the first degree.\n1. Any person age eighteen years or older operating a wheeled\nnon-motorized means of conveyance, including, but not limited to\nbicycles, in-line skates, roller skates and skate boards, who, knowing\nor having cause to know, that serious physical injury, as defined in\nsubdivision ten of section 10.00 of the penal law, has been caused to\nanother person, due to the operation of such non-motorized means of\nconveyance by such person, shall, before leaving the place where the\nsaid serious physical injury occurred, stop, and provide his name and\nresidence, including street and street number, to the injured party, if\npractical, and also to a police officer, or in the event that no police\nofficer is in the vicinity of the place of said injury, then such person\nshall report said incident as soon as physically able to the nearest\npolice station or judicial officer.\n  2. Leaving the scene of an incident involving a wheeled non-motorized\nmeans of conveyance without reporting in the first degree is a class B\nmisdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>