<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1272"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1272"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1272"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1272/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1272/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1272/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1272/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1272">
        <num>1272</num>
        <heading>Operating electric personal assistive mobility devices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1272. Operating electric personal assistive mobility devices. 1. No\nelectric personal assistive mobility device shall be used to carry more\npersons at one time than the number for which such device is designed\nand equipped. No person operating an electric personal assistive\nmobility device shall carry any person as a passenger in a pack fastened\nto the operator or fastened to such device.\n  2. No person shall operate an electric personal assistive mobility\ndevice outside during the period of time between one-half hour after\nsunset and one-half hour before sunrise unless such person is wearing\nreadily visible reflective clothing or material which is of a light or\nbright color.\n  3. No person operating an electric personal assistive mobility device\nshall carry any package, bundle or article which prevents the operator\nfrom keeping at least one hand upon the handle bars or which obstructs\nhis or her vision in any direction.\n  4. Every person operating an electric personal assistive mobility\ndevice shall yield the right of way to pedestrians and motor vehicles.\n  5. Every operator of an electric personal assistive mobility device\nshall be sixteen years of age or older.\n  6. No person shall operate an electric personal assistive mobility\ndevice in a state park or historic site.\n  7. If the governing body of any county not wholly included within a\ncity, city with a population of less than one million, town or village\nshall authorize the use of electric personal assistive mobility devices\nupon any sidewalk, such authorization shall not permit the operation\nthereof at a speed in excess of eight miles per hour. Additionally, if\nsuch authorization is granted, no operator of an electric personal\nassistive mobility device shall overtake a pedestrian on a sidewalk\nunless there is adequate space for the personal assistive mobility\ndevice to pass around the pedestrian and warning is given to such\npedestrian through the audible device defined in subdivision two of\nsection twelve hundred seventy-five of this article.\n  8. A first violation of the provisions of this section shall result in\nno fine. A second or subsequent violation shall result in a civil fine\nnot to exceed fifty dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>