<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1274"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1274"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1274"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1274/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1274/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1274/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1274/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1274">
        <num>1274</num>
        <heading>Riding on roadways, shoulders and lanes reserved for non-motorized vehicles and devices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1274. Riding on roadways, shoulders and lanes reserved for\nnon-motorized vehicles and devices. 1. Upon all roadways, any electric\npersonal assistive mobility device shall be operated either on a usable\nbicycle or in-line skate lane or, if a usable bicycle or in-line skate\nlane has not been provided, near the right-hand curb or edge of the\nroadway or upon a usable right-hand shoulder in such a manner as to\nprevent undue interference with the flow of traffic except when\npreparing to enter into a crosswalk to turn left at or to cross an\nintersection or when reasonably necessary to avoid conditions that would\nmake it unsafe to continue along near the right-hand curb or edge of the\nroadway. Conditions to be taken into consideration include, but are not\nlimited to, fixed or moving objects, vehicles, bicycles, in-line\nskaters, pedestrians, animals, surface hazards and traffic lanes too\nnarrow for an electric personal assistive mobility device and a vehicle\nto travel safely side-by-side within the lane.\n  2. Persons operating electric personal assistive mobility devices upon\na roadway shall ride single file. Persons operating electric personal\nassistive mobility devices upon a shoulder, bicycle or in-line skate\nlane, or bicycle or in-line skate path, intended for the use of\nbicycles, electric personal assistive mobility devices or in-line skates\nmay ride two or more abreast if sufficient space is available, except\nthat when passing a vehicle, bicycle, electric personal assistive\nmobility device, person on in-line skates or pedestrian standing or\nproceeding along such shoulder, lane or path, persons operating electric\npersonal assistive mobility devices shall operate such devices in single\nfile.\n  3. Any person operating an electric personal assistive mobility device\nwho is entering the roadway from a private road, driveway, alley or over\na curb shall come to a full stop before entering the roadway.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>