<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1286"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1286"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-08-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1286"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1286/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1286/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1286/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1286/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1286">
        <num>1286</num>
        <heading>Operators to wear protective headgear</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1286. Operators to wear protective headgear. 1. No person sixteen or\nseventeen years of age shall ride upon, propel or otherwise operate an\nelectric scooter unless such person is wearing a helmet meeting\nstandards established by the commissioner pursuant to the provisions of\nsubdivision two-a of section twelve hundred thirty-eight of this title.\nAs used in this subdivision, wearing a helmet means having a properly\nfitting helmet fixed securely on the head of such wearer with the helmet\nstraps securely fastened.\n  2. Any person who violates the provisions of subdivision one of this\nsection shall pay a civil fine not to exceed fifty dollars.\n  3. The court shall waive any fine for which a person who violates the\nprovisions of subdivision one of this section would be liable if such\nperson supplies the court with proof that between the date of violation\nand the appearance date for such violation such person purchased or\nrented a helmet, which meets the requirements of subdivision one of this\nsection, or if the court finds that due to reasons of economic hardship\nsuch person was unable to purchase a helmet or due to such economic\nhardship such person was unable to obtain a helmet from the statewide\nin-line skate and bicycle helmet distribution program, as established in\nsection two hundred six of the public health law or a local distribution\nprogram. Such waiver of fine shall not apply to a second or subsequent\nviolation of subdivision one of this section.\n  4. The failure of any person to comply with the provisions of this\nsection shall not constitute contributory negligence or assumption of\nrisk, and shall not in any way bar, preclude or foreclose an action for\npersonal injury or wrongful death by or on behalf of such person, nor in\nany way diminish or reduce the damages recoverable in any such action.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>