<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1287"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1287"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-08-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1287"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1287/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1287/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1287/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1287/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1287">
        <num>1287</num>
        <heading>Leaving the scene of an incident involving an electric scooter without reporting in the second degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1287. Leaving the scene of an incident involving an electric scooter\nwithout reporting in the second degree. 1. Any person age eighteen years\nor older operating an electric scooter who, knowing or having cause to\nknow, that physical injury, as defined in subdivision nine of section\n10.00 of the penal law, has been caused to another person, due to the\noperation of such electric scooter by such person, shall, before leaving\nthe place where such physical injury occurred, stop, and provide his or\nher name and residence, including street and street number, to the\ninjured party, if practical, and also to a police officer, or in the\nevent that no police officer is in the vicinity of the place of said\ninjury, then such person shall report such incident as soon as\nphysically able to the nearest police station or judicial officer.\n  2. Leaving the scene of an incident involving an electric scooter\nwithout reporting in the second degree is a violation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>