<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1621"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1621"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1621"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1621/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1621/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1621/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1621/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1621">
        <num>1621</num>
        <heading>Other traffic regulations on state highways and on indian reservations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1621__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of transportation with respect to state\nhighways maintained by the state, the intersection of any highway with a\nstate highway maintained by the state, and any highway intersecting or\nmeeting a state highway maintained by the state for a distance not\nexceeding one hundred feet from such state highway maintained by the\nstate, may by order, rule or regulation:\n  1. Designate through highways and order stop signs, flashing signals\nor yield signs erected at specified entrances thereto or designate any\nintersection as a stop intersection or a yield intersection and order\nlike signs or signals at one or more entrances to such intersection.\n  2. Prohibit, restrict or regulate the operation of vehicles on any\ncontrolled-access highway or the use of any controlled-access highway by\nany limited use vehicle, pedestrian, horseback rider or vehicle or\ndevice moved by human or animal power.\n  3. Prohibit or regulate the turning of vehicles or specified types of\nvehicles at intersections or other designated locations.\n  4. Authorize angle parking on any roadway.\n  5. Regulate the crossing of any roadway by pedestrians.\n  6. Upon a roadway which is divided into three lanes, allocate the\ncenter lane exclusively for traffic moving in a specified direction.\n  7. Order signs erected directing slow-moving traffic, trucks, buses or\nspecified types of vehicles to use a designated lane, or with signs,\nsignals or markings designate those lanes to be used by traffic moving\nin a particular direction regardless of the center of the roadway.\n  8. Designate any highway or any separate roadway thereof for one-way\ntraffic.\n  9. Exclude trucks, commercial vehicles, tractors, tractor-trailer\ncombinations, tractor-semitrailer combinations, or\ntractor-trailer-semitrailer combinations from highways specified by the\ncommissioner. Such exclusion shall not be construed to prevent the\ndelivery or pickup of merchandise or other property along the highways\nfrom w...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1621__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of transportation shall cause to be determined, for\nall bridges and elevated structures under its jurisdiction, the capacity\nin tons of two thousand pounds which the bridge or structures will\nsafely carry. At bridges or structures of insufficient strength to carry\nsafely the legal loads permissible by section three hundred eighty-five\nof this chapter, the department of transportation shall cause signs to\nbe erected to inform persons of the safe capacity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1621__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such department of transportation shall cause signs to be erected\nto inform persons of the legal overhead clearance for all bridges and\nelevated structures on highways under its jurisdiction. The legal\nclearance shall be one foot less than the measured clearance. The\nmeasured clearance shall be the minimum height to the bridge or\nstructure measured vertically from the traveled portion of the roadway.\nOn bridges or structures having fourteen feet or more of measured\nclearance, no such signs shall be required.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1621__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of transportation may by order, rule or regulation\ntemporarily exclude from any portion of any state highway and any\nhighway and bridge constructed or to be constructed by the state on any\nindian reservation any vehicle with a gross weight of over four or more\ntons or any vehicle with a gross weight in excess of any designated\nweight on any wheel, axle, any number of axles, or per inch width of\ntire when in its opinion such highway would be materially injured by the\noperation of any such vehicle thereon. Such exclusion shall take effect\nupon the erection of signs on the section of highway from which vehicles\nare excluded, and a notice that such vehicles are excluded shall be\npublished in a newspaper in the county where the highway is situated.\nThe exclusion shall remain in effect until the removal of the signs is\ndirected by the department of transportation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>