<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1624"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1624"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1624"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1624">
        <num>1624</num>
        <heading>Limitation on scope of local speed limits; reports of local speeding convictions to department of transportation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1624__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On any state\nhighway maintained by the state within any city, village or suburban\ntown governed pursuant to article three-A of the town law, the\ndepartment of transportation may designate any such state highway or\nsection of such highway on which any such city, village or suburban town\nshall not by local law, ordinance, order, rule or regulation establish\nany maximum speed limits at which vehicles may proceed on or along such\nstate highway.  Such designation shall be made by an order in writing of\nthe department of transportation and served by mail on the mayor or\nsupervisor or a member of the governing board of such city, village or\nsuburban town ten days before the same shall take effect. At the\nexpiration of ten days after service of such order upon any city,\nvillage or suburban town the speed of any vehicle upon such state\nhighway or section of such highway shall not be subject to any such\nmaximum speed limit established by such city, village or suburban town.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1624__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of transportation may in its discretion at any time\nmake a written order requiring any city, village or suburban town to\nreport to the department of transportation the punishment inflicted upon\nconviction of exceeding the lawful maximum speed limit in such city,\nvillage or suburban town. Such order shall be in writing and shall be\nserved in like manner as the order provided for in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1624__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis section. Any city, village or suburban town upon which such order\nis served shall thereafter, at the close of each month and before the\nfifth day of the following month, make a report to the department of\ntransportation showing the name and residence of each person fined or\notherwise punished during the month, and the fines or punishment\nimposed. Such report shall be duly verified by the officer or officers,\nor magistrate or magistrates imposing the fines or punishment. The\ndepartment of transportation may at any time suspend or rescind the\norder requiring such reports.  If any city, village or suburban town\nfail to make any such report as required by the order of the department\nof transportation within the time prescribed by law, the right or power\nof such city, village or suburban town to impose any punishment upon\nconviction of exceeding the lawful maximum speed limit within such city,\nvillage or suburban town shall be suspended until the report is made as\nrequired.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>