<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1630"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1630"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1630"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1630/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1630/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1630/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1630/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1630">
        <num>1630</num>
        <heading>Regulation of traffic on highways under the jurisdiction of certain public authorities and commissions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1630__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision eleven\nof section three hundred seventy-six of the vehicle and traffic law)\ncoupled together shall consist of more than three vehicles.\n  2. Parking, standing, stopping and backing of vehicles.\n  3. The prohibition or regulation of the use of any highway by\nparticular vehicles or classes or types thereof or devices moved by\nhuman power, except hearses operated by or for a licensed funeral\ndirector or undertaker during a burial or funeral procession while\ntravelling either to or from a funeral, interment or cremation and\nexcept specialized vehicles as defined by section four hundred one of\nthis chapter.\n  4. Charging of tolls, taxes, fees, licenses or permits for the use of\nthe highway or any of its parts or entry into or remaining within the\ncentral business district established by article forty-four-C of this\nchapter, where the imposition thereof is authorized by law.\n  5. Establishment of maximum and minimum speed limits at which vehicles\nmay proceed on or along such highways. No such maximum speed limit shall\nbe established at less than twenty-five miles per hour, except that\nschool speed limits may be established at not less than fifteen miles\nper hour, for a distance not to exceed one thousand three hundred twenty\nfeet, on a highway passing a school building, entrance or exit of a\nschool abutting on the highway, and except that, with respect to bridge\nand elevated structures that are a part of any such highway, a lower\nmaximum speed limit may be established if it is determined that such\nlower maximum speed limit is the maximum speed limit which may be\nmaintained without structural damage to such bridge or structure, and\nexcept that, with respect to any highway under the jurisdiction of the\noffice of parks, recreation and historic preservation, other than a\nparkway as defined in subdivision seventeen of section 1.03 of the\nparks, recreation and historic preservation law, the department of\nagriculture and markets or th...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>