<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1640-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1640_M">
        <num>1640-M</num>
        <heading>Residential parking permit system in the city of Albany</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1640-m. Residential parking permit system in the city of Albany. 1.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of any law to the contrary, the city of\nAlbany may, by adoption of a local law or ordinance, provide for a\nresidential parking permit system and fix and require the payment of\nfees applicable to parking within certain areas of the city or as\ndelineated by the common council of the city of Albany in accordance\nwith the provisions of this section.\n  2. Such residential parking permit system may only be established\nwithin the areas of the city of Albany described as follows: an area\nwithin a one mile radius of the Nelson A. Rockefeller Empire State\nPlaza. The permitted streets within this area shall be described in a\nlocal law or ordinance adopted by the common council of the city of\nAlbany pursuant to this section.\n  3. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, no permit shall be\nrequired on streets where the adjacent properties are zoned for\ncommercial, office and/or retail use.\n  4. The local law or ordinance providing for such residential parking\npermit system shall:\n  a. Set forth the specific factors which necessitate the implementation\nof said system and shall include, but not be limited to, findings of\nfacts as to the existence of such traffic hazards, congestion and air\nand noise pollution within any such areas;\n  b. Provide that motor vehicles registered pursuant to section four\nhundred four-a of this chapter shall be exempt from any permit\nrequirement;\n  c. Provide the times of the day and the days of the week during which\npermit requirements shall be in effect;\n  d. Make not less than twenty percent of all spaces within the permit\narea or areas available to nonresidents which shall provide short-term\nparking of not less than ninety minutes in duration in such area or\nareas;\n  e. Make not more than three thousand five hundred of the approximately\nnine thousand residential spaces within the permit area or areas\navailable for residential parking by permit;\n  f. Provide the schedule of fees to be paid for residential permits;\nand\n  g. Provide that such fees shall be credited to the general fund of the\ncity of Albany.\n  5. No local law or ordinance shall be adopted pursuant to this section\nuntil a public hearing thereon has been held by the common council of\nthe city of Albany concerning the designation of the certain area or\nareas in which said parking permit system is to be implemented.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>