<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1640"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1640/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1640">
        <num>1640</num>
        <heading>Traffic regulations in all cities and villages</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1640__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The\nlegislative body of any city or village, with respect to highways (which\nterm for the purposes of this section shall include private roads open\nto public motor vehicle traffic) in such city or village; subject to the\nlimitations imposed by section sixteen hundred eighty-four may by local\nlaw, ordinance, order, rule or regulation:\n  1. Designate through highways and order stop signs, flashing signals\nor yield signs erected at specified entrances thereto or designate any\nintersection as a stop intersection or a yield intersection and order\nlike signs or signals at one or more entrances to such intersection.\n  2. Prohibit or regulate the turning of vehicles or specified types of\nvehicles at intersections or other designated locations.\n  3. Regulate the crossing of any roadway by pedestrians.\n  4. Designate any highway or any separate roadway thereof for one-way\ntraffic.\n  5. Exclude trucks, commercial vehicles, tractors, tractor-trailer\ncombinations, tractor-semitrailer combinations, or\ntractor-trailer-semitrailer combinations from highways specified by such\nlegislative body. Such exclusion shall not be construed to prevent the\ndelivery or pickup of merchandise or other property along the highways\nfrom which such vehicles and combinations are otherwise excluded.\n  6. Prohibit, restrict or limit the stopping, standing or parking of\nvehicles; provided, however, that a vehicle may not be found to be in\nviolation of a parking regulation if it is parked at a broken parking\nmeter at a time when metered parking is authorized.\n  7. Determine those highways or portions of highways which shall be\nmarked to indicate where overtaking and passing or driving to the left\nof or crossing such markings would be especially hazardous in accordance\nwith the standards, minimum warrants and sign or marking specifications\nestablished by the department of transportation.\n  8. Designate safety zones.\n  9. Provide for the installation, operation, maintenance, p...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1640__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such a legislative body also may by local law, ordinance, order,\nrule or regulation prohibit, restrict or limit the stopping, standing or\nparking of vehicles upon property owned or leased by such city or\nvillage.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1640__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each such legislative body shall cause to be determined, for all\nbridges and elevated structures under its jurisdiction, the capacity in\ntons of two thousand pounds which the bridge or structure will safely\ncarry. At bridges or structures of insufficient strength to carry safely\nthe legal loads permissible by section three hundred eighty-five, the\nlegislative body of such city or village shall cause signs to be erected\nto inform persons of the safe capacity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1640__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each such legislative body of a city or a village shall cause\nsigns to be erected to inform persons of the legal overhead clearance\nfor all bridges and structures on highways under its jurisdiction. The\nlegal clearance shall be one foot less than the measured clearance. The\nmeasured clearance shall be the minimum height to the bridge or\nstructure measured vertically from the traveled portion of the roadway.\nOn bridges or structures having fourteen feet or more of measured\nclearance, no such signs shall be required.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1640__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No legislative body of a city or a village shall enact any law\nthat prohibits the use of sidewalks by persons with disabilities who use\neither a wheelchair or an electrically-driven mobility assistance device\nbeing operated or driven by such person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>