<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1641"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1641"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1641"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1641/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1641/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1641/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1641/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1641">
        <num>1641</num>
        <heading>Additional traffic regulations on all highways except state highways maintained by the state in cities and villages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1641. Additional traffic regulations on all highways except state\nhighways maintained by the state in cities and villages. In addition to\nthe other powers granted by this article, the legislative body of any\ncity or village with respect to highways (which term for the purposes of\nthis section shall include private roads open to public motor vehicle\ntraffic) in such city or village except state highways maintained by the\nstate, may by local law, ordinance, order, rule or regulation:\n  1. Prohibit, restrict or regulate the operation of vehicles on any\ncontrolled-access highway or the use of any controlled-access highway by\nany vehicle, device moved by human power or pedestrian.\n  2. Authorize angle parking on any roadway.\n  3. Upon a roadway which is divided into three lanes, allocate the\ncenter lane exclusively for traffic moving in a specified direction.\n  4. Order signs erected directing slow-moving traffic, trucks, buses or\nspecified types of vehicles to use a designated lane, or with signs,\nsignals or markings designate those lanes to be used by traffic moving\nin a particular direction regardless of the center of the roadway.\n  5. Designate a portion of a slope as a path for the use of bicycles.\n  6. Order signs or markings to identify the portion of the highway to\nbe used for bicycle travel.\n  7. Prohibit, restrict or regulate the operation of limited use\nvehicles on any street or highway.\n  8. Designate preferential use lanes for specified types or classes of\nvehicles.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>