<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1642-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1642_A">
        <num>1642-A</num>
        <heading>Bus permit system in cities having a population of one million or more</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>mass transportation services provided to the general public by any\npublic benefit corporation constituting a transportation authority, or a\nsubsidiary thereof, or any public transportation corporation constituted\nas an instrumentality of a state, or a subsidiary thereof, directly or\nthrough a contact with another entity, or\n  (ii) mass transportation services provided to the general public by\nany county, city, town or village directly or through a contract with\nanother entity pursuant to section one hundred nineteen-r of the general\nmunicipal law, or provided to the general public by another state or any\ncounty, city, town or village in a state other than New York directly or\nthrough a contract with another entity pursuant to a similar law of such\nother state.\n  2. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, any city\nhaving a population of one million or more may prohibit intercity buses\nfrom loading or unloading passengers on streets within such city except\non designated streets and at designated locations on such streets\npursuant to a permit in accordance with the provisions of this section.\n  3. The mayor of such city which acts pursuant to subdivision two of\nthis section shall designate an agency to promulgate rules to implement\nthis section. Such city agency shall promulgate such rules which shall\ncomply with chapter forty-five of the New York city charter including a\npublic hearing. Such rules shall:\n  a. Establish a system of permits for allocating locations on\ndesignated streets where intercity buses may load and unload passengers,\nand prohibit loading and unloading of passengers other than at such\ndesignated locations on such designated streets pursuant to a permit;\n  b. Require the owner or operator of an intercity bus to submit an\napplication for a permit for each proposed location for loading and\nunloading of passengers. Such application shall include the following\ninformation:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and motor\ncarrier number of the intercity bus owner or operator, the United States\ndepartment of transportation number and/or New York state department of\ntransportation number for each bus that would use such proposed\nlocation;\n  (ii) A proposed location or locations to be used by the specified\nintercity buses for loading or unloading passengers, and two or more\nalternative proposed locations;\n  (iii) The number of intercity buses that would use the proposed\nlocation or locations;\n  (iv) The number of passengers anticipated for each such intercity bus;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642_A__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The proposed intercity bus schedule;\n  (vi) The planned garage or parking location of the intercity buses\nduring periods when such buses are not being used; and\n  (vii) Any other information deemed necessary by the commissioner of\nthe city agency designated pursuant to this subdivision.\n  c. Establish criteria for assigning locations to permit applicants,\nwhich shall include traffic and safety considerations, the preferences\nof the applicant, consultation with the local community board as\nprovided in paragraph b of subdivision four of this section and other\ncriteria deemed appropriate by the commissioner of such city agency;\n  d. Provide that such permit shall be issued for a term of up to three\nyears, except that such city may relocate a designated location for the\nloading and unloading of passengers by an intercity bus, upon ninety\ndays notice to the holder of a permit and after consultation with the\nlocal community board as provided in paragraph b of subdivision four of\nthis section, pursuant to the criteria established in accordance with\nparagraph c of this subdivision;\n  e. Include criteria under which intercity bus owners or operators\nassigned a designated location for loading and unloading passengers\nprior to the effective date of this section shall be issued a permit to\nuse such location for the loading and unloading of passengers for a\nperiod of up to three years from the effective date of this section;\n  f. Establish a timeframe of up to one hundred fifty days for\ndeterminations on permit applications, and a process for reviewing the\ndetermination on the application;\n  g. Require intercity bus owners or operators to notify such city\nagency of changes to information provided in such permit application;\n  h. Require intercity bus owners or operators to prominently display a\ncopy of the permit in each intercity bus;\n  i. Require the posting of all approved applications on a website for\npublic access by such city agency within thi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the same manner as is prescribed for\nservice of process by article three of the civil practice law and rules\nor article three of the business corporation law; (ii) by delivering\nsuch notice to the operator of the intercity bus, and mailing a copy of\nthe notice to the owner or operator of the intercity bus, provided that\nproof of such service shall be filed with the environmental control\nboard within twenty days, and service shall be complete ten days after\nsuch filing; or (iii) by affixing such notice to the intercity bus, and\nmailing a copy of the notice to the owner or operator of the intercity\nbus, provided that proof of such service shall be filed with the\nenvironmental control board within twenty days, and service shall be\ncomplete ten days after such filing. Civil penalties may also be\nrecovered in a proceeding commenced in a court of competent\njurisdiction. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such civil\npenalties imposed by such environmental control board shall be paid into\nthe general fund of such city. Notwithstanding section one hundred\nfifty-five of this chapter or any other provision of law, where a person\nhas been adjudicated to be in violation of any rules promulgated\npursuant to subdivision three of this section, such adjudication shall\nnot have the force and effect of a conviction of a traffic infraction or\nof a violation of any provision of this chapter for any purpose not\nspecified in this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>