<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-06-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1642"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1642/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1642">
        <num>1642</num>
        <heading>Additional traffic regulations in cities having a population in excess of one million</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the other powers granted by\nthis article, the legislative body of any city having a population in\nexcess of one million, may by local law, ordinance, order, rule,\nregulation or health code provision prohibit, restrict or regulate\ntraffic on or pedestrian use of any highway (which term, for the\npurposes of this section, shall include any private road open to public\nmotor vehicle traffic) in such city. The provisions of section sixteen\nhundred shall be applicable to such local laws, ordinances, orders,\nrules, regulations, and health code provisions, provided, however, that\nsuch local laws, ordinances, orders, rules, regulations and health code\nprovisions shall supersede the provisions of this chapter where\ninconsistent or in conflict with respect to the following enumerated\nsubjects:\n  1. Weights and dimensions of vehicles.\n  2. Parking, standing, stopping and backing of vehicles.\n  3. The prohibition or regulation of the use of any highway by\nparticular vehicles or classes or types thereof or devices moved by\nhuman power.\n  4. Charging of tolls, taxes, fees, licenses or permits for the use of\nthe highway or any of its parts, where the imposition thereof is\nauthorized by law.\n  5. Establishment of minimum speed limits at which vehicles may proceed\non or along such highways.\n  6. Operation of authorized emergency vehicles.\n  7. Control of persons and equipment engaged in work on the highway.\n  8. Hitchhiking and commercial activities.\n  9. Use of medial strips and dividing malls or sections and use of\nshoulders of the highway.\n  10. Right of way of vehicles and pedestrians.\n  11. Use of the highway by pedestrians, equestrians and animals.\n  12. Turning of vehicles.\n  13. Regulation of the direction of the movement of traffic and the use\nof traffic lanes.\n  14. Regulation of the use of horns, lights and other required\nequipment of vehicles.\n  15. Towing and pushing of vehicles, including, but not limited to, the\nestabli...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>With respect to highways (which term for the purposes of this\nparagraph shall include private roads open to public motor vehicle\ntraffic) in such city, other than state highways maintained by the state\non which the department of transportation shall have established higher\nor lower speed limits than the statutory fifty-five miles per hour speed\nlimit as provided in section sixteen hundred twenty of this title, or on\nwhich the department of transportation shall have designated that such\ncity shall not establish any maximum speed limit as provided in section\nsixteen hundred twenty-four of this title, subject to the limitations\nimposed by section sixteen hundred eighty-four of this title,\nestablishment of maximum speed limits at which vehicles may proceed\nwithin such city or within designated areas of such city higher or lower\nthan the fifty-five miles per hour maximum statutory limit. No such\nspeed limit applicable throughout such city or within designated areas\nof such city shall be established at less than twenty miles per hour,\nexcept that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>school speed limits may be established at no less than\nfifteen miles per hour pursuant to the provisions of section sixteen\nhundred forty-three of this article, and (ii) on portions of highways\nthat consist of three or more vehicular travel lanes in the same\ndirection outside of New York county, speed limits shall be established\nat no less than twenty-five miles per hour.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A city shall not lower or raise a speed limit pursuant to this\nparagraph unless such city provides written notice and an opportunity to\ncomment to the community board or community boards established pursuant\nto section twenty-eight hundred of the New York city charter with\njurisdiction over the area in which the lower or higher speed limit\nshall apply. Such notice may be provided by electronic mail and shall be\nprovided sixty days prior to the establishment of such lower or higher\nspeed limit and a community board may issue an advisory opinion prior to\nthe raising or lowering of such speed limit. Notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provision of this subdivision, a speed limit applicable\nthroughout such city shall only be lowered or raised pursuant to a local\nlaw.\n  27.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishment of maximum speed limits below twenty miles per\nhour at which motor vehicles may proceed on or along designated highways\nwithin such city for the explicit purpose of implementing traffic\ncalming measures as such term is defined herein; provided, however, that\nno speed limit shall be set below ten miles per hour nor shall such\nspeed limit be established where the traffic calming measure to be\nimplemented consists solely of a traffic control sign. Establishment of\nsuch a speed limit shall, where applicable, be in compliance with the\nprovisions of sections sixteen hundred twenty-four and sixteen hundred\neighty-four of this title. Nothing contained herein shall be deemed to\nalter or affect the establishment of school speed limits pursuant to the\nprovisions of section sixteen hundred forty-three of this article. For\nthe purposes of this paragraph, "traffic calming measures" shall mean\nany physical engineering measure or measures that reduce the negative\neffects of motor vehicle use, alter driver behavior and improve\nconditions for non-motorized street users such as pedestrians and\nbicyclists.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any city establishing maximum speed limits below twenty miles per\nhour pursuant to clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subparagraph shall submit a report\nto the governor, the temporary president of the senate and the speaker\nof the assembly on or before March first, two thousand fifteen and\nbiannually thereafter on the results of using traffic calming measures\nand speed limits lower than twenty miles per hour as authorized by this\nparagraph. This report shall also be made available to the public by\nsuch city on its website. Such report shall include, but not be limited\nto the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description of the designated highways where traffic calming\nmeasures and a lower speed limit were established;\n  (ii) a description of the specific traffic calming measures used and\nthe maximum speed limit established;\n  (iii) an explanation of the reasons for setting lower speed limits,\nhow those lower speed limits comply with engineering standards, and how\nthey will ensure that motor vehicles can operate at safe speeds in a\nmanner that optimizes all road users' safety and convenience; and\n  (iv) a comparison of the aggregate type, number, and severity of\naccidents reported on streets on which street calming measures and lower\nspeed limits were implemented in the year preceding the implementation\nof such measures and policies and the year following the implementation\nof such measures and policies, to the extent this information is\nmaintained by any agency of the state or the city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1642__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The police commissioner of any such city may, in any emergency,\nsuspend within such city or any part thereof, for a period of\nforty-eight hours, any provision of title seven of this chapter or any\nlocal law, ordinance, order, rule or regulation adopted pursuant to this\narticle. In the event of any such suspension, the police commissioner\nshall forthwith give notice thereof to the official, board or agency of\nsuch city having jurisdiction to promulgate traffic regulations in\nrelation to any place affected by such suspension.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>