<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1650"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1650"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1650"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1650/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1650/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1650/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1650/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1650">
        <num>1650</num>
        <heading>Traffic regulations on county roads</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1650__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The county\nsuperintendent of highways of a county with respect to county roads in\nsuch county, may by order, rule or regulation:\n  1. Upon a roadway which is divided into three lanes, allocate the\ncenter lane exclusively for traffic moving in a specified direction.\n  2. Order signs erected directing slow-moving traffic, trucks, buses or\nspecified types of vehicles to use a designated lane, or with signs,\nsignals or markings designate those lanes to be used by traffic moving\nin a particular direction regardless of the center of the roadway.\n  3. Determine those highways or portions of highways which shall be\nmarked to indicate where overtaking and passing or driving to the left\nof or crossing such markings would be especially hazardous in accordance\nwith the standards, minimum warrants and sign or marking specifications\nestablished by the department of transportation.\n  4. Temporarily exclude from any portion of any county road any vehicle\nwith a gross weight of over four or more tons or any vehicle with a\ngross weight in excess of any designated weight on any wheel, axle, any\nnumber of axles, or per inch width of tire when in his opinion such\nhighway would be materially injured by the operation of any such vehicle\nthereon.  Such exclusion shall take effect upon the erection of signs on\nthe section of highway from which such vehicles are excluded, and a\nnotice that such vehicles are excluded shall be published in a newspaper\nin the county where the highway is situated. The exclusion shall remain\nin effect until the removal of the signs as directed by the county\nsuperintendent of highways. Upon written application by any operator of\na vehicle subject to this section, the county superintendent of highways\nmay issue a permit providing appropriate exemption to such vehicle, if\nit is deemed that said vehicle is performing essential local pickup or\ndelivery service and that a failure to grant such permit would create\nhardship. Every such permit...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1650__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each such county superintendent of highways shall cause to be\ndetermined, for all bridges and elevated structures under his\njurisdiction, the capacity in tons of two thousand pounds which the\nbridge or structure will safely carry. At bridges or structures of\ninsufficient strength to carry safely the legal loads permissible by\nsection three hundred eighty-five of this chapter, the county\nsuperintendent of highways shall cause signs to be erected to inform\npersons of the safe capacity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1650__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each such county superintendent of highways shall cause signs to\nbe erected to inform persons of the legal overhead clearance for all\nbridges, and elevated structures on highways under his jurisdiction.\nThe legal clearance shall be one foot less than the measured clearance.\nThe measured clearance shall be the minimum height to the bridge or\nstructure measured vertically from the traveled portion of the roadway.\nOn bridges or structures having fourteen feet or more of measured\nclearance, no such signs shall be required.\n  d. The legislative body of any county with respect to county roads in\nsuch county, may by local law, ordinance, order, rule or regulation,\nprovide for the removal and storage of vehicles parked or abandoned on\nhighways during snowstorms, floods, fire or other public emergencies, or\nfound unattended where they constitute an obstruction to traffic or any\nplace where stopping, standing or parking is prohibited, and for the\npayment of reasonable charges for such removal and storage by the owner\nor operator of any such vehicle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1650__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The legislative body of any county with respect to county roads in\nsuch county, may by local law or ordinance prohibit vehicles engaged in\nretail sales of frozen desserts as that term is defined in subdivision\nthirty-seven of section three hundred seventy-five of this chapter\ndirectly to pedestrians from stopping for the purpose of such sales on\nany such road or on all such roads. Nothing herein shall be construed to\nprohibit the operator of such vehicle from stopping such vehicle off of\nsuch road, in a safe manner, for the sole purpose of delivering such\nretail product directly to the residence of a consumer or to the\nbusiness address of a customer of such retailer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>