<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1652-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1652-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1652-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1652-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1652-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1652-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1652-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1652_A">
        <num>1652-A</num>
        <heading>Traffic signs, signals and marking on highways, roads and streets</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1652-a. Traffic signs, signals and marking on highways, roads and\nstreets. The county superintendent of highways of a county, except the\ncounty of Suffolk, having a functioning traffic engineering unit may,\nwhen authorized by the county governing board, have the responsibility\nand authority for the installation, removal and maintenance of traffic\nsigns, signals and markings on, and provide traffic engineering services\nin relation to any highway, road or street within a city, town or\nvillage within such county, except state highways maintained by the\nstate, providing the governing body of the city, town or village\nconsents thereto by written agreement with the county governing board as\nto the extent of the authority and responsibility of the county\nsuperintendent of highways and any apportionment of costs for the\ninstallation, removal and maintenance of the signs, signals and markings\nand traffic engineering services. The power granted to the county\nsuperintendent of highways by this section shall in no way diminish any\npower over roads granted to counties or county highway superintendents\nbut shall be in addition to any such powers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>