<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1660"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1660"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1660"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1660/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1660/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1660/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1660/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1660">
        <num>1660</num>
        <heading>Traffic regulation in all towns</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1660__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The town board of any\ntown with respect to highways outside of villages in any such town, but\nnot including state highways maintained by the state except with respect\nto subdivisions six, eight, nine and ten, subject to the limitations\nimposed by section sixteen hundred eighty-four may by ordinance, order,\nrule or regulation:\n  1. Designate county roads and town highways as through highways and\norder stop signs, flashing signals or yield signs erected on county\nroads or town highways at specified entrances to such through highways\nor designate any intersection except those where one or more entering\nhighways is a state highway maintained by the state as a stop\nintersection or a yield intersection and order like signs or signals at\none or more entrances to such intersections.\n  2. Upon a roadway which is divided into three lanes, allocate the\ncenter lane exclusively for traffic moving in a specified direction.\n  3. Order signs erected directing slow-moving traffic, trucks, buses or\nspecified types of vehicles to use a designated lane, or with signs,\nsignals or markings designate those lanes to be used by traffic moving\nin a particular direction regardless of the center of the roadway.\n  4. Determine those highways or portions of highways which shall be\nmarked to indicate where overtaking and passing or driving to the left\nof or crossing such markings would be especially hazardous in accordance\nwith the standards, minimum warrants and sign or marking specifications\nestablished by the department of transportation.\n  5. Regulate traffic by means of traffic-control signals.\n  6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1660__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>License, regulate or prohibit speed contests, races,\nexhibitions of speed, processions, assemblages, or parades. Whenever\nsuch a speed contest, race, exhibition of speed, procession, assemblage\nor parade authorized by a local authority will block the movement of\ntraffic on a state highway maintained by the state, or on a highway\nwhich connects two state highways maintained by the state to make a\nthrough route, for a period in excess of ten minutes, such authority\nmust, prior to such blocking, provide and designate with conspicuous\nsigns a detour adequate to prevent unreasonable delay in the movement of\ntraffic on said state highway maintained by the state.\n  (ii) Prohibit vehicles engaged in retail sales of frozen desserts as\nthat term is defined in subdivision thirty-seven of section three\nhundred seventy-five of this chapter directly to pedestrians from\nstopping for the purpose of such sales on any highway within such town\nor on all such highways. Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit\nthe operator of such vehicle from stopping such vehicle off of such\nhighway, in a safe manner, for the sole purpose of delivering such\nretail product directly to the residence of a consumer or to the\nbusiness address of a customer of such retailer.\n  7. Prohibit or regulate the operation and the stopping, standing or\nparking of vehicles in cemeteries and in public parks.\n  8. Provide for the removal and storage of vehicles parked or abandoned\non highways during snowstorms, floods, fires or other public\nemergencies, or found unattended where they constitute an obstruction to\ntraffic or any place where stopping, standing or parking is prohibited\nand for the payment of reasonable charges for such removal and storage\nby the owner or operator of any such vehicle.\n  9. Provide for the installation, operation, maintenance, policing and\nsupervision of parking meters, establish parking time limits at such\nmeters, designate hours of operation of such meters...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1660__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each such town board shall cause to be determined, for all bridges\nand elevated structures under its jurisdiction, the capacity in tons of\ntwo thousand pounds which the bridge or structure will safely carry.\nUpon bridges or structures of insufficient strength to carry safely the\nlegal loads permissible by section three hundred eighty-five of this\nchapter, the town board shall cause signs to be erected to inform\npersons of the safe capacity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1660__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each such town board shall cause signs to be erected to inform\npersons of the legal overhead clearance for all bridges and elevated\nstructures on highways under its jurisdiction. The legal clearance shall\nbe one foot less than the measured clearance. The measured clearance\nshall be the minimum height to the bridge or structure measured\nvertically from the traveled portion of the roadway. On bridges or\nstructures having fourteen feet or more of measured clearance, no such\nsigns shall be required.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1660__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such a town board also may by ordinance, order, rule or regulation\nprohibit, restrict or limit the stopping, standing or parking of\nvehicles upon property owned or leased by such town.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1660__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any town with a population of seven hundred thousand or more may\nby local law or ordinance, provide for the removal and storage of\nvehicles parked on private property upon request of the owner of such\nprivate property, where such vehicles constitute an obstruction to the\nprivate property owner's right of ingress and egress, and for the\npayment of reasonable charges for such removal and storage by the owner\nor operator of any such vehicle. Such local law or ordinance shall be\napplicable only in the unincorporated areas of such town.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1660__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No town shall enact any local law or ordinance to prohibit the use\nof sidewalks by persons with disabilities who use either a wheelchair or\nan electrically-driven mobility assistance device being operated or\ndriven by such person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>