<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1662-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1662_A">
        <num>1662-A</num>
        <heading>Speed limits in certain towns</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1662-a. Speed limits in certain towns. The town board of any\nsuburban town governed pursuant to article three-A of the town law and\nthe town board of any other town having a population exceeding fifty\nthousand, with respect to highways (which term for the purposes of this\nsection shall include private roads open to public motor vehicle\ntraffic) in such towns outside any village, other than state highways\nmaintained by the state on which the department of transportation shall\nhave established higher or lower speed limits than the statutory\nfifty-five miles per hour speed limit as provided in section sixteen\nhundred twenty of this title, or on which the department of\ntransportation shall have designated that such towns shall not establish\nany maximum speed limit as provided in section sixteen hundred\ntwenty-four of this title, subject to the limitations imposed by section\nsixteen hundred eighty-four of this title may by local law, ordinance,\norder, rule or regulation establish maximum speed limits at which\nvehicles may proceed within such towns, within designated areas of such\ntowns or on or along designated highways within such towns lower than\nthe fifty-five miles per hour maximum statutory limit. No such speed\nlimit applicable throughout such towns or within designated areas of\nsuch towns shall be established at less than thirty miles per hour,\nexcept that in the town of Hempstead speed limits may be established at\nnot less than fifteen miles per hour on any portion of a highway in the\ncommunity known as Point Lookout and on all or any portion of the\nfollowing highways in the community known as Lido Beach: Ocean\nBoulevard, Allevard Street, Bath Street, Buxton Street, Cheltenham\nStreet, Pinehurst Street, Harrogate Street, Matlock Street, Nantwick\nStreet, Biarritz Street, Royat Street, Luchon Street, Woodhail Street,\nLeamington Street, Saratoga Street, Kensington Street, and Prescott\nStreet; provided, however, that no such speed limit in such town may be\nestablished unless a majority of the residents of each such community\nfile a petition with the town board of such town requesting such speed\nlimit. No such speed limit applicable on or along designated highways\nwithin such towns shall be established at less than twenty-five miles\nper hour, except that school speed limits may be established at not less\nthan fifteen miles per hour, for a distance not to exceed one thousand\nthree hundred twenty feet, on a highway passing a school building,\nentrance or exit of a school abutting on the highway, and except further\nthat in the town of Hempstead speed limits may be established at not\nless than fifteen miles per hour on any portion of a highway in the\ncommunities known as Point Lookout and Lido Beach; provided, however,\nthat no such speed limit in such town may be established unless a\nmajority of the residents of each such community file a petition with\nthe town board of such town requesting such speed limit.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>