<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1662-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1662-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1662_B">
        <num>1662-B</num>
        <heading>Residential parking system in the town of Eastchester in the county of Westchester</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nwithin the area of the town consisting of the following roadways:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Garth road;\n  (ii) Grayrock road;\n  (iii) Essex place;\n  (iv) Buckingham place and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>within the area generally bounded by the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On the north side by the northerly corporate boundary between the\ntown of Eastchester and the village of Scarsdale, from Scarsdale Avenue\neast to White Plains Road Rt. 22;\n  (ii) On the east side by White Plains Rd. Rt. 22, from the corporate\nboundary of the Village of Scarsdale south to the intersection of Hall\nAvenue, excluding the following streets:\n  Gabriel Resigno drive;\n  Swift avenue;\n  Fairway drive;\n  Park drive (north of Clubway);\n  Hilldale place;\n  Burnham road;\n  (iii) On the south side by Hall avenue west to the corporate boundary\nbetween the town of Eastchester and the village of Tuckahoe;\n  (iv) On the south side northerly along the corporate boundary of the\nvillage of Tuckahoe until the intersection of Benedict avenue and\ncontinuing north along the Metro-North Commuter Railroad tracks until\nthe corporate boundary of the village of Scarsdale, at Scarsdale avenue.\n  3. Notwithstanding the foregoing, no permit shall be required on those\nportions of such streets where the adjacent properties are zoned for\ncommercial/retail use.\n  4. The local law or ordinance providing for such residential parking\nsystem shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>set forth factors necessitating the enactment of such parking\nsystem;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide that motor vehicles registered pursuant to section four\nhundred four-a of this chapter shall be exempt from any permit\nrequirement;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide the times of the day and days of the week during which\npermit requirements shall be in effect;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make not less than fifteen percent of the spaces within the permit\narea available to nonresidents, and shall provide short term parking of\nnot less than sixty minutes in duration in the permit area;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide the schedule of fees to be paid for such permits; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1662_B__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide that such fees shall be credited to the general fund of\nthe town of Eastchester unless otherwise specified in such local law.\n  5. No ordinance shall be adopted pursuant to this section until a\npublic hearing thereon has been had in the same manner as required for\npublic hearings on a local law pursuant to the municipal home rule law.\n  6. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any state highway\nmaintained by the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>