<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1673"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1673"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1673"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1673/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1673/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1673/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1673/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1673">
        <num>1673</num>
        <heading>Membership of board</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1673__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such board shall be composed of not\nless than ten members interested in traffic safety and traffic problems\nappointed by the city council, town board, borough president or board of\nsupervisors or other governing body of the city, town, borough or county\nfor which such board has been created.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1673__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each member shall be a resident of the city, town or county for\nwhich such board has been created and shall be a qualified elector\nthereof.  For any county not wholly included within a city, at least one\nbut not more than three of such members shall be a resident or residents\nof and be appointed from each one of the cities contained in the county,\nand the balance of such members shall be appointed from the county at\nlarge.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1673__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term of office of such members shall be three years, except\nthat the members first appointed to such board shall be appointed as\nfollows: one-third shall be appointed for a term of three years;\none-third for a term of two years and the remaining members of the board\nfor a term of one year. Upon the expiration of the term of office of any\nmember, his or her successor shall be appointed to membership in such\nboard for a term of three years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1673__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members of such board shall receive no compensation for\nservices but shall be entitled to their reasonable and necessary\nexpenses, incurred in the performance of their duties, within any\nappropriation made for such purpose.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>