<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1674"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1674"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1674"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1674/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1674/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1674/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1674/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1674">
        <num>1674</num>
        <heading>Organization and reports by the board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1674. Organization and reports by the board.  The traffic safety\nboard shall:\n  1. Meet and organize within fifteen days after its members are\nappointed.\n  2. Elect annually a chairman, vice-chairman and a secretary from its\nmembers.\n  3. Adopt rules for the conduct of its business.\n  4. Within the limits of the appropriations made therefor by the city\ncouncil, town board, borough president or board of supervisors or other\ngoverning body of the city, town, borough or county for which such board\nhas been created, authorize the employment of such personnel as may be\nnecessary to properly perform the functions and carry out the objectives\nof this article.\n  5. Appoint an executive secretary who shall be the executive and\nadministrative officer of the board.\n  6. Render annually to the city council, town board, borough president\nor board of supervisors or other governing body of the city, town,\nborough or county for which such board has been created, and from time\nto time as required, a verified account of all moneys received and\nexpended by it or under its direction and an account of its proceedings\nand of other pertinent matters in such form and manner as may be\nrequired by such board or body.\n  7. Submit annually to the proper fiscal authorities of the city, town,\nborough or county for which such board has been created, at such time in\nsuch manner as may be required by the law applicable thereto, an\nestimate of the funds required to carry out the purposes of this\narticle.\n  8. Submit a report of activities annually to the state and, from time\nto time, such other information or reports as may be required by the\nstate pursuant to the provisions of article 16-a of the executive law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>