<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1675"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1675"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1675"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1675/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1675/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1675/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1675/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1675">
        <num>1675</num>
        <heading>Functions of the board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1675. Functions of the board. The board is authorized:\n  1. To promote and encourage street and highway traffic safety.\n  2. To formulate highway safety programs and coordinate efforts of\ninterested parties and agencies engaged in traffic safety education\nwithin such city, town, borough or county.\n  3. To cooperate with local officials in the formulation and execution\nof traffic safety programs and activities.\n  4. To study traffic conditions on streets and highways, study and\nanalyze reports of accidents and causes thereof, and recommend to the\nappropriate legislative bodies, departments or commissions, such changes\nin rules, orders, regulations and existing law as the board may deem\nadvisable.\n  5. To conduct meetings whenever and wherever the board shall deem it\nadvisable and to invite to such meetings parties and agencies, public\nand private, interested in traffic regulation, control and safety\neducation.\n  6. To promote safety education for drivers and pedestrians.\n  7. To obtain and assemble motor vehicle accident data, and to analyze,\nstudy and consolidate such data for educational and informational\npurposes.\n  8. Coordinate and direct local activities related to the\nimplementation of the state highway safety program, as approved by the\ngovernor or his designee.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>