<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1683"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1683"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-04-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1683"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1683/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1683/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1683/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1683/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1683">
        <num>1683</num>
        <heading>Signs or markings required</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1683__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No ordinance, order, rule or\nregulation made by any local authority under the powers conferred by\nthis title shall be effective until signs or markings giving notice\nthereof are posted, except under such conditions as may be authorized in\nwriting by the department of transportation or as otherwise provided in\nsubsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1683__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, if the effect of such order, ordinance,\nrule or regulation is to:\n  1. Designate through highways and order stop signs, flashing signals\nor yield signs erected at specified entrances thereto or designated any\nintersection as a stop intersection or a yield intersection and order\nlike signs or signals at one or more entrances to such intersection.\n  2. Prohibit, restrict or regulate the operation of vehicles on any\ncontrolled-access highway or the use of any controlled-access highway by\nany vehicle, device moved by human power or pedestrian.\n  3. Prohibit or regulate the turning of vehicles or specified types of\nvehicles at intersections or other designated locations.\n  4. Authorize angle parking on any roadway.\n  5. Upon a roadway which is divided into three lanes, allocate the\ncenter lane exclusively for traffic moving in a specified direction.\n  6. Designate any highway or separate roadway thereof for one-way\ntraffic.\n  7. Exclude trucks, commercial vehicles, tractors, tractor-trailer\ncombinations or trucks in excess of any designated weight from\ndesignated highway.\n  8. Prohibit, restrict or limit the stopping, standing or parking of\nvehicles.\n  9. Designate no-passing zones and no changing lane zones and indicate\nsuch zones in accordance with the standards, minimum warrants and sign\nor marking specifications established by the department of\ntransportation.\n  10. Designate safety zones.\n  11. Establish a system of truck routes upon which all trucks, tractors\nand tractor-trailer combinations having a total gross weight in excess\nof ten thousand pounds are permitted to travel and operate and excluding\nsuch vehicles and combinations from all highways except those which\nconstitute such truck route system.\n  12. Prohibit, regulate or restrict the operation or the stopping,\nstanding or parking of vehicles on any bridge or in any tunnel, or the\nuse of any bridge or tunnel by any vehicle, device moved by human power\nor pe...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1683__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such signs shall be required for orders, ordinances, rules, or\nregulations made by the New York state thruway authority, the office of\nparks and recreation, a county park commission, a parkway authority, a\nbridge authority, a bridge and tunnel authority or the legislative body\nof a city having a population in excess of one million or any board,\nbody or official to whom the power of such local authority has been\ndesignated only in so far as such local authorities in their discretion\nmay deem practicable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>