<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1691"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1691"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-06-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1691"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1691/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1691/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1691/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1691/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1691">
        <num>1691</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>used by a transportation network company driver to provide a TNC\nprearranged trip originating within the state of New York; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>owned, leased or otherwise authorized for use by the\ntransportation network company driver;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such term shall not include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a taxicab, as defined in section one hundred forty-eight-a of this\nchapter and section 19-502 of the administrative code of the city of New\nYork, or as otherwise defined in local law;\n  (ii) a livery vehicle, as defined in section one hundred twenty-one-e\nof this chapter, or as otherwise defined in local law;\n  (iii) a black car, limousine, or luxury limousine, as defined in\nsection 19-502 of the administrative code of the city of New York, or as\notherwise defined in local law;\n  (iv) a for-hire vehicle, as defined in section 19-502 of the\nadministrative code of the city of New York, or as otherwise defined in\nlocal law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bus, as defined in section one hundred four of this chapter;\n  (vi) any motor vehicle weighing more than six thousand five hundred\npounds unloaded;\n  (vii) any motor vehicle having a seating capacity of more than seven\npassengers; and\n  (viii) any motor vehicle subject to section three hundred seventy of\nthis chapter.\n  2. "Digital network" means any system or service offered or utilized\nby a transportation network company that enables TNC prearranged trips\nwith transportation network company drivers.\n  3. "Transportation network company" or "TNC" means a person,\ncorporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, or other entity that is\nlicensed pursuant to this article and is operating in New York state\nexclusively using a digital network to connect transportation network\ncompany passengers to transportation network company drivers who provide\nTNC prearranged trips.\n  4. "Transportation network company driver" or "TNC driver" means an\nindividual who:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Receives connections to potential passengers and related services\nfrom a transportation network company in exchange for payment of a fee\nto the transportation network company; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Uses a TNC vehicle to offer or provide a TNC prearranged trip to\ntransportation network company passengers upon connection through a\ndigital network controlled by a transportation network company in\nexchange for compensation or payment of a fee.\n  5. "Transportation network company passenger" or "passenger" means a\nperson or persons who use a transportation network company's digital\nnetwork to connect with a transportation network company driver who\nprovides TNC prearranged trips to the passenger in the TNC vehicle\nbetween points chosen by the passenger.\n  6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"TNC prearranged trip" or "trip" means the provision of\ntransportation by a transportation network company driver to a passenger\nprovided through the use of a TNC's digital network:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>beginning when a transportation network company driver accepts a\npassenger's request for a trip through a digital network controlled by a\ntransportation network company;\n  (ii) continuing while the transportation network company driver\ntransports the requesting passenger in a TNC vehicle; and\n  (iii) ending when the last requesting passenger departs from the TNC\nvehicle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "TNC prearranged trip" does not include transportation\nprovided through any of the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1691__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shared expense carpool or vanpool arrangements, including those as\ndefined in section one hundred fifty-eight-b of this chapter; and\n  (ii) use of a taxicab, livery, luxury limousine, or other for-hire\nvehicle, as defined in this chapter, section 19-502 of the\nadministrative code of the city of New York, or as otherwise defined in\nlocal law.\n  7. "Group policy" means an insurance policy issued pursuant to section\nthree thousand four hundred fifty-five of the insurance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>