<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1703"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1703"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1703"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1703">
        <num>1703</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1703. Definitions. For the purposes of this article, unless the\ncontext otherwise requires:\n  1. "City" means the city of New York.\n  2. "Central business district toll" means a toll charged for entry\ninto or remaining in the central business district as described in\nsection seventeen hundred four of this article.\n  3. "Central business district tolling program" means the program for\ncharging tolls for vehicles that enter or remain in the central business\ndistrict and includes the central business district tolling\ninfrastructure, the central business district tolling collection system\nand the central business district tolling customer service center.\n  4. "Central business district" means the area described in section\nseventeen hundred four of this article for which tolls shall be charged\nfor a vehicle's entry into or remaining in such district.\n  5. "Central business district tolling infrastructure" means the\ndevices and structures including but not limited to gantries, clear\nsignage delineating entry into the central business district and toll\namounts, and power and communication lines that the Triborough bridge\nand tunnel authority will plan, design, construct, and use as part of\nthe central business district tolling program. Such infrastructure shall\nbe planned, designed, installed and constructed pursuant to the\nmemorandum of understanding executed pursuant to subdivision two-a of\nsection seventeen hundred four of this article.\n  6. "Central business district tolling collection system" means the\nelectronic system of collecting tolls or other charges using electronic\ndata and/or images that the Triborough bridge and tunnel authority will\nplan, design, install and construct pursuant to the memorandum of\nunderstanding executed pursuant to subdivision two-a of section\nseventeen hundred four of this article, and that such authority shall\noperate as part of the central business district tolling program.\n  7. "Central business district tolling customer service center" means\nthe customer contact and back-office system and operation services for\nthe collection of central business district tolls and enforcement of\ncentral business district toll violations that the Triborough bridge and\ntunnel authority will plan, design, implement and operate as part of the\ncentral business district tolling program.\n  8. "Operation date" means the date determined by the Triborough bridge\nand tunnel authority, which shall not be earlier than December\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty, for the beginning of the operation\nand enforcement of the central business district tolling program. The\noperation and enforcement date shall commence only after an initial\nprogram testing period of thirty days where no collection of any tolls,\nfees, or other charges shall be authorized. As of the commencement date\nof operation and enforcement, there shall be a period of sixty days\nwhere only the established tolls may be collected without the collection\nof other fees or charges or fines.\n  9. "Triborough bridge and tunnel authority" means the corporation\norganized pursuant to section five hundred fifty-two of the public\nauthorities law as consolidated pursuant to section five hundred\nfifty-two-a of the public authorities law or any successor corporation\nor corporation into which it may be consolidated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>