<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1704"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1704"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-06-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1704"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1704">
        <num>1704</num>
        <heading>Establishment of central business district tolling program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1704__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, the Triborough bridge\nand tunnel authority, pursuant to the memorandum of understanding\nexecuted pursuant to subdivision two-a of this section with the city\ndepartment of transportation shall plan, design, install, construct, and\nmaintain the central business district tolling infrastructure. The city\nof New York shall cooperate and consult with the Triborough bridge and\ntunnel authority to facilitate the planning, design, construction,\ntimely implementation, and maintenance of the central business district\ntolling infrastructure and shall not unduly hinder or delay the\nplanning, designing, installation, operation, construction, timely\nimplementation, or maintenance of the same. Notwithstanding any\nprovision of law to the contrary, the city of New York shall, pursuant\nto the memorandum of understanding executed pursuant to subdivision\ntwo-a of this section with the Triborough bridge and tunnel authority,\nbe authorized to provide for the use of existing systems, devices and\nother facilities owned and operated by the city, including, but not\nlimited to systems and devices installed pursuant to sections one\nthousand one hundred eleven-a, one thousand one hundred eleven-c, and\none thousand one hundred eighty-b of this chapter to facilitate the\nTriborough bridge and tunnel authority's central business district\ntolling program and shall work with the Triborough bridge and tunnel\nauthority to facilitate the same.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1704__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Triborough bridge and tunnel authority shall, pursuant to the\nmemorandum of understanding executed pursuant to subdivision two-a of\nthis section with the city department of transportation, plan, design,\ninstall, construct, and maintain a central business district toll\ncollection system and implement and operate the same to collect the\ncentral business district toll.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1704__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Triborough bridge and tunnel authority shall plan, design,\nimplement and operate a central business district toll customer service\ncenter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1704__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The central business district tolling program shall be planned,\ndesigned, implemented and operated to facilitate payment of central\nbusiness district tolls by credit or debit card, check or automated\nclearing house payment, by telephone or over the internet or any other\nmethod of payment that the Triborough bridge and tunnel authority may\nimplement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1704__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All procurements of goods, services or construction of any kind by\nthe Triborough bridge and tunnel authority for the central business\ndistrict tolling program shall be deemed to be subject only to the same\nrequirements that otherwise apply to procurements by the Triborough\nbridge and tunnel authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1704__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Signage shall be clearly delineated to provide notice at a\nreasonable distance prior to, and upon entry into, the central business\ndistrict and upon exit from the central business district. Signage prior\nto entry must include the toll rates to be charged. Additionally,\nsignage shall be provided, where practicable, to provide drivers\nadequate notice to avoid entry into the central business district.\nDesign, placement and installation of signage by the Triborough bridge\nand tunnel authority shall be performed pursuant to the memorandum of\nunderstanding executed pursuant to subdivision two-a of this section\nwith the city department of transportation.\n  4. The central business district tolling infrastructure, the central\nbusiness district toll collection system and the central business\ndistrict tolling customer service center shall be completed by the\noperation date.\n  5. Responsibility for maintenance of the central business district\ntolling infrastructure after the operation date shall be performed by\nthe Triborough bridge and tunnel authority pursuant to the memorandum of\nunderstanding executed pursuant to subdivision two-a of this section\nwith the city department of transportation.\n  6. The planning, designing, constructing, installing or maintaining of\nthe central business district tolling program and the planning,\ndesigning, installing, constructing, operating or maintaining of the\ncentral business district toll collection system by the Triborough\nbridge and tunnel authority including the establishment by such\nauthority of central business district tolls, and any other fees or\nrentals for the use of its projects and any changes thereafter shall not\nbe subject to the provisions of article eight of the environmental\nconservation law, the provisions of chapter six of article forty-three\nor chapter five of title sixty-two of the rules of the city of New York,\nor the provisions of section one hundred ninety-seven-c of the New York\ncity cha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>