<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1706"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1706"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1706"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1706/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1706/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1706/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1706/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1706">
        <num>1706</num>
        <heading>Reporting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1706. Reporting. Beginning one year after the operation date and\nevery two years thereafter, the Triborough bridge and tunnel authority,\nin consultation with the city department of transportation shall report\non the effect of the central business district tolling program on\ntraffic congestion in and around the central business district and on\nmass transit use and taxi and for-hire vehicle use including the\nvehicle-miles traveled for each trip within the central business\ndistrict for taxis and for-hire vehicles; the current and historic\nvolume and type of vehicles including, but not limited to, commercial\ntrucks, transportation network companies, taxis, private cars, and tour\nbuses, entering the central business district; environmental\nimprovements, including but not limited to, air quality, and emissions\ntrends in and around the central business district; congestion reduction\nmeasures; and transit ridership and average bus speeds within the\ncentral business district, and on all receipts and expenditures relating\nto the central business district tolling program. The department of\ntransportation of the city of New York shall be required to assist in\ngathering and providing to the Triborough bridge and tunnel authority\ntraffic impact data and other related data as directed by the Triborough\nbridge and tunnel authority for purposes of compiling such report. The\nreport shall be readily available to the public, and shall be posted on\nthe authority's website and be submitted to the governor, the director\nof the budget, the temporary president of the senate, the speaker of the\nassembly, the mayor and council speaker of the city of New York, the\nmetropolitan transportation authority board and the metropolitan\ntransportation authority capital program review board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>