<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1803"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1803"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1803"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1803/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1803/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1803/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1803/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1803">
        <num>1803</num>
        <heading>Disposition of fines and forfeitures</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section sixteen\nhundred forty of this chapter prohibiting, restricting or limiting the\nstopping, standing or parking of vehicles shall be paid to such village\nwhether or not the village has established the office of village\njustice.\n  c. for compliance with or violations of subdivision nineteen of\nsection three hundred eighty-five of this chapter, notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provision of law, except as provided in section ninety of\nthe state finance law, the fees and fines collected by the state\npursuant to sections two hundred twenty-seven, three hundred eighty-five\nand eighteen hundred three of this chapter and section ninety-nine-a of\nthe state finance law, shall be made available to the state comptroller\nfor deposit in the general fund except that fines collected within a\ncity not wholly included within one county shall be paid to such city in\naccordance with the procedures set forth in subdivision four of section\ntwo hundred twenty-seven of this chapter for deposit into the general\nfund of such city.\n  d. for violations of section eleven hundred eighty which are not\nincluded in paragraph a or paragraph b of this subdivision, violations\nof sections eleven hundred eighty-two, eleven hundred ninety-two, except\nin those counties adopting a special traffic option program for driving\nwhile intoxicated pursuant to section eleven hundred ninety-seven of\nthis chapter, and section twelve hundred twelve of this chapter, and\nviolations of this chapter or of any act relating to the use of highways\nby motor vehicles or trailers, now in force or hereafter enacted, for\nwhich no other distribution is prescribed, all fines, penalties and\nforfeitures shall be paid to the state.\n  e. for a violation which occurs within a county which has established\na traffic and parking violations agency pursuant to section three\nhundred seventy of the general municipal law, other than parking,\nstanding or stopping violations except for those set forth in sec...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1803__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>imposed and collected for violations of\nsubparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two or\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of section five\nhundred eleven of this chapter;</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1803__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>imposed and collected in accordance\nwith section eleven hundred ninety-three of this chapter for violations\nof section eleven hundred ninety-two of this chapter;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1803__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>collected by\nany court, judge, magistrate or other officer imposed upon a conviction\nfor: aggravated vehicular assault, pursuant to section 120.04-a of the\npenal law; vehicular assault in the first degree, pursuant to section\n120.04 of the penal law; vehicular assault in the second degree,\npursuant to section 120.03 of the penal law; aggravated vehicular\nhomicide, pursuant to section 125.14 of the penal law; vehicular\nmanslaughter in the first degree, pursuant to section 125.13 of the\npenal law; and vehicular manslaughter in the second degree, pursuant to\nsection 125.12 of the penal law; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1803__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>civil penalties imposed\npursuant to subdivision two of section eleven hundred ninety-four-a of\nthis chapter, shall be paid to such county. In addition, any surcharges\nimposed pursuant to section eighteen hundred nine-c and paragraph b of\nsubdivision one of section eighteen hundred nine-e of this chapter shall\nbe paid to such county in such manner and for such purposes as provided\nfor in section eleven hundred ninety-seven of this chapter.\n  b. Any such fine, penalty, or forfeiture collected by any court,\njudge, magistrate or other officer referred to in subdivision one of\nsection thirty-nine of the judiciary law, establishing a unified court\nbudget, shall be paid to that county within the first ten days of the\nmonth following collection.\n  c. Any such fine, penalty, or forfeiture collected by any other court,\njudge, magistrate or other officer, including, where appropriate, a\nhearing officer acting on behalf of the commissioner, shall be paid to\nthe state comptroller wit...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred eighty of this chapter in\naccordance with section eleven hundred eighty-e of this chapter, any\nfine or penalty collected by a court, judge, magistrate or other officer\nfor an imposition of liability which occurs pursuant to such program\nshall be paid to the state comptroller within the first ten days of the\nmonth following collection, except as otherwise provided in subdivision\nthree of section ninety-nine-a of the state finance law. Every such\npayment shall be accompanied by a statement in such form and detail as\nthe comptroller shall provide. Notwithstanding the provisions of\nsubdivision five of this section, eighty percent of any such fine or\npenalty imposed for such liability shall be paid to the general fund,\nand twenty percent of any such fine or penalty shall be paid to the\ncity, town or village in which the violation giving rise to the\nliability occurred, provided, however, that within a county that has\nestablished a traffic and parking violations agency pursuant to section\nthree hundred seventy of the general municipal law and such liability is\ndisposed of by such agency, eighty percent of any such fine or penalty\nimposed for such liability shall be paid to the general fund, and twenty\npercent of any such fine or penalty shall be paid to the county in which\nthe violation giving rise to the liability occurred. With respect to the\npercentage of fines or penalties paid to the general fund, no less than\nsixty percent shall be dedicated to department of transportation work\nzone safety projects after deducting the expenses necessary to\nadminister such demonstration program, provided, however, that such\nfunds provided pursuant to this subdivision shall be payable on the\naudit and warrant of the comptroller and shall only be used to\nsupplement and not supplant current expenditures of state funds on work\nzone safety projects. For the purposes of this subdivision, "work zone\nsafety projects" shall apply to work zo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred eighty of\nthis chapter in accordance with section eleven hundred eighty-e of this\nchapter, any fine or penalty collected by a court, judge, magistrate or\nother officer for an imposition of liability which occurs pursuant to\nsuch program shall be paid to the state comptroller within the first ten\ndays of the month following collection, except as otherwise provided in\nsubdivision three of section ninety-nine-a of the state finance law.\nEvery such payment shall be accompanied by a statement in such form and\ndetail as the comptroller shall provide. Notwithstanding the provisions\nof subdivision five of this section, eighty percent of any such fine or\npenalty imposed for such liability shall be paid to the thruway\nauthority, and twenty percent of any such fine or penalty shall be paid\nto the city, town or village in which the violation giving rise to the\nliability occurred, provided, however, that within a county that has\nestablished a traffic and parking violations agency pursuant to section\nthree hundred seventy of the general municipal law and such liability is\ndisposed of by such agency, eighty percent of any such fine or penalty\nimposed for such liability shall be paid to the thruway authority, and\ntwenty percent of any such fine or penalty shall be paid to the county\nin which the violation giving rise to the liability occurred. With\nrespect to the percentage of fines or penalties paid to the thruway\nauthority, no less than sixty percent shall be dedicated to thruway\nauthority work zone safety projects after deducting the expenses\nnecessary to administer such demonstration program, provided, however,\nthat such funds provided pursuant to this subdivision shall be payable\non the audit and warrant of the comptroller and shall only be used to\nsupplement and not supplant current expenditures of state funds on work\nzone safety projects. For the purposes of this subdivision, "work zone\nsafety projects" shall apply to wor...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\neleven hundred eleven of this chapter in accordance with section eleven\nhundred eleven-g of this chapter, any fine or penalty collected by a\ncourt, judge, magistrate or other officer for an imposition of liability\nwhich occurs within a city, town or village within such county pursuant\nto such program shall be paid to the state comptroller within the first\nten days of the month following collection, except as otherwise provided\nin subdivision three of section ninety-nine-a of the state finance law.\nEvery such payment shall be accompanied by a statement in such form and\ndetail as the comptroller shall provide. The comptroller shall pay\neighty percent of any such fine or penalty imposed for such liability to\nthe county of Westchester, and twenty percent of any such fine or\npenalty to the city, town or village in which the violation giving rise\nto the liability occurred. All fines, penalties and forfeitures paid to\na city, town or village pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision\nshall be credited to the general fund of such city, town or village,\nunless a different disposition is prescribed by charter, special law,\nlocal law or ordinance.\n  * NB Repealed December 1, 2027\n  ** 14. Where the chair of the triborough bridge and tunnel authority\nhas established a demonstration program imposing monetary liability on\nthe owner of a vehicle for failure of an operator thereof to comply with\nsection three hundred eighty-five of this chapter and the rules of the\ntriborough bridge and tunnel authority in relation to gross vehicle\nweight and/or axle weight in accordance with section three hundred\neighty-five-a of this chapter, any fine or penalty collected by the\nparking violations bureau of the city of New York for an imposition of\nliability which occurs pursuant to such program shall be paid to the\nstate comptroller within the first ten days of the month following\ncollection, except as otherwise provided in subdivision three of section...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred eighty-five-a of this\nchapter. All fines, penalties and forfeitures paid to the city of New\nYork pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision shall be credited to\nthe general fund of such city, unless a different disposition is\nprescribed by charter, special law, local law or ordinance.\n  * NB Repealed December 1, 2030\n  * NB There are two sb 14's\n  ** 14. Where the chair of the Triborough bridge and tunnel authority\nhas established a demonstration program imposing monetary liability on\nthe owner of a vehicle for failure of an operator thereof to comply with\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred eighty of\nthis chapter in accordance with section eleven hundred eighty-e of this\nchapter, any fine or penalty collected by the New York city parking\nviolations bureau for an imposition of liability which occurs pursuant\nto such program shall be paid to the state comptroller within the first\nten days of the month following collection, except as otherwise provided\nin subdivision three of section ninety-nine-a of the state finance law.\nEvery such payment shall be accompanied by a statement in such form and\ndetail as the comptroller shall provide. Notwithstanding the provisions\nof subdivision five of this section, eighty percent of any such fine or\npenalty imposed for such liability shall be paid to the Triborough\nbridge and tunnel authority, and twenty percent of any such fine or\npenalty shall be paid to the city of New York. With respect to the\npercentage of fines or penalties paid to the Triborough bridge and\ntunnel authority, no less than sixty percent shall be dedicated to\nTriborough bridge and tunnel authority work zone safety projects after\ndeducting the expenses necessary to administer such demonstration\nprogram, provided, however, that such funds provided pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be payable on the audit and warrant of the comptroller\nand shall only be used to supplement and not supplant current\nexpenditures of Triborough bridge and tunnel authority funds on work\nzone safety projects. For the purposes of this subdivision, "work zone\nsafety projects" shall apply to work zones under the jurisdiction of the\nTriborough bridge and tunnel authority and shall include, but not be\nlimited to, inspection and implementation of work zone design,\nmaintenance, traffic plans and markings, worker safety training,\ncontractor outreach, and enforcement efforts. For the purposes of this\nsubdivision, the term "Triborough bridge and tunnel authority" shall\nmean the New York state Triborough bridge and tunnel authority, ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three\nhundred eighty-five-a of this chapter. All fines, penalties and\nforfeitures paid to a city, town or village pursuant to the provisions\nof this subdivision shall be credited to the general fund of such city,\ntown or village, unless a different disposition is prescribed by\ncharter, special law, local law or ordinance.\n  * NB Repealed December 1, 2030\n  * NB There are two sb 15's\n  ** 15. Where the chair of the New York state bridge authority has\nestablished a demonstration program imposing monetary liability on the\nowner of a vehicle for failure of an operator thereof to comply with\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred eighty of\nthis chapter in accordance with section eleven hundred eighty-e of this\nchapter, any fine or penalty collected by a court, judge, magistrate or\nother officer for an imposition of liability which occurs pursuant to\nsuch program shall be paid to the state comptroller within the first ten\ndays of the month following collection, except as otherwise provided in\nsubdivision three of section ninety-nine-a of the state finance law.\nEvery such payment shall be accompanied by a statement in such form and\ndetail as the comptroller shall provide. Notwithstanding the provisions\nof subdivision five of this section, eighty percent of any such fine or\npenalty imposed for such liability shall be paid to the bridge\nauthority, and twenty percent of any such fine or penalty shall be paid\nto the city, town or village in which the violation giving rise to the\nliability occurred. With respect to the percentage of fines or penalties\npaid to the bridge authority, no less than sixty percent shall be\ndedicated to bridge authority work zone safety projects after deducting\nthe expenses necessary to administer such demonstration program,\nprovided, however, that such funds provided pursuant to this subdivision\nshall be payable on the audit and warrant of the comptroller and shall\nonly be used to supplement and not supplant current expenditures of\nbridge authority funds on work zone safety projects. For the purposes of\nthis subdivision, "work zone safety projects" shall apply to work zones\nunder the jurisdiction of the bridge authority and shall include, but\nnot be limited to, inspection and implementation of work zone design,\nmaintenance, traffic plans and markings, worker safety training,\ncontractor outreach, and enforcement efforts. For the purposes of this\nsubdivision, the term "bridge authority" shall mean the New York state\nbridge authority, a body corporate and politic constituting a public\nbenefit corporation created and const...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred\neighty-five-a of this chapter. All fines, penalties and forfeitures paid\nto the city of New York pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision\nshall be credited to the general fund of such city, unless a different\ndisposition is prescribed by charter, special law, local law or\nordinance.\n  * NB Repealed December 1, 2030\n  * 17. Where the chair of the New York state thruway authority has\nestablished a demonstration program imposing monetary liability on the\nowner of a vehicle for failure of an operator thereof to comply with\nsection three hundred eighty-five of this chapter and the rules of the\nthruway authority in relation to gross vehicle weight and/or axle weight\nin accordance with section three hundred eighty-five-a of this chapter,\nany fine or penalty collected by a court, judge, magistrate or other\nofficer for an imposition of liability which occurs pursuant to such\nprogram shall be paid to the state comptroller within the first ten days\nof the month following collection, except as otherwise provided in\nsubdivision three of section ninety-nine-a of the state finance law.\nEvery such payment shall be accompanied by a statement in such form and\ndetail as the comptroller shall provide. Notwithstanding the provisions\nof subdivision five of this section, eighty percent of any such fine or\npenalty imposed for such liability shall be paid to the thruway\nauthority, and twenty percent of any such fine or penalty shall be paid\nto the city, town or village in which the violation giving rise to the\nliability occurred. With respect to the percentage of fines or penalties\npaid to the thruway authority, one hundred percent shall be dedicated to\ncapital projects related to the thruway and thruway bridges after\ndeducting the expenses necessary to administer such demonstration\nprogram, provided, however, that such funds provided pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be payable on the audit and warrant of the\ncomptroller. For th...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1803__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred eighty-five-a of this\nchapter and the term "thruway" shall mean generally a divided highway\nunder the jurisdiction of the thruway authority for mixed traffic with\naccess limited as the authority may determine and generally with grade\nseparations at intersections. All fines, penalties and forfeitures paid\nto a city, town or village pursuant to the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall be credited to the general fund of such city, town or\nvillage, unless a different disposition is prescribed by charter,\nspecial law, local law or ordinance.\n  * NB Repealed December 1, 2030\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>