<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1809-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1809-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1809-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1809-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1809-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1809-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-1809-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1809_B">
        <num>1809-B</num>
        <heading>Mandatory surcharge required for certain violations relating to handicapped parking spaces</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1809-b. Mandatory surcharge required for certain violations relating\nto handicapped parking spaces. 1. Notwithstanding any other provision of\nlaw, whenever proceedings in an administrative tribunal or a court\nresult in a finding of liability, or conviction for a violation of\nsection twelve hundred three-a, twelve hundred three-b or twelve hundred\nthree-c of this chapter or any other statute, local law, ordinance or\nrule involving the parking, stopping or standing of motor vehicles\nregistered pursuant to section four hundred four-a of this chapter or\nthose possessing a special vehicle identification parking permit issued\nin accordance with section one thousand two hundred three-a of this\nchapter, there shall be levied a mandatory surcharge in addition to any\nother sentence, fine or penalty otherwise permitted or required, in the\namount of thirty dollars. Such surcharge shall not be deemed a monetary\npenalty for the purposes of section two hundred thirty-seven of this\nchapter or section 19-203 of the administrative code of the city of New\nYork.\n  2. The mandatory surcharge provided for in subdivision one of this\nsection shall be paid to the clerk of the court or administrative\ntribunal that made the determination of liability. Within the first ten\ndays of the month next succeeding the collection of such surcharge, the\ncollecting authority shall pay fifteen dollars of such surcharge to the\nchief fiscal officer of the county in which such violation occurred or\nof the city of New York, for deposit to the credit of the handicapped\nparking education fund of such county or city established pursuant to\nsection twelve hundred three-g of this chapter which shall be used by\nsuch county or city solely for a handicapped parking education program\npursuant to such section. The remaining amount of the surcharge shall be\npaid to the chief fiscal officer of the municipality from which it\noriginated and used by such municipality for its local criminal justice\nprograms and purposes; provided, however, that such municipality shall\nuse ten percent of such funds for developing and implementing a\ndisability awareness program for local law enforcement agencies for the\npurpose of training local law enforcement personnel to recognize and\nappropriately respond to persons with disabilities with whom such\npersonnel come into contact in the course of their duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>