<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207">
        <num>207</num>
        <heading>Uniform traffic summons and complaint</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 207. Uniform traffic summons and complaint. 1. Except as otherwise\nprovided, the commissioner shall be authorized to prescribe the form of\nsummons and complaint in all cases involving a violation of any\nprovision of this chapter, including section twelve hundred three-c, or\nof any provision of the tax law or of the transportation law regulating\ntraffic, or of any ordinance, rule or regulation relating to traffic,\nand to establish procedures for proper administrative controls over the\ndisposition thereof. The commissioner is not authorized to prescribe the\nform of summons and complaint for parking, stopping or standing\nviolations or a violation of article forty-seven or forty-eight of this\nchapter.\n  2. The chief executive officer of each local police force including\ncounty, town, city and village police departments, sheriffs, and the\nsuperintendent of state police shall prepare or cause to be prepared\nsuch records and reports as may be prescribed hereunder.\n  3. The commissioner shall have the power from time to time to adopt\nsuch rules and regulations as may be necessary to accomplish the\npurposes and enforce the provisions of this section including\nrequirements for reporting by trial courts having jurisdiction over\ntraffic violations.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall not apply to or supersede any\nordinance, rule or regulation heretofore or hereafter made, adopted or\nprescribed pursuant to law in any city having a population of one\nmillion or over, and the commissioner may limit the application of any\nrule or regulation to exclude specified violations based upon conditions\nor factors making differentiation or separate classification necessary\nor desirable.\n  5. Any person who disposes of any uniform traffic summons and\ncomplaint in any manner other than that prescribed by law shall be\nguilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>