<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209">
        <num>209</num>
        <heading>Bureau of motor vehicles abolished; transfer of functions; officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209. Bureau of motor vehicles abolished; transfer of functions;\nofficers and employees. The bureau of motor vehicles in the department\nof taxation and finance is hereby abolished. The functions, powers and\nduties of the bureau of motor vehicles in the department of taxation and\nfinance are hereby assigned to the department of motor vehicles. Each\ndeputy commissioner in the bureau of motor vehicles in the department of\ntaxation and finance shall continue in office as deputy commissioner in\nthe department of motor vehicles and shall serve during the pleasure of\nthe commissioner. All civil service employees in the existing bureau of\nmotor vehicles in the department of taxation and finance, in service at\nthe time this section takes effect, shall retain their present civil\nservice classification and be transferred to the department of motor\nvehicles without further examination or classification, and such\nemployees shall perform such duties therein as may be assigned to them\nby the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>