<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2107"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2107">
        <num>2107</num>
        <heading>Issuance and records</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall file each\napplication received and, when satisfied as to its genuineness and\nregularity and that the applicant is entitled to the issuance of a\ncertificate of title, shall issue a certificate of title of the vehicle,\nexcept that the commissioner may require that any such vehicle be\ninspected in a manner prescribed by him for conformity to the\ndescription given in the application before he issues a certificate of\ntitle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall maintain a record of all certificates of\ntitle issued by him:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2107__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Under a distinctive title number assigned to the vehicle;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2107__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Under the identifying number of the vehicle;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2107__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Alphabetically, under the name of the owner, unless he maintains\nalphabetical records of all owners holding certificates of registration;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2107__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Under the registration number of the vehicle; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2107__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the discretion of the commissioner, in any other method he\ndetermines.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the commissioner issues a certificate of title for a vehicle\nas a result of an original application for a title or as a result of the\nfiling of a security interest, he shall also issue and mail to the\nlienholder or lienholders named in the original application, or to the\nlienholder who filed the subsequent security interest a notice of\nrecorded lien.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall not issue a certificate of title to a\nmanufactured home with respect to which there has been filed an\naffidavit of affixation pursuant to paragraph five of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection twenty-one hundred seventeen-a of this article, paragraph five\nof subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twenty-one hundred seventeen-b of this\narticle, and paragraph five of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twenty-one\nhundred seventeen-c of this article.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall file, upon receipt, each affidavit of\naffixation that is delivered in accordance with subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection three hundred forty-four-b of the real property law and each\ndeclaration that is delivered pursuant to paragraph six of subdivision\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twenty-one hundred seventeen-c of this article when\nsatisfied as to its genuineness and regularity.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall maintain a record of each affidavit of\naffixation the commissioner files in accordance with subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis section. The record shall state the vehicle information or serial\nnumber of the manufactured home, the county of recordation, the date of\nrecordation, the book and page number of each book of deeds where there\nhas been recorded an affidavit of affixation pursuant to paragraph (iii)\nof subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred forty-four-b of the real\nproperty law and this article, and if applicable, a statement that filed\nwith the affidavit of affixation is a declaration pursuant to paragraph\nsix of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twenty-one hundred seventeen-c of this\narticle, and any other data the commissioner prescribes.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall file, upon receipt, each application for\nsurrender of the manufacturer's certificate of origin relating to a\nmanufactured home that is delivered in accordance with section\ntwenty-one hundred seventeen-a of this article, when satisfied as to its\ngenuineness and regularity.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall maintain a record of each manufactured\nhome manufacturer's certificate of origin that the commissioner accepts\nfor surrender as provided in section twenty-one hundred seventeen-a of\nthis article. The record shall state the vehicle information or serial\nnumber of the manufactured home, the date the manufacturer's certificate\nof origin was delivered for surrender, the county of recordation, the\ndate of recordation, and the book and page number of each book of deeds\nwhere there has been recorded an affidavit of affixation pursuant to\nparagraph (iii) of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred forty-four-b\nof the real property law and this article, and any other data the\ncommissioner prescribes.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall file, upon receipt, each application for\nsurrender of the certificate of title relating to a manufactured home\nthat is delivered in accordance with section twenty-one hundred\nseventeen-b of this article, when satisfied as to its genuineness and\nregularity.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall maintain a record of each manufactured\nhome certificate of title that the commissioner accepts for surrender as\nprovided in section twenty-one hundred seventeen-b of this article. The\nrecord shall state the vehicle information or serial number of the\nmanufactured home, the date the certificate of title was delivered for\nsurrender, the county of recordation, the date of recordation, the book\nand page number of each book of deeds where there has been recorded an\naffidavit of affixation pursuant to paragraph (iii) of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof section three hundred forty-four-b of the real property law and this\narticle, and any other data the commissioner prescribes.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall file, upon receipt, each application for\nconfirmation of conversion relating to a manufactured home that is\ndelivered in accordance with section twenty-one hundred seventeen-c of\nthis article, when satisfied as to its genuineness and regularity.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall maintain a record of each application for\nconfirmation of conversion accepted as provided in section twenty-one\nhundred seventeen-c of this article. The record shall state the vehicle\ninformation or serial number of the manufactured home, the county of\nrecordation, the date of recordation, the book and page number of each\nbook of deeds where there has been recorded an affidavit of affixation\npursuant to paragraph (iii) of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred\nforty-four-b of the real property law and this article, and any other\ndata the commissioner prescribes.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the\ncommissioner shall maintain the records required by this section\nindefinitely.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall establish electronic public access to the\nrecords maintained in accordance with subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2107__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this section.\n  * NB Effective December 12, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>