<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2225"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2225"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2225"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2225">
        <num>2225</num>
        <heading>Certificate of registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2225. Certificate of registration. 1. Certificate. Upon the filing\nof the application and payment of the fee as provided in this article,\nthe commissioner shall assign to such snowmobile a distinctive number,\nand, without further expense to the applicant, issue a certificate of\nregistration, in such manner and form as the commissioner shall\nprescribe. In the event of the loss, mutilation or destruction of any\ncertificate of registration, the owner of the registered snowmobile may\nfile such statement and proof of the facts as the commissioner shall\nrequire with a fee of one dollar, with the department, for the issuance\nof a duplicate or substitute.\n  2. Carrying certificate. Every person operating a snowmobile\nregistered in accordance with any of the provisions of this article\nshall, upon demand of any magistrate, police officer or peace officer,\nwhen acting pursuant to his special duties, produce for inspection the\ncertificate of registration for such snowmobile and shall furnish to\nsuch person any information necessary for the identification of such\nsnowmobile and its owner. The failure to produce the certificate of\nregistration as provided herein shall not be an offense, but shall be\npresumptive evidence of operating a snowmobile which is not registered\nas required by this article.\n  3. Change of residence. It shall be the duty of every owner holding a\ncertificate of registration to notify the department, in writing, of any\nchange of residence of such owner within fifteen days after such change\noccurs, and to inscribe on such certificate, in the place provided a\nrecord of such change of residence.\n  4. Change of ownership. Whenever a snowmobile is transferred or its\nuse discontinued, the registration portion of the certificate of\nregistration shall be properly signed and executed by the owner showing\nthat the ownership of the snowmobile has been transferred or its use\ndiscontinued and such certificate shall be returned to the department\nwithin fifteen days after such transfer or discontinuance. In the case\nof transfer, the new owner shall apply for a new certificate by\ncompleting an application for registration, using the original number\nissued for such snowmobile. Such application shall be submitted to the\ndepartment together with the renewal or transfer of the old certificate\nof registration, properly signed by the previous owner, and the required\nfee of five dollars. The renewal or transfer of the old certificate of\nregistration, properly signed by the previous owner, shall constitute a\ntemporary registration for such new owner for a period determined by the\ncommissioner from the date such snowmobile was transferred to the new\nowner. In the event that such snowmobile was purchased from a registered\ndealer, the application must be accompanied by a dealer's form,\nnumbered, completed and signed by the dealer or his agent and signed by\nthe new owner, as prescribed by the commissioner.\n  5. Destruction, theft or removal from state. It shall be the duty of\nevery owner of a snowmobile registered pursuant to the provisions of\nthis article to notify the department, in writing, of the destruction,\ntheft or permanent removal of such snowmobile from the state, within\nfifteen days of acquiring knowledge thereof. In the event of destruction\nor theft, the certificate of registration shall be surrendered with such\nnotice.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>