<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2230"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2230"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2230"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2230/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2230/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2230/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2230/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2230">
        <num>2230</num>
        <heading>Suspension and revocation of registrations; offenses; penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2230. Suspension and revocation of registrations; offenses;\npenalties.  1. The commissioner may suspend or revoke a registration\nissued pursuant to the provisions of this article, upon satisfactory\nproof of a violation of any provision of this article, or of the parks,\nrecreation and historic preservation law at the request of the\ncommissioner of parks, recreation and historic preservation, or of any\nrule, regulation, order, local law or ordinance adopted or promulgated\npursuant thereto.  Such suspension or revocation shall be issued only\nafter a hearing unless such a hearing is waived by the registrant. Upon\nsaid suspension or revocation, all rights and privileges accruing to\nsuch registrant shall terminate.\n  2. a. Except as provided in paragraph b of this subdivision, any\nperson who violates any provision of this article or regulation adopted\npursuant thereto shall be guilty of a violation punishable by a fine of\nup to two hundred dollars, and one-half of such fine shall be deposited\nin the snowmobile trail development and maintenance fund as set forth in\nsection 21.07 of the parks, recreation and historic preservation law.\n  b. Any person who violates the provisions of paragraph a of\nsubdivision one of section twenty-two hundred twenty-two of this article\nshall be guilty of a violation punishable by a fine of not less than two\nhundred dollars nor more than five hundred dollars, except if the\nviolation consists of failure to renew a registration which was valid\nwithin sixty days the fine shall be not more than fifty dollars.\nOne-half of such fines shall be deposited in the snowmobile trail\ndevelopment and maintenance fund as set forth in section 21.07 of the\nparks, recreation and historic preservation law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>