<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-224-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-224-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="224-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-224-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-224-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-224-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-224-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_224_A">
        <num>224-A</num>
        <heading>Establishment of the highway construction and maintenance safety education program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 224-a. Establishment of the highway construction and maintenance\nsafety education program. 1. The commissioner of transportation, after\nconsultation with the commissioner of the department, shall promulgate\nrules and regulations regarding the establishment and implementation of\na highway construction and maintenance safety education program. The\nhighway construction and maintenance safety education program shall be\nestablished for the purpose of providing education, advocacy and\nincreased awareness of laws pertaining to protecting the safety of\nhighway construction and maintenance workers. The program shall provide\nfunding for activities such as public service announcements, public\neducation and awareness campaigns, distribution of literature, and any\nother activities that are consistent with such purposes.\n  2. It shall be the duty of the commissioner of transportation to make\na biennial report to the governor, the temporary president of the senate\nand the speaker of the assembly which shall be due on the first of April\nevery second year following implementation of the program and shall\ninclude an assessment of the effectiveness of the program,\nrecommendations for expanding or improving the program and any problems\nor other matters related to the administration of the program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>