<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2253"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2253"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2253"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2253/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2253/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2253/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2253/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2253">
        <num>2253</num>
        <heading>Certificates of registration, registration numbers, and validating stickers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2253. Certificates of registration, registration numbers, and\nvalidating stickers. 1. Issuance. Upon the approval of an application\nfor registration and payment of the fee as provided in this article, the\ncommissioner shall assign to a vessel a registration number, and,\nwithout further expense to the applicant, issue a certificate of\nregistration and, effective April first, nineteen hundred eighty-six, a\nvalidating sticker or stickers, in such manner and form as the\ncommissioner shall prescribe.\n  2. Certificate of registration. The certificate of registration issued\nby the commissioner shall be available at all times for inspection on\nthe vessel for which it is issued whenever such vessel is in operation,\nunless otherwise provided by a rule or regulation of the commissioner.\nEvery person operating a vessel shall, upon demand of any peace officer,\nfederal officer or other person having the authority to enforce the\nprovisions of this chapter, produce the certificate of registration for\ninspection. The failure to produce the certificate of registration, as\nprovided herein, shall not be an offense, but shall be presumptive\nevidence of operating a vessel which is not registered as required by\nthis article.\n  3. Registration number. A registration number once assigned under this\nsection shall remain with the vessel until the vessel is destroyed,\nabandoned or permanently removed from the state, or until changed or\nterminated by the commissioner. The registration number assigned to the\nvessel shall be painted on or attached to each side of the forward half\nof the vessel by the owner in such a position as to be displayed in a\nconspicuous manner with figures and letters at least three inches in\nheight. The registration number shall be maintained in a legible\ncondition so that the figures and letters are readily discernible during\ndaylight hours at a distance of one hundred feet. No other number shall\nbe carried on the forward half of such vessel. Notwithstanding the\nforegoing provisions of this subdivision, a vessel having a valid marine\ndocument issued by the United States or a foreign government shall not\nbe required to display its assigned registration number on the vessel.\n  4. Validating stickers. Effective April first, nineteen hundred\neighty-six, at the time of the original registration and at the time of\neach renewal thereof, the commissioner shall also issue to said\nregistrant a validating sticker or stickers indicating the validity of\nthe current registration and the expiration date thereof, which\nvalidating sticker or stickers shall be affixed to the vessel in such\nmanner as the commissioner may prescribe provided, however, that where\nthe hull of a vessel equipped with a windshield is constructed of wood,\nsuch validating sticker or stickers may be affixed to the windshield of\nthe vessel. From that time and notwithstanding the fact that a vessel\nhas been assigned a registration number, it shall not be considered as\nvalidly registered within the meaning of this article unless a\nvalidating sticker and current registration certificate have been\nissued. In addition, the commissioner may issue a validating sticker or\nstickers to the holder of a certificate of registration issued prior to\nApril first, nineteen hundred eighty-six, without further expense to the\nholder, indicating the validity of the current registration and the\nexpiration date thereof, which validating sticker or stickers shall be\naffixed to the vessel in such a manner as the commissioner may\nprescribe. The commissioner shall establish by regulation such terms and\nconditions as may be necessary to accomplish the issuance of such\nvalidating sticker or stickers and the date upon which their issuance\nshall be completed. From thirty days after such date and notwithstanding\nthe fact that a vessel has been assigned a registration number and has a\ncurrent certificate of registration, it shall not be considered as\nvalidly registered within the meaning of this article unless a\nvalidating sticker or stickers is displayed on the vessel.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>