<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2257"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2257"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2257"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2257/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2257/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2257/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2257/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2257">
        <num>2257</num>
        <heading>Registration of dealers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2257__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon payment of\nthe required fee, a dealer shall be entitled to receive one or more\ndemonstrator numbers, which may be used in lieu of a registration issued\nunder section twenty-two hundred fifty-one of this article for the\noperation of any vessel owned or controlled by the registrant and held\nfor sale or demonstration. Demonstrator numbers shall be displayed in a\nmanner prescribed by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2257__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon payment of the required fee, a dealer shall be entitled to\nreceive one or more number plates which may be used in lieu of any\nregistration issued under section four hundred one of this chapter for\nthe operation of any boat trailer owned or controlled by the dealer and\nheld for the purpose of sale or demonstration, provided such operation\nis directly related to the sale or demonstration of any boat trailer or\nvessel. The provisions of section four hundred two of this chapter with\nrespect to the care and display of number plates shall apply to number\nplates issued under this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2257__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may, in his discretion, limit the number of\ndemonstrator numbers or number plates which shall be issued to any\nregistrant. The fee for the replacement of lost, mutilated, or destroyed\ndemonstrator numbers or number plates shall be two dollars.\n  5. Fees. Every application, other than a renewal application, shall be\naccompanied by an application fee of ten dollars, which shall in no\nevent be refunded. The triennial fee for such registration or renewal\nthereof shall be seventy-five dollars. The triennial fee for\ndemonstrator numbers or number plates shall be sixty dollars for each\nnumber or number plate. The application for registration, demonstrator\nnumbers and number plates shall be accompanied by the required fees.\nThere shall be no refund of any registration fee or any fee for\ndemonstrator numbers or number plates.\n  6. No dealer shall sell a vessel except in accordance with regulations\nestablished by the commissioner. The commissioner may, in his\ndiscretion, require a registrant to maintain a record in a prescribed\nform of all vessels received or disposed of by him. Upon request of an\nagent of the commissioner or of any peace officer acting pursuant to his\nspecial duties, a registrant shall produce such records and permit said\nagent or peace officer to examine them, and any vessels on the premises\nsubject to the record keeping requirements of this section during usual\nbusiness hours or while the registrant is conducting business. The\nfailure to produce such records or to permit such inspection as required\nby this subdivision shall be a violation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>