<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2261"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2261"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2261"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2261/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2261/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2261/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2261/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2261">
        <num>2261</num>
        <heading>Registration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2261__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fees for the registration, renewal, reregistration or\namendment or duplicate of a registration of a limited use automobile\nshall be the same fees as if such vehicle were registered pursuant to\nsection four hundred one of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2261__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The annual fee for the registration, renewal, reregistration or\namendment or duplicate of a registration of a limited use motorcycle\nshall be six dollars and twenty-five cents. Any such registration,\nrenewal, or reregistration shall take effect and expire on dates to be\ndetermined by the commissioner. A fee for a registration for periods of\nmore or less than one year shall not be prorated.\n  4. Carrying certificate. Every person operating a limited use vehicle\nregistered in accordance with any of the provisions of this article,\nshall, upon the demand of any magistrate, police officer, peace officer,\nwhen acting pursuant to his special duties, or motor vehicle hearing\nofficer produce for inspection the certificate of registration for such\nlimited use vehicle and shall furnish to such person any information\nnecessary for the identification of such limited use vehicle and its\nowner. The failure to produce the certificate of registration as\nprovided herein shall not be an offense, but shall be presumptive\nevidence of operating a limited use vehicle which is not registered as\nrequired by this article.\n  5. Out-of-state limited use vehicle registration. The registration\nprovisions of this article shall not apply to a non-resident who has\nregistered his limited use vehicle in compliance with the registration\nor licensing laws of the state, province or country of his residence,\nprovided that the limited use vehicle so registered in accordance with\nthe laws of the state, province or country of residence of such owner is\nappropriately identified by an identification plate, sticker or other\nidentifying device issued by such state, province or country.\n  6. Registration at time of sale. Every limited use motorcycle, as\ndefined by section one hundred twenty-one-b of this chapter, sold by a\ndealer shall be registered at the time of sale of such vehicle. Such\nregistration shall take effect and expire on dates to be determined by\nthe commissioner. Any l...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>