<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2264"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2264"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2264"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2264/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2264/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2264/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2264/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2264">
        <num>2264</num>
        <heading>Display of registration number plate or plates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2264. Display of registration number plate or plates. 1. The\nregistration number plate or plates assigned to a limited use vehicle\nshall be displayed on the vehicle at all times such vehicle is operated\non the public highways in such manner as the commissioner may, be\nregulation, prescribe. One registration number plate shall be issued by\nthe commissioner for a limited use motorcycle. One or two registration\nnumber plates, as determined by the commissioner, shall be issued by the\ncommissioner for a limited use automobile. No number other than the\nregistration number plate assigned to a limited use vehicle by the\ncommissioner, or the identification number of the registration issued by\nanother state shall be painted, attached or otherwise displayed on a\nlimited use vehicle when such vehicle is being operated on a public\nhighway. Nothing herein shall prohibit the display of a vehicle\nidentification number plate or number affixed by the manufacturer or his\nagent in accordance with section twenty-two hundred sixty-seven of this\nchapter.\n  2. Dealer demonstrator number plates shall conform to the requirements\nset forth in subdivision one of this section with the exception that\nsuch number plates may be temporarily but firmly affixed to the limited\nuse vehicle being demonstrated or tested.\n  3. The use of dealer demonstrator number plates shall be subject to\nthe provisions of sections four hundred fifteen and four hundred sixteen\nof this chapter.\n  4. No dealer shall permit a dealer demonstrator number plate to be\nused on any vehicle unless such vehicle would qualify for the issuance\nof such a number plate when registered.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>