<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2282"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2282"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2282"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2282/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2282/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2282/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2282/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2282">
        <num>2282</num>
        <heading>Registration and permit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An annual fee of twelve dollars and fifty cents for each\nindividual resident registration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An annual fee of twelve dollars and fifty cents for each\nindividual nonresident registration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An annual fee of twenty-five dollars for each dealer registration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An annual fee of five dollars for each additional dealer\ndemonstrator registration number.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A fee of three dollars for replacement of a lost, mutilated or\ndestroyed certificate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provided, however, that the provisions of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision with respect to the payment of dealer registration\nfees shall not apply to dealers registered pursuant to section four\nhundred fifteen of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Annual fees shall not be prorated and such fees shall be\napplicable to a year or any portion of a year.\nNotwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this section, the\ndifference collected between the fees set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision in effect on and after September first, two\nthousand nine and the fees set forth in such paragraphs in effect prior\nto such date shall be deposited to the credit of the dedicated highway\nand bridge trust fund.\n  5. Application. The owner of each ATV requiring registration under\nthis section shall present an application for registration to the\ncommissioner, on a blank to be prepared and furnished by the\ncommissioner for that purpose. Such application shall contain or be\naccompanied by such evidence of the ownership of the ATV described in\nthe application as may be required by the commissioner.\n  6. Dealers.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who is a dealer, and who is not registered\nas a dealer pursuant to section four hundred fifteen of this chapter,\nshall register as an ATV dealer and operate in accordance with the rules\nand regulations of the commissioner for ATV dealers. The commissioner,\nupon receipt of an application and the required fee, shall assign a\ndistinctive dealer registration number to the registrant and issue an\nappropriate registration certificate to him and assign two dealer\ndemonstrator registration numbers and upon the payment of the\nappropriate fee, such additional numbers as shall be requested. Dealer\nregistrations and dealer demonstrator registration numbers shall not be\ntransferable. Provided, however, the commissioner may limit the number\nof dealer demonstration registration numbers issued to a dealer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No dealer shall sell or offer for retail sale any ATV, other than\nan ATV identified and sold for use only in off-highway competitions,\nwhich is not equipped with all equipment necessary for the registration\nof an ATV.\n  6-a. Registration at time of sale. Every all terrain vehicle defined\nby section twenty-two hundred eighty-one of this article sold by a\ndealer shall be registered at the time of sale of such vehicle. Such\nregistration shall be valid until the thirty-first day of August\nfollowing the date of such sale; provided, however, that any all terrain\nvehicle sold after April first of each year shall be issued a\nregistration valid until the thirty-first day of August in the year\nfollowing that in which the all terrain vehicle is sold. Any all terrain\nvehicle purchased for use exclusively outside of the state of New York\nshall not require registration at the time of purchase, and the\npurchaser of such all terrain vehicle shall sign a declaration, provided\nby the dealer, which shall state that such purchaser understands the\nconditions under which an all terrain vehicle must be registered and the\npenalty for violation of such registration provisions. Each signed\ndeclaration shall be forwarded by the dealer to the commissioner. The\nform of such declaration shall be provided by the commissioner to each\ndealer.\n  7. Renewal. Every owner of an ATV and dealer shall renew his\nregistration in such manner as the commissioner shall prescribe, on\npayment of the same registration fees as provided in subdivision four of\nthis section.\n  8. Indicia of registration. At the time of the original registration\nand at the time of each renewal thereof, the commissioner shall also\nissue validating forms in a manner he has prescribed indicating the\nvalidity of the current registration and the expiration date thereof,\nwhich indicia of registration shall be affixed to the vehicle in such\nmanner as the commissioner may prescribe.\n  No ATV shall be considered ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ATVs owned and used by the United States, another state, or a\npolitical subdivision thereof, but such ATV shall display the name of\nthe owner on the vehicle thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2282__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ATVs covered by a valid registration or license of another state,\nprovince or country, as provided in subdivision twelve of this section.\n  12. Out of state ATV registration. The registration provisions of this\narticle shall not apply to non-resident owners who have registered their\nATVs in compliance with the registration and licensing laws of the\nstate, province, district or country of residence, provided that the ATV\nis appropriately identified in accordance with the laws of the state of\nresidence. The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to a\nresident of another state, province, district or country which does not\nhave an ATV registration and identification law. Nothing in this\nsubdivision shall be construed to authorize the operation of any ATV\ncontrary to the provisions of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>