<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2403"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2403"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2403"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2403/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2403/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2403/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2403/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2403">
        <num>2403</num>
        <heading>Operation of ATVs; where permitted</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2403__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An ATV may make a direct crossing on a highway other than an\ninterstate highway or a controlled access highway, provided:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2403__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the crossing is made at an angle of approximately ninety degrees\nto the direction of the highway and at a place where no obstruction\nprevents a quick and safe crossing;\n  (ii) the vehicle is brought to a complete stop before crossing the\nshoulder or main travelled way of the highway;\n  (iii) the driver yields the right-of-way to all oncoming traffic that\nconstitutes an immediate hazard;\n  (iv) in crossing a divided highway, the crossing is made only at an\nintersection of the highway with another public street or highway, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2403__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the crossing is made between the hours of one-half hour after\nsunset to one-half hour before sunrise or in conditions of reduced\nvisibility, only if both front and rear lights are lighted.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2403__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An ATV may be operated on any highway which has been designated\nand posted as open for travel by ATVs in accordance with the provisions\nof section twenty-four hundred five of this article.\n  2. Public lands other than highways. No person shall operate an ATV on\nany public lands, waters and property other than a highway, except that\nan ATV may be operated on any such lands which have been designated and\nposted for travel by ATVs in accordance with the provisions of section\ntwenty-four hundred five of this article.\n  3. Private property. No person shall operate an ATV on the private\nproperty of another without the consent of the owner or lessee thereof.\n  3-a. Real property of a farm operation. No person shall operate an ATV\non the real property of a farm operation, as defined in subdivision\neleven of section three hundred one of the agriculture and markets law,\nwithout the consent of the owner or lessee thereof, where such owner or\nlessee has erected or maintained any sign, structure, display, or device\nprohibiting the trespass thereon, and which shall include a sign\nstating: "No Trespassing". A violation of this subdivision shall be a\ntraffic infraction, and shall, upon a conviction of a first violation be\npunishable by a fine of not more than two hundred fifty dollars or by\nimprisonment for not more than fifteen days or by both such fine and\nimprisonment; upon a conviction of a second violation, both of which\nwere committed within a period of eighteen months, shall be punishable\nby a fine of not more than four hundred dollars or by imprisonment for\nnot more than forty-five days or by both such fine and imprisonment;\nupon a conviction of a third or subsequent violation, all of which were\ncommitted within a period of eighteen months, shall be punishable by a\nfine of not more than five hundred fifty dollars or by imprisonment for\nnot more than ninety days or by both such fine and imprisonment.\n  4. Emergency vehicle. The provisions of subdi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>