<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2407"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2407"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2407"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2407/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2407/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2407/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2407/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2407">
        <num>2407</num>
        <heading>Liability insurance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2407__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\nfour of section three hundred eleven of this chapter. In lieu of such\ninsurance coverage as hereinabove provided, the commissioner, in his\ndiscretion and upon application of a governmental agency having\nregistered in its name one or more ATVs, may waive the requirement of\ninsurance by a private insurance carrier and issue a certificate of\nself-insurance, when he is satisfied that such governmental agency is\npossessed of financial ability to respond to judgments obtained against\nit, arising out of the ownership, use or operation of such ATVs. The\ncommissioner may also waive the requirement of insurance by a private\ninsurance carrier and issue a certificate of self-insurance upon\napplication of any person or any other corporation, having registered in\nits name, one or more ATVs and furnishing of proof that a certificate of\nself-insurance has been issued and is in effect pursuant to the\nprovisions of section three hundred sixteen of this chapter.\n  2. Proof of insurance as required by this section shall be produced\nand displayed by the owner or operator of such ATV upon the request of\nany magistrate or any person having authority to enforce the provisions\nof this chapter. The failure to produce such proof upon the request of\nany such person shall not be an offense but shall be presumptive\nevidence that the ATV is being operated without having such insurance in\nforce and effect.\n  3. Proof of insurance as required by this section shall be produced\nand displayed by the owner or operator of such ATV to any person who has\nsuffered or claims to have suffered either personal injury or property\ndamage as a result of the operation of such ATV by the owner or\noperator, if such insurance coverage was required under the\ncircumstances of such operation. It shall be an affirmative defense to\nany prosecution for a violation of this subdivision that such proof was\nso produced or displayed within twenty-four hours of receiving notice of\nsuc...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>