<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2408"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2408"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2408"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2408/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2408/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2408/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2408/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2408">
        <num>2408</num>
        <heading>Special events</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2408. Special events. 1. The commissioner shall adopt and may, from\ntime to time, amend rules and regulations determining the special events\nwhich shall be subject to permit and designating the equipment and\nfacilities necessary for safe operation of ATVs and for the safety of\noperators, participants, and observers in such special events. Copies of\nsuch regulations shall be furnished by the commissioner to any person\nmaking an application therefor.\n  2. Whenever a special event is proposed to be held, the person in\ncharge thereof shall, at least thirty days prior thereto, file an\napplication with appropriate governmental agencies having jurisdiction\nover the site of such event to hold such special event. The application\nshall set forth the date and location of the proposed special event and\nsuch other information as the governmental agencies may require, and\nsuch event shall not be conducted without written authorization from\nsuch governmental agencies. Governmental agencies shall either grant or\ndeny authorization to hold a special event within thirty days after\nreceipt of an application for authorization. The commissioner shall be\nfurnished with a copy of all such applications. No permit shall be\nrequired for a closed-circuit special event held entirely on private\nproperty, but appropriate governmental agencies shall be notified of\nsuch event at least thirty days prior thereto.\n  3. ATVs operated at special events shall be exempted from the\nprovisions of this article concerning mufflers, lights and tires during\nthe time of such event, including all pre-race practice at the location\nof said event.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>