<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2410"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2410"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2410"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2410">
        <num>2410</num>
        <heading>Operation by minors</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2410. Operation by minors.  1. Except as provided by subdivision two\nof this section, no person under the age of sixteen years shall operate\nan ATV except upon lands owned or leased by his or her parent or\nguardian, unless he or she is under general supervision of a person\neighteen years of age or over.  "Leased lands" as herein used shall not\ninclude lands leased by an organization of which said operator or his or\nher parent or guardian is a member.\n  2. A person fourteen years of age but less than sixteen years of age\nwho has received safety training as prescribed by the commissioner and\nhas received the appropriate ATV safety certificate issued by the\ncommissioner may operate an ATV in the same manner as a person who is\nsixteen years of age or older.\n  3. The failure of a person to exhibit an ATV safety certificate upon\ndemand to any magistrate or any other officer having authority to\nenforce the provisions of this article shall not be an offense, but\nshall be presumptive evidence that such person is not the holder of such\ncertificate.\n  4. No parent or guardian shall authorize or knowingly permit his child\nor ward, if under sixteen years of age, to operate an ATV in violation\nof any provision of this article, any rules or regulations promulgated\nthereunder, or the provisions of any local law or ordinance.\n  5. No owner or other person in possession of any ATV shall authorize\nor knowingly permit any person under sixteen years of age to operate\nsuch an ATV in violation of any provision of this article, any rules or\nregulations promulgated thereunder, or the provisions of any local law\nor ordinance.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>