<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2413"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2413"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2413"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2413/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2413/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2413/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-2413/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2413">
        <num>2413</num>
        <heading>Accidents; reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2413. Accidents; reports. 1. The operator of any ATV involved in any\naccident resulting in injuries to or death of any person or in which\nproperty damage in the estimated amount of six hundred dollars or more\nis sustained, shall immediately notify the nearest law enforcement\nagency and shall within ten days after such accident report the matter\nin writing to the department, with a copy thereof to the sheriff or\npolice commissioner of the county in which said accident occurred. If\nsuch operator is physically incapable of making such report and there is\nanother participant in the accident not so incapacitated such\nparticipant shall make the report within the allotted time after such\naccident. In the event that there is no other participant and the\noperator is other than the owner, then the owner shall within the\nprescribed period of time, after learning of the facts of such accident,\nreport the matter to the department, together with such information as\nmay have come to his knowledge relating to such accident. Every such\noperator of an ATV, or participant of any such accident, or the owner,\nof the ATV involved in any such accident, shall make such other and\nadditional reports as the commissioner shall require.\n  2. Whenever any ATV meets with an accident involving a loss of life,\npersonal injury or damage to property and the operator thereof has\nknowledge of such accident, he shall stop and give his name and address,\nthe name and address of the owner thereof and the registration number\nassigned to said ATV to the injured person or the person sustaining the\ndamage, or to a peace or police officer. In the event the person\nsustaining the damage is not present at the place where the damage\noccurred, the operator shall, as soon as physically able, report the\nsame to the nearest law enforcement agency.\n  3. A peace, police, or judicial officer who investigates or receives\ninformation of an accident involving an ATV shall make a written report\nof the investigation or information received, and such additional facts\nrelating to the accident as may come to his knowledge and mail the same\nwithin forty-eight hours to the department and keep a record thereof in\nhis office.\n  4. Failure of any person to report an accident as herein provided or\nfailure to give correctly the information required of him by the\ncommissioner in connection with such report shall be a misdemeanor and\nshall constitute a ground for suspension or revocation of the ATV safety\ncertificate of any person or the certificate of registration of any ATV\ninvolved in the accident. The commissioner may temporarily suspend the\nATV safety certificate of the person failing to make such report or the\ncertificate of registration of the ATV involved in the accident until\nsuch report has been filed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>