<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-302"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-302"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="302"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-302/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-302/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_302">
        <num>302</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the commissioner</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_302__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the duty\nof the commissioner to administer the provisions of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_302__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may authorize the acceptance of a certificate of\ninspection issued in another state having inspection requirements\nsubstantially similar to those of this state. He may also extend, on any\nreasonable ground, the time within which a certificate shall be obtained\nby the owner of a motor vehicle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_302__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may, consistent with federal law and regulations,\npermit any person, association, corporation or subsidiary corporation of\na parent corporation having registered in his or its name in this state\nmore than twenty-five motor vehicles, and qualified dealers of motor\nvehicles held by them for sale or demonstration, who maintain approved\ninspection facilities, to conduct the inspection or inspections required\nby this article under regulation prescribed by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_302__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of motor vehicles may appoint and at pleasure\nremove inspectors, consultants and such other assistants and employees\nas he may deem necessary, within the amount available therefor by\nappropriation, to carry out the provisions of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_302__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner is empowered to make reasonable rules and\nregulations for the administration and enforcement of this article and\nthe periods during which motor vehicles are required to be inspected.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_302__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of motor vehicles may, consistent with federal\nlaw and regulations, upon application of any municipality, and upon a\ndetermination that such municipality has sufficient personnel and\napproved inspection facilities to conduct the inspection or inspections\nrequired by this article under the regulations prescribed by the\ncommissioner, permit such municipality to conduct the inspection\nrequired by this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>