<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="304"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_304">
        <num>304</num>
        <heading>Inspection and certificates of inspection</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No certificate\nor certificates of inspection shall be issued by an official inspection\nstation until the mechanisms and other equipment, as specified in\nsection three hundred one</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this chapter, of the motor vehicle\ninspected are in proper and safe condition and comply with the rules and\nregulations of the commissioner and with the laws of this state and the\nemissions of such motor vehicle conform with subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nthree hundred one of this article and regulations promulgated pursuant\nthereto at the time the certificate is issued.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If such inspection discloses the necessity for adjustments,\ncorrections or repairs the owner shall be so notified and shall have\nsuch adjustments, corrections or repairs made within a period of thirty\ndays. If such inspection discloses improper tire pressure, the owner\nshall be so notified and may have such adjustments, corrections or\nrepairs made as authorized by this subdivision. The commissioner shall\nestablish procedures for reporting the results of such inspections and\nfor notifying the owners. The owner may have such adjustments,\ncorrections and repairs made in any way and by any person provided that\nsuch repairs are made in a manner consistent with federal law and\nregulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall issue certificates of inspection to\nofficial inspection stations. Such certificates of inspection shall be\nserially numbered and shall bear such information as the commissioner\nmay require, and shall include a notice that any complaint against an\nofficial inspection station for inadequate inspection or for making\nexcessive or unreasonable repairs, may be made in writing to the\ndepartment of motor vehicles at Albany, New York. Each certificate shall\nbe valid until the end of the inspection period during which the motor\nvehicle must again be inspected, as determined by the rules and\nregulations of the commissioner, or until the end of the repair period\ndesignated under section three hundred four</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, whichever occurs first.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>