<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-03-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="305"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_305">
        <num>305</num>
        <heading>Fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fee for a certificate of inspection issued by the\ncommissioner, to be collected from the owner of an official inspection\nstation to whom issued, shall be as follows:\n  *</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fee for a certificate representing that a safety inspection\nhas been performed shall be two dollars, which shall be deposited into\nthe transportation safety account established pursuant to section\nninety-one of the state finance law through March thirty-first, two\nthousand four and to the dedicated highway and bridge trust fund from\nApril first, two thousand four and thereafter, and\n  * NB Effective until April 1, 2026\n  *</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fee for a certificate representing that a safety inspection\nhas been performed shall be two dollars, which shall be deposited into\nthe transportation safety account established pursuant to section\nninety-one of the state finance law, and\n  * NB Effective April 1, 2026\n  *</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fee for a certificate representing that an emissions\ninspection has been successfully completed shall be set by the\ncommissioner through regulation, at an amount not to exceed four dollars\nor eight dollars if performed on a biennial basis. Such fees shall be\ndeposited into the mobile source account of the clean air fund\nestablished by section ninety-seven-oo of the state finance law.\n  * NB Effective until April 1, 2026\n  *</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_305__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fee for a certificate representing that an emissions\ninspection has been successfully completed shall be set by the\ncommissioner through regulation, at an amount not to exceed two dollars\nor four dollars if performed on a biennial basis. Such fees shall be\ndeposited into the mobile source account of the clean air fund\nestablished by section ninety-seven-oo of the state finance law.\n  * NB Effective April 1, 2026\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No fee authorized by subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section shall apply\nto the state, a city, county, village, town or school district, or any\nof the departments thereof nor to a certificate issued by a licensed\nemissions inspection station to such a public entity. A refund may be\nmade, or credit allowed, for unused certificates of inspection, or for\ncertificates lost, mutilated or destroyed, to the extent provided by the\nregulations promulgated by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may establish maximum fees to be charged by an\nofficial inspection station. Such fees shall be prominently displayed at\nsuch station.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fees assessed under this article shall be paid to the\ncommissioner for deposit to the transportation safety account\nestablished pursuant to section ninety-one of the state finance law\nthrough March thirty-first, two thousand four and from April first, two\nthousand four and thereafter shall be deposited into the dedicated\nhighway and bridge trust fund, except that fees that are authorized to\nbe collected for each certificate of emissions inspection issued by the\ncommissioner, collected pursuant to paragraph two of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis section, shall be deposited into the mobile source account of the\nclean air fund, as established by section ninety-seven-oo of the state\nfinance law.\n  * NB Effective until April 1, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fees assessed under this article shall be paid to the\ncommissioner for deposit to the transportation safety account\nestablished pursuant to section ninety-one of the state finance law,\nexcept that fees that are authorized to be collected for each\ncertificate of emissions inspection issued by the commissioner,\ncollected pursuant to paragraph two of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section,\nshall be deposited into the mobile source account of the clean air fund,\nas established by section ninety-seven-oo of the state finance law.\n  * NB Effective April 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>