<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-330"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-330"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="330"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_330">
        <num>330</num>
        <heading>Commissioner to administer article; may require proof; court review</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_330__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall administer and enforce the provisions\nof this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_330__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner is hereby authorized to adopt and enforce such\nregulations as may be necessary for the administration of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_330__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon any reasonable ground, appearing on the records of the\nbureau, the commissioner may suspend or revoke the operator's or\nchauffeur's license of any person and may suspend or revoke any and all\nof the registration certificates or registration plates for any motor\nvehicle and may refuse to issue to any such person any new or renewal\nlicense or to register in the name of such person any motor vehicle\nunless and until such person gives proof of his financial responsibility\nin the future as hereinafter provided in this article.\n  Any person furnishing proof of financial responsibility pursuant to\nthis subdivision may be relieved from continuing to furnish such proof\nin the discretion of the commissioner provided three years have elapsed\nsince such proof was first furnished during which period such person has\nnot been convicted of, or forfeited bail given on being charged with,\nany of the offenses specified in subdivision two of section five hundred\nten of this chapter and no charges of any of such offenses are pending\nagainst such person. The affidavit of such person shall be accepted as\nproof of the facts therein stated, in the absence of evidence to the\ncontrary before the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_330__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person aggrieved by an order or act of the commissioner under\nthis section or under provisions of this article, may maintain a\nproceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and\nrules to review, but the commencement of such a proceeding shall not\nsuspend the order or act unless a stay thereof shall be allowed by said\ncourt pending final determination of the review.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_330__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of subdivision seven of section five hundred ten of\nthis chapter shall apply to a suspension under this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>