<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-332"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-332"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="332"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-332/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-332/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-332/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-332/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_332">
        <num>332</num>
        <heading>Proof required in the event of certain judgments</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_332__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The\ncommissioner shall also suspend the operator's or chauffeur's license\nand any and all of the registration certificates and registration plates\nissued to any person upon receiving authenticated report as hereinafter\nprovided that such person has failed for a period of fifteen days to\nsatisfy any judgment in amounts and upon a cause of action as\nhereinafter stated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_332__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The judgment herein referred to shall mean any judgment in excess\nof one thousand dollars for damages because of injury to or destruction\nof property, including loss of use thereof, or any judgment for damages,\nincluding damages for care and loss of services, because of bodily\ninjury to or death of any person arising out of the ownership,\nmaintenance, use or operation of any motor vehicle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_332__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall take action as required in this section\nupon receiving proper evidence that any person in another state, the\nDistrict of Columbia, any district court of the United States, or any\nprovince of Canada, has failed for a period of fifteen days to satisfy\nany judgment in amount as stated in section three hundred thirty-three\nand upon a cause of action as stated in this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_332__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person whose license, registration or non-resident's driving\nprivilege is subject to suspension hereunder, may be relieved from the\neffect of failure to satisfy such judgment, if such person files with\nthe commissioner proper evidence that a bond or insurance policy as\nprovided for in this article was in force and effect at the time of the\naccident resulting in the judgment, and was available for the\nsatisfaction of the judgment to the extent provided for in section three\nhundred thirty-three and that such judgment was so satisfied.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>