<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-376"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-376"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="376"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-376/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-376/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-376/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-376/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_376">
        <num>376</num>
        <heading>Lamps, signaling devices and reflectors on vehicles</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It\nshall be unlawful to operate, drive or park a vehicle, except a\nmotorcycle operated during the period from one-half hour before sunrise\nto one-half hour after sunset, on any public highway or street in this\nstate at any time during the day or night unless such vehicle is\nequipped with signaling devices and reflectors of a type approved by the\ncommissioner which are in good working condition; or to operate, drive\nor park a vehicle, except a motorcycle, on any public highway or street\nin this state, during the period from one-half hour after sunset to\none-half hour before sunrise, unless such vehicle is equipped with lamps\nof a type approved by the commissioner which are lighted and in good\nworking condition; or to operate, drive or park self-propelled\nagricultural equipment on any public highway or street in this state,\nduring the period from one-half hour after sunset to one-half hour\nbefore sunrise and during such other times as visibility for a distance\nof one thousand feet ahead of or behind such agricultural equipment is\nnot clear, unless such agricultural equipment is equipped with lamps of\na type approved by the commissioner which are lighted and in good\nworking condition.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of motor vehicles is hereby authorized and\nempowered to promulgate rules and regulations with respect to lamps,\nreflectors and signaling devices, their number, type, design,\nconstruction, location, attachment and use on vehicles being driven,\noperated or parked on any public highway or street in this state. In\npromulgating such rules and regulations the commissioner shall be guided\nby the requirements with regard to lights, reflectors, signaling devices\nand associated equipment on vehicles of rules and regulations\npromulgated by the United States department of transportation.\n  2. Wiring used on commercial vehicles shall be of such size that when\nall connections are made in an acceptable and workmanlike manner the\nloss in voltage will not be sufficient to cause a lamp to produce less\nthan the minimum candlepower, under normal operating conditions, when\nthe lamp is in good working order. All wiring should be enclosed in\nweather proof and abrasion proof cable or conduit except wiring which is\ncompletely enclosed within the body of the vehicle.\n  3. All lights, signals and reflectors shall be of a type and design\napproved by the commissioner. No light having a candlepower rating in\nexcess of thirty-two candle power shall be used on any vehicle, unless\nit is of a type approved by the commissioner. The provisions of section\nthree hundred seventy-five of this chapter governing the approval of\nequipment and the adjustment of headlamps shall apply to the equipment\nand headlamps required by this section. The commissioner is hereby\nauthorized and empowered to adopt and from time to time amend such\nregulations not inconsistent with this section, governing the size,\ntype, construction, location, and use of lights, signals and reflectors,\nincluding the exemption of specific vehicles from the requirements of\nthis section where the construction of such vehicles makes compliance\nherewith impracticable, or impossible.\n  4. All existing p...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>