<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-377"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-377"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="377"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-377/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-377/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-377/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-377/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_377">
        <num>377</num>
        <heading>Vehicles engaged in the transportation of logs and other materials</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 377. Vehicles engaged in the transportation of logs and other\nmaterials.  1. No vehicle which is designed or used for the purpose of\nhauling logs or other materials which by their very nature may shift or\nroll so as to be likely to fall from such vehicle, shall be operated or\nmoved over any highway unless its load is securely fastened by such\nsafety chains, cables or other suitable devices as will effectively\nprevent the shifting or falling of such load or any part thereof, from\nthe vehicle.\n  2. The commissioner is authorized to make necessary rules and\nregulations to carry into effect the provisions of this section,\napplying such provisions to specific conditions and prescribing means,\nmethods and practices to effectuate such provisions. Before any such\nrule or regulation is adopted, amended or repealed there shall be a\npublic hearing thereon, notice of which shall be published at least\nonce, not less than ten days prior thereto, in such newspaper as the\ncommissioner may prescribe.\n  3. A violation of any of the provisions of this section or of any rule\nor regulation promulgated hereunder shall constitute a misdemeanor\npunishable by a fine of not more than one hundred dollars for a first\noffense, three hundred fifty dollars for a second offense, or seven\nhundred fifty dollars for each subsequent offense, or by imprisonment\nfor not more than thirty days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>