<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-392"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-392"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="392"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-392/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-392/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-392/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-392/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_392">
        <num>392</num>
        <heading>False statements, alteration of records or substitution in connection with any examination</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 392. False statements, alteration of records or substitution in\nconnection with any examination. Any person knowingly making a false\nstatement in an application for any document issued by the commissioner\nor in any proof or statement in writing in connection with such an\napplication, or who shall deceive or substitute or cause another to\ndeceive or substitute in connection with any examination hereunder, or\nwho shall wilfully alter a number plate (except for restoration purposes\npursuant to schedule G of subdivision seven of section four hundred one\nof this chapter), or make a material alteration on any document issued\npursuant to this chapter, or unlawfully use a validating device on a\ncertificate of registration, license or any other form, shall be guilty\nof a misdemeanor. A person who operates a motor vehicle upon the public\nhighway displaying or using any document that he or she knows has been\nobtained in violation of this section, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\nNothing contained in this section shall prohibit the imposition of a\ncharge of any other offense set forth in this chapter or any other\nprovision of law for any acts arising out of the same incident.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>