<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-395"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-395"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="395"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-395/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-395/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-395/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-395/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_395">
        <num>395</num>
        <heading>Certain private service bureaus to be licensed</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 395. Certain private service bureaus to be licensed.  Except as\notherwise provided herein, no person, firm, association or corporation\nshall, engage in the business of assisting for hire in securing licenses\nto drive motor vehicles or registrations or titles of motor vehicles,\nnor shall any person, firm, association or corporation for compensation\ngive instructions as to procuring licenses to drive motor vehicles or\nregistrations or titles of motor vehicles, without being the holder of a\nlicense for such purpose issued by the commissioner of motor vehicles.\nAn applicant for a license shall furnish the commissioner with such\ninformation and such references as to moral character as he may\nreasonably require. Every application shall be accompanied by a fee of\ntwenty-five dollars, which shall be regarded as an application fee and\nshall in no event be refunded. If an application be approved by the\ncommissioner, the applicant upon the payment of an additional fee of\ntwenty-five dollars shall be granted a license which shall expire on the\nthirtieth day of June following the date of its issuance. The\ncommissioner shall issue a license certificate to each licensee which\ncertificate shall be conspicuously displayed in the place of business of\nthe licensee, or, if the licensee has no place of business, such\ncertificates shall be exhibited at the request of any person. In case of\nthe loss, mutilation or destruction of a certificate, the commissioner\nshall issue a duplicate upon proof of the facts and the payment of a fee\nof one dollar. The refusal to issue a license may be reviewed by a\nproceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and\nrules. Such license shall be renewed annually upon the payment of a fee\nof twenty-five dollars, such renewal to take effect on the first day of\nJuly in each year.  Upon renewal, the commissioner may, in his\ndiscretion, issue a license which shall be valid for a two year period.\nThe fee for any such two year renewal shall be fifty dollars.\n  No license shall be issued under this section nor shall any renewal of\na license issued under this section be made for conducting business in a\ncity having a population of fifty thousand or more, according to the\nlatest federal census if the place of business of the licensee, or\nbranch thereof, is within fifteen hundred feet of a building, owned or\nleased by the state, a county or a city, in which motor vehicle\nregistrations or licenses to drive motor vehicles are issued to the\npublic.  The said distance of fifteen hundred feet shall be measured\nalong the public streets by the nearest route from such place of\nbusiness, or branch thereof, to such building. The provisions of this\nparagraph shall not apply to a holder of a certificate of registration\nissued pursuant to section four hundred fifteen of this chapter.\n  A licensee shall be subject to such reasonable regulations concerning\nthe business conducted under his license as the commissioner may\nprescribe and he shall permit the commissioner, or his representatives,\nto inspect his place of business on any business day and shall furnish\nto the commissioner, or his representative, such information concerning\nthe conduct of the business as may be reasonably required.\n  The provisions of subdivisions five and six of section three hundred\nninety-four of this chapter shall be applicable with respect to this\nsection.\n  The holder of a license issued pursuant to section three hundred\nninety-four of this chapter or the holder of a certificate of\nregistration issued pursuant to section four hundred fifteen of this\nchapter shall not be required to secure a license under this section in\norder to conduct a business for which a license is required by this\nsection but any such licensee, or registrant, who shall conduct such\nbusiness, shall be subject to the same visitation and regulation by the\ncommissioner with reference to such business as provided in this section\nwith respect to a licensee under this section.\n  As used in this section the phrase "licenses to drive motor vehicles"\nincludes the term "learners' permits".\n  A violation of any of the provisions of this section shall constitute\na misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>