<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-R"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-R"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-R"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_R">
        <num>399-R</num>
        <heading>Regulations, fees and privacy</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 399-r. Regulations, fees and privacy. 1. The commissioner is\nauthorized and directed to promulgate any rules and regulations\nnecessary to implement the provisions of this article and to insure that\ninternet delivered pre-licensing courses as approved by the commissioner\nand established pursuant to this article, can validate: student identity\nat registration and throughout the course; participation throughout the\ncourse; that time requirements are met; and successful completion of the\ncourse. Provided, however, that any rules and regulations promulgated\npursuant to this article shall not stipulate any particular location for\ndelivery of a pre-licensing course or limit the time of day during which\nsuch course may be taken.\n  2. The commissioner is authorized to impose a fee upon each internet\npre-licensing course sponsoring agency approved for participation in the\npilot program to deliver such course, which shall not exceed eight\ndollars for each student who completes such course by means of the pilot\nprogram established pursuant to this article. Such fees, excluding\nadministrative expenses of the department, shall be deposited in the\ndedicated highway and bridge trust fund established pursuant to section\neighty-nine-b of the state finance law.\n  3. No internet pre-licensing course sponsoring agency shall disclose\nor otherwise make available to any person or entity any personal\ninformation obtained by such provider about any student who registers\nfor such course. For the purposes of this article, "personal\ninformation" shall mean information that identifies an individual,\nincluding an individual's photo image, social security number, driver\nidentification number, name, address (but not the five-digit zip code),\ntelephone number, and medical or disability information.\n  * NB Repealed June 30, 2030\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>