<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-399-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399_F">
        <num>399-F</num>
        <heading>Proof of effectiveness</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 399-f. Proof of effectiveness. Proof of effectiveness shall be\nverifiable research documentation submitted by the applicant for\nsponsorship showing evidence of effectiveness comparable to that of the\nnational safety council's defensive driving course as determined by the\ncommissioner in terms of reduced convictions or accidents or both. This\nresearch documentation shall employ accepted research principles and\ninclude treatment and non-treatment control groups comprised of samples\nof the representative driver base. In order to establish verifiable\neffectiveness, each sample group should be comprised of a minimum of\nthree thousand drivers selected randomly. The documentation shall\ninclude conviction or accident data for each motorist for a period of at\nleast eighteen months prior to the course completion date and at least\neighteen months subsequent to such date, and equivalent time periods for\nnon-treatment control groups. The documentation shall also include a\ndescription of the sampling and analytic procedures used, and the\nmotorist identification number and course completion date for all course\nattendees. The applicant for sponsorship shall provide, at the request\nof the commissioner and at the applicant's expense, all driving record\ndata and analysis used in the development of the submitted research\ndocumentation. Submission of any fraudulent or intentionally misleading\ndata will disqualify that organization and all owners and principals\nfrom participating or approval in the accident prevention course for a\nperiod of ten years from submission date. The commissioner may, by\nregulation, provide for a smaller sample group for specialized courses.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>