<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-401-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-401-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="401-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-401-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-401-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-401-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-401-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_401_A">
        <num>401-A</num>
        <heading>In-transit permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 401-a. In-transit permits. The owner of a vehicle intended to be\noperated upon a public highway or street only for the purpose of\ntransporting the same to a jurisdiction, within this state or to any\nother state, where the same is to be registered, may file with the\ncommissioner or any agent of the commissioner an application for\nissuance of an in-transit permit for such vehicle. The application shall\nbe made on a form furnished by the commissioner for such purpose and\nshall contain such information as the commissioner shall require. If\nsatisfied that the vehicle is to be operated as provided in this\nsection, the commissioner shall upon payment of a fee of twelve dollars\nand fifty cents assign to such vehicle a distinctive number and issue\nand deliver to the applicant an in-transit permit, valid for a period of\nthirty days from the date of issuance, in such form as the commissioner\nshall prescribe, indicating the extent to which the vehicle covered by\nsuch permit may be operated on the public highways and such vehicle may\nbe operated only as so indicated. Notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovision of this section, the difference collected between the fees set\nforth in this paragraph in effect on and after September first, two\nthousand nine and the fees set forth in this paragraph in effect prior\nto such date shall be deposited to the credit of the dedicated highway\nand bridge trust fund.\n  If an in-transit permit is issued by a county clerk, acting as agent\nof the commissioner, such county clerk shall be entitled to the sum of\nthirty-five cents for each such in-transit permit issued, which sum\nshall be deducted before remitting the fee for such in-transit permit to\nthe commissioner.\n  The provisions of this chapter with respect to the issuance and\ndisplay of number plates shall not apply to vehicles operated only as\nprovided in this section, and which display the in-transit permit issued\nby the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>