<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-403-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-403-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="403-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-403-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-403-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-403-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-403-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_403_A">
        <num>403-A</num>
        <heading>Temporary indicia of registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 403-a. Temporary indicia of registration. The commissioner may\npromulgate regulations to provide for temporary indicia of registration\nwhich shall permit a person to operate or park a motor vehicle or\ntrailer on the public highways of this state without number plates\nissued by the commissioner or validating stickers for a period not to\nexceed fifteen days when the number plate or plates or validating\nsticker for such motor vehicle or trailer has been lost, stolen,\nmutilated or destroyed. Such regulations may provide for the charging of\na fee of not more than three dollars for any issuance of temporary\nindicia of registration. Any person who operates or parks a motor\nvehicle or trailer on the public highways of this state, which motor\nvehicle or trailer is in fact validly registered pursuant to the\nprovisions of section four hundred one or four hundred ten of this\nchapter, without a number plate or plates or validating sticker, and who\nhas complied with any such regulations promulgated by the commissioner\nunder this section shall not be deemed to be operating or parking a\nmotor vehicle or trailer in violation of subdivision one or three of\nsection four hundred two or section four hundred three of this chapter.\nFalsifying any temporary indicia of registration prescribed by any\nregulation of the commissioner issued pursuant to this section shall be\na traffic infraction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>