<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_D">
        <num>404-D</num>
        <heading>Distinctive plates for members of the organized militia and reserve</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 404-d. Distinctive plates for members of the organized militia and\nreserve. 1. Any member of the organized militia of the state of New York\nand any member of a reserve unit from this state of any branch of the\narmed forces of the United States or the spouse of any such member\nshall, upon request, be issued a license plate bearing a militiaman and\nthe appropriate organization -- army national guard, air national guard,\nstate guard or naval militia, army reserve, marine corps reserve, air\nforce reserve, navy reserve or coast guard reserve. If a distinctive\nplate is issued to a member of the organized militia pursuant to this\nsection, such a distinctive plate shall not be issued to the spouse of\nsuch member of the organized militia. Application for said license plate\nshall be filed with the commissioner in such form and detail as the\ncommissioner shall prescribe, and shall be verified annually by the\napplicant.\n  2. The distinctive plate authorized in subdivision one of this section\nshall be issued upon proof, satisfactory to the commissioner, that the\napplicant or the spouse of the applicant is presently an active member\nof the organized militia or reserve.\n  3. A distinctive plate issued pursuant to this section shall be issued\nin the same manner as other number plates upon payment of the regular\nregistration fee prescribed by section four hundred one of this article\nprovided, however, that an additional one-time service charge of ten\ndollars shall be charged for such plate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>