<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-V*3"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_V*3">
        <num>404-V*3</num>
        <heading>Distinctive plates for the arts and cultural institutions and museums</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 404-v. Distinctive plates for the arts and cultural institutions\nand museums. 1. Any person residing in this state shall, upon request,\nbe issued a distinctive New York state cultural institutions and museums\nlicense plate of a design approved by the commissioner. Application for\nsuch license plate shall be filed with the commissioner in such form and\ndetail as the commissioner shall prescribe.\n  2. A distinctive New York state cultural institutions and museums\nplate issued pursuant to this section shall be issued in the same manner\nas other number plates upon the payment of the regular registration fees\nprescribed by section four hundred one of this article; provided,\nhowever, that an additional annual service charge of twenty-five dollars\nshall be charged for such plate. Fifteen dollars from each twenty-five\ndollars received as annual service charges under this section shall be\ndeposited to the credit of the arts capital revolving fund established\npursuant to section ninety-seven-z of the state finance law; provided,\nhowever, that one year after the effective date of this section, funds\nin the amount of five thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be\navailable shall be allocated from such fund to the department to offset\ncosts associated with the production of such license plate.\n  * NB There are 7 ยง 404-v's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>