<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-U"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-U"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-U"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_U">
        <num>404-U</num>
        <heading>Distinctive "keep kids drug free" license plates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 404-u. Distinctive "keep kids drug free" license plates. 1. Any\nperson residing in this state shall, upon request, be issued a\ndistinctive "keep kids drug free" license plate in support of youth drug\nprevention and treatment programs. Application for such license plate\nshall be filed with the commissioner in such form and detail as the\ncommissioner shall prescribe.\n  2. A distinctive "keep kids drug free" license plate issued pursuant\nto this section shall be issued in the same manner as other number\nplates upon the payment of the regular registration fee prescribed by\nsection four hundred one of this article, provided, however, that an\nadditional annual service charge of twenty-five dollars shall be charged\nfor such plate. The additional service charge of twenty-five dollars\nshall be deposited to the credit of the office of alcoholism and\nsubstance abuse services and shall be used to support programs which\nseek to reduce alcoholism and substance abuse among the youth population\nin New York state through prevention and/or treatment. Such deposits\nshall not be used to replace, offset, or supplant any existing funding\nstreams which aid the office, but shall be in addition thereto.\nProvided, however, that one year after the effective date of this\nsection, funds in the amount of five thousand dollars, or so much\nthereof as may be available, shall be allocated to the department to\noffset costs associated with the production of such license plates.\n  * NB There are 4 ยง404-u's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>