<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_A">
        <num>404-A</num>
        <heading>Registration of motor vehicles of severely disabled persons</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Has limited or no use of one or both lower limbs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Has a neuro-muscular dysfunction which severely limits mobility;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Has a physical or mental impairment or condition which is other\nthan those specified above, but is of such nature as to impose unusual\nhardship in utilization of public transportation facilities and such\ncondition is certified by a physician, physician assistant or nurse\npractitioner, to the extent authorized by law and consistent with\nsubdivision three of section six thousand nine hundred two of the\neducation law, duly licensed to practice in this state, or, pursuant to\nsubdivision four-a of this section, a podiatrist duly licensed to\npractice podiatry in this state or, pursuant to subdivision four-b of\nthis section, an optometrist duly licensed to practice optometry in this\nstate, as constituting an equal degree of disability (specifying the\nparticular condition) so as to prevent such person from getting around\nwithout great difficulty in accordance with subdivision two of this\nsection; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A blind person.\n  4-a. Certification of disability by a podiatrist. A podiatrist duly\nlicensed to practice podiatry in this state may certify only those\nconditions which he or she treats in the course of the practice of\npodiatry, as defined by section seventy hundred one of the education\nlaw.\n  4-b. Certification of disability by an optometrist. An optometrist\nduly licensed to practice optometry in this state may certify only those\nconditions which he or she treats in the course of the practice of\noptometry, as defined in section seventy-one hundred one of the\neducation law.\n  5. Application for registration.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The application for registration\nunder this section shall be filed with the commissioner of motor\nvehicles in such form and detail as the commissioner shall prescribe,\nsetting forth such information as the commissioner may reasonably\nprescribe beyond such information required under section four hundred\none of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may require the applicant for registration to\nfurnish such proof of his or her disability or such proof of disability\nof such members of his or her family from a physician, physician\nassistant or nurse practitioner, to the extent authorized by law and\nconsistent with subdivision three of section six thousand nine hundred\ntwo of the education law, or podiatrist pursuant to subdivision four-a\nof this section or optometrist pursuant to subdivision four-b of this\nsection, as the commissioner deems necessary either for initial\nregistration or renewal thereof; provided, however, that a handicapped\nor disabled permit issued by a municipality to such applicant pursuant\nto section twelve hundred three-a of this chapter shall be deemed\nsufficient proof of disability for purposes of this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Application under this section shall only apply to a vehicle\nsubject to registration pursuant to subdivision six of section four\nhundred one of this chapter and to a van or pick-up truck as provided in\nsubdivision two of this section.\n  6. Fee requirements. As provided in section four hundred one of this\nchapter, the registration and disabled person plates shall be\naccompanied only by the required fee otherwise required to be paid for\nvehicle registration.\n  7. Refueling notice. Upon the issuance or renewal of a registration\npursuant to this section, the commissioner shall notify the registrant\nof the availability of full service motor vehicle refueling at self\nservice prices as provided for in section three hundred ninety-six-bb of\nthe general business law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>