<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-W"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-W"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-W"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-W/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-W/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_W">
        <num>404-W</num>
        <heading>Distinctive plates for war on terror veterans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_W__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person who served in the armed forces of the United States in\nthe hostilities that occurred in the Persian Gulf from the eleventh day\nof September, two thousand one, to the end of such hostilities, who</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_W__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nwas discharged therefrom under other than dishonorable conditions, or\n(ii) has a qualifying condition, as defined in section one of the\nveterans' services law, and has received a discharge other than bad\nconduct or dishonorable from such service, or (iii) is a discharged LGBT\nveteran, as defined in section one of the veterans' services law, and\nhas received a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from\nsuch service; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_W__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person who served in the armed forces of the United States, in\nthe hostilities that occurred in Afghanistan from the eleventh day of\nSeptember, two thousand one, to the end of such hostilities, who</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_W__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>was\ndischarged therefrom under other than dishonorable conditions, or (ii)\nhas a qualifying condition, as defined in section one of the veterans'\nservices law, and has received a discharge other than bad conduct or\ndishonorable from such service, or (iii) is a discharged LGBT veteran,\nas defined in section one of the veterans' services law, and has\nreceived a discharge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from such\nservice.\n  2. The distinctive plate authorized by this section shall be issued\nupon proof, satisfactory to the commissioner, that the applicant is a\nwar on terror veteran.\n  3. A distinctive plate issued pursuant to this section shall be issued\nin the same manner as other number plates upon payment of the regular\nregistration fee prescribed by section four hundred of this article,\nprovided, however, that an additional one-time service charge of ten\ndollars shall be charged for such plate.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 404-w's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>