<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-T*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_T*2">
        <num>404-T*2</num>
        <heading>Distinctive conserve habitat license plates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 404-t. Distinctive conserve habitat license plates. 1. Any person\nresiding in this state shall, upon request, be issued a distinctive\n"Conserve Habitat" license plate of a design approved by the\ncommissioner, after consultation with the commissioner of environmental\nconservation. Application for said license plate shall be filed with the\ncommissioner in such form and detail as the commissioner shall\nprescribe.\n  2. A distinctive conserve habitat plate issued pursuant to this\nsection shall be issued in the same manner as other number plates upon\nthe payment of the regular registration fees prescribed by section four\nhundred one of this article; provided, however, that an additional\nannual service charge of twenty-five dollars shall be charged for such\nplate. Such service charge under this section shall be deposited to the\ncredit of the conservation fund established pursuant to section\neighty-three of the state finance law; provided, however, that one year\nafter the effective date of this section, funds up to a maximum of six\nthousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be available, shall be\nallocated from such fund to the department to offset costs associated\nwith the production of such license plate.\n  * NB There are 3 ยง 404-t's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>