<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_C">
        <num>404-C</num>
        <heading>Distinctive plates for former prisoners of war</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 404-c. Distinctive plates for former prisoners of war. 1. Any former\nprisoner of war residing in this state or the spouse of any such former\nprisoner of war shall, upon request, be issued a license plate bearing\nthe words "former prisoner of war". If a distinctive plate is issued to\na former prisoner of war pursuant to this section, additional\ndistinctive plates may be issued for every vehicle registered in the\nname of the former prisoner of war residing in this state or the spouse\nof such former prisoner of war. Application for said license plate shall\nbe filed with the commissioner in such form and detail as the\ncommissioner shall prescribe.\n  2. The distinctive plate authorized herein shall be issued upon proof,\nsatisfactory to the commissioner, that the applicant or the spouse of\nthe applicant is a former prisoner of war.\n  3. A distinctive plate issued pursuant to this section shall be issued\nin the same manner as other number plates upon payment of the regular\nregistration fee prescribed by section four hundred one of this chapter\nprovided, however, that no additional service charge shall be charged\nfor such plate.\n  4. The unremarried widow or widower of a former prisoner of war\nmarried to such former prisoner at the time of his or her imprisonment\nshall be included in the term "spouse" for the purposes of this section.\nA distinctive plate issued pursuant to this subdivision shall be issued\nin the same manner as other number plates upon the payment of the\nregular registration fee prescribed by section four hundred one of this\nchapter, provided, however, that no additional service charge shall be\ncharged for such plate.\n  5. Notwithstanding subdivision three of this section and the fees\nprescribed or permitted by section four hundred one of this article,\nthere shall be no charge for the issuance of a number plate pursuant to\nthis section to a former prisoner of war, nor shall there be imposed an\nadditional service charge for the issuance of such a plate to such a\nperson. Furthermore, upon the issuance of a distinctive plate pursuant\nto this section, such a former prisoner of war shall be exempt from the\npayment of any fees relating to the registration or renewal thereof as\nprescribed by section four hundred one of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>