<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_Q">
        <num>404-Q</num>
        <heading>Distinctive "drive for the cure" license plates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 404-q. Distinctive "drive for the cure" license plates. 1. Any\nperson residing in this state shall, upon request, be issued a\ndistinctive "drive for the cure" license plate in support of breast,\nprostate and testicular cancer research bearing the phrase "drive for\nthe cure". Application for said license plate shall be filed with the\ncommissioner in such form and detail as the commissioner shall\nprescribe.\n  2. A distinctive "drive for the cure" license plate issued pursuant to\nthis section shall be issued in the same manner as other number plates\nupon the payment of the regular registration fee prescribed by section\nfour hundred one of this article, provided, however, that an additional\nannual service charge of twenty-five dollars shall be charged for such\nplate. Twelve dollars and fifty cents from each twenty-five dollars\nreceived as annual service charges under this section shall be deposited\nto the credit of the breast cancer research and education fund\nestablished pursuant to section ninety-seven-yy of the state finance law\nand shall be used for research and education programs undertaken\npursuant to section twenty-four hundred ten of the public health law.\nTwelve dollars and fifty cents from each twenty-five dollars received as\nannual service charges under this section shall be deposited to the\ncredit of the New York State prostate and testicular cancer research and\neducation fund established pursuant to section ninety-five-e of the\nstate finance law and shall be used for research and education programs\nundertaken pursuant to section ninety-five-e of the state finance law.\nProvided, however that one year after the effective date of this section\nfunds in the amount of six thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may\nbe available, shall be allocated to the department to offset costs\nassociated with the production of such license plates.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 404-q's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>