<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_S">
        <num>404-S</num>
        <heading>Issuance of distinctive "I Love New York" plates</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_S__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\ntwenty-five dollar fee required to be paid for the issuance of a set of\nreflectorized number plates pursuant to paragraph a of subdivision three\nof section four hundred one of this article, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404_S__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the fee of three\ndollars and twenty-five cents for the issuance of a new set of number\nplates pursuant to paragraph b of subdivision three of section four\nhundred one of this article.\n  4. A person who, prior to January first, two thousand fourteen,\npossesses a lifetime license pursuant to section 11-0702 of the\nenvironmental conservation law or a lifetime vehicle access pass, also\nknown as a lifetime empire passport, or a three or five year vehicle\naccess pass pursuant to article thirteen of the parks, recreation and\nhistoric preservation law shall, on request between April first, two\nthousand fourteen and March thirty-first, two thousand fifteen, be\nissued a distinctive plate pursuant to this section in the same manner\nas other number plates upon the payment of the regular registration fee\nprescribed by section four hundred one of this article; provided,\nhowever, that commencing upon the third registration period after the\ninitial issuance of such plate, an additional annual service charge of\nfifteen dollars shall be charged for such plate. Such service charge\nshall be deposited and made available in the same manner as set forth in\nsubdivision two of this section. Additionally, such person shall be\nexempt from the payment of the fee of three dollars and twenty-five\ncents for the issuance of a new set of number plates pursuant to\nparagraph b of subdivision three of section four hundred one of this\narticle.\n  5. Any New York resident who possesses a hunting, fishing or trapping\nlicense issued pursuant to title seven of article eleven of the\nenvironmental conservation law or an annual vehicle access pass, also\nknown as an empire passport, pursuant to article thirteen of the parks,\nrecreation and historic preservation law shall, upon request, be issued\nthe distinctive plate available to a person who purchases a lifetime\nlicense or passport, which shall be issued in the same manner as other\nnumber plates upon the payment of the regular reg...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>