<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-T"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-T/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_T">
        <num>404-T</num>
        <heading>Distinctive marine and coastal district of New York license plates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 404-t. Distinctive marine and coastal district of New York license\nplates. 1. Any person residing in this state shall, upon request, be\nissued a distinctive marine and coastal district of New York license\nplate in support of conservation, education, and research projects\nrelating to such district, as described in section 13-0103 of the\nenvironmental conservation law. The design of such distinctive plate\nshall be developed by the commissioner in consultation with the\ncommissioner of the department of environmental conservation and the\ncommissioner of the department of economic development. Application for\nsaid license plate shall be filed with the commissioner in such form and\ndetail as the commissioner shall prescribe.\n  2. A distinctive plate issued pursuant to this section shall be issued\nin the same manner as other number plates upon the payment of the\nregular registration fee prescribed by section four hundred one of this\narticle provided, however, that an additional annual service charge of\ntwenty-five dollars shall be charged for such plate. All monies received\nfor the annual service charge pursuant to this section shall be\ndeposited to the credit of the marine and coastal district of New York\nconservation, education, and research fund established pursuant to\nsection ninety-five-c of the state finance law and shall be used for\nconservation, education, and research projects approved by the marine\nand coastal district of New York conservation, education, and research\nboard established pursuant to section 13-0503 of the environmental\nconservation law. Provided, however, that one year after the effective\ndate of this section, funds in the amount of six thousand dollars, or so\nmuch thereof as may be available, shall be allocated from such fund to\nthe department to offset costs associated with the production of such\nlicense plates.\n  * NB There are 3 ยง 404-t's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>