<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*6"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*6"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-V*6"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*6/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*6/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*6/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-V*6/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_V*6">
        <num>404-V*6</num>
        <heading>Distinctive autism awareness license plates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 404-v. Distinctive autism awareness license plates. 1. Any person\nresiding in this state shall, upon request, be issued a distinctive\nlicense plate in support of autism awareness and research bearing the\nphrase "Autism Society of America" and any other phrases and design\napproved by the commissioner in consultation with the Autism Society of\nAmerica.\n  2. An application for such license plate shall be filed with the\ncommissioner in such form and detail as the commissioner shall\nprescribe.\n  3. A distinctive plate issued pursuant to this section shall be issued\nin the same manner as other number plates upon the payment of the\nregular registration fee prescribed by section four hundred one of this\narticle; provided, however, that an additional annual service charge of\ntwenty-five dollars shall be charged for such plates.\n  4. Each twenty-five dollars received as the annual service charge\nunder this section shall be deposited to the credit of the New York\nstate autism awareness and research fund established pursuant to section\nninety-five-e of the state finance law and shall be used for research\nprograms undertaken pursuant to section ninety-five-e of the state\nfinance law. Provided, however, that one year after the effective date\nof this section, funds in the amount of five thousand dollars, or so\nmuch thereof as may be available, shall be allocated from such fund to\nthe department to offset costs associated with the production of such\nlicense plates except that no such funds shall be so allocated if the\ndepartment has received funds for such purpose from the Autism Society\nof America.\n  * NB There are 7 ยง 404-v's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>