<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404_N">
        <num>404-N</num>
        <heading>Issuance of distinctive conservation plates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 404-n. Issuance of distinctive conservation plates. 1.  On or after\nApril first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, any person residing in this\nstate, upon filing a complete application and paying a fee as provided\nin subdivision two of this section, shall be issued his or her choice of\na distinctive conservation license plate from those approved by the\ncommissioner.  Application for said license plate shall be filed with\nthe commissioner in such form and detail as the commissioner shall\nprescribe.\n  2. A distinctive conservation plate issued pursuant to this section\nshall be issued in the same manner as other number plates upon the\npayment of the regular registration fee prescribed by section four\nhundred one of this article provided, however, that an additional annual\nservice charge of twenty-five dollars shall be charged for such plate.\nAll moneys received as annual service charges under this section shall\nbe deposited to the credit of the environmental protection fund\nestablished pursuant to section ninety-two-s of the state finance law;\nand shall be used for open space land conservation projects undertaken\npursuant to title three of article fifty-four of the environmental\nconservation law.\n  3. The proceeds under this section shall be deposited in the\nenvironmental protection fund established pursuant to section\nninety-two-s of the state finance law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>