<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404">
        <num>404</num>
        <heading>Issuance of special number plates</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_404__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>payment of a one-time service\ncharge of ten dollars in addition to the regular registration fee\nprescribed by section four hundred one of this article, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_404__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nsubmission of proof, satisfactory to the commissioner, that the\napplicant is presently a member of the veterans organization for which\nsuch plate is requested. Such membership shall be verified annually by\nthe applicant. Application for such plates shall be made in accordance\nwith regulations promulgated by the commissioner with respect to the\nissuance of such plates. Provided, however, that nothing contained\nherein shall be deemed to supersede the provisions of section four\nhundred four-d, four hundred four-e, four hundred four-h, four hundred\nfour-i, four hundred four-j, four hundred four-k, four hundred four-p,\nfour hundred four-aa, or four hundred four-dd of this article.\n  2. For purposes of this section, a special number plate shall be a\nplate which contains not more than eight letters, numerals or any\ncombination thereof and which is reserved by the commissioner for\nissuance in accordance with the provisions of this section, or a plate\nreserved for issuance in a series for vehicles owned by public officers,\nphysicians, visiting nurses, accredited representatives of the press or\nother groups. In issuing special number plates the commissioner shall\ngive those applicants who held a special number plate at the time of the\nenactment of this section the right to retain such special number plate\nupon the payment of the annual service charge of thirty-one dollars and\ntwenty-five cents. Provided, however, that such right of retention shall\napply only to the first renewal of the registration of such special\nnumber plate following the enactment of this section. Notwithstanding\nany inconsistent provision of this section, the difference collected\nbetween the annual service charge set forth in this subdivision in\neffect on and after September first, two thousand nine and the annual\nservice charge set forth in this subdivision in effect prior to such\ndate shall be deposited to the credit of the dedicated highway and\nbridge trust fund.\n  3. Thi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>