<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-405-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-405-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="405-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-405-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-405-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-405-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-405-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_405_B">
        <num>405-B</num>
        <heading>Administration of agreement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 405-b. Administration of agreement. The commissioner may: 1. Accept\napplications for registrations, trip permits and any other document\nwhich he may be empowered to issue under any agreement authorized by\nsection four hundred five of this article;\n  2. Collect from any applicant any and all fees required to be paid\neither to this state or to any other jurisdiction which is a party to\nsuch agreement;\n  3. Provide for the crediting of fees previously paid for the unexpired\nportion of a registration when a conversion is made from a registration\nissued under article fourteen of this chapter to a registration issued\nunder such agreement;\n  4. Accept any fees which are due to this state under any such\nagreement which are paid to any other jurisdiction or agency and which\nhave been transmitted to him pursuant to any such agreement;\n  5. Pay or authorize the payment of any moneys collected by him on\nbehalf of any other jurisdiction which is party to such agreement to\nsuch other jurisdictions;\n  6. Issue any number plate or plates, cab card, trip permit or any\nother document which he is authorized to issue under such agreement;\n  7. Appoint agents to act for him in the issuance of trip permits,\nprovided that such agents shall not receive compensation from the state;\nand\n  8. By regulation establish limitations upon the period of validity of\nany trip permit issued for operation in this state or the number of such\npermits which may be issued to any vehicle or applicant.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>