<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-410-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-410-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-410-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-410-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-410-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-410-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_A">
        <num>410-A</num>
        <heading>Motorcycle safety program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 410-a. Motorcycle safety program. 1. The commissioner shall\nestablish and administer a motorcycle safety program which shall consist\nof approved motorcycle rider training courses, motorcycle course\ninstructor training, program promotion, and public awareness. Approved\nrider training courses shall meet nationally recognized standards for\nmotorcycle rider training courses, or standards for motorcycle rider\nsafety programs which are approved by the department and are comparable\nto the standards of the motorcycle safety foundation's motorcycle rider\nsafety program. Approved courses shall include at least eight hours of\ninstruction in the actual operation of a motorcycle. Monies from the\nmotorcycle safety fund established pursuant to section ninety-two-g of\nthe state finance law shall be used for the establishment and\nimplementation of this program.\n  2. The commissioner shall issue a request for proposals for the\ncoordination of a motorcycle safety program which shall set requirements\nfor the preparation of bids. The commissioner shall enter into a\ncontract, for a period of five years, with a motorcycle rider training\ncoordinating organization selected pursuant to such process. The\ncontract shall be awarded following the consideration of factors which\nshall include, but not be limited to, the most favorable financial\nadvantage for the state, the greatest utility to the motorcyclist, the\ncomprehensiveness and effectiveness of such organization and its\ncompatibility with the existing rider education programs. The motorcycle\nrider training coordination organization shall be subject to periodic\nreporting requirements established by the department outlining the\nadministration and effectiveness of its program and an itemization of\nall motorcycle safety fund allocations. Such motorcycle rider training\ncoordinating organization shall have at least three years experience in\nthe administration of a statewide motorcycle rider education program,\nand have as its administrator an individual who has no financial or\nproprietary interest in a motorcycle training school or facility.\n  3. The motorcycle rider training coordinating organization shall\nsubmit to the commissioner for approval requests for advances pursuant\nto a contract and reimbursements from the motorcycle safety fund for\nequipment, operating and administrative costs and other expenses\nnecessary to carry out the provisions of this section. The commissioner\nshall approve all such requests for expenditures that are in accordance\nwith the provisions of this section.\n  4. The commissioner shall annually file a report on expenditures from\nthe motorcycle safety fund, established pursuant to section ninety-two-g\nof the state finance law, with the legislature. Such report shall\ninclude the name of the funded motorcycle rider training coordinating\norganization and the amount of funds distributed to it and shall provide\nan evaluation of the overall effectiveness of the funded programs and\nany recommendations for programmatic changes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>