<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-411-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-411-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="411-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-411-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-411-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-411-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-411-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_411_B">
        <num>411-B</num>
        <heading>Registration fee schedule for historical motorcycles</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 411-b. Registration fee schedule for historical motorcycles. For\neach motorcycle which is owned and operated as an exhibition piece or\ncollectors item, and is used for participation in club activities,\nexhibit, tours, parades, occasional transportation and similar uses, but\nnot used for general daily transportation, an annual fee of twenty-five\ndollars. For purposes of this section, a historical motorcycle shall\nmean any motorcycle manufactured more than twenty-five years prior to\nthe current calendar year, and any other model, year and type motorcycle\nwhich has unique characteristics and which is determined by the\ncommissioner to be of historical, classic or exhibition value.\nRegistration plates for such motorcycles shall be of a type and design\napproved by the commissioner, but shall be of a distinctive nature,\nexcept that, with the approval of the commissioner, an owner of any such\nmotorcycle may utilize registration plates of this state with the date\nof year corresponding to the model year date when the vehicle was\nmanufactured, if the model year date registration plate is legible and\nserviceable, as determined by the department, in lieu of the\nregistration plates otherwise required by this chapter. Such plates\nshall be used only for the operation of the motorcycle listed on the\nregistration application and on other motorcycles which would qualify\nfor registration under this schedule owned by persons other than the\nregistrant for the purpose of test driving by the registrant or his\nagent in anticipation of possible purchase. No such registration will be\nissued unless evidence of financial security, in a form prescribed by\nthe commissioner, is submitted which provides coverage for the\nmotorcycle listed on the registration application and for non-owned\nmotorcycles being operated with such plates. Notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provision of this section, the difference collected between\nthe fees set forth in this section in effect on and after September\nfirst, two thousand nine and the fees set forth in this section in\neffect prior to such date shall be deposited to the credit of the\ndedicated highway and bridge trust fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>