<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="415-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_415_A">
        <num>415-A</num>
        <heading>Vehicle dismantlers and other persons engaged in the transfer or disposal of junk and salvage vehicles</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided\nherein, no registration shall be issued or renewed unless the applicant\nhas a permanent place of business at which the activity requiring\nregistration is performed which conforms to section one hundred\nthirty-six of the general municipal law as such section applies and to\nall local laws or ordinances and the applicant and all persons having a\nfinancial interest in the business have been determined by the\ncommissioner to be fit persons to engage in such business. However, the\ncommissioner may issue a temporary registration pending final\ninvestigation of an application.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this subdivision requiring a place of business\nat which the activity requiring registration is performed shall not\napply to a mobile car crusher nor to an itinerant vehicle collector.\nHowever, the mobile car crusher or itinerant vehicle collector must\notherwise comply with all applicable local licensing laws or ordinances.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, the commissioner may issue a registration to an applicant\nfor registration as a vehicle dismantler or salvage pool to a person who\nmay not comply with local laws relating to zoning provided that the\napplicant has engaged in business at that location as a vehicle\ndismantler since September first, nineteen hundred seventy-three.\nHowever, the issuance of such registration shall not be a defense with\nrespect to any action brought with respect to violation of any such\nlocal law.\n  5. Records and identification.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any records required by this\nsection shall apply only to vehicles or parts of vehicles for which a\ncertificate of title has been issued by the commissioner or which would\nbe eligible to have such a certificate of title issued. Every person\nrequired to be registered pursuant to this section shall maintain a\nrecord of all motor vehicles, trailers, and major component parts\nthereof, coming into his or her possession together with a record of the\ndisposition of any such motor vehicle, trailer or part thereof and the\ndate such motor vehicle, trailer or part thereof is received and shall\nmaintain proof of ownership for any motor vehicle, trailer or major\ncomponent part thereof while in his or her possession. For the purposes\nof this article an inflatable restraint system shall be a major\ncomponent part and a catalytic converter shall be a major component\npart. Such records shall be maintained in a manner and form prescribed\nby the commissioner. The commissioner may, by regulation, exempt\nvehicles or major component parts of vehicles from all or a portion of\nthe record keeping requirements based upon the age of the vehicle if the\ncommissioner deems that such record keeping requirements would not\nfurther the purposes of the motor vehicle theft prevention program\nestablished by section two hundred twenty-three of this chapter. Upon\nrequest of an agent of the commissioner or of any police officer and\nduring his or her regular and usual business hours, a vehicle dismantler\nshall produce such records and permit said agent or police officer to\nexamine them and any vehicles or parts of vehicles which are subject to\nthe record keeping requirements of this section and which are on the\npremises. In addition, the commissioner shall require every vehicle\ndismantler to produce, every sixty days, all records regarding the\nnumber of catalytic converters they took in within such sixty-day period\nsubject to the record keeping requirements of this section. Upon r...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every vehicle dismantler and salvage pool shall display at his\nplace of business at least one sign upon which his registration number\nand any other information required by the commissioner is affixed in a\nmanner prescribed by the commissioner and further shall affix his\nregistration number on all advertising, business cards, and vehicles\nused by him in connection with his business. The commissioner is hereby\nempowered to require, by regulation, that vehicle dismantlers and\nsalvage pools mark, stamp or tag major component parts of vehicles in\ntheir possession in a manner prescribed by the commissioner so as to\nenable the part so marked to be identified as having come from a\nparticular vehicle and from a particular vehicle dismantler and salvage\npool. A violation of this paragraph shall be a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this article, the term "catalytic converter"\nshall mean a device installed in the exhaust system of an internal\ncombustion engine that utilizes catalytic action to oxidize hydrocarbon\nand carbon monoxide emissions to carbon dioxide and water.\n  5-a. Improper display of signs.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The holder of a vehicle dismantler\nor salvage pool registration shall remove or cause to be removed any\nsign which contains the license number of the facility which is visible\nto the public and which is required to be displayed by this article or\nregulations promulgated thereunder if the registration is revoked or\nsuspended or the vehicle dismantler or salvage pool is out of business.\nIf the registration is only suspended, the holder may cover up the sign\ninstead of removing it.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall permit the display of any sign required to be\ndisplayed by this article or regulations promulgated thereunder\nindicating to the public that an official vehicle dismantler or salvage\npool is operating unless a dismantler or salvage pool registration has\nbeen issued to that person and is currently valid.\n  6. Suspension, revocation and refusal to renew a registration; civil\npenalty.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A registration may be suspended or revoked, or renewal of a\nregistration refused upon a conviction of any provision of the penal law\nrelating to motor vehicle theft, illegal possession of a stolen vehicle\nor illegal possession of stolen motor vehicle parts, or after the\nregistrant has had an opportunity to be heard upon any change of status\nof the registrant which would have resulted in refusal to issue a\nregistration, any false statement in an application for a registration,\nan egregious and willful violation of title twenty-three of article\ntwenty-seven of the environmental conservation law, any violation of\nsubdivision five of this section or regulations promulgated by the\ncommissioner with respect to this section, or any violation of title ten\nof this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Civil penalty. The commissioner, or any person deputized by him,\nin addition to or in lieu of revoking or suspending the registration of\na registrant in accordance with the provisions of this article, may in\nany one proceeding by order require the registrant to pay to the people\nof this state a civil penalty in a sum not exceeding one thousand\ndollars for each violation and upon the failure of such registrant to\npay such penalty within twenty days after the mailing of such order,\npostage prepaid, registered or certified, and addressed to the last\nknown place of business of such registrant, unless such order is stayed\nby an order of a court of competent jurisdiction, the commissioner may\nrevoke the registration of such registrant or may suspend the same for\nsuch period as he may determine. Civil penalties assessed under this\nsubdivision shall be paid to the commissioner for deposit into the state\ntreasury, and unpaid civil penalties may be recovered by the\ncommissioner in a civil action in the name of the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition, as an alternative to such civil action and provided\nthat no proceeding for judicial review shall then be pending and the\ntime for initiation of such proceeding shall have expired, the\ncommissioner may file with the county clerk of the county in which the\nregistrant is located a final order of the commissioner containing the\namount of the penalty assessed. The filing of such final order shall\nhave the full force and effect of a judgment duly docketed in the office\nof such clerk and may be enforced in the same manner and with the same\neffect as that provided by law in respect to executions issued against\nproperty upon judgments of a court of record.\n  7. Registration as a dealer and as a vehicle dismantler or salvage\npool.  A person may be registered as a dealer under section four hundred\nfifteen of this chapter as well as a vehicle dismantler or a salvage\npool under this section. However, any such person must obtain a separate\nregistration for each activity and must maintain separate records for\neach activity.\n  8. Vehicle rebuilders.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A vehicle rebuilder is any person engaged\nin the business of acquiring damaged vehicles for the purpose of\nrepairing and reselling such vehicles. In order to engage in such\nbusiness, a person must be registered as a vehicle dismantler pursuant\nto this section or as a dealer pursuant to section four hundred fifteen\nof this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A vehicle rebuilder shall maintain a record of all vehicles or\nmajor component parts thereof coming into his possession for the purpose\nof rebuilding and all major component parts used in connection with such\nrebuilding in a manner prescribed by the commissioner. Upon request of\nan agent of the commissioner or any police officer during his regular\nand usual business hours, a vehicle rebuilder shall produce such records\nand permit said agent or police officer to examine them and any vehicles\nor parts of vehicles which are subject to the record keeping\nrequirements of this section and which are on the premises. The failure\nto produce such records or to permit such records or to permit such\ninspection as required by this paragraph shall be a class A misdemeanor.\n  9. Scrap processor.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A scrap processor is any person required to be\nlicensed under article six-C of the general business law who purchases\nmaterial which is or may have been a vehicle or vehicle part for\nprocessing into a form other than a vehicle or vehicle part, but who,\nexcept as otherwise provided by regulation of the commissioner, does not\nsell any such material as a motor vehicle, a trailer or a major\ncomponent part thereof. No person shall engage in business or operate as\na scrap processor as defined in this paragraph unless he has given\nnotice to the commissioner that he is a scrap processor and that he has\ncomplied with article six-C of the general business law, and he has been\ncertified by the commissioner as a scrap processor. A violation of this\nparagraph shall be a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A scrap processor shall maintain a record of vehicles and a record\nof major component parts by weight coming into his possession thereof in\na manner prescribed by the commissioner. This paragraph shall not apply\nto any major component part included in a mixed load. Upon request of an\nagent of the commissioner or any police officer or during his regular\nand usual business hours, a scrap processor shall produce such records\nand permit such agent or police officer to inspect them and to inspect\nany vehicles or major component parts of vehicles at the time of the\ndelivery of such vehicles or parts to him. The failure to produce such\nrecords or to permit such inspection as required by this paragraph shall\nbe a class A misdemeanor.\n  10. Scrap collectors and repair shops.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A scrap collector is any\nperson, other than a governmental agency, whose primary business is the\ncollection of miscellaneous scrap for disposal, who may as an incident\nof such business collect vehicular parts as scrap. No person shall\nengage in the business or operate as a scrap collector as defined in\nthis paragraph unless he has given notice to the commissioner that he is\na scrap collector and has been certified as a scrap collector by the\ncommissioner. A violation of this provision shall be a class A\nmisdemeanor. No person shall be certified as a scrap collector eligible\nto do business within a city having a population of one million or more,\nor any county contiguous to such city, unless such person complies with\nall local requirements applicable to such business.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If required by regulation of the commissioner, a scrap collector\nshall keep records of his acquisition and disposition of vehicular scrap\nin a manner prescribed by the commissioner. Upon request of an agent of\nthe commissioner or any police officer, a scrap collector shall produce\nsuch records as may be required to be kept and permit said agent or\npolice officer to inspect them during usual business hours or while\nbusiness is being conducted. The failure to produce such records as\nrequired by this paragraph shall be a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A repair shop registered pursuant to article twelve-A of this\nchapter which disposes of vehicular scrap to a certified scrap processor\nshall apply to the commissioner for certification to carry out this\ndisposal. The repair shop shall include in the application for\ncertification the names and addresses of those scrap processors with\nwhom it arranges for the disposal of its scrap. Thereafter the repair\nshop shall give notice to the commissioner within thirty days of any\nchange in the scrap processors with whom it deals. The failure to comply\nwith this paragraph or to make fraudulent statements regarding the scrap\nprocessors with which a repair shop arranges for the disposal of\nvehicular scrap shall be a class A misdemeanor.\n  11. Out-of-state businesses. A person doing business in this state who\ndoes not have a place of business in this state, but has a place of\nbusiness or engages in such business in another state or province of\nCanada and who would be required to be registered or certified pursuant\nto this section if it were in this state, shall apply to the\ncommissioner for an identification number in a manner prescribed by the\ncommissioner. Such identification number shall be issued provided that\nsuch person complies with all the laws and regulations of the\njurisdiction in which he has his principal place of business or engages\nin such business applicable to such business.\n  12. Identification of certified persons.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every person who is\ncertified or who has been issued an identification number by the\ncommissioner shall display such certification or identification number\nupon any vehicle used by him for the business of transporting vehicles\nor parts of vehicles, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the\ncommissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be a class A misdemeanor for any person required to be\nregistered or certified pursuant to the provisions of this section to\ntransport a vehicle or major component parts out of New York state\nwithout having and displaying his registration or certification number\nas provided for in this section.\n  13. Suspension or revocation of identification number or\ncertification.  An identification number and/or certification issued\npursuant to subdivision eight, nine, ten or eleven of this section may\nbe suspended or revoked upon conviction of any provision of the penal\nlaw relating to motor vehicle theft, illegal possession of a stolen\nvehicle or illegal possession of stolen motor vehicle parts. The\ncommissioner may also revoke or suspend registration or certification,\nafter an appropriate hearing where the holder of the registration or\ncertification has had an opportunity to be heard, upon a finding of:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthat there has been a change to the holder's status which would have\nresulted in a refusal to issue in the first instance, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the\nissuance was based upon a false statement by the holder, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that\nthere was a violation of the record keeping requirements, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that\nthere was a violation of the regulations promulgated by the commissioner\npursuant to this section, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that there was a violation of title X\nof this chapter.\n  14. Restrictions on scrap processors. A certified scrap processor\nshall not purchase any material which may have been a vehicle or a major\ncomponent part of a vehicle, if recognizable as such, from any person\nother than a dealer registered pursuant to section four hundred fifteen\nof this chapter, an insurance company, a governmental agency, a person\nin whose name a certificate of title or other ownership document has\nbeen issued for such vehicle or a person registered or certified or\nissued an identification number pursuant to this section. A violation of\nthis subdivision shall be a class A misdemeanor.\n  15. Regulations. The commissioner shall prescribe such rules and\nregulations as he shall deem necessary to carry out the provisions of\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>