<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-06-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="415"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-415/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_415">
        <num>415</num>
        <heading>Registration of manufacturers, dealers, repairmen and others</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any such vehicle which has been\nconverted for use as a tow truck, or (ii) a motor vehicle for which the\ncurrent ownership document is a statement of acquisition issued pursuant\nto section four hundred twenty-nine of this title, a salvage\ncertificate, salvage certificate of title, nonrepairable certificate, or\nsimilar document issued by any state or jurisdiction; or (iii) any motor\nvehicle commonly classified as a bus, school bus, garbage truck, marine\ntrailer, tow truck, motorcycle, recreational vehicle, snowmobile,\ntrailer, mobile home or construction equipment; and provided further\nthat:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a dealer is a new motor vehicle dealer only with respect to\nthose vehicles which are of the same make as those which that dealer is\nauthorized to sell at that location pursuant to a valid franchise\nagreement; and (ii) a dealer is not acting as a new motor vehicle dealer\nwhen displaying, advertising, storing and/or demonstrating a new\nmobility vehicle.\n  g. "Qualified dealer" means a dealer, other than a new motor vehicle\ndealer or a dealer owned in whole or in part, directly or indirectly, by\na manufacturer, who:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>acting through a single person, but operating at one or more\nlocations of such single person, has displayed new motor vehicles for\nsale and/or lease, and has sold and/or leased (excluding sales or leases\nof any affiliates) a minimum of four thousand new and/or used motor\nvehicles annually (of which at least forty percent annually were new\nmotor vehicles) at retail regardless of make or model from any one or\nmore locations of such single person within the state, in each year from\nnineteen hundred ninety-five through and including nineteen hundred\nninety-eight, exclusively; or\n  (ii) has displayed new motor vehicles for sale and/or lease, and has\nsold and/or leased (excluding sales or leases of any affiliates) a\nminimum of two hundred twenty-five new and/or used motor vehicles (of\nwhich at least thirty-three and one-third percent were new motor\nvehicles) at retail, regardless of make or model, from any one or more\nlocations within the state, in the twelve-month period preceding August\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-nine; or\n  (iii) was issued an original certificate of registration as a dealer\nwith a validation date of May, nineteen hundred ninety-nine, has\ndisplayed new motor vehicles for sale and/or lease, and has sold and/or\nleased (excluding sales or leases of any affiliates) a minimum of one\nhundred fifty new and/or used motor vehicles (of which at least fifty\nwere new motor vehicles), regardless of make or model, from any one or\nmore locations within the state, in the period between July first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-nine and the effective date of chapter seven of\nthe laws of two thousand. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision\neighteen of this section, the total number of locations from which a\nqualified dealer eligible pursuant to this subparagraph may operate\nshall not exceed that number of locations operated by such qualified\ndealer on August thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-nine; or\n  (iv) was issued a certif...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a motor vehicle which has not been placed in consumer use; or\n  (ii) a motor vehicle which has not been transferred to someone other\nthan a distributor, new motor vehicle dealer, or qualified dealer; or\n  (iii) a motor vehicle which has less than one thousand miles on the\nodometer.\n  Provided, however, that such term shall not include any such vehicle\nwhich has been converted for use as a tow truck or any motor vehicle\ncommonly classified as a bus, school bus, garbage truck, marine trailer,\ntow truck, motorcycle, recreational vehicle, snowmobile, trailer, mobile\nhome or construction equipment.\n  i. "Used motor vehicle" means any vehicle not included in the\ndefinition of a new motor vehicle. Provided, however, that such term as\nused in paragraph g of this subdivision shall include only those motor\nvehicles commonly classified as a passenger automobile, sport utility\nvehicle, light truck, pick up truck, van, minivan or suburban, with a\ngross vehicle weight rating of ten thousand pounds or less, which</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is\nnot deemed to be a "new motor vehicle" pursuant to paragraph h of this\nsubdivision, or (ii) has not been converted for use as a tow truck, or\n(iii) is not commonly classified as a bus, school bus, garbage truck,\nmarine trailer, tow truck, motorcycle, recreational vehicle, snowmobile,\ntrailer, mobile home, or construction equipment.\n  j. "Lease" means to arrange for a person to enter into an agreement\nsubject to the provisions of article nine-A of the personal property\nlaw, or to act as a lessor as defined in such article.\n  k. "Mobility vehicle" means a motor vehicle that is specially\nconverted and equipped to transport a person with a disability and is\naltered or modified for such use by an alterer or final stage\nmanufacturer pursuant to parts 567 and 568 of title 49 of the code of\nfederal regulations or a modifier pursuant to part 595 of title 49 of\nthe code of federal regulations and that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has a chassis that contains: (A) a permanently lowered floor or\npermanently lowered frame; or (B) a permanently raised roof and raised\ndoor; and\n  (ii) contains at least one of the following: (A) an electronic or\nmechanical wheelchair, scooter, or platform lift that enables a person\nto enter or exit the vehicle while occupying a wheelchair or scooter;\n(B) an electronic or mechanical wheelchair ramp that is installed as an\nintegral part or permanent attachment to the motor vehicle.\n  For the purposes of this section, the terms "alterer" and "final-stage\nmanufacturer" shall have the same meanings as such terms are defined in\npart 567.3 of title 49 of the code of federal regulations, and the term\n"modifier" shall mean any motor vehicle repair business that modifies a\nmotor vehicle to enable a person with a disability to operate, or ride\nas a passenger in, the motor vehicle.\n  l. "New mobility vehicle" means a mobility vehicle that has not\npreviously been titled or registered for operation by a consumer, either\nas a mobility vehicle or as a motor vehicle.\n  m. "Automobile broker business" shall have the meaning set forth in\nsubdivision one of section seven hundred thirty-six of the general\nbusiness law.\n  2. Registration of manufacturers, repairmen and certain others. A\nperson engaged in a business requiring the limited operation of motor\nvehicles, motorcycles or trailers in order to facilitate the delivery,\nrepair or improvement thereof, or the foreclosure or repossession\nthereof or the installation of something thereon or for the purpose of\ndismantling such motor vehicle, motorcycle or trailer, may, instead of\nobtaining vehicle registration, as provided by sections four hundred one\nand four hundred ten of this chapter, apply to the commissioner for\nregistration under this section.\n  3. Registration of new motor vehicle dealers, qualified dealers, and\nother motor vehicle dealers. a. No person shall engage in business as a\nnew motor vehicl...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nthree hundred one-j of the tax law.\n  * NB Effective until April 1, 2026\n  * 6-a. Fees; deposited. Fees assessed under this section shall be paid\nto the commissioner for deposit to the general fund.\n  * NB Effective April 1, 2026\n  6-b. Dealer, qualified dealer, and new motor vehicle dealer surety\nbond.  a. As a condition to obtaining a registration certificate\npursuant to this section, every new motor vehicle dealer applicant and\nevery qualified dealer applicant shall obtain and continue in effect a\nsurety bond in an amount of fifty thousand dollars executed by a surety\ncompany authorized to transact business in the state by the department\nof financial services of the state. As a condition to obtaining a\nregistration certificate pursuant to this section, every dealer\napplicant who is applying for a registration certificate in the first\ninstance or who sold fifty motor vehicles or fewer in the previous\ncalendar year shall obtain and continue in effect a surety bond in an\namount of twenty thousand dollars executed by a surety company\nauthorized to transact business in the state by the department of\nfinancial services of the state. As a condition of obtaining a\nregistration certificate pursuant to this section, every dealer\napplicant who sold more than fifty motor vehicles in the previous\ncalendar year shall obtain and continue in effect a surety bond in an\namount of one hundred thousand dollars executed by a surety company\nauthorized to transact business in the state by the department of\nfinancial services of the state. The bonds shall be approved as to form\nby the commissioner and shall be conditioned on the new motor vehicle\ndealer's, qualified dealer's, and dealer's: payment of all valid bank\ndrafts, including checks, drawn by such dealer for the purchase of motor\nvehicles; transfer of good title to each motor vehicle such dealer\nsells; safekeeping of all customer deposits related to the sale of a\nmotor vehicle between the...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any dealer,\nother than a new motor vehicle dealer, engaged in displaying,\nadvertising, storing and/or demonstrating mobility vehicles shall notify\nprospective purchasers regarding any warranty on the mobility\nmodifications and the effect of any such modifications or alterations on\nany warranty on the underlying motor vehicle and, upon the sale of any\nsuch mobility vehicle, provide the purchaser with any warranty\ninformation available to any such dealer relating to the underlying\nmotor vehicle.\n  (ii) Notwithstanding the provisions of article twelve-A of this\nchapter, a dealer engaged in displaying, advertising, storing and/or\ndemonstrating mobility vehicles may, without obtaining a repair shop\nlicense pursuant to such article twelve-A, perform repairs on those\nparts of the mobility vehicle that are unique to the modifications made\nthereto and which are not part of the original manufactured motor\nvehicle.\n  d. The commissioner may, in his or her discretion, issue such\ncertificates of registration and number plates on a staggered expiration\nbasis, in which event the fees set forth in subdivision six of this\nsection for such certificate shall be prorated on a monthly basis. A\nregistrant shall notify the commissioner of any change of address of his\nor her principal place of business within thirty days after such change\nis made, and the commissioner shall be authorized to cancel the\nregistration upon failure to give such notice.\n  e. A registration issued under this section may be renewed upon\napplication therefor in such form as the commissioner may prescribe,\nupon payment of the fee as herein prescribed.\n  f. Except as provided in paragraph (bb) of subdivision two of section\nfour hundred sixty-three of this title and subparagraph (iii) of this\nparagraph:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall not issue any certificate of registration\nauthorized by this section to any franchisor, manufacturer, distributor,\ndistributor branch or factory branch, as such terms are defined in\nsection four hundred sixty-two of this title, or to any subsidiary,\naffiliate or controlled entity thereof, except that the commissioner may\nrenew such certificate previously issued or otherwise approved to\noperate to a franchisor prior to July first, two thousand six. Nothing\nin this section shall preclude the establishment of such facilities\nnecessary to continue the ongoing operation of any holder of a\ncertificate of registration authorized by this section or otherwise\napproved to operate to a franchisor provided such original certificate\nor approval was granted prior to July first, two thousand six.\n  (ii) On or after the effective date of this subparagraph, the\ncommissioner shall not issue any certificate of registration, or renew\nany certificate, unless the original certificate was issued before July\nfirst, two thousand six, to any motor vehicle dealer in which a\nfranchisor, manufacturer, distributor, distributor branch or factory\nbranch, as such terms are defined in section four hundred sixty-two of\nthis title, or any subsidiary, affiliate or controlled entity thereof,\nhas acquired, or possesses, a controlling interest in the franchise\nentity except:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_415__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>when operating such franchise for a temporary period, not to\nexceed one year, during the transition from one owner of the motor\nvehicle dealership to another, provided, however, that such temporary\nperiod may be extended once for an additional period not to exceed one\nyear for good cause. Provided that for franchisors of house coaches, the\nperiod of temporary ownership of a franchised house coach dealership may\nbe extended in one year increments for good cause shown, except that the\naggregate of such extensions shall not exceed five years; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_415__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>when operating such franchise temporarily under a plan with an\nindependent individual who is obligated to make a significant investment\nin the dealership that is subject to loss and has an ownership interest\nor expects to acquire full ownership in a reasonable period under\nreasonable terms and conditions, provided that a reasonable period shall\nbe presumed to not exceed eight years.\n  (iii) Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph or any\nprovision of paragraph (bb) of subdivision two of section four hundred\nsixty-three of this title, the commissioner may renew any certificate of\nregistration that was issued to a franchisor, manufacturer, distributor,\ndistributor branch or factory branch, as such terms are defined in\nsection four hundred sixty-two of this title, or to any subsidiary,\naffiliate or controlled entity thereof, prior to March twenty-sixth, two\nthousand fourteen; provided, however, that such franchisor,\nmanufacturer, distributor, distributor branch ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_415__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is a\nmanufacturer that manufactures or assembles exclusively buses, or is a\nsubsidiary, affiliate, or controlled entity of such a manufacturer; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_415__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>sells such buses under such certificate of registration solely to\npublic transportation providers. For purposes of this subparagraph, the\nterm "public transportation provider" shall mean public transportation\nsystems eligible to receive operating assistance under the provisions of\nsection eighteen-b of the transportation law, and the term "public\ntransportation system" shall mean: (A) any public benefit corporation\nconstituting a transportation authority, or a subsidiary thereof, or any\npublic transportation corporation constituted as an instrumentality of\nthe state, or a subsidiary thereof, directly or through a contract with\nanother entity, that provides mass transportation services to the\ngeneral public; or (B) any Indian tribe or any county, city, town or\nvillage that provides mass transportation services to the general public\ndirectly or through a contract with another entity pursuant to section\none hundred nineteen-r of the general municipal law.\n  8. Use. Transport...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No registration shall be\nsuspended or revoked, or renewal refused, except upon notice to the\nregistrant and after an opportunity to be heard. Provided however, upon\na written notice of temporary suspension delivered by certified mail to\nthe registrant, a registration may be temporarily suspended pending a\nhearing. Any such notice of temporary suspension shall provide that the\nsuspension is effective seventy-two hours after mailing of such notice\nand shall provide that a hearing be scheduled within ten days after the\neffective date of the temporary suspension.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The applicant may be heard in person or by counsel. The hearing\nshall be at such time and place as the commissioner shall prescribe. The\ncommissioner or the commissioner's designee may inspect the pertinent\nbooks, records, letters and contracts of a registrant relating to any\nwritten complaint or charge against such registrant. The commissioner or\nthe commissioner's designee shall have the power to subpoena and bring\nbefore a hearing officer any person in this state, and administer an\noath to and take testimony of any person or cause the person's\ndeposition to be taken. A subpoena issued under this section shall be\nregulated by the civil practice law and rules.\n  10. Suspension and revocation of number plates. The commissioner may\nsuspend or revoke number plates issued pursuant to subdivision four of\nthis section, if he determines that the registrant to whom these plates\nhave been issued has used or permitted the use of such number plates\ncontrary to law or to the regulations of the commissioner with respect\nto the use thereof. The registrant to whom such number plates have been\nissued shall have an opportunity to be heard, and the provisions of\nsubdivision nine of this section shall apply to hearings held under this\nsubdivision, and to review of determinations made by the commissioner\nhereunder.\n  11. Following the suspension or revocation of the certificate of\nregistration of a dealer, manufacturer, or transporter or number plates,\npursuant to this section, the failure of the holder or any other person\npossessing the certificate of registration, number plates or\ncertificates of sale issued to a dealer pursuant to the regulations of\nthe commissioner, to deliver the same to the suspending or revoking\nofficer, peace officer acting pursuant to his or her special duties,\npolice officer directed by the commissioner to secure possession\nthereof, or agent of the commissioner, displaying authorization to act\nin such capacity along with a certif...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>agrees to accept the amount so found, if offered by the\nregistrant, and (ii) is not a party to any litigation which is pending\nor which has gone to judgment in relation to the same matter in any\ncivil court.\n  b. The amount of financial loss which may be found and proposed as\nrestitution shall be limited to an amount necessary to compensate the\ncomplainant or complainants for actual losses caused by the registrant's\nimproper activity. Neither punitive nor incidental damages may be\nincluded in the finding of financial loss.\n  c. If payment of restitution to the complainant is authorized in lieu\nof all or a portion of a suspension or civil penalty, in order for the\nregistrant to exercise the option to make such payment, such payment\nmust be made by means of a certified check or money order payable to the\ncomplainant or complainants delivered to an office of the department as\ndirected by the commissioner or his agent within thirty days of the date\nof notice of suspension and/or civil penalty. Upon receipt of such\ncertified check or money order, the department shall forward the same to\nthe complainant or complainants. In the event that the registrant should\nfail to make payment for restitution within such thirty days, but, at a\nlater time, pays such civil penalty, the department shall deduct from\nsuch civil penalty the amount assessed for restitution, and shall mail a\ncheck for such amount to the complainant or complainants.\n  d. If payment of restitution may be substituted in lieu of a civil\npenalty or portion of a civil penalty, and the registrant does not\nexercise the option to make such payment, the civil penalty becomes due\nas provided in subdivision twelve of this section and the provisions of\nthat subdivision and subdivision thirteen of this section relating to\nsuspension of registration and recovery of civil penalties shall apply.\n  e. Any payment made in compliance with such a finding of financial\nloss shall not preclude any civil a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who operates as a dealer while his registration is\nrevoked or suspended, shall pay to the people of this state a civil\npenalty in the sum of one thousand dollars. Such civil penalty may not\nbe avoided.\n  (ii) Any person who operates as a dealer without being registered as\nrequired by subdivision three of this section who has previously had a\ncivil penalty assessed for unregistered operation shall pay to the\npeople of this state a civil penalty in the sum of one thousand dollars.\nAny person who operates as a dealer without being registered as required\nby subdivision three of this section who has had two previous civil\npenalties assessed for unregistered operation not arising from the same\nincident all of which were committed within a period of thirty months\nshall pay to the people of this state a civil penalty in the sum of four\nthousand ten dollars. Such civil penalties may not be avoided.\n  (iii) No person who operates as a dealer without being registered as\nrequired by subdivision three of this section or while his or her\nregistration is revoked or suspended shall park a motor vehicle, which\nhe or she owns or controls and holds for sale or demonstration, upon a\npublic highway of this state without first being registered in\naccordance with the provisions of section four hundred one of this\nchapter. Any such person shall, in addition to any penalties imposed\npursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision or subparagraph (ii) of this\nparagraph, be required to pay to the people of this state an additional\ncivil penalty of three hundred dollars for each motor vehicle owned or\ncontrolled and held for sale or demonstration by such person which is\nparked upon the public highways of this state without first being\nregistered in accordance with the provisions of section four hundred one\nof this chapter.\n  d. The commissioner, or any person deputized by him, in addition to\nimposing a civil penalty for unregistered operation as a dealer, ma...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>agrees to accept the amount so found, if offered by the\nunregistered dealer, and (ii) is not a party to any litigation which is\npending or in which judgment has been entered in any civil action in any\ncourt of competent jurisdiction.\n  e. Civil penalties assessed under this section shall be paid to the\ncommissioner for deposit into the state treasury, and unpaid civil\npenalties may be recovered by the commissioner in a civil action in the\nname of the commissioner. In addition, as an alternative to such civil\naction and provided that no proceeding for judicial review shall then be\npending and the time for initiation of such proceeding shall have\nexpired, the commissioner may file with the county clerk of the county\nin which the registrant is located a final order of the commissioner\ncontaining the amount of the penalty assessed. The filing of such final\norder shall have the full force and effect of a judgment duly docketed\nin the office of such clerk and may be enforced in the same manner and\nwith the same effect as that provided by law in respect to executions\nissued against property upon judgments of a court of record.\n  f. No allegation of unregistered operation as a dealer shall be heard\nor determined unless notice of such allegation has been mailed to such\nperson within two years after the date of the alleged unregistered\noperation.\n  17. Improper display of signs. a. The holder of a dealer registration\nshall remove or cause to be removed any sign which contains the\nregistration number of the dealer which is visible to the public and\nwhich is required to be displayed by this article or regulations\npromulgated thereunder if the registration is revoked or suspended or\nthe dealer is out of business. If the registration is only suspended,\nthe holder may cover up the sign instead of removing it.\n  b. No person shall permit the display of any sign required to be\ndisplayed by this article or regulations promulgated thereunder\nindicating to...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the controlling equity\ninterest of such qualified dealer is transferred (in any one or series\nof transactions) to any person or persons, other than the parent,\nspouse, child or sibling of an individual who is an equity holder of\nsuch qualified dealer, or (ii) there occurs any merger, combination or\nconsolidation of, with or into the business entity which constitutes\nsuch qualified dealer.\n  g. Nothing contained herein shall</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>prohibit a qualified dealer or\nthe parent, spouse, child or sibling who is the equity holder of such\nqualified dealer from forming a corporation or limited liability company\nto operate and wholly own the qualified dealer; (ii) restrict the\nability of a qualified dealer to transfer a controlling equity interest\nto a corporation or a limited liability company operated and wholly\nowned by an individual who is an equity holder of such qualified dealer;\nor (iii) restrict the ability of a qualified dealer to transfer an\nequity interest in the stock and/or assets of a qualified dealer to a\nfull-time employee of such qualified dealer.\n  21. New motor vehicle etching kits. Every new motor vehicle dealer and\nevery qualified dealer shall be required to stock etching kits that are\ncapable of etching a traceable serial number onto the catalytic\nconverter of a new motor vehicle that can be clearly seen and quickly\nlinked back to the vehicle. Such etching kits shall be offered by every\nnew motor vehicle dealer and qualified dealer to any person purchasing a\nnew motor vehicle, at no more than the cost of such etching kit to such\ndealer.\n  22. Compliance. All dealers and automobile broker businesses\nregistered under subdivisions three and three-a of this section shall\ncertify and attest to compliance with sections three hundred\nninety-nine-cc, as added by chapter 655 of the laws of 2005, three\nhundred ninety-nine-dd, as added by chapter 487 of the laws of 2006,\nthree hundred ninety-nine-ddd, three hundred ninety-nine-h, three\nhundred ninety-nine-oo, three hundred ninety-nine-p, three hundred\nninety-nine-pp, eight hundred ninety-nine-bb of the general business\nlaw, and part three hundred fourteen of title sixteen of the code of\nfederal regulations as applicable.\n  23. Automobile broker record requirements.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each completed\ntransaction and within three business days of consummation thereof,\nautomobile brokers shall maintain a permanent paper file record that\nclearly evidences and records the make, model, year, color and vehicle\nidentification number of all previously unregistered motor vehicles for\nwhich such broker has provided a service of purchasing, arranging,\nassisting, facilitating or effecting the purchase or lease of such motor\nvehicle. Such records shall be maintained for a six-year period after\nconsummation of the transaction. Such records shall also include the\nname and address of the purchaser or lessee of such motor vehicle, the\ndate of sale or commencement of lease with respect to such motor vehicle\nand the name and address of the dealer from which the motor vehicle was\npurchased or leased.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The records maintained by the automobile broker businesses shall\ninclude a copy of the dealer rate sheets received by the automobile\nbroker from the dealers that were relied upon by the automobile broker\nin connection with such transaction.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such records shall be open for inspection by the commissioner, or\nhis or her agent, during reasonable business hours.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As an alternative to paper file records, an automobile broker may\nuse a computer and appropriate software to maintain the records required\nto be kept by this section, provided all information required by\nparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_415__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision are duly recorded and\nmaintained in accordance with this subdivision.\n  24. Maintenance records. For each sale or lease of a motor vehicle\nthat involves an automobile broker business, the dealer must obtain\nevidence of the automobile broker business' registration and the\nbroker's registration number and maintain such records in the deal\njacket for each transaction which also shall contain the purchase order,\ncopies of the title and registration documents, the bill of sale and the\nretail installment sale contract required under article ten of the\npersonal property law or the retail lease agreement required under\narticle nine-A of the personal property law.\n  25. Broker compensation. No dealer may offer or pay an automobile\nbroker business any fee, or commission, other than compensation\ndisclosed pursuant to section seven hundred thirty-eight or seven\nhundred forty-one-b of the general business law or section three hundred\ntwo or three hundred thirty-seven of the personal property law;\nprovided, however, that the automobile broker business may not accept\nany such fee or commission from the dealer if the broker has or will\naccept payment from the buyer or lessee of the automobile.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>