<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="416-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_416_A">
        <num>416-A</num>
        <heading>Bumper quality label requirements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 416-a. Bumper quality label requirements. 1. It shall be unlawful\nafter January first, nineteen hundred ninety-three for any manufacturer\nto sell or lease or to offer to sell or lease in this state for the\npurpose of registration in this state any new passenger type motor\nvehicle manufactured or assembled after said date designated as a\nnineteen hundred ninety-three or subsequent model, except omnibus and\nmultipurpose passenger vehicles, unless such vehicle has affixed thereto\na bumper quality label, placed conspicuously upon that window or\nwindshield where the manufacturer's suggested retail price sticker has\nbeen posted. The commissioner shall determine the size, type legibility\nand placement of such label. Such label shall include the following\ninformation: "This vehicle is equipped with a front bumper that has been\ntested at an impact speed of (specified by vehicle manufacturer) _____\nmiles per hour and a rear bumper that has been tested at an impact speed\nof (specified by the vehicle manufacturer) _______ miles per hour, and\nhas sustained no damage to the vehicle's body and minimal damage to the\nbumper and attachment hardware. Minimal damage to the bumper means\ndamage that can be repaired with the use of a common repair materials\nand without replacing any parts. The stronger the bumper, the less\nlikely the car will require repair after a low-speed collision."\n  2. The impact speed required to be specified in the notice pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section is the maximum speed of impact upon the\nbumper of the vehicle at which the vehicle sustains no damage to the\nbody and safety systems and only minimal damage to the bumper when\nsubjected to the fixed barrier and pendulum impact tests, and when\nsubjected to the corner impact test at not less than sixty percent of\nthat maximum speed, conducted pursuant to the practices, procedures and\nregulations promulgated under the concurrent authority of the Federal\nMotor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act (Cost Savings Act)(15\nU.S.C. 1901 et seq.) and the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety\nAct (15 U.S.C. 1381, et seq.)\n  3. For purposes of this section, "no damage" means that, when a\npassenger vehicle is subjected to applicable impact testing practices\nand procedures, the exterior surfaces shall have no separations of\nsurface materials, paint, polymeric coatings or other covering materials\nfrom the surface to which they are bonded, and no permanent deviations\nfrom their original contours thirty minutes after completion of each\npendulum and barrier impact test, except where such damage occurs to the\nbumper face bar and the components and associated fasteners that\ndirectly attach the bumper face bar to the chassis frame. There shall be\nno breakage or release of fasteners or joints except as described above.\n  4. Any manufacturer who violates subdivision one of this section,\nwithout just cause, shall be subject to a civil fine of not more than\nfifty dollars per vehicle with respect to which there has been a\nviolation of this section.  Civil penalties so assessed may not be\ndeducted as an expense from any tax liability due to any local or state\ntax jurisdiction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>