<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-06-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="416"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-416/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_416">
        <num>416</num>
        <heading>Limited use of dealer's, manufacturer's, and transporter's number plates by vendee or lessee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 416. Limited use of dealer's, manufacturer's, and transporter's\nnumber plates by vendee or lessee. Upon the sale or lease of a motor\nvehicle or motorcycle the vendee or lessee shall be allowed to operate\nthe same upon the public highways for the period of five days after\ntaking possession thereof, without carrying number plates issued upon a\nregistration under section four hundred one, if a motor vehicle, or\nunder section four hundred ten, if a motorcycle, provided the motor\nvehicle or motorcycle shall have attached thereto and displayed thereon,\nin the manner therein provided, a set of dealer's, manufacturer's, or\ntransporter's number plates issued to the vendor or lessor under section\nfour hundred fifteen, and if a proper application for registration and\nnumber plates for such vehicle, under the provisions of section four\nhundred one or four hundred ten of this title, as the case may be, shall\nhave been mailed or presented to the commissioner, or agent, accompanied\nwith the payment of the required fee within twenty-four hours after he\nor she has taken possession thereof. If the motor vehicle or motorcycle\nis to be registered in a jurisdiction other than the state of New York,\nthe requirement for filing or presenting such application shall not\napply.\n  No person shall operate or drive upon the public highways any motor\nvehicle or motorcycle on which is fastened or displayed any such\ndealer's, manufacturer's, or transporter's number plates after a sale or\nlease of such vehicle by the dealer or lessor, except in compliance with\nthe foregoing provisions.\n  A vendee or lessee to whom number plates are delivered or by whom they\nare held under the provisions of this section shall return the same, and\nthe accompanying registration certificate, to the dealer or lessor\nbefore the expiration of six days after he or she took possession of the\nmotor vehicle or motorcycle purchased or leased. If number plates so\ndelivered or held, or such certificate, are not returned within the time\nabove limited, the dealer or lessor shall immediately notify the\ncommissioner of that fact by mail, describing the plates according to\nthe general and distinctive numbers and characters thereon.\n  The provisions of this section shall apply also to the sale or lease\nof a trailer and to the use by the vendee or lessee of dealer's,\nmanufacturer's, or transporter's number plates on the trailer sold or\nleased, and for the purpose of applying such provisions a trailer shall\nbe deemed to be a motor vehicle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>