<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-465"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-465"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-09-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="465"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-465/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-465/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-465/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-465/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_465">
        <num>465</num>
        <heading>Procedures relating to warranties and sales incentives</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_465__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>parts sold at wholesale;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_465__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>tires;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_465__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>routine maintenance not covered under any retail customer warranty\nsuch as fluids, filters and belts not provided in the course of repairs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_465__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>vehicle reconditioning; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_465__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>batteries replaced as part of a\nroutine maintenance operation. If the franchisor rejects the declaration\nor attempts to rebut the declaration because of an error in the dealer's\nsubmission, the franchisor shall identify with specificity the reason\nfor rejection and identify the error or errors within the submission. In\nthe event the franchisor rejects or rebuts the dealer's initial\ndeclaration, the dealer shall have the opportunity, within sixty days to\nresubmit the full and corrected declaration addressing the alleged error\nor errors identified by the franchisor. The franchisor shall respond\nwithin sixty days. The one hundred eighty day requirement for the repair\norders shall be stayed from the date of initial submission. In any\naction or proceeding held pursuant to this subdivision, the franchisor\nshall have the burden of proving that the rate declared by the dealer\nwas unreasonable as described in this subdivision and that the proposed\nadjustment of the average percentage markup or rejection of the\nsubmission is reasonable pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision.\nA warranty claim timely made shall not be deemed invalid solely because\nunavailable parts cause additional use and mileage on the vehicle.\n  2. All warranty or sales incentive claims shall be either approved or\ndisapproved within thirty days after their receipt. When any such claim\nis disapproved the franchised motor vehicle dealer shall be notified in\nwriting of its disapproval within said period. Each such notice shall\nstate the specific grounds upon which the disapproval is based. Failure\nto disapprove a claim within thirty days shall be deemed approval.\n  3. No franchisor shall conduct an audit or charge back any warranty\npayment, or any sales, advertising or marketing incentive payment\n("incentive payments") or otherwise hold a franchised motor vehicle\ndealer liable for charges more than one year, or five years in the case\nof fraud, after the date the franchisor ma...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>