<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-491"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-491"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="491"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-491/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-491/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-491/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-491/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_491">
        <num>491</num>
        <heading>Period of validity of identification card; required fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any person sixty-two years of age or older or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any\nrecipient of supplemental security income benefits defined in section\ntwo hundred eight of the social services law, shall be eligible for a\ncard which expires ten years after the date of issuance. Such dates of\nissuance and expiration shall be noted on the identification card.\nHowever, the prior identification card shall expire on the date of\nissuance of a renewal of such prior identification card. The\ncommissioner may extend the period of validity of an identification card\nin a manner and form prescribed by the commissioner.\n  2. Fees.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fee for an identification card shall be fifty cents\nfor each six months, or any portion thereof of the identification card's\nvalidity, except that the fee which shall be charged for the issuance of\nany original, duplicate, or renewal identification card issued</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any\nperson sixty-two years of age or older or (ii) any recipient of\nsupplemental security income benefits as defined in section two hundred\neight of the social services law, shall be one dollar and fifty cents\nfor a period of ten years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fee for a duplicate of an identification card shall be three\ndollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to other fees prescribed herein, an additional fee\nshall be charged for the issuance of any original, duplicate or renewal\nidentification card which contains a photograph of the holder. Such fee\nshall not exceed the additional cost of providing a photograph on an\nidentification card rounded to the next highest twenty-five cents.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be no fee other than a fee prescribed in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision for an amended identification card.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any other fee prescribed in this section, an\nadditional fee of thirty dollars shall be charged for any non-driver\nidentification card, issued to a New York state resident who is a\ncitizen of the United States, that can be used for certain land and sea\nborder crossings pursuant to section 7209 of the Intelligence Reform and\nTerrorism Prevention Act of Two Thousand Four, Public Law 108-458, or\nthe regulations promulgated thereunder.\n  3. Waiver of fee. The commissioner may waive the payment of fees\nrequired by subdivision two of this section if the applicant is</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an\nincarcerated individual in an institution or correctional facility under\nthe jurisdiction of a state department or agency, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_491__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a victim of a\ncrime and the identification card applied for is a replacement for one\nthat was lost or destroyed as a result of the crime.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>