<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-501-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-501-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="501-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-501-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-501-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-501-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-501-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_501_B">
        <num>501-B</num>
        <heading>Additional restrictions on certain learners' permits and drivers' licenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_501_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>operate a motor vehicle with any front seat occupants other than\nthe supervising driver;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_501_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>operate a motor vehicle unless every occupant of such vehicle is\nproperly restrained by a safety belt or child safety seat in accordance\nwith the provisions of subdivision three-a of section twelve hundred\ntwenty-nine-c of this chapter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_501_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>operate a motor vehicle with more than one passenger who is under\nthe age of twenty-one and who is not a member of such holder's immediate\nfamily, provided, however, that the provisions of this paragraph shall\nnot apply when such holder is accompanied by a duly licensed parent,\nguardian, person in a position of loco parentis, driver education\nteacher or driving school instructor;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_501_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be eligible for issuance of a class DJ, MJ, D or M license unless\nsuch permit has been valid for at least six months. Any time period in\nwhich such class DJ or MJ learner's permit has been suspended or revoked\nshall not be counted in determining the length of time that such\nlearner's permit has been valid.\n  2. In addition to the restrictions contained in subdivision three of\nsection five hundred one of this article, no holder of a class DJ or\nclass MJ license shall operate a motor vehicle:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_501_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>unless every occupant of such vehicle is properly restrained by a\nsafety belt or child safety seat in accordance with the provisions of\nsubdivision three-a of section twelve hundred twenty-nine-c of this\nchapter; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_501_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>with more than one passenger who is under the age of twenty-one\nand who is not a member of such holder's immediate family, provided,\nhowever, that the provisions of this paragraph shall not apply when such\nholder is accompanied by a duly licensed parent, guardian, person in a\nposition of loco parentis, driver education teacher or driving school\ninstructor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>