<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-506"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-506"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="506"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_506">
        <num>506</num>
        <heading>Reexamination of licensees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 506. Reexamination of licensees. 1. If the commissioner has\nreasonable grounds to believe that a person holding a license issued\npursuant to this article is not qualified to drive a motor vehicle, the\ncommissioner may require such person to submit to an examination to\ndetermine his qualifications.\n  2. The commissioner may require every person holding a license issued\npursuant to this article to submit to such an examination as shall be\ndetermined by him to be appropriate if such person has been involved in\nthree accidents while driving a motor vehicle or motorcycle within a\nperiod of eighteen months, if such accidents were required to be\nreported by section six hundred five of this chapter.\n  3. If the licensee satisfactorily passes any such examination, he\nshall be so informed and his license shall continue to be valid. If he\nfails to pass, the commissioner shall take such reasonable action as may\nbe required.  Such action may consist of imposing restrictions on the\nuse of the license of such person, in suspending such license for a\ndefinite or indefinite period, or in revoking such license. If any such\nperson fails after reasonable notice or refuses to submit to an\nexamination, the commissioner may revoke his license or suspend it for\nan indefinite period solely because of such failure or refusal.\n  4. Any person holding a license issued pursuant to this chapter who\nsuffers permanent loss of use of one or both hands or arms or of one or\nboth feet or legs, or one eye shall, before operating any motor vehicle\nor motorcycle make report thereof to the commissioner, who shall take\nsuch reasonable action as may be proper under the provisions of this\nsection.\n  5. Upon the permanent loss of use of both eyes a license issued under\nthis article shall be null and void.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>