<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-507"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-507"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="507"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_507">
        <num>507</num>
        <heading>Miscellaneous provisions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_507__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of\nsection five hundred two of this article; provided however, the Yeshiva\nof Staten Island, which operates as a high school, may provide driver\neducation courses at the Arthur Kill Road Jewish Community Center of\nStaten Island and the Manor Road Jewish Community Center of Staten\nIsland, located in the county of Richmond; provided however, the Hebrew\nAcademy of Nassau County, a unified school that operates a high school,\nmay provide a driver education course approved by the state education\ndepartment in a middle school or elementary school location provided\nsuch course instruction occurs when elementary or middle school is not\nin session. No such driver education course may be approved unless\nclassroom training is provided by a person approved by the state\neducation department and the commissioner. However, a school district\nmay contract with one or more licensed drivers' schools to provide\nbehind the wheel training, pursuant to regulations promulgated by the\ncommissioner. The commissioner shall prescribe the requirements for\nlicensing of such minors. A student enrolled in such an approved driver\neducation course may operate a motor vehicle without holding a driver's\nlicense or a learner's permit while under the immediate supervision of\nan instructor in such course or a driver's school instructor providing\nbehind the wheel training in such a course, provided such operation is\nin accordance with the rules established by the commissioner. Every\nstudent who successfully completes such course in a day, evening or\nsummer school program offered by a public or private school shall\nreceive certification of such completion on a certificate prescribed by\nthe commissioner.\n  2. Failure to exhibit license. Failure by a licensee to exhibit a\nlicense valid for operation under this chapter to any magistrate, motor\nvehicle license examiner, motor vehicle investigator, peace officer,\nacting pursuant to his special duties, or police off...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>