<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-508"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-508"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="508"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_508">
        <num>508</num>
        <heading>Administrative procedures</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 508. Administrative procedures. 1. The commissioner shall appoint\nagents to act in his behalf with respect to the acceptance of\napplications and the issuance of licenses and permits prescribed in this\narticle, and he may prescribe the internal procedures to be followed by\nsuch agents with respect to such matters.\n  2. Any application required to be filed under this article shall be in\na manner and on a form or forms prescribed by the commissioner. The\napplicant shall furnish all information required by statute and, except\nas otherwise provided in this title, such other information as the\ncommissioner shall deem appropriate.\n  3. License record. The commissioner shall keep a record of every\nlicense issued which record shall be open to public inspection during\nreasonable business hours. Provided, however, that the following\ninformation whenever contained within the record of non-commercial\ndrivers' licenses and learners' permits shall not be open to public\ninspection: the photo image, social security number, client\nidentification number, name, address, telephone number, place of birth,\ncountry of origin, place of employment, school or educational\ninstitution attended, source of income, status as a recipient of public\nbenefits, the customer identification number associated with a public\nutilities account, medical information or disability information of any\nholders of, or applicants for, such licenses and permits, and whether\nsuch licenses or permits meet federal standards for identification or do\nnot meet federal standards for identification. Neither the commissioner\nnor his agent shall be required to allow the inspection of an\napplication, or to furnish a copy thereof, or information therefrom,\nuntil a license has been issued thereon.\n  4. The commissioner may promulgate regulations with respect to the\nadministration of the provisions of this article.\n  5. The commissioner is directed to develop license application and\nrenewal forms which shall solicit a voluntary one dollar donation from\npersons applying for or renewing a driver's license at the time of such\napplication or renewal. Of monies collected pursuant to this\nsubdivision, the first one hundred fifty thousand dollars shall be\nretained by the department to offset its initial program costs.\nSubsequently, five percent of any monies collected pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be retained by the department for continuing\nadministrative costs. The remainder of such monies collected pursuant to\nthis subdivision shall be deposited in the life pass it on trust fund\nestablished pursuant to section ninety-five-d of the state finance law,\nas added by chapter four hundred fifteen of the laws of two thousand\nthree.\n  6. The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of the\ndepartment of veterans' services, is directed to establish a process by\nwhich the department shall refer driver's license and non-driver\nidentification card applicants requesting and obtaining a notation upon\nsuch license or non-driver identification card that such applicant is a\nveteran of the United States armed forces pursuant to subdivision three\nof section four hundred ninety of this chapter or subdivision one of\nsection five hundred two of this article, upon such applicant's request,\nto the department of veterans' services, consistent with the provisions\nof section seven of the veterans' services law.\n  * 7. The commissioner is directed to establish a process by which the\ndepartment shall refer driver's license and non-driver identification\ncard applicants who consent to having their information shared with the\nC.W. Bill Young Cell Transplantation Program established in 42 U.S.C.\nSection 274k or the national marrow donor program ("registry operator")\nfor the purposes of receiving information from the registry operator\nabout enrolling as a potential volunteer bone marrow or blood cell donor\non the national registry. The commissioner is directed to further amend\nthe public website of the department to include a link to access\npublicly available information about the registry operator.\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2028\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>