<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-BB"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-BB"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="509-BB"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_509_BB">
        <num>509-BB</num>
        <heading>Reexamination of bus drivers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 509-bb. Reexamination of bus drivers. (1) Any person employed as a\nbus driver who has on three occasions been the operator of a motor\nvehicle involved in an accident of a nature or type set forth in section\nfive hundred nine-a of this article, where such accidents occurred\nwithin an eighteen-month period, shall be subject to reexamination,\nincluding a road test, as provided in this section; provided, however,\nthat if such person is subject to a period of disqualification pursuant\nto section five hundred nine-c or five hundred nine-cc of this article,\nsuch reexamination shall occur not more than forty-five days prior to\nthe completion of such period of disqualification; and provided,\nfurther, that accidents in which the driver was completely without fault\nshall not be included in determining whether such reexamination is\nrequired.\n  (2) The commissioner may require any person who meets the criteria set\nforth in subdivision one of this section to submit to such an\nexamination as the commissioner shall deem appropriate.  Every required\nroad test shall be administered on an appropriate vehicle defined as a\nbus pursuant to section five hundred nine-a of this article.\n  (3) For purposes of this section, one such accident shall not be\ncounted if the person successfully completes a motor vehicle accident\nprevention course approved by the commissioner.\n  (4) Upon the failure of the licensee to successfully complete a\nreexamination authorized by this section, the commissioner shall take\nsuch reasonable action as may be required. Such action may consist of\nimposing restrictions on the use of the license of such person,\nsuspending such license for a definite or indefinite period, or revoking\nsuch license. The commissioner may revoke or suspend for an indefinite\nperiod the license of any person who after reasonable notice fails or\nrefuses to submit to such reexamination. No person whose license has\nbeen suspended or revoked under this section shall be qualified to\noperate a bus until such person successfully completes a reexamination\nauthorized by this section.\n  (5) Upon a driver's successful completion of a reexamination required\nby this section, the commissioner shall issue an eighteen-month\nprobationary license to such driver and all of the provisions of section\nfive hundred ten-b of this article shall apply.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>