<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-04-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="509-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_509_G">
        <num>509-G</num>
        <heading>Examinations and tests</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_509_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All motor carriers shall be required to conduct pre-employment\nand random drug and alcohol testing in accordance with the provisions\nand requirements of Part 382 of Title 49 of the Code of Federal\nRegulations on all drivers of a school bus, as defined by section one\nhundred forty-two of this chapter, regardless of commercial driver's\nlicense endorsement. Every such school bus driver shall be included in\nthe random testing pool from which drivers are randomly selected for\ntesting, and every such driver shall submit to such testing when\nselected, as required in Part 382 of Title 49 of the Code of Federal\nRegulations. For the purposes of this section "motor carriers" shall\nmean a school or municipality that transports children to and from\nschool or any person, corporation or entity in contract with a\nmunicipality or school district for the purposes of transporting\nchildren to and from school.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_509_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Drug testing administered pursuant to this section shall, at a\nminimum, be in conformance with drug testing procedures as set forth in\nPart 382 of Title 49 of the Code of Federal Regulations.\n  7. In addition to the other provisions of this section, in the event\nthe commissioner authorizes or requires the pre-trip safety briefings\nrequired pursuant to subdivision nine of section five hundred nine-m of\nthis article to be live and in-person, all motor carriers shall conduct\na regular observation of the proficiency of each driver who operates\naltered motor vehicles commonly referred to as "stretch limousines"\ndirected or operated by such motor carrier, designed to carry nine or\nmore passengers including the driver pursuant to operating authority\nissued by the commissioner of transportation, in providing such pre-trip\nsafety briefings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>