<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="509-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_509_I">
        <num>509-I</num>
        <heading>Notification of a conviction resulting from a violation of this chapter in this state or a motor vehicle conviction in another state and ...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 509-i. Notification of a conviction resulting from a violation of\nthis chapter in this state or a motor vehicle conviction in another\nstate and license revocation. 1. A driver who receives a notice that his\nor her license, permit or privilege to operate a motor vehicle has been\nrevoked, suspended or withdrawn or who is convicted of a violation of\nsuch provisions of this chapter as shall constitute a misdemeanor or a\nfelony in any jurisdiction shall notify the motor carrier that employs\nsuch person of the contents of the notice before the end of the business\nday following the day he or she received it. A driver who fails to\nnotify his or her employer of such suspension, revocation or conviction\nof a violation of such provisions of this chapter as shall constitute a\nmisdemeanor or a felony shall be subject to a five (5) working day\nsuspension, or a suspension equivalent to the number of working days\nsuch driver was not in compliance with this article, whichever is\nlonger.\n  1-a. A driver who is convicted of a traffic infraction in any\njurisdiction shall notify his or her employer within five (5) working\ndays from the date of conviction. A driver who fails to notify his or\nher employer of such conviction within the five (5) working day period\nshall be subject to a five (5) working day suspension; provided,\nhowever, that a first such infraction occurring on or before September\nsixteenth, nineteen hundred eighty-six, shall not subject such violator\nto the said suspension.\n  1-b. A driver who is involved in an accident of a nature or type set\nforth in section five hundred nine-a of this article in any jurisdiction\nshall notify his or her employer within five working days from the date\nof the accident. A driver who fails to notify his or her employer of\nsuch accident within the five working day period shall be subject to a\nfive working day suspension.\n  2. Any driver who is convicted of an offense listed in section five\nhundred nine-c of this article that would disqualify such driver from\noperating a bus shall provide notice of such conviction in writing by\nthe following business day to the motor carrier that employs such\nperson. The motor carrier shall not permit any driver who fails to\nprovide such notice to operate a bus.\n  3. The commissioner upon receipt of information that a driver's\nlicense, permit or privilege to operate a motor vehicle has been\nrevoked, suspended or withdrawn in this state or elsewhere shall notify\nall motor carriers who have notified the commissioner of the employment\nof such driver; and may, if requested by a political subdivision which\ncontracts with a motor carrier for the transportation of school\nchildren, provide such notice to the political subdivision.\n  4. In addition to the requirements of subdivision three of this\nsection, the commissioner shall notify the motor carrier of any\nconviction for any traffic violation or accident resulting from\noperation of a motor vehicle against a bus driver employed by the motor\ncarrier, shall require payment of the fee necessary to defray the cost\nof the notification, and shall require all motor carriers to establish\nan escrow account with the department which shall be used to pay for the\ncosts incurred by the department when it informs the motor carrier of a\ndriver's conviction or accident; and may, if requested by a political\nsubdivision which contracts with a motor carrier for the transportation\nof school children, provide such notice to the political subdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>