<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="509"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_509">
        <num>509</num>
        <heading>Violations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_509__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of title 49 of the code of\nfederal regulations.\n  8. No licensee shall fail to notify the commissioner in writing of a\nchange of residence as required by this article.\n  9. Whenever notice of disability is required to be given to the\ncommissioner as required by this article, no person shall operate any\nmotor vehicle until such notice has been given.\n  10. No person shall hold an unexpired license issued by the\ncommissioner while holding a driver's license issued by any other\njurisdiction. This prohibition shall not apply to any license which by\nits terms is valid only within the jurisdiction of issuance. Nor shall\nit apply if such person has informed the commissioner of such multiple\nlicenses and the commissioner has determined that it is necessary for\nsuch person to hold more than one license to comply with the laws of\neach of the jurisdictions in which such licenses were issued. The\nforegoing exceptions shall not be applicable to commercial driver's\nlicenses after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred eighty-nine.\n  11. A violation of any provision of this section shall be punishable\nby a fine of not less than seventy-five nor more than three hundred\ndollars, or by imprisonment for not more than fifteen days, or by both\nsuch fine and imprisonment except, if the violation consists of failure\nto renew a license which was valid within sixty days, the fine shall be\nnot more than forty dollars, and except that a violation of subdivision\nseven or eight of this section shall be punishable by a fine of not more\nthan seventy-five dollars.\n  12. A violation of subdivision two of this section involving the\noperation for hire of any vehicle as a taxicab, livery as defined in\nsection one hundred twenty-one-e of this chapter, coach, limousine, van\nor wheelchair accessible van or tow truck within the state without the\nappropriate license therefor, shall be punishable by a fine of not less\nthan two hundred twenty-five dollars nor more than four hun...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>