<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-10-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="510-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_510_B">
        <num>510-B</num>
        <heading>Suspension and revocation for violations committed during probationary periods</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon the\nfirst conviction of the licensee of a violation, committed during the\nprobationary period provided for in subdivision four of section five\nhundred one of this title, of any provision of section eleven hundred\ntwenty-nine of this chapter, section eleven hundred eighty of this\nchapter or any ordinance or regulation limiting the speed of motor\nvehicles and motorcycles, section eleven hundred eighty-two of this\nchapter, subdivision one of section eleven hundred ninety-two of this\nchapter or section twelve hundred twelve of this chapter; or (ii) upon\nthe second conviction of the licensee of a violation, committed during\nthe aforesaid probationary period, of any other provision of this\nchapter or of any other law, ordinance, order, rule or regulation\nrelating to traffic.\n  2. A license, other than a class DJ or class MJ license, considered\nprobationary pursuant to subdivision three of this section shall be\nrevoked upon the conviction of the licensee of a violation or violations\ncommitted within six months following the restoration or issuance of\nsuch license, which conviction or convictions would result in the\nsuspension of a probationary license pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection or subparagraph (xvi) of paragraph b of subdivision two of\nsection five hundred ten of this article.\n  3. Any license, other than a class DJ or class MJ license, which is\nrestored or issued to a person who has had his last valid license\nsuspended or revoked pursuant to the provisions of this section or the\nprovisions of subparagraph (xii) of paragraph a or subparagraph (xvi) of\nparagraph b of subdivision two of section five hundred ten of this\narticle shall be considered probationary until the expiration of six\nmonths following the date of restoration or issuance thereof.\n  4. The provisions of subdivisions one, five, six and seven of section\nfive hundred ten of this chapter shall apply to any suspension or\nrevocation under this section. However, t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>