<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-10-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="510-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_510_C">
        <num>510-C</num>
        <heading>Suspension and revocation of learner's permits and driver's licenses for violations committed by holders of class DJ or class MJ learner'...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A learner's permit or a driver's\nlicense shall be suspended for a period of sixty days:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon a conviction or finding of a serious traffic violation as\ndefined in subdivision two of this section, when such violation was\ncommitted while the holder had a class DJ or class MJ learner's permit\nor a class DJ or MJ license; or\n  (ii) upon the second conviction or finding of such permit or license\nholder of a violation of any other provision of this chapter or any\nother law, ordinance, order, rule or regulation relating to traffic, and\nwhen such violation was committed while such holder had a class DJ or\nclass MJ learner's permit or a class DJ or MJ license.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A learner's permit or a driver's license shall be revoked for a\nperiod of sixty days upon the conviction or finding of the permit or\nlicense holder of a violation or violations, committed within six months\nafter the restoration of such permit or license suspended pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, which convictions or findings would\nresult in the suspension of such permit or license pursuant to paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n  2. For purposes of this section, the term "serious traffic violation"\nshall mean operating a motor vehicle in violation of any of the\nfollowing provisions of this chapter: articles twenty-five and\ntwenty-six; subdivision one of section six hundred; section six hundred\none; sections eleven hundred eleven, eleven hundred seventy, eleven\nhundred seventy-two and eleven hundred seventy-four; subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred eighty, provided that\nthe violation involved ten or more miles per hour over the established\nlimit; section eleven hundred eighty-two; subdivision three-a of section\ntwelve hundred twenty-nine-c for violations involving use of safety\nbelts or seats by a child under the age of sixteen; and section twelve\nhundred twelve of this chapter.\n  3. Any suspension or revocation required for a violation of section\ntwelve hundred twenty-five-c or section twelve hundred twenty-five-d of\nthis chapter shall be subject to the provisions of subdivisions two and\nsix of section five hundred ten of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>