<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-11-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="510-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_510_D">
        <num>510-D</num>
        <heading>Suspension and revocation of class E driver's licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 510-d. Suspension and revocation of class E driver's licenses. 1. A\nclass E driver's license shall be suspended by the commissioner for a\nperiod of one year where the holder is convicted of a violation of\nsection 230.20, 230.25, 230.30, 230.32, 230.34, 230.34-a or 230.40 of\nthe penal law and the holder used a for hire motor vehicle to commit\nsuch crime.\n  2. A class E driver's license may be revoked by the commissioner when\nthe holder, who had his or her driver's license suspended under\nsubdivision one of this section within the last ten years, is convicted\nof a second violation of section 230.20, 230.25, 230.30, 230.32, 230.34,\n230.34-a or 230.40 of the penal law and the holder used a for hire motor\nvehicle to commit such crime.\n  3. Any revocation or suspension of a class E driver's license issued\npursuant to this article shall be applicable only to that portion of the\nholder's driver's license or privilege which permits the operation of a\nmotor vehicle transporting passengers for hire, and the commissioner\nshall immediately issue a license, other than a class E driver's\nlicense, to such person, provided that such person is otherwise eligible\nto receive such license and further provided that issuing a license to\nsuch person does not create a substantial traffic safety hazard.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall not be construed to prevent\nany person who has the authority to suspend or revoke a license to drive\nor privilege of operating pursuant to section five hundred ten of this\narticle from exercising any such authority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>