<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-AA"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-AA"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="510-AA"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-510-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_510_AA">
        <num>510-AA</num>
        <heading>Downgrade of commercial driver's licenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_AA__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of title 49 of the code of federal regulations, or upon\nthe holder's failure to submit such medical certification or medical\nvariance documentation at such intervals as required by the federal\nmotor carrier safety improvement act of 1999 and Part 383.71</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_AA__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of title\n49 of the code of federal regulations and in a manner prescribed by the\ncommissioner. A commercial driver's license shall also be downgraded to\na non-commercial driver's license by the commissioner within sixty days\nof the holder's medical certification status becoming "not-certified"\nbased upon receipt of information from the issuing medical examiner or\nthe federal motor carrier safety administration that a medical\ncertification or medical variance was issued in error or rescinded. Such\ndowngrade shall be terminated, and the commercial driver's license\nrestored, upon:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_510_AA__subsec_h__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the holder's submission of the required valid\nmedical examiner's certificate or medical variance documentation; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_510_AA__subsec_h__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nthe holder's self-certification specifying the type of commercial motor\nvehicle operation he or she engages, or expects to engage in, and that\nthe holder is therefore not subject to the physical qualification\nrequirements of the federal motor carrier safety improvement act of 1999\nand Part 383.71</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_AA__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of title 49 of the code of federal regulations. The\ncommissioner shall, upon a holder's status becoming "not-certified",\nnotify the holder of such commercial driver's license by first class\nmail to the address of such person on file with the department or at the\ncurrent address provided by the United States postal service of his or\nher "not-certified" medical certification status and that his or her\ncommercial driver's license will be downgraded to a non-commercial\ndriver's license unless he or she submits a current medical certificate\nand/or medical variance in accordance with Part 383.71</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_AA__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of title 49 of\nthe code of federal regulations or changes his or her self-certification\nto driving only in excepted or intrastate commerce in accordance with\nPart 383.71</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_AA__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>(ii)(B), (C) or (D) of title 49 of the code of federal\nregulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>