<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-516-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-516-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="516-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-516-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-516-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-516-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-516-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_516_B">
        <num>516-B</num>
        <heading>Reciprocal agreements concerning reporting of traffic offenses and administrative action thereon</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_516_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may\nexecute a reciprocal compact or agreement not inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this chapter with the motor vehicle administrator or other\nauthorized official of another state concerning the reporting of\nconvictions for traffic offenses occurring in each state by a person\nlicensed in, or a resident of, the other state to such licensing or\nresidence state and the treating of any such reported conviction in the\nsame manner as if the conviction occurred in the licensing or residence\nstate for the purpose of administrative action. Any such compact or\nagreement shall specify the offenses subject to the compact or\nagreement, and shall include a determination of comparable offenses in\neach state if any such offenses are of a substantially similar nature\nbut are not denominated or described in precisely the same words in each\nparty state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_516_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The word "state" when used in this section shall mean any state,\nterritory, a possession of the United States, District of Columbia or\nany province of Canada.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Traffic offenses which may be subject to a reciprocal compact or\nagreement entered into pursuant to this section shall be limited to the\nfollwing types of offenses in this state and equivalent offenses in each\nparty state:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Manslaughter, criminally negligent homicide and assault arising\nfrom the operation of a motor vehicle;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Operating a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol or\na drug;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any felony in the commission of which a motor vehicle is used;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Leaving the scene of a personal injury or fatal incident without\nreporting;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any speeding offense;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any offense consisting of disobeying any traffic control device;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any offense involving failure to yield the right-of-way;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any offense involving direction of traffic, overtaking or passing;\n  9. Any offense involving failure to use a safety belt or child re-\nstraint device;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reckless driving; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_516_B__subsec_c__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Passing a stopped school bus.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_516_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the\nreporting or recording of convictions or youthful offender or other\njuvenile adjudications other than those included in a reciprocal compact\nor agreement executed pursuant to this section when the laws of either\nstate require or permit action to be taken or sanctions to be imposed on\nthe basis of such convictions or youthful offender or other juvenile\nadjudications.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>