<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-517"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-517"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="517"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-517/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-517/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-517/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-517/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_517">
        <num>517</num>
        <heading>Interstate compact guaranteeing appearance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 517. Interstate compact guaranteeing appearance. a. The commissioner\nmay execute a reciprocal compact or agreement not inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this chapter with the motor vehicle administrator or other\nauthorized official of another state concerning the appearance of a\nperson licensed in one state to answer a summons or an appearance ticket\nfor a moving traffic violation issued by the other state.  Such compact\nshall provide that if a person licensed by either state is issued a\nsummons or an appearance ticket by the other state for a moving traffic\nviolation covered by the compact or agreement, he shall not be detained\nor required to furnish bail or collateral, and that if he fails to\nappear in response to such summons or appearance ticket, his license may\nbe suspended by the state that issued the license until he submits to\nthe jurisdiction of the court or administrative tribunal in which such\nsummons or appearance ticket is returnable.  Such compact shall also\nprovide such terms and procedures as are necessary and proper to\nfacilitate its administration.\n  b. Such interstate compacts may also provide that if a registration or\nrenewal of a motor vehicle would be denied pursuant to either\nsubdivision five-a of section four hundred one of this chapter, for\nfailing to answer summonses or other processes issued for parking\ninfractions, or subdivision four of section one hundred forty-five of\nthe transportation law, with respect to the transportation of household\ngoods, returnable in any court or an administrative tribunal of the\ndepartment of transportation or for failing to comply with the rules and\nregulations of any administrative tribunal of appropriate jurisdiction\nfollowing entry of a final determination with respect to such summons or\nprocess, the state issuing the registration or renewal shall likewise\ndeny the registration or renewal, until such applicant submits to the\njurisdiction of the court or administrative tribunal in which such\nsummonses or other processes are returnable.\n  c. The word "state" when used in this section shall mean any state,\nterritory or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia\nor any province of the Dominion of Canada.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>