<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-518"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-518"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-04-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="518"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-518/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-518/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-518/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-518/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_518">
        <num>518</num>
        <heading>Reciprocal agreements concerning suspension or revocation of registration of a motor vehicle for violations of toll collection regulations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 518. Reciprocal agreements concerning suspension or revocation of\nregistration of a motor vehicle for violations of toll collection\nregulations. a. The commissioner may execute a reciprocal compact or\nagreement regarding toll collection violations with the motor vehicle\nadministrator or other authorized official of another state not\ninconsistent with the provisions of this chapter. Such compact or\nagreement shall provide that if a registration of a motor vehicle would\nbe suspended or revoked pursuant to paragraph d of subdivision three of\nsection five hundred ten of this chapter, or pursuant to a comparable\nlaw or regulation of another state, because a registrant of such motor\nvehicle failed to pay tolls and related fees, or have such tolls or fees\ndismissed or transferred, then the state issuing the registration shall\nlikewise suspend or revoke the registration or bar renewal of such\nregistration, until such registrant has paid such tolls and fees or\ncomplied with the rules and regulations of the tolling authority that\nimposed such tolls and fees. Such compact or agreement shall also\nprovide that no such action by a state against a motor vehicle\nregistration shall be taken pursuant to such compact or agreement unless\nthe tolling authority in the other state provides notice, due process,\nan opportunity to be heard and appeal protections for registrants of\nmotor vehicles, and allows motor vehicle registrants in this state to\npresent evidence by mail, telephone, electronic means or other means to\ninvoke rights of due process without having to appear personally in the\njurisdiction where the violations occurred.\n  b. Such compact or agreement shall also provide such terms and\nprocedures as are necessary and proper to facilitate its administration.\nAny such compact or agreement shall specify the violations subject to\nthe compact or agreement, and shall include a determination of\ncomparable violations in each state if any such violations are of a\nsubstantially similar nature but are not denominated or described in\nprecisely the same words in each party state.\n  c. The word "state" when used in this section shall mean any state,\nterritory, a possession of the United States, the District of Columbia\nor any province of Canada.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>