<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-523-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-523-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="523-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-523-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-523-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-523-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-523-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_523_A">
        <num>523-A</num>
        <heading>Driver improvement clinic programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 523-a. Driver improvement clinic programs. In addition to the driver\nrehabilitation program authorized by section eleven hundred ninety-six\nof this chapter, the commissioner may establish, by regulation,\nguidelines for alcohol and highway safety programs. The purpose of such\nprograms should be to inform participants of the effects of alcohol on\ndriving, to discuss problem drinking and its effects, to provide\nassistance to individuals with referral to alcoholism treatment agencies\nand to provide instruction with respect to proper driving techniques and\ndriver attitude. The commissioner shall establish criteria for requiring\nattendance at such clinics, and may, pending attendance at such clinic,\nsuspend the driver's license or privilege of any person who fails to\nattend such clinic as required by such regulations. Such criteria may\nprovide for the required attendance at such clinic of any person who, as\na result of the conviction for a moving traffic violation, is referred\nby the trial court for such attendance. The commissioner shall establish\na fee to be paid by any person who attends any such program. Such fee\nshall be used to defray the ongoing expenses of the program. Where the\ncommissioner has approved any driver improvement program conducted by\nlocal authorities, any such fee shall be paid to the agency conducting\nsuch program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>