<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-543"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-543"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="543"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-543/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-543/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-543/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-543/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_543">
        <num>543</num>
        <heading>Appointment; compensation; meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 543. Appointment; compensation; meetings. 1. The members of the\nboard shall be appointed by the commissioner. Before such appointments\nare made, the commissioner shall consult with the medical society of the\nstate of New York in order to obtain their advice regarding the\nphysician appointments. The commissioner shall consult with the\noptometric council of New York state and the New York state optometric\nassociation regarding the appointment of an optometrist, and the New\nYork state psychological association regarding the appointment of a\npsychologist. The board members shall be appointed to serve three year\nterms except that four such members initially appointed shall serve one\nyear terms, five shall serve two year terms and five shall serve three\nyear terms. The commissioner shall designate the chairman of the board.\nMembers representing other specialties and interests may be appointed by\nthe commissioner upon recommendation of the board.\n  2. Board members shall serve without compensation but shall be allowed\ntheir actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their\nduties.\n  3. The board shall meet at such times as the commissioner shall\ndirect.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>