<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VAT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="604"/>
          <FRBRname value="VAT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vat/section-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_604">
        <num>604</num>
        <heading>Reports; contents; preparation; distribution; filing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 604. Reports; contents; preparation; distribution; filing. Reports\nof accidents required under sections six hundred three and six hundred\nthree-a of this article, or under the rules and regulations of the\ncommissioner, shall be upon forms prepared by the commissioner and\ncontain such information as the commissioner shall prescribe; provided,\nhowever, that the commissioner shall provide space on such forms to\nindicate the type or types of vehicles involved, including passenger\nmotor vehicles, commercial motor vehicles, motorcycles, limited use\nmotorcycles, off-highway motorcycles, electric scooters, bicycles with\nelectric assist, and/or bicycles. Blank forms for such reports shall be\nprinted by the commissioner and a supply sent to all city, town and\nvillage clerks and to the chief officer of every city police department\nfor general distribution and use as herein provided. Reports of\naccidents, required under the preceding section, shall be sent to and\nfiled with the commissioner at the main office of the bureau of motor\nvehicles in the city of Albany, except as otherwise provided by the\nrules and regulations of the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>