<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_D">
        <num>11-D</num>
        <heading>One-day marriage officiant license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-d. One-day marriage officiant license. 1. A town or city clerk\nshall issue a one-day marriage officiant license upon request. Such\none-day marriage officiant shall have the authority to solemnize a\nmarriage which marriage shall be valid if performed in accordance with\nother provisions of law. Nothing herein contained shall nullify the\nauthority of other persons authorized to solemnize marriages.\n  2. Such one-day marriage officiant shall be eighteen years of age or\nover and need not be a resident of the town or city to which they apply\nor a resident of the state. A one-day marriage officiant shall have the\nauthority to solemnize a marriage anywhere in the state.\n  3. An applicant for a one-day marriage officiant license must apply\nfor such license in the same town or city clerk's office as the couple\nto be married. Such applicant shall not be required to personally\nappear.\n  4. A town or city clerk shall be entitled to a fee of twenty-five\ndollars for issuing a one-day marriage officiant license. Such license\nshall be issued only after payment of such fee and submission of a\ncompleted application form.\n  5. The application form shall require the following information of the\napplicant: name, date of birth, address, email address and telephone\nnumber. The application form shall also require the following\ninformation of the parties to be married: names, dates of birth, and\naddresses as they appear on the application for a marriage license.\n  6. Such license shall only be valid for the parties to be married as\nstated on the application and shall expire upon the earlier of either\ncompletion of such solemnization or the expiration of the marriage\nlicense.\n  7. One-day marriage officiants shall be exempt from registration as\nrequired pursuant to section eleven-b of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>