<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-115"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-115"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="115"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_115">
        <num>115</num>
        <heading>General provisions relating to private-placement adoptions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_115__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided in this title, private-placement\nadoptions shall be effected in the same manner as provided in sections\none hundred twelve and one hundred fourteen of title two of this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_115__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person or persons seeking to commence a private-placement\nadoption shall, prior to the submission of a petition for such adoption\nand prior to any transfer of physical custody of an adoptive child, be\ncertified as a qualified adoptive parent or parents by a court of\ncompetent jurisdiction pursuant to section one hundred fifteen-d of this\ntitle.  The provisions of such section may be waived upon the court's\nown motion or upon the application of any party for good cause shown.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_115__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A non-resident person or persons seeking to commence a\nprivate-placement adoption of a child present within the state at the\ntime of placement shall, prior to any transfer of physical custody of an\nadoptive child, make application for certification as a qualified\nadoptive parent or parents by a court of competent jurisdiction pursuant\nto section one hundred fifteen-d of this title. Upon application of such\nperson or persons, the court of the county to which the certification\npetition is properly filed may take or retain jurisdiction of the\nadoption proceeding. The provisions of this paragraph may be waived upon\nthe court's own motion or upon the application of any party for good\ncause shown.\n  2. The proceeding shall be instituted in the county where the adoptive\nparents reside or, if such adoptive parents do not reside in this state,\nin the county where the adoptive child resides.\n  3. The adoptive parents or parent, the adoptive child and all persons\nwhose consent is required by section one hundred eleven of this article\nmust appear for examination before the judge or surrogate of the court\nwhere the adoption proceedings are instituted. The judge or surrogate\nmay dispense with the personal appearance of the adoptive child or of an\nadoptive parent who is on active duty in the armed forces of the United\nStates.\n  4. The agreement of adoption shall be executed by the adoptive parents\nor parent.\n  5. Where the petition alleges that either or both of the birth parents\nof the child have been deprived of civil rights or are mentally ill or\ndevelopmentally disabled, proof shall be submitted that such disability\nexists at the time of the proposed adoption.\n  6. The adoptive parent or parents shall also present in an affidavit a\ndescription of any change of circumstances since their certification as\na qualified adoptive parent or parents, pursuant to section one hundred\nfifteen-d of this title, which may be relevant and material to such\ncertif...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_115__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the child who is being adopted was placed or brought into\nNew York for the purpose of adoption from a state which is a party to\nthe interstate compact on the placement of children and the provisions\nof the compact applied to such placements, the petition must contain a\nstatement that the provisions of section three hundred seventy-four-a of\nthe social services law were complied with and where applicable, that\nthe provisions of section three hundred eighty-two of such law were also\ncomplied with.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_115__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the child who is being adopted was placed or brought into New\nYork for the purpose of adoption from a state which is not a party to\nthe interstate compact on the placement of children, the petition, where\napplicable, must contain a statement that the provisions of section\nthree hundred eighty-two of the social services law were complied with.\n  13. If the placement of a child into the state of New York is subject\nto the provisions of sections three hundred seventy-four-a and/or three\nhundred eighty-two of the social services law, there shall be attached\nto the petition a copy of the document signed by New York's\nadministrator of the interstate compact on the placement of children or\nhis designee which informs the agency or person who placed the child\ninto the state that such placement complied with the provisions of the\ncompact and/or a copy of the license which is issued pursuant to the\nprovisions of section three hundred eighty-two of the social services\nlaw to the person, institution, corporation or agency which placed or\nbrought the child into this state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>