<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-116"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-116"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="116"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_116">
        <num>116</num>
        <heading>Orders of investigation and order of adoption</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_116__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the marital and family status, and history, of the adoptive\nparents and adoptive child;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_116__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the physical and mental health of the adoptive parents and\nadoptive child;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_116__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the property owned by and the income of the adoptive parents;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_116__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the compensation paid or agreed upon with respect to the placement\nof the child for adoption;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_116__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether either adoptive parent has ever been respondent in any\nproceeding concerning allegedly abused, neglected, abandoned or\ndelinquent children;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_116__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other facts relating to the familial, social, religious,\nemotional and financial circumstances of the adoptive parents which may\nbe relevant to a determination of adoption.\n  The written report of investigation shall be submitted to the judge or\nsurrogate within thirty days after the same is directed to be made,\nunless for good cause shown the judge or surrogate shall grant a\nreasonable extension of such period. The report shall be filed with the\njudge or surrogate, in any event, before the final order of adoption is\ngranted.\n  4. Stage two of private-placement adoption. If the judge or surrogate\nhas found that there has been compliance with all the requirements\nhereof and is satisfied that the best interests of the child will be\npromoted by granting an order of adoption, the provisions of section one\nhundred fourteen of title two of this article shall apply.\n  5. As used in this section, "disinterested person" includes the\nprobation service of the family court, a licensed master social worker,\nlicensed clinical social worker, or an authorized agency specifically\ndesignated by the court to conduct pre-placement investigations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>