<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-12"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-12"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-12/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-12/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-12/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-12/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12">
        <num>12</num>
        <heading>Marriage, how solemnized</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 12. Marriage, how solemnized. No particular form or ceremony is\nrequired when a marriage is solemnized as herein provided by a clergyman\nor magistrate, or one-day marriage officiant as designated by a town or\ncity clerk pursuant to section eleven-d of this article, but the parties\nmust solemnly declare in the presence of a clergyman, magistrate, or\nsuch one-day marriage officiant and the attending witness or witnesses\nthat they take each other as spouses. In every case, at least one\nwitness beside the clergyman, magistrate, or such one-day marriage\nofficiant must be present at the ceremony.\n  The preceding provisions of this chapter, so far as they relate to the\nmanner of solemnizing marriages, shall not affect marriages among the\npeople called friends or quakers; nor marriages among the people of any\nother denominations having as such any particular mode of solemnizing\nmarriages; but such marriages must be solemnized in the manner\nheretofore used and practiced in their respective societies or\ndenominations, and marriages so solemnized shall be as valid as if this\narticle had not been enacted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>