<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-15-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-15-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-15-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-15-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-15-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-15-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_B">
        <num>15-B</num>
        <heading>Temporary provisions authorizing issuance of marriage license, upon court order, without consent of a parent in armed forces of United St...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 15-b. Temporary provisions authorizing issuance of marriage\nlicense, upon court order, without consent of a parent in armed forces\nof United States, merchant marine and allied forces, and absent from the\nUnited States. Notwithstanding the provisions of section fifteen of this\nchapter or any other provision of law, the written consent of a parent\nof a minor to the marriage of such minor may be dispensed with by order\nof a judge or justice of the supreme court of this state or the county\njudge of the county in which the minor resides or, in case the minor be\na woman between fourteen and sixteen years of age, of such a justice of\nthe supreme court or the county judge or judge of the children's court\nof the county in which such woman resides, upon proof satisfactory to\nsuch judge or justice that it is impracticable to require such consent\nbecause such parent is a member of the armed forces of the United\nStates, merchant marine and allied forces, and is absent from the United\nStates, and any such judge or justice is hereby authorized to make such\nan order if satisfied of the existence of such circumstances and that\nthe public interest will not be injuriously affected by dispensing with\nsuch consent; provided, however, that no such order shall be granted\nexcept upon application therefor both by the minor whose parent is so\nabsent and by the other parent, or if the other parent be dead or his or\nher consent to such marriage be unnecessary for any reason, then by the\nperson under whose care or government the minor may be. Upon the filing\nof such an order with the town or city clerk, he shall issue the license\nwithout the written consent of the parent whose consent is ordered\ndispensed with therein, provided all the other provisions of this\nchapter in connection with the issuance of the license are complied\nwith. The provisions of this section shall remain in force and effect\nonly until July first, nineteen hundred forty-seven.\n  * NB Expired July 1, 1947\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>