<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="20-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20_A">
        <num>20-A</num>
        <heading>Certified transcripts of records; state commissioner of health may furnish</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 20-a. Certified transcripts of records; state commissioner of health\nmay furnish. The state commissioner of health or person authorized by\nhim shall, upon request, supply to any applicant a certified transcript\nof any marriage registered under the provisions of this article, unless\nhe is satisfied that the same does not appear to be necessary or\nrequired for judicial or other proper purposes. Any transcript of the\nrecord of a marriage, when properly certified by the state commissioner\nof health or person authorized to act for him, shall be prima facie\nevidence in all courts and places of the facts therein stated. For any\nsearch of the files and records conducted for authorized research\npurposes, the state commissioner of health shall be entitled to a fee of\ntwenty dollars for each hour or fractional part of an hour of time of\nsearch, together with a fee of two dollars for each uncertified copy or\nabstract of such marriage record requested by the applicant, said fees\nto be paid by the applicant. Each applicant for a certified transcript\nof a marriage record shall remit to the state commissioner of health a\nfee of thirty dollars in payment for the search of the files and records\nand the furnishing of a certified copy if such record is found or for a\ncertification that a search discloses no record of a marriage.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>