<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-10-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="20-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20_C">
        <num>20-C</num>
        <heading>Certification of marriage; new certificate in case of subsequent change of name or gender</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_20_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a judgment,\norder or decree affirming a change of name or gender designation of\neither party to a marriage;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_20_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an amended birth certificate\ndemonstrating a change of name or gender designation;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_20_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of\na change of gender designation, a notarized affidavit from the\nindividual attesting to their change of gender designation; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_20_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such\nother proof as may be established by the commissioner of health.\n  2. When a new marriage certificate is made pursuant to this section,\nthe town or city clerk shall substitute such new certificate for the\nmarriage certificate then on file, if any, and shall send the state\ncommissioner of health a digital copy of the new marriage certificate in\na format prescribed by the commissioner, with the exception of the city\nclerk of New York who shall retain their copy. The town or city clerk\nshall make a copy of the new marriage certificate for the local record\nand hold the contents of the original marriage certificate confidential\nalong with all supporting documentation, papers and copies pertaining\nthereto. It shall not be released or otherwise divulged except by order\nof a court of competent jurisdiction.\n  3. The town or city clerk shall be entitled to a fee of ten dollars\nfor the amendment and certified copy of any marriage certificate in\naccordance with the provisions of this section.\n  4. The state commissioner of health may, in their discretion, report\nto the attorney general any town or city clerk that, without cause,\nfails to issue a new marriage certificate upon receipt of proper proof\nof a change of name or gender designation in accordance with this\nsection.  The attorney general shall thereupon, in the name of the state\ncommissioner of health or the people of the state, institute such action\nor proceeding as may be necessary to compel the issuance of such new\nmarriage certificate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>