<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-77-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-77-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="77-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-77-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-77-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-77-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-77-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_77_J">
        <num>77-J</num>
        <heading>Warrant to take physical custody of child</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_77_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>recite the facts upon which a conclusion of imminent serious\nphysical harm or removal from the jurisdiction is based;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_77_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>direct law enforcement officers to take physical custody of the\nchild immediately and deliver the child to the petitioner or, where\nnecessary, to act jointly with the local child protective service to\ntake immediate steps to protect the child; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_77_J__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide for the placement of the child pending final relief.\n  4. The respondent must be served with the petition, warrant, and order\nimmediately after the child is taken into physical custody.\n  5. A warrant to take physical custody of a child is enforceable\nthroughout this state. If the court finds on the basis of the testimony\nof the petitioner or other witness that a less intrusive remedy is not\neffective, it may authorize law enforcement officers to enter private\nproperty in order to execute the warrant and take physical custody of\nthe child. If required by exigent circumstances of the case and\nnecessary to the protection of the child, the court may authorize law\nenforcement officers to make a forcible entry at any hour.\n  6. The court may impose conditions upon placement of a child to ensure\nthe appearance of the child and the child's custodian.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>