<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-155.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-155.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="155.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-155.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-155.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-155.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-155.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_155_30">
        <num>155.30</num>
        <heading>Grand Larceny in the fourth degree</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_155_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has a value of at least one hundred dollars; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_155_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is kept for or used in connection with religious worship in any\nbuilding, structure or upon the curtilage of such building or structure\nused as a place of religious worship by a religious corporation, as\nincorporated under the religious corporations law or the education law;\nor\n  10. The property consists of an access device which the person intends\nto use unlawfully to obtain telephone service; or\n  11. The property consists of anhydrous ammonia or liquified ammonia\ngas and the actor intends to use, or knows another person intends to\nuse, such anhydrous ammonia or liquified ammonia gas to manufacture\nmethamphetamine; or\n  12. The property consists of retail goods or merchandise stolen\npursuant to a common scheme or plan or a single, ongoing intent to\ndeprive another or others of the property or to appropriate the property\nto the actor or another person and the value of the property exceeds one\nthousand dollars, which value may be determined by the aggregate value\nof all such property regardless of whether the goods or merchandise were\nstolen from the same owner. Nothing in this subdivision shall be read to\nlimit the ability to aggregate the value of any property or the ability\nto charge the larceny of retail goods or merchandise under another\napplicable provision of law.\n  Grand larceny in the fourth degree is a class E felony.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>