<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-165.45"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-165.45"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="165.45"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-165.45/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-165.45/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-165.45/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-165.45/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_165_45">
        <num>165.45</num>
        <heading>Criminal possession of stolen property in the fourth degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 165.45 Criminal possession of stolen property in the fourth degree.\n  A person is guilty of criminal possession of stolen property in the\nfourth degree when he knowingly possesses stolen property, with intent\nto benefit himself or a person other than an owner thereof or to impede\nthe recovery by an owner thereof, and when:\n  1. The value of the property exceeds one thousand dollars; or\n  2. The property consists of a credit card, debit card or public\nbenefit card; or\n  3. He is a collateral loan broker or is in the business of buying,\nselling or otherwise dealing in property; or\n  4. The property consists of one or more firearms, rifles and shotguns,\nas such terms are defined in section 265.00 of this chapter; or\n  5. The value of the property exceeds one hundred dollars and the\nproperty consists of a motor vehicle, as defined in section one hundred\ntwenty-five of the vehicle and traffic law, other than a motorcycle, as\ndefined in section one hundred twenty-three of such law; or\n  6. The property consists of a scroll, religious vestment, vessel or\nother item of property having a value of at least one hundred dollars\nkept for or used in connection with religious worship in any building or\nstructure used as a place of religious worship by a religious\ncorporation, as incorporated under the religious corporations law or the\neducation law.\n  7. The property consists of anhydrous ammonia or liquified ammonia gas\nand the actor intends to use, or knows another person intends to use,\nsuch anhydrous ammonia or liquified ammonia gas to manufacture\nmethamphetamine.\n  Criminal possession of stolen property in the fourth degree is a class\nE felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>