<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.57"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.57"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="180.57"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.57/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.57/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.57/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-180.57/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_180_57">
        <num>180.57</num>
        <heading>Rent gouging in the first degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 180.57 Rent gouging in the first degree.\n  A person is guilty of rent gouging in the first degree when, in the\ncourse of a scheme constituting a systematic ongoing course of conduct\nin connection with the leasing, rental or use of three or more apartment\nunits, the rental price of which is regulated pursuant to the provisions\nof federal, state or local law, he solicits, accepts or agrees to accept\nfrom one or more persons in three separate transactions some\nconsideration of value, knowing that such consideration is in addition\nto lawful rental and other lawful charges established pursuant to the\nprovisions of such federal, state or local law, and upon an agreement or\nunderstanding that the furnishing of such consideration will increase\nthe possibility that any person may obtain or renew the lease, rental or\nuse of such property, or that a failure to furnish it will decrease the\npossibility that any person may obtain or renew same, and thereby\nobtains such consideration from one or more persons.\n  Rent gouging in the first degree is a class E felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>