<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.50"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.50"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="215.50"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-215.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_215_50">
        <num>215.50</num>
        <heading>Criminal contempt in the second degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 215.50 Criminal contempt in the second degree.\n  A person is guilty of criminal contempt in the second degree when he\nengages in any of the following conduct:\n  1. Disorderly, contemptuous, or insolent behavior, committed during\nthe sitting of a court, in its immediate view and presence and directly\ntending to interrupt its proceedings or to impair the respect due to its\nauthority; or\n  2. Breach of the peace, noise, or other disturbance, directly tending\nto interrupt a court's proceedings; or\n  3. Intentional disobedience or resistance to the lawful process or\nother mandate of a court except in cases involving or growing out of\nlabor disputes as defined by subdivision two of section seven hundred\nfifty-three-a of the judiciary law; or\n  4. Contumacious and unlawful refusal to be sworn as a witness in any\ncourt proceeding or, after being sworn, to answer any legal and proper\ninterrogatory; or\n  5. Knowingly publishing a false or grossly inaccurate report of a\ncourt's proceedings; or\n  6. Intentional failure to obey any mandate, process or notice, issued\npursuant to articles sixteen, seventeen, eighteen, or eighteen-a of the\njudiciary law, or to rules adopted pursuant to any such statute or to\nany special statute establishing commissioners of jurors and prescribing\ntheir duties or who refuses to be sworn as provided therein; or\n  7. On or along a public street or sidewalk within a radius of two\nhundred feet of any building established as a courthouse, he calls\naloud, shouts, holds or displays placards or signs containing written or\nprinted matter, concerning the conduct of a trial being held in such\ncourthouse or the character of the court or jury engaged in such trial\nor calling for or demanding any specified action or determination by\nsuch court or jury in connection with such trial.\n  Criminal contempt in the second degree is a class A misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>