<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.50"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.50"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220.50"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220_50">
        <num>220.50</num>
        <heading>Criminally using drug paraphernalia in the second degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 220.50 Criminally using drug paraphernalia in the second degree.\n  A person is guilty of criminally using drug paraphernalia in the\nsecond degree when he knowingly possesses or sells:\n  1. Diluents, dilutants or adulterants, including but not limited to,\nany of the following: quinine hydrochloride, mannitol, mannite, lactose\nor dextrose, adapted for the dilution of narcotic drugs or stimulants\nunder circumstances evincing an intent to use, or under circumstances\nevincing knowledge that some person intends to use, the same for\npurposes of unlawfully mixing, compounding, or otherwise preparing any\nnarcotic drug or stimulant; or\n  2. Gelatine capsules, glassine envelopes, vials, capsules or any other\nmaterial suitable for the packaging of individual quantities of narcotic\ndrugs or stimulants under circumstances evincing an intent to use, or\nunder circumstances evincing knowledge that some person intends to use,\nthe same for the purpose of unlawfully manufacturing, packaging or\ndispensing of any narcotic drug or stimulant; or\n  3. Scales and balances used or designed for the purpose of weighing or\nmeasuring controlled substances, under circumstances evincing an intent\nto use, or under circumstances evincing knowledge that some person\nintends to use, the same for purpose of unlawfully manufacturing,\npackaging or dispensing of any narcotic drug or stimulant.\n  Criminally using drug paraphernalia in the second degree is a class A\nmisdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>