<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.78"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.78"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220.78"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.78/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.78/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.78/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-220.78/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220_78">
        <num>220.78</num>
        <heading>Witness or victim of drug or alcohol overdose</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_78__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Drug or alcohol overdose" or "overdose" means an acute condition\nincluding, but not limited to, physical illness, coma, mania, hysteria\nor death, which is the result of consumption or use of a controlled\nsubstance or alcohol and relates to an adverse reaction to or the\nquantity of the controlled substance or alcohol or a substance with\nwhich the controlled substance or alcohol was combined; provided that a\npatient's condition shall be deemed to be a drug or alcohol overdose if\na prudent layperson, possessing an average knowledge of medicine and\nhealth, could reasonably believe that the condition is in fact a drug or\nalcohol overdose and (except as to death) requires health care.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_78__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Health care" means the professional services provided to a person\nexperiencing a drug or alcohol overdose by a health care professional\nlicensed, registered or certified under title eight of the education law\nor article thirty of the public health law who, acting within his or her\nlawful scope of practice, may provide diagnosis, treatment or emergency\nservices for a person experiencing a drug or alcohol overdose.\n  4. It shall be an affirmative defense to a criminal sale controlled\nsubstance offense under this article or a criminal sale of cannabis\noffense under article two hundred twenty-two of this title, not covered\nby subdivision one or two of this section, with respect to any\ncontrolled substance or cannabis which was obtained as a result of such\nseeking or receiving of health care, that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_78__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant, in good faith, seeks health care for someone or for\nhim or herself who is experiencing a drug or alcohol overdose or other\nlife threatening medical emergency; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_78__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant has no prior conviction for the commission or\nattempted commission of a class A-I, A-II or B felony under this\narticle.\n  5. Nothing in this section shall be construed to bar the admissibility\nof any evidence in connection with the investigation and prosecution of\na crime with regard to another defendant who does not independently\nqualify for the bar to prosecution or for the affirmative defense; nor\nwith regard to other crimes committed by a person who otherwise\nqualifies under this section; nor shall anything in this section be\nconstrued to bar any seizure pursuant to law, including but not limited\nto pursuant to section thirty-three hundred eighty-seven of the public\nhealth law.\n  6. The bar to prosecution described in subdivisions one and two of\nthis section shall not apply to the prosecution of a class A-I felony\nunder this article, and the affirmative defense described in subdivision\nfour of this section shall not apply to the prosecution of a class A-I\nor A-II felony under this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>