<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.95"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.95"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225.95"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.95/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.95/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.95/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-225.95/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225_95">
        <num>225.95</num>
        <heading>Unlawful manufacture, sale, distribution, marking, altering or modification of equipment and devices associated with gaming</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 225.95 Unlawful manufacture, sale, distribution, marking, altering or\n           modification of equipment and devices associated with gaming.\n  A person is guilty of unlawful manufacture, sale, distribution,\nmarking, altering or modification of equipment and devices associated\nwith gaming when if he or she:\n  1. Manufactures, sells or distributes any cards, chips, cheques,\ntokens, dice, vouchers, game or device and he or she knew or reasonably\nshould have known it was intended to be used to violate any provision of\nthis article; or\n  2. Marks, alters or otherwise modifies any associated gaming equipment\nor device in a manner that either affects the result of the wager by\ndetermining win or loss or alters the normal criteria of random\nselection in a manner that affects the operation of a game or determines\nthe outcome of a game, and he or she knew or reasonably should have\nknown that it was intended to be used to violate any provision of this\narticle.\n  Unlawful manufacture, sale, distribution, marking, altering or\nmodification of equipment and devices associated with gaming is a class\nA misdemeanor provided, however, that if the person has previously been\nconvicted of this crime within the past five years this crim shall be a\nclass E felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>