<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.55"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.55"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="240.55"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_240_55">
        <num>240.55</num>
        <heading>Falsely reporting an incident in the second degree</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 240.55 Falsely reporting an incident in the second degree.\n  A person is guilty of falsely reporting an incident in the second\ndegree when, knowing the information reported, conveyed or circulated to\nbe false or baseless, he or she:\n  1. Initiates or circulates a false report or warning of an alleged\noccurrence or impending occurrence of a fire, explosion, or the release\nof a hazardous substance under circumstances in which it is not unlikely\nthat public alarm or inconvenience will result;\n  2. Reports, by word or action, to any official or quasi-official\nagency or organization having the function of dealing with emergencies\ninvolving danger to life or property, an alleged occurrence or impending\noccurrence of a fire, explosion, or the release of a hazardous substance\nwhich did not in fact occur or does not in fact exist; or\n  3. Knowing the information reported, conveyed or circulated to be\nfalse or baseless and under circumstances in which it is likely public\nalarm or inconvenience will result, he or she initiates or circulates a\nreport or warning of an alleged occurrence or an impending occurrence of\na fire, an explosion, or the release of a hazardous substance upon any\nprivate premises.\n  Falsely reporting an incident in the second degree is a class E\nfelony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>