<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.63"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.63"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="240.63"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.63/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.63/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.63/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.63/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_240_63">
        <num>240.63</num>
        <heading>Placing a false bomb or hazardous substance in a sports stadium or arena, mass transportation facility or enclosed shopping mall</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 240.63 Placing a false bomb or hazardous substance in a sports stadium\n           or arena, mass transportation facility or enclosed shopping\n           mall.\n  A person is guilty of placing a false bomb or hazardous substance in a\nsports stadium or arena, mass transportation facility or enclosed\nshopping mall when he or she places, or causes to be placed, in a sports\nstadium or arena, mass transportation facility or enclosed shopping\nmall, in which it is likely that persons are present, any device or\nobject that by its design, construction, content or characteristics\nappears to be or to contain a bomb, destructive device, explosive or\nhazardous substance, but is, in fact, an inoperative facsimile or\nimitation of such a bomb, destructive device, explosive or hazardous\nsubstance and which he or she knows, intends or reasonably believes will\nappear to be a bomb, destructive device, explosive or hazardous\nsubstance under circumstances in which it is likely to cause public\nalarm or inconvenience. For purposes of this section, "sports stadium or\narena, mass transportation facility or enclosed shopping mall" shall\nhave its natural meaning.\n  Placing a false bomb or hazardous substance in a sports stadium or\narena, mass transportation facility or enclosed shopping mall is a class\nD felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>