<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.32"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.32"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="240.32"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.32/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-240.32/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_240_32">
        <num>240.32</num>
        <heading>Aggravated harassment of an employee by an incarcerated individual</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 240.32 Aggravated harassment of an employee by an incarcerated\n           individual.\n  An incarcerated individual or respondent is guilty of aggravated\nharassment of an employee by an incarcerated individual when, with\nintent to harass, annoy, threaten or alarm a person in a facility whom\nhe or she knows or reasonably should know to be an employee of such\nfacility or the board of parole or the office of mental health, or a\nprobation department, bureau or unit or a police officer, he or she\ncauses or attempts to cause such employee to come into contact with\nblood, seminal fluid, urine, feces, or the contents of a toilet bowl, by\nthrowing, tossing or expelling such fluid or material.\n  For purposes of this section, "incarcerated individual" means an\nincarcerated individual or detainee in a correctional facility, local\ncorrectional facility or a hospital, as such term is defined in\nsubdivision two of section four hundred of the correction law. For\npurposes of this section, "respondent" means a juvenile in a secure\nfacility operated and maintained by the office of children and family\nservices who is placed with or committed to the office of children and\nfamily services. For purposes of this section, "facility" means a\ncorrectional facility or local correctional facility, hospital, as such\nterm is defined in subdivision two of section four hundred of the\ncorrection law, or a secure facility operated and maintained by the\noffice of children and family services.\n  Aggravated harassment of an employee by an incarcerated individual is\na class E felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>