<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.01-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.01-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-11-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="265.01-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.01-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.01-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.01-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-265.01-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_265_01_A">
        <num>265.01-A</num>
        <heading>Criminal possession of a weapon on school grounds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 265.01-a Criminal possession of a weapon on school grounds.\n  A person is guilty of criminal possession of a weapon on school\ngrounds when he or she knowingly has in his or her possession a rifle,\nshotgun, or firearm in or upon a building or grounds, used for\neducational purposes, of any school, college, or university, except the\nforestry lands, wherever located, owned, maintained or held in trust for\nthe benefit of the New York State College of Forestry at Syracuse\nUniversity, now known as the State University of New York college of\nenvironmental science and forestry, or upon a school bus as defined in\nsection one hundred forty-two of the vehicle and traffic law, without\nthe written authorization of such educational institution; provided,\nhowever no school, as defined in subdivision ten of section eleven\nhundred twenty-five of the education law, shall issue such written\nauthorization to any teacher, school administrator, or other person\nemployed at the school who is not primarily employed as a school\nresource officer, police officer, peace officer, or security guard who\nhas been issued a special armed guard registration card as defined in\nsection eighty-nine-f of the general business law, regardless of whether\nthe person is employed directly by such school or by a third party.\n  Criminal possession of a weapon on school grounds is a class E felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>