<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-400.01"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-400.01"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-09-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="400.01"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-400.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-400.01/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-400.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-400.01/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_400_01">
        <num>400.01</num>
        <heading>License to carry and possess firearms for retired sworn members of the division of state police</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 400.01 License to carry and possess firearms for retired sworn members\n               of the division of state police.\n  1. A license to carry or possess a firearm or to purchase or take\npossession of a semiautomatic rifle for a retired sworn member of the\ndivision of state police shall be granted in the same manner and upon\nthe same terms and conditions as licenses issued under section 400.00 of\nthis article provided, however, that applications for such license may\nbe made to, and the licensing officer may be, the superintendent of\nstate police.\n  2. For purposes of this section, a "retired sworn member of the\ndivision of state police" shall mean a former sworn member of the\ndivision of state police, who upon separation from the division of state\npolice was immediately entitled to receive retirement benefits under the\nprovisions of the retirement and social security law.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall only apply to license\napplications made or renewals which must be made on or after the\neffective date of this section. A license to carry or possess a pistol\nor revolver or to purchase or take possession of a semiautomatic rifle\nissued pursuant to the provisions of section 400.00 of this article to a\nperson covered by the provisions of this section shall be valid until\nsuch license would have expired pursuant to the provisions of section\n400.00 of this article; provided that, on or after the effective date of\nthis section, an application or renewal of such license shall be made\npursuant to the provisions of this section.\n  4. Except for the designation of the superintendent of state police as\nthe licensing officer for retired sworn members of the division of state\npolice who have opted to obtain such license under this section, all of\nthe provisions and requirements of section 400.00 of this article and\nany other provision of law shall be applicable to individuals licensed\npursuant to this section. In addition all provisions of section 400.00\nof this article, except for the designation of the superintendent of\nstate police as licensing officer are hereby deemed applicable to\nindividuals licensed pursuant to this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>