<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="405.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-405.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_405_00">
        <num>405.00</num>
        <heading>Permits for public displays of fireworks</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The name of the body sponsoring the display and the names of the\npersons actually to be in charge of the firing of the display who shall\npossess a valid certificate of competence as a pyrotechnician as\nrequired under the general business law and article sixteen of the labor\nlaw. The permit application shall further contain a verified statement\nfrom the applicant identifying the individuals who are authorized to\nfire the display including their certificate numbers, and that such\nindividuals possess a valid certificate of competence as a\npyrotechnician.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The date and time of day at which the display is to be held.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The exact location planned for the display.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The number and kind of fireworks to be discharged.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The manner and place of storage of such fireworks prior to the\ndisplay.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A diagram of the grounds on which the display is to be held\nshowing the point at which the fireworks are to be discharged, the\nlocation of all buildings, highways and other lines of communication,\nthe lines behind which the audience will be restrained and the location\nof all nearby trees, telegraph or telephone lines or other overhead\nobstructions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such other information as the permit authority may deem necessary\nto protect persons or property.\n  3. Applications for permits. All applications for permits for the\ndisplay of fireworks shall be made at least five days in advance of the\ndate of the display and the permit shall contain provisions that the\nactual point at which the fireworks are to be fired be in accordance\nwith the rules promulgated by the commissioner of labor pursuant to\nsection four hundred sixty-two of the labor law and that all the persons\nin actual charge of firing the fireworks shall be over the age of\neighteen years, competent and physically fit for the task, that there\nshall be at least two such operators constantly on duty during the\ndischarge and that at least two approved type fire extinguishers shall\nbe kept at as widely separated points as possible within the actual area\nof the display. For any applications made for the display of fireworks\non state property, the state fire administrator shall coordinate the\nissuance of such permits with the head of the police or fire department\nor both, where there are such departments. The legislative body of a\ncounty park, city, village or town may provide for approval of such\npermit by the head of the police or fire department or both where there\nare such departments. No permit granted and issued hereunder shall be\ntransferable. After such permit shall have been granted, sales,\npossession, use and distribution of fireworks for such display shall be\nlawful solely therefor.\n  3-a. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision three of this\nsection, no permit may be issued to conduct a display of fireworks upon\nany property where the boundary line of such property is less than five\nhundred yards from the boundary line of any property which is owned,\nleased or operated by any breeder as defined in subdivision four of\nsection two hundred fifty-one of the racing, pari-mutuel wagering and\nbreeding law.\n  4. Bonds. Before gran...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All local ordinances regulating or\nprohibiting the display of fireworks are hereby superseded by the\nprovisions of this section. Every city, town or village shall have the\npower to enact ordinances or local laws regulating or prohibiting the\nuse, or the storage, transportation or sale for use of fireworks in the\npreparation for or in connection with television broadcasts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, a county may\nenact a local law to prohibit the sale and use of "sparkling devices",\nas such term is defined in section 270.00 of this chapter, provided,\nhowever, any such local law shall not establish:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an offense greater than a violation for a person who shall use,\nexplode or cause to be exploded a sparkling device; or\n  (ii) an offense greater than a class B misdemeanor for a person who\nshall offer or expose for sale, sell or furnish a sparkling device\nvalued at less than five hundred dollars unless such offer, sale or\nfurnishing is to a person less than eighteen years of age.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, any city wholly\ncontained within the county of Orange may enact a local law to prohibit\nthe sale and use of "sparkling devices" as defined in section 270.00 of\nthis chapter, in accordance with subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_405_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, notwithstanding that such county has not\nenacted a local law to prohibit the sale and use of such sparkling\ndevices.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>