<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-410.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-410.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-410.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-410.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-410.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-410.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_00">
        <num>410.00</num>
        <heading>Seizure and forfeiture of equipment used in photographing, filming, producing, manufacturing, projecting or distributing pornographic sti...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>personally on the owners of the seized property or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nby registered mail to the owners' last known address and by publication\nof the notice once a week for two successive weeks in a newspaper\npublished or circulated in the county wherein the seizure was made.\n  5. Forfeiture shall not be adjudged where the owners established by\npreponderance of the evidence that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the use of such seized property\nwas not intentional on the part of any owner, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>said seized\nproperty was used by any person other than an owner thereof, while such\nseized property was unlawfully in the possession of a person who\nacquired possession thereof in violation of the criminal laws of the\nUnited States, or of any state.\n  6. The district attorney or the police department having custody of\nthe seized property, after such judicial determination of forfeiture,\nshall, by a public notice of at least five days, sell such forfeited\nproperty at public sale. The net proceeds of any such sale, after\ndeduction of the lawful expenses incurred, shall be paid into the\ngeneral fund of the county wherein the seizure was made except that the\nnet proceeds of the sale of property seized in the cities of New York\nand Buffalo shall be paid into the respective general funds of such\ncities.\n  7. Whenever any person interested in any property which is seized and\ndeclared forfeited under the provisions of this section files with a\njustice of the supreme court a petition for the recovery of such\nforfeited property, the justice of the supreme court may restore said\nforfeited property upon such terms and conditions as he deems reasonable\nand just, if the petitioner establishes either of the affirmative\ndefenses set forth in subdivision five of this section and that the\npetitioner was without personal or actual knowledge of the forfeiture\nproceeding.  If the petition be filed after the sale of the forfeited\nproperty, any judgment in favor of the petitioner shall be limited to\nthe net proceeds of such sale, after deduction of the lawful expenses\nand costs incurred by the district attorney, police department or\ncorporation counsel.\n  8. No suit or action under this section for wrongful seizure shall be\ninstituted unless such suit or action is commenced within two years\nafter the time when the property was seized.\n  9. For the purposes of this section only, a pornographic still or\nmotion picture, is defined as a still or motion picture s...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>