<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-420.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-420.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="420.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-420.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-420.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-420.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-420.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_420_00">
        <num>420.00</num>
        <heading>Seizure and destruction of unauthorized recordings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 420.00 Seizure and destruction of unauthorized recordings.\n  Any article produced in violation of article two hundred seventy-five\nof this chapter may be seized by any police officer upon the arrest of\nany individual in possession of same. Upon final determination of the\ncharges, the court shall, upon proper notice by the district attorney or\nrepresentative of the crime victim or victims, after prior notice to the\ndistrict attorney and custodian of the seized property, enter an order\npreserving any goods manufactured, sold, offered for sale, distributed\nor produced in violation of this article, as evidence for use in other\ncases, including a civil action. This notice must be received within\nthirty days of final determination of the charges. The cost of storage,\nsecurity, and destruction of goods so ordered for preservation and use\nas evidence in a civil action, other than a civil action under article\nthirteen-A of the civil practice law and rules initiated by the district\nattorney, shall be paid by the party seeking preservation of the\nevidence for a civil action. If no such order is entered within the\nthirty day period, the district attorney or custodian of the seized\nproperty must cause such articles to be destroyed. Destruction shall not\ninclude auction, sale, or distribution of the items in their original\nform.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>