<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-470.25"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-470.25"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="470.25"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-470.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-470.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-470.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-470.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_470_25">
        <num>470.25</num>
        <heading>Money laundering; fines</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 470.25 Money laundering; fines.\n  1. Any person convicted of a violation of section 470.05, 470.10,\n470.15, or 470.20 of this article may be sentenced to pay a fine not in\nexcess of two times the value of the monetary instruments which are the\nproceeds of specified criminal activity. When a fine is imposed pursuant\nto this subdivision, the court shall make a finding as to the value of\nsuch monetary instrument or instruments. If the record does not contain\nsufficient evidence to support such a finding the court may conduct a\nhearing upon the issue. In imposing a fine, the court shall consider the\nseriousness of the conduct, whether the amount of the fine is\ndisproportionate to the conduct in which he engaged, its impact on\nvictims, as well as the economic circumstances of the convicted person,\nincluding the effect of the imposition of such a fine upon his immediate\nfamily.\n  2. The imposition of a fine pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection or paragraph b of subdivision one of section 80.00 of this\nchapter, shall preclude the imposition of any other order or judgment of\nforfeiture or fine based upon the same criminal conduct.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>