<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="70.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_70_00">
        <num>70.00</num>
        <heading>Sentence of imprisonment for felony</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For a class A felony, the term shall be life imprisonment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For a class B felony, the term shall be fixed by the court, and\nshall not exceed twenty-five years;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For a class C felony, the term shall be fixed by the court, and\nshall not exceed fifteen years;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For a class D felony, the term shall be fixed by the court, and\nshall not exceed seven years; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For a class E felony, the term shall be fixed by the court, and\nshall not exceed four years.\n  3. Minimum period of imprisonment. The minimum period of imprisonment\nunder an indeterminate sentence shall be at least one year and shall be\nfixed as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the case of a class A felony, the minimum period shall be fixed\nby the court and specified in the sentence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For a class A-I felony, such minimum period shall not be less than\nfifteen years nor more than twenty-five years; provided, however, that\n(A) where a sentence, other than a sentence of death or life\nimprisonment without parole, is imposed upon a defendant convicted of\nmurder in the first degree as defined in section 125.27 of this chapter\nsuch minimum period shall be not less than twenty years nor more than\ntwenty-five years, and, (B) where a sentence is imposed upon a defendant\nconvicted of murder in the second degree as defined in subdivision five\nof section 125.25 of this chapter or convicted of aggravated murder as\ndefined in section 125.26 of this chapter, the sentence shall be life\nimprisonment without parole, and, (C) where a sentence is imposed upon a\ndefendant convicted of attempted murder in the first degree as defined\nin article one hundred ten of this chapter and subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, (ii) or\n(iii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one and paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section 125.27 of this chapter or attempted\naggravated murder as defined in article one hundred ten of this chapter\nand section 125.26 of this chapter such minimum period shall be not less\nthan twenty years nor more than forty years.\n  (ii) For a class A-II felony, such minimum period shall not be less\nthan three years nor more than eight years four months, except that for\nthe class A-II felony of predatory sexual assault as defined in section\n130.95 of this chapter or the class A-II felony of predatory sexual\nassault against a child as defined in section 130.96 of this chapter,\nsuch minimum period shall be not less than ten years nor more than\ntwenty-five years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_00__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For any other felony, the minimum period shall be fixed by the\ncourt and specified in the sentence and shall be not less than one year\nnor more than one-third of the maximum term imposed.\n  4. Alternative definite sentence for class D and E felonies. When a\nperson, other than a second or persistent felony offender, is sentenced\nfor a class D or class E felony, and the court, having regard to the\nnature and circumstances of the crime and to the history and character\nof the defendant, is of the opinion that a sentence of imprisonment is\nnecessary but that it would be unduly harsh to impose an indeterminate\nor determinate sentence, the court may impose a definite sentence of\nimprisonment and fix a term of one year or less.\n  5. Life imprisonment without parole. Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of law, a defendant sentenced to life imprisonment without\nparole shall not be or become eligible for parole or conditional\nrelease. For purposes of commitment and custody, other than parole and\nconditional release, such sentence shall be deemed to be an\nindeterminate sentence. A defendant may be sentenced to life\nimprisonment without parole upon conviction for the crime of murder in\nthe first degree as defined in section 125.27 of this chapter and in\naccordance with the procedures provided by law for imposing a sentence\nfor such crime. A defendant who was eighteen years of age or older at\nthe time of the commission of the crime must be sentenced to life\nimprisonment without parole upon conviction for the crime of terrorism\nas defined in section 490.25 of this chapter, where the specified\noffense the defendant committed is a class A-I felony; the crime of\ncriminal possession of a chemical weapon or biological weapon in the\nfirst degree as defined in section 490.45 of this chapter; or the crime\nof criminal use of a chemical weapon or biological weapon in the first\ndegree as defined in section 490.55 of this chapter; provided, however,\nthat nothing i...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>