<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.35"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.35"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="70.35"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-70.35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_70_35">
        <num>70.35</num>
        <heading>Merger of certain definite and indeterminate or determinate sentences</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_35__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision five of section 70.25 of this article. A person who is\nserving a definite sentence at the time an indeterminate or determinate\nsentence is imposed shall be delivered to the custody of the state\ndepartment of corrections and community supervision to commence service\nof the indeterminate or determinate sentence immediately unless the\nperson is serving a definite sentence pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_35__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision five of section 70.25 of this article. In any case where the\nindeterminate or determinate sentence is revoked or vacated, the person\nshall receive credit against the definite sentence for each day spent in\nthe custody of the state department of corrections and community\nsupervision.\n  * NB Effective until September 1, 2027\n* ยง 70.35 Merger of certain definite and indeterminate sentences.\n  The service of an indeterminate sentence of imprisonment shall satisfy\nany definite sentence of imprisonment imposed on a person for an offense\ncommitted prior to the time the indeterminate sentence was imposed,\nexcept as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_35__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of section 70.25\nof this article. A person who is serving a definite sentence at the time\nan indeterminate sentence is imposed shall be delivered to the custody\nof the state department of corrections and community supervision to\ncommence service of the indeterminate sentence immediately unless the\nperson is serving a definite sentence pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_35__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision five of section 70.25 of this article. In any case where the\nindeterminate sentence is revoked or vacated, the person shall receive\ncredit against the definite sentence for each day spent in the custody\nof the state department of corrections and community supervision.\n  * NB Effective September 1, 2027\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>