<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.05"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.05"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="80.05"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-80.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_80_05">
        <num>80.05</num>
        <heading>Fines for misdemeanors and violation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 80.05 Fines for misdemeanors and violation.\n  1. Class A misdemeanor. A sentence to pay a fine for a class A\nmisdemeanor shall be a sentence to pay an amount, fixed by the court,\nnot exceeding one thousand dollars, provided, however, that a sentence\nimposed for a violation of section 215.80 of this chapter may include a\nfine in an amount equivalent to double the value of the property\nunlawfully disposed of in the commission of the crime.\n  2. Class B misdemeanor. A sentence to pay a fine for a class B\nmisdemeanor shall be a sentence to pay an amount, fixed by the court,\nnot exceeding five hundred dollars.\n  3. Unclassified misdemeanor. A sentence to pay a fine for an\nunclassified misdemeanor shall be a sentence to pay an amount, fixed by\nthe court, in accordance with the provisions of the law or ordinance\nthat defines the crime.\n  4. Violation. A sentence to pay a fine for a violation shall be a\nsentence to pay an amount, fixed by the court, not exceeding two hundred\nfifty dollars.\n  In the case of a violation defined outside this chapter, if the amount\nof the fine is expressly specified in the law or ordinance that defines\nthe offense, the amount of the fine shall be fixed in accordance with\nthat law or ordinance.\n  5. Alternative sentence. If a person has gained money or property\nthrough the commission of any misdemeanor or violation then upon\nconviction thereof, the court, in lieu of imposing the fine authorized\nfor the offense under one of the above subdivisions, may sentence the\ndefendant to pay an amount, fixed by the court, not exceeding double the\namount of the defendant's gain from the commission of the offense;\nprovided, however, that the amount fixed by the court pursuant to this\nsubdivision upon a conviction under section 11-1904 of the environmental\nconservation law shall not exceed five thousand dollars.  In such event\nthe provisions of subdivisions two and three of section 80.00 shall be\napplicable to the sentence.\n  6. Exception. The provisions of this section shall not apply to a\ncorporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>