<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PEN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="85.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="PEN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pen/section-85.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_85_15">
        <num>85.15</num>
        <heading>Subsequent sentences</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 85.15 Subsequent sentences.\n  * 1. Indeterminate and determinate sentences. The service of an\nindeterminate or a determinate sentence of imprisonment shall satisfy\nany sentence of intermittent imprisonment imposed on a person for an\noffense committed prior to the time the indeterminate or determinate\nsentence was imposed. A person who is serving a sentence of intermittent\nimprisonment at the time an indeterminate or a determinate sentence of\nimprisonment is imposed shall be delivered to the custody of the state\ndepartment of corrections and community supervision to commence service\nof the indeterminate or determinate sentence immediately.\n  * NB Effective until September 1, 2027\n  * 1. Indeterminate and reformatory sentences. The service of an\nindeterminate or a reformatory sentence of imprisonment shall satisfy\nany sentence of intermittent imprisonment imposed on a person for an\noffense committed prior to the time the indeterminate or reformatory\nsentence was imposed. A person who is serving a sentence of intermittent\nimprisonment at the time an indeterminate or a reformatory sentence of\nimprisonment is imposed shall be delivered to the custody of the state\ndepartment of corrections and community supervision to commence service\nof the indeterminate or reformatory sentence immediately.\n  * NB Effective September 1, 2027\n  2. Definite sentences. If a definite sentence of imprisonment is\nimposed on a person who is under a previously imposed sentence of\nintermittent imprisonment, such person shall commence service of the\ndefinite sentence immediately. Where such definite sentence is for a\nterm in excess of thirty days, the service of such sentence shall\nsatisfy the sentence of intermittent imprisonment unless the sentence of\nintermittent imprisonment is revoked, or a warrant is issued pursuant to\nsubdivision three of section 85.10 of this article and prior to\nsatisfaction of, or conditional release under, such definite sentence of\nimprisonment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>