<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="100"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_100">
        <num>100</num>
        <heading>Legislative intent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 100. Legislative intent. The legislature finds and determines that\nthe gaming industries constitute a vital sector of New York state's\noverall economy. The legislature also finds and determines that\nresponsive, effective, innovative, state gaming regulation is necessary\nto operate in a global, evolving and increasingly competitive market\nplace. The legislature additionally finds and determines that this\nlegislation is necessary to modernize and transform the present state\ngaming agencies into a new integrated state gaming commission.\n  The continued growth of the gaming industry will contribute to\neconomic development and job creation in this state. Therefore, it is\nessential to maintain the public confidence and trust in the credibility\nand integrity of legalized gaming activities. To ensure such public\nconfidence and trust, this article provides that the regulation of such\ngaming is to be conducted in the most efficient, transparent and\neffective manner possible. By consolidating various regulatory functions\ninto a single oversight body with broad powers, this article ensures\nstrict state regulation of all corporations, associations and persons\nengaged in gaming activity. Further, by consolidating regulatory\nfunctions into a single oversight body, this article will increase\nefficiency, reduce costs and eliminate any unnecessary redundancies in\nregulation. The improved regulatory structure established by this\narticle will ensure, so far as practicable, the exclusion of unsuitable\npersons or entities from participating in any legalized gaming activity\nwithin this state. The goal of this article is that all gaming activity\nconducted in this state will be of the highest integrity, credibility\nand quality and that the best interests of the public, both gaming and\nnon-gaming, will be served. Additionally, during the term of appointment\nor employment, every member, officer and employee of the commission\nshall be held to the highest ethical standards and avoid any conflict of\ninterest or appearance thereof. Finally, it is determined by the\nlegislature that the public interest is best served by those persons or\nentities engaged in gaming activity paying the cost of regulating such\nactivity through reasonable regulatory fees.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>