<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1000"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1000"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1000"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1000/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1000/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1000/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1000/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1000">
        <num>1000</num>
        <heading>Legislative intent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1000. Legislative intent. The legislature finds that the racing,\nbreeding and pari-mutuel wagering industry is an important sector of the\nagricultural economy of this state, provides substantial revenue for\nstate and local governments, and employs tens of thousands of state\nresidents.\n  The legislature further determines that simulcasting, the simultaneous\ntelecast of live audio and visual signals of horse races on which\npari-mutuel betting is permitted, holds the potential to strengthen and\nfurther these economic contributions and that it is in the best interest\nof the state to encourage experimentation with such live telecasts.\n  The purpose of such experimentation shall be to determine if that\ntechnology can promote the overall growth of the industry resulting in\nadditional revenues for the support of the racing associations and\ncorporations, purses, breeders, off-track betting corporations, labor\nand government.\n  No simulcasts shall be authorized which jeopardize present racing or\nemployment opportunities or which infringe on current operations or\nmarkets of the racetracks and the regional off-track betting\ncorporations which generate significant revenues for local governments\nin the state.\n  Accordingly, the legislature hereby authorizes experimentation with\nthe telecasts of horse races, on which pari-mutuel wagering shall be\npermitted, under the regulation of the commission in the manner and\nsubject to the conditions provided in this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>