<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1001"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1001">
        <num>1001</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1001. Definitions. As used in this article, in addition to the\ndefinitions set forth in section one hundred one of this chapter, the\nfollowing terms shall have the following meanings:\n  a. "Simulcast" means the telecast of live audio and visual signals of\nrunning, harness or quarter horse races for the purposes of pari-mutuel\nwagering;\n  b. "Track" means the grounds or enclosures within which horse races\nare conducted by any person, association or corporation lawfully\nauthorized to conduct such races in accordance with the terms and\nconditions of this chapter or the laws of another jurisdiction;\n  c. "Sending track" means any track from which simulcasts originate;\n  d. "Receiving track" means any track where simulcasts originated from\nanother track are displayed;\n  e. "Applicant" means any association, corporation or business entity\napplying for a simulcast license in accordance with the provisions of\nthis article;\n  f. "Operator" means any association, corporation or business entity\noperating a simulcast facility in accordance with the provisions of this\narticle;\n  g. "Regional track or tracks" means any or all tracks located within a\nregion defined as an off-track betting region, except that for the\npurposes of section one thousand eight of this article any track located\nin New York city, or Nassau, Suffolk and Westchester counties, shall be\ndeemed a regional track for all regions located in district one, as\ndefined in this section;\n  h. "Branch office" means an establishment maintained and operated by\nan off-track betting corporation, where off-track pari-mutuel betting on\nhorse races may be placed in accordance with the terms and conditions of\nthis chapter and rules and regulations issued pursuant thereto;\n  i. "Simulcast facility" means those facilities within the state that\nare authorized pursuant to the provisions of this article to display\nsimulcasts for pari-mutuel wagering purposes;\n  j. "Off-track betting region" means those regions as defined in\nsection five hundred nineteen of this chapter;\n  k. "Simulcast theater" means a simulcast facility that is also a\npublic entertainment and wagering facility, which may include any or all\nof the following: a large-screen television projection and display unit,\na display system for odds, pools, and payout prices, areas for viewing\nand seating, a food and beverage facility, and any other convenience\ncurrently provided at racetracks and not inconsistent with local zoning\nordinances;\n  l. "Simulcast districts" means one or more of the following named\ndistricts comprising the counties within which pari-mutuel racing events\nare conducted as follows:\n    District 1                    New York City, Suffolk, Nassau, and\n                                    Westchester counties\n    District 2                    Sullivan county\n    District 3                    Saratoga county\n    District 4                    Oneida county\n    District 5                    Erie, Genesee and Ontario counties\n  m. "Initial out-of-state thoroughbred track" means the track\ncommencing full-card simulcasting to New York prior to any other\nout-of-state thoroughbred track after 1:00 PM on any calendar day.\n  n. "Second out-of-state thoroughbred track" means the track (or\nsubsequent track or tracks where otherwise authorized by this article)\nconducting full-card simulcasting to New York after the race program\nfrom the initial out-of-state thoroughbred track that has commenced\nsimulcasting on any calendar day.\n  o. "Mixed meeting" means a race meeting that has a combination of\nthoroughbred, quarter horse, Appaloosa, paint, and/or Arabian racing on\nthe same race program.\n  p. "Account wagering" means a form of pari-mutuel wagering in which a\nperson establishes an account with an account wagering licensee and\nsubsequently communicates via telephone or other electronic media to the\naccount wagering licensee wagering instructions concerning the funds in\nsuch person's account and wagers to be placed on the account owner's\nbehalf.\n  q. "Account wagering licensee" means racing associations, and\ncorporations; franchised corporations, off-track betting corporations,\nand commission-approved multi-jurisdictional account wagering providers\nthat have been authorized by the commission to offer account wagering.\n  r. "Dormant account" means an account wagering account held by an\naccount wagering licensee in which there has been no wagering activity\nfor three years.\n  s. "Multi-jurisdictional account wagering provider" means a business\nentity domiciled in a jurisdiction, other than the state of New York,\nthat does not operate either a simulcast facility that is open to the\npublic within the state of New York or a licensed or franchised\nracetrack within the state, but which is licensed by such other\njurisdiction to offer pari-mutuel account wagering on races such\nprovider simulcasts and other races it offers in its wagering menu to\npersons located in or out of the jurisdiction issuing such license.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>