<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1005"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1005"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1005"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1005/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1005/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1005/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1005/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1005">
        <num>1005</num>
        <heading>Power of the commission to impose fines and penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1005. Power of the commission to impose fines and penalties. In\naddition to its power to suspend or revoke licenses granted by it, the\ncommission is hereby authorized and empowered to impose monetary fines\nupon any corporation, association or person participating in any way in\nsimulcasts on which pari-mutuel betting is conducted, other than as a\npatron, and whether licensed by the commission or not, for a violation\nof any provision of this chapter or the rules promulgated by the\ncommission pursuant thereto, not exceeding the amounts set forth in\nsection one hundred sixteen of this chapter. The commission is further\nauthorized and empowered to impose monetary fines, not exceeding the\namounts set forth in section one hundred sixteen of this chapter, upon\nany such corporation, association or person for a violation of any order\nissued by the commission pursuant to the provisions of this chapter or\nthe rules promulgated by the commission pursuant thereto, provided that\na copy of such order shall have been served, either personally or by\nregistered mail, upon the corporation, association or person to whom the\nsame was directed, prior to the occurrence of the violation for which\nsuch fine is imposed. Such fines shall be paid into the state treasury.\nThe action of the board in imposing any monetary fine shall be\nreviewable in the supreme court in the manner provided by and subject to\nthe provisions of article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and\nrules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>