<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1007"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1007"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1007"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1007">
        <num>1007</num>
        <heading>Simulcasts track to track</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1007__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Of the sums retained by a receiving track located in\nWestchester County, two and one-half percent of total pools shall be\nused exclusively for increasing purses to be awarded at races conducted\nby such receiving track.\n  (ii) Of the sums retained by other receiving tracks while such tracks\nare conducting a race meeting, fifty percent of the net amounts\nremaining after payments required in this section and fifty percent of\nthe net amounts derived from all simulcasting authorized by chapter two\nhundred eighty-one of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-four and other\nsuch direct expenses as are necessary to provide the track-to-track\nprogram but excluding charges for depreciation, administration overhead\nexpenses, taxes not directly related to such program and management fees\nshall be used exclusively for increasing purses awarded at races\nconducted by such receiving track. Nothing in this section shall\npreclude the right of a horsemen's organization representing owners and\ntrainers at the receiving track from entering into an agreement with\nsuch receiving track to provide for an audit or other such verification\nof such net amounts available for purses.\n  (iii) Of the sums retained by a receiving track located in Westchester\ncounty on races received from a franchised corporation, for the period\ncommencing January first, two thousand eight and continuing through June\nthirtieth, two thousand twenty-six, the amount used exclusively for\npurses to be awarded at races conducted by such receiving track shall be\ncomputed as follows: of the sums so retained, two and one-half percent\nof the total pools. Such amount shall be increased or decreased in the\namount of fifty percent of the difference in total commissions\ndetermined by comparing the total commissions available after July\ntwenty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-five to the total commissions that\nwould have been available to such track prior to July twenty-first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-five.\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>