<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1012-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1012-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1012-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1012-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1012-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1012-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1012-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1012_A">
        <num>1012-A</num>
        <heading>Multi-jurisdictional account wagering providers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1012_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pay a market origin fee equal to five and forty-five hundredths\npercent on each wager accepted from New York residents.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1012_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pay an additional fee equal to one percent on each wager accepted\nfrom New York residents which shall be directed to the general fund of\nthe state treasury.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1012_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make the required payments to the market origin account on or\nbefore the fifth business day of each month and such required payments\nshall cover payments due for the period of the preceding calendar month;\nprovided, however, that such payments required to be made on April\nfifteenth shall be accompanied by a report under oath, showing the total\nof all such payments, together with such other information as the\ncommission may require. A penalty of five percent and interest at the\nrate of one percent per month from the date the report is required to be\nfiled to the date the payment shall be payable in case any payments\nrequired by this subdivision are not paid when due. If the commission\ndetermines that any moneys received under this subdivision were paid in\nerror, the commission may cause the same to be refunded without interest\nout of any moneys collected thereunder, provided an application therefor\nis filed with the commission within one year from the time the erroneous\npayment was made. The commission shall pay into the racing regulation\naccount, under the joint custody of the comptroller and the commission,\nthe total amount of the fee collected pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1012_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>