<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1014"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1014"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1014"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1014/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1014/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1014/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1014/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1014">
        <num>1014</num>
        <heading>Simulcasting of out-of-state thoroughbred races</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1014__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition, licensed harness tracks shall receive one and\none-half percent on total handle on races conducted at an out-of-state\nor out-of-country thoroughbred track provided such harness track is\nneither accepting wagers nor displaying the signal from an out-of-state\ntrack.\n  (ii) In those regions in which there is more than one licensed harness\ntrack, if no track is accepting wagers or displaying the live simulcast\nsignal from the out-of-state track, the total sum shall be divided among\nthe tracks in proportion to the ratio the wagers placed on races\nconducted by each track bears to the corporation's total in-region\nharness handle. If one or more tracks are accepting wagers or displaying\nthe live simulcast signal, the total amount shall be divided among those\ntracks not accepting wagers or displaying the simulcast signal for an\nout-of-state track.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The terms used in this section shall have the same applicability\nand meaning as interpreted and applied in sections five hundred\ntwenty-three and five hundred twenty-seven of this chapter.\n  i. Any facility authorized to accept wagers on out-of-state tracks\nshall distribute all sums deposited in any pari-mutuel pool to the\nholders of winning tickets therein, provided such tickets are presented\nfor payment prior to April first of the year following the year of their\npurchase less eighteen percent of the total deposits in pools resulting\nfrom regular bets, less twenty-one percent of the total deposits in\npools resulting from multiple bets, less twenty-six percent of the total\ndeposits in pools resulting from exotic bets, less thirty-six percent of\nthe total deposits in pools resulting from super exotic bets plus the\nbreaks as defined in section two hundred thirty-six of this chapter\nexcept that the retention rates and breaks shall be as prescribed by\nanother state or countr...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Of the sum so retained, the applicable tax rate shall be one and\none-half percent of all such wagers plus fifty percent of the breaks;\nprovided, however, fifty percent of the breaks accruing from off-track\nbetting corporations licensed in accordance with section one thousand\neight of this article and from simulcast theaters licensed in accordance\nwith section one thousand nine of this article, shall be paid to the\nagriculture and New York state horse breeding and development fund and\nto the thoroughbred breeding and development fund, the total of such\npayments to be apportioned fifty percent to each such fund.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Of the sums so retained, one-half of one percent of all wagers\nshall be paid to the New York state thoroughbred breeding and\ndevelopment fund, except that of the sums so retained on such wagers at\nlicensed harness tracks, one-half of one percent shall be paid to the\nagricultural and New York State horse breeding and development fund.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Of the sum so retained, two percent of all wagers shall be paid to\na franchised corporation to be used exclusively for the purpose of\nincreasing purses, including stakes, premiums and prizes, provided\nfurther that such amount shall not exceed the amount paid to such\nnon-profit racing association in nineteen hundred ninety-three from\nwagers placed on out-of-state tracks on a day when no racing was being\nconducted by the non-profit racing association and a racing program was\nbeing conducted by a thoroughbred racing corporation located in the\nstate. The excess, if any, shall be paid to a thoroughbred racing\ncorporation located in the state until August thirty-first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-five and on and after July nineteen, nineteen hundred\nninety-six to be used exclusively for the purpose of increasing purses,\nincluding stakes, premiums and prizes.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any thoroughbred racing corporation or harness racing association\nor corporation or off-track betting corporation authorized pursuant to\nthis section shall pay to the commission as a regulatory fee, which fee\nis hereby levied, six-tenths of one percent of all wagering pools.\n  j.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All wagers authorized by this section shall be combined so as\nto produce common pari-mutuel betting pools for the calculation of odds\nand the determination of payouts from such pools, which payouts shall be\nmade pursuant to the rules of the commission. Every location authorized\nto accept wagers or display simulcasting pursuant to this section shall\nbe subject to all appropriate provisions of this chapter.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every regional off-track betting corporation may simulcast all\nout-of-state races authorized by this section at any licensed simulcast\nfacility except for those facilities located in a thoroughbred special\nbetting district.\n  Facilities located in such special betting district may display the\nsimulcast signal with the permission of the thoroughbred track located\nin such district or if such track displays the signal from an\nout-of-state or out-of-country track.\n  k. The provisions of section five hundred thirty-two of this chapter\nshall apply as follows:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for all wagers placed at facilities licensed to receive such\nout-of-state or out-of-country simulcasts in accordance with section one\nthousand eight of this article, distribution shall first be made in\naccordance with subdivision three-a of section five hundred thirty-two\nof this chapter, and then fifty percent of the remaining amount in\naccordance with paragraph a of subdivision three of section five hundred\nthirty-two of this chapter and the other fifty percent shall be retained\nby such operator for its general purpose.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1014__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>upon application of any facility licensed in accordance with\nsections one thousand seven and one thousand nine of this article, the\ncommission shall authorize the imposition of a sum equal to the amount\nauthorized by section five hundred thirty-two of this chapter which\nshall apply to wagers placed at such facility. Such sums received by\nfacilities licensed in accordance with section one thousand nine of this\narticle shall be retained for the general purpose of the corporation.\nSuch sums received by such facilities licensed in accordance with\nsection one thousand seven of this article shall be distributed as\nfollows:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1014__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fifty percent shall be used exclusively for purses awarded in\nraces conducted by such licensed facility; and\n  (ii) fifty percent shall be retained by such licensed facility for its\ngeneral purposes.\n  2. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the\nacceptance of wagers on races conducted at out-of-state tracks without\nthe display of the live simulcast signal if authorized under any other\nprovision of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>