<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1016"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1016"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1016"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1016/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1016/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1016/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1016/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1016">
        <num>1016</num>
        <heading>Simulcasting of out-of-state thoroughbred races 1</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1016__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such licensed regional harness track shall receive in lieu of any\nother payments on wagers placed at off-track betting facilities outside\nthe special betting district on races conducted by an in-state\nthoroughbred racing corporation, two and eight-tenths percent on regular\nand multiple bets during a regional meeting and one and nine-tenths\npercent of such bets if there is no regional meeting and four and\neight-tenths percent on exotic bets on days on which there is a regional\nmeeting and three and four-tenths percent of such bets if there is no\nregional meeting.\n  (ii) Such licensed regional harness track shall receive one and\none-half percent on total regional handle on races conducted at\nout-of-state or out-of-country thoroughbred tracks.\n  (iii) In those regions in which there is more than one licensed\nregional harness track, if no track is accepting wagers or displaying\nthe live simulcast signal from the out-of-state track, the total sum\nshall be divided among the tracks in proportion to the ratio the wagers\nplaced on races conducted by each track bears to the corporation's total\nin-region harness handle. If one or more tracks are accepting wagers or\ndisplaying the live simulcast signal, the total amount shall be divided\namong those tracks not accepting wagers or displaying the simulcast\nsignal for an out-of-state track or in-state thoroughbred corporation or\nassociation.\n  (F) Of the sums retained by a licensed harness facility, fifty percent\nshall be used exclusively for purses awarded in races conducted by such\nlicensed facility and the remaining fifty percent shall be retained by\nsuch licensed facility for its general purposes, provided, however, that\nin a harness special betting district the portion of the sums retained\nby a licensed harness facility to be used for purses or the methodology\nfor calculating the amount to be used for purses may be specified in a\nwritten contract between a harness racing association or corporation ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1016__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Distribution of wagers placed on other than the initial\nout-of-state thoroughbred track at facilities licensed in accordance\nwith section one thousand seven of this article.\n  (A) Of the sums so retained on days when a franchised corporation is\nnot conducting a race meeting within the state and a thoroughbred racing\ncorporation is conducting a race meeting\n                                                                  Super-\n                                    Regular   Multiple   Exotic   exotic\n                                    bets      bets       bets     bets\nState Tax                           1.00      1.00       1.00     1.00\nNon-franchised\nThoroughbred Racing\ncorporation payments to purses      1.00      1.00       1.00     1.25\nFranchised corporation              0.50      0.50       0.50     0.50\nFranchised corporation\npayments to purses                  1.00      1.00       1.25     2.00\n  (B) Of the sums so retained on days when a franchised corporatio...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1016__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such licensed regional harness track shall receive in lieu of any\nother payments on wagers placed at off-track betting facilities outside\nthe special betting district on races conducted by an in-state\nthoroughbred racing corporation, two and eight-tenths percent on regular\nand multiple bets during a regional meeting and one and nine-tenths\npercent of such bets if there is no regional meeting and four and\neight-tenths percent on exotic bets on days on which there is a regional\nmeeting and three and four-tenths percent of such bets if there is no\nregional meeting.\n  (ii) Such licensed regional harness track shall receive one and\none-half percent on total regional handle on races conducted at\nout-of-state or out-of-country thoroughbred tracks.\n  (iii) In those regions in which there is more than one licensed\nregional harness track, if no track is accepting wagers or displaying\nthe live simulcast signal from the out-of-state track, the total sum\nshall be divided among the tracks in proportion to the ratio the wagers\nplaced on races conducted by each track bears to the corporation's total\nin-region harness handle. If one or more tracks are accepting wagers or\ndisplaying the live simulcast signal, the total amount shall be divided\namong those tracks not accepting wagers or displaying the simulcast\nsignal for an out-of-state track or in-state thoroughbred corporation.\n  (G) Of the sums retained by a licensed harness facility, fifty percent\nshall be used exclusively for purses awarded in races conducted by such\nlicensed facility and the remaining fifty percent shall be retained by\nsuch licensed facility for its general purposes, provided, however, that\nin a harness special betting district the portion of the sums retained\nby a licensed harness facility to be used for purses or the methodology\nfor calculating the amount to be used for purses may be specified in a\nwritten contract between a harness racing association or corporation and\nits represe...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1016__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All wagers authorized by this section shall be combined so as\nto produce common pari-mutuel betting pools, which shall be combined\nwith the sending track, for the calculation of odds and the\ndetermination of payouts from such pools, which payouts shall be made\npursuant to the rules of the commission. Every location authorized to\naccept wagers or display simulcasting pursuant to this section shall be\nsubject to all appropriate provisions of this chapter.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1016__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every regional off-track betting corporation may simulcast all\nout-of-state races authorized by this section at any licensed simulcast\nfacility except for those facilities located in a thoroughbred special\nbetting district. Facilities located in such special betting district\nmay display the simulcast signal with the permission of the thoroughbred\ntrack located in such district or if such track displays the signal from\nan out-of-state or out-of-country track.\n  d. The provisions of section five hundred thirty-two of this chapter\nshall apply as follows:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1016__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for all wagers placed at facilities licensed to receive such\nout-of-state or out-of-country simulcasts in accordance with section one\nthousand eight of this article, distribution shall first be made in\naccordance with subdivision three-a of section five hundred thirty-two\nof this chapter, and then fifty percent of the remaining amount in\naccordance with paragraph a of subdivision three of section five hundred\nthirty-two of this chapter and the other fifty percent shall be retained\nby such operator for its general purpose.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1016__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>upon application of any facility licensed in accordance with\nsections one thousand seven and one thousand nine of this article, the\ncommission shall authorize the imposition of a sum equal to the amount\nauthorized by section five hundred thirty-two of this chapter that\napplies to wagers placed at such facility. Such sums received by\nfacilities licensed in accordance with section one thousand nine of this\narticle shall be retained for the general purpose of the corporation.\nSuch sums received by such facilities licensed in accordance with\nsection one thousand seven of this article shall be distributed as\nfollows:\n  (A) fifty percent shall be used exclusively for purses awarded in\nraces conducted by such licensed facility; and\n  (B) fifty percent shall be retained by such licensed facility for its\ngeneral purposes.\n  e. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the\nacceptance of wagers on races conducted at out-of-state tracks without\nthe display of the live ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>