<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-10-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="102"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_102">
        <num>102</num>
        <heading>New York state gaming commission</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_102__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>significant service as a certified public accountant experienced\nin accounting and auditing,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_102__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a comprehensive knowledge of corporate finance and securities,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_102__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>professional experience in gaming or racing regulatory\nadministration or gaming or racing industry management,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_102__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>significant experience in the fields of criminal investigation,\nlaw enforcement, or law, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_102__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>significant experience in the prevention or treatment of problem\ngambling.\n  3. A member shall be designated as chair of the commission by the\ngovernor to serve in such capacity at the pleasure of the governor or\nuntil his or her term as commission member expires, whichever first\noccurs. The members shall be appointed for terms of five years;\nprovided, however, that initial appointments to the commission shall be\nfor terms as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_102__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one member appointed by the governor shall serve for a one year\nterm, one member appointed by the governor shall serve for a two year\nterm, one member appointed by the governor shall serve for a three year\nterm, one member appointed by the governor shall serve for a four year\nterm, one member appointed by the governor shall serve for a five year\nterm; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_102__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>each of the members appointed by the governor upon the\nrecommendation of the temporary president of the senate and upon the\nrecommendation of the speaker of the assembly shall serve for a four\nyear term.\n  4. The members shall, when performing the work of the commission, be\ncompensated at a rate of three hundred dollars per day, together with an\nallowance for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of\ntheir duties.\n  5. The members of the commission shall not hold any other public\noffice or public employment for which they shall receive compensation,\nother than necessary travel or other expenses incurred in the\nperformance of the duties of such office or employment. Members may\nengage in private employment or in a profession or business, provided,\nhowever, such employment does not interfere or conflict with the\nperformance or proper discharge of his or her duties.\n  6. Each member of the commission shall be a resident of the state of\nNew York. No member of the legislature or person holding any elective or\nappointive office in the federal, state or local government shall be\neligible to serve as a member of the commission.\n  7. The governor may remove any member for inefficiency, neglect of\nduty or misconduct in office after giving him or her a copy of the\ncharges against them, and an opportunity of being heard in person or by\ncounsel in their own defense, upon not less than ten days' notice. If\nsuch member shall be removed, the governor shall file in the office of\nthe department of state a complete statement of charges made against\nsuch member, and his or her findings thereon, together with a complete\nrecord of the proceeding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>