<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-104"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-104"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="104"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-104/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-104/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_104">
        <num>104</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the commission</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_104__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>would identify a confidential source\nor disclose confidential information relating to a criminal\ninvestigation,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>would interfere with law enforcement investigations\nor judicial proceedings,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reveal criminal investigative techniques or\nprocedures, that, if disclosed, could endanger the life or safety of any\nperson, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>constitutes records received from other state, local or\nfederal agencies that the attorney general is prohibited by law,\nregulation or agreement from disclosing.\n  15.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commission shall have the power to appoint such deputies,\nsecretary, officers, representatives and counsel as the commission may\ndeem necessary, who shall be designated to be in the exempt class of\ncivil service. Any newly hired employees who are not designated to be in\nthe exempt class of civil service pursuant to this subdivision and who\nare not subject to the transfer provisions set forth in section one\nhundred eighteen of this article shall be considered for purposes of\narticle fourteen of the civil service law to be public employees in the\ncivil service of the state, and shall be assigned to the appropriate\ncollective bargaining unit. Employees serving in positions in newly\ncreated titles shall be assigned to the same collective bargaining unit\nas they would have been assigned to were such titles created prior to\nthe establishment of the commission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the duty of the secretary to keep a full and faithful\nrecord of the proceedings of the commission, preserve at the general\noffice of the commission all books, maps, documents and papers entrusted\nto his or her care, prepare for service such papers and notices as may\nbe required by the commission, and perform such other duties as the\ncommission may prescribe.\n  16. To operate, or immediately appoint or contract with an independent\nthird party to operate, any video lottery gaming facility subject to\nlicensure by the commission on an interim basis in the event that the\nlicensed operator or operators of such facility discontinues operations\ndue to financial, regulatory or any other circumstances, including, but\nnot limited to, license revocation, relinquishment or expiration, and\nthe commission determines, after notice and an opportunity for hearing,\nthat it would further the public interest to continue such operations.\nSuch operation shall be on a temporary basis, not to exceed one hundred\neighty days, until such time as a permanent operator is licensed and\nauthorized to operate such facility.\n  17. To retain and employ private consultants and agencies on a\ncontract basis for rendering technical or other assistance and advice\nfor the performance of its duties.\n  18. To annually report to the governor, the speaker of the assembly\nand the temporary president of the senate, its proceedings for the\npreceding calendar year and any suggestions and recommendations as it\nshall deem desirable.\n  19. To promulgate any rules and regulations that it deems necessary to\ncarry out its responsibilities.\n  20. The commission shall serve as a host racing commission and an\noff-track betting commission for purposes of 15 U.S.C. 3001, et seq.\n  * 21. Prior to transporting into this state any gambling devices for\nthe purpose of exhibition or marketing, an officer of the manufacturer\nor distributor of the gambling devices shall file with the gaming\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>