<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1106"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1106">
        <num>1106</num>
        <heading>Compact committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1106. Compact committee. a. There is hereby created an interstate\ngovernmental entity known as the compact committee, to be comprised of\none official from the racing commission, or its equivalent, of each\nparty state, who shall be selected, serve, and be removed in accordance\nwith the laws of his or her party state. Each official shall have,\npursuant to the laws of that party state, the assistance of that state's\nracing commission, or its equivalent, in considering issues related to\nlicensing of participants in live racing and in acting as representative\nof that state in the compact committee. Where an official is unable to\nperform any duty in the compact committee, his or her alternate shall\nserve until the original can return to duty, as that party state's\nofficial in the compact committee. Such a designation shall be\ncommunicated by that party state's racing commission, or its equivalent,\nto the compact committee, as required by the applicable by-laws.\n  b. The chair of the state gaming commission shall designate the\nofficial, and his or her alternate, to represent New York state in the\ncompact committee.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>