<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1107"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1107">
        <num>1107</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of compact committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1107. Powers and duties of compact committee. The compact committee\nis hereby granted, to carry out its purposes, the power and duty:\n  a. to determine which categories of participants in live racing, such\nas owners, trainers, jockeys, drivers, grooms, mutuel clerks, racing\nofficials, veterinarians, farriers, or others, shall be licensed by the\ncompact committee, and to establish the term, initial requirements, and\nrenewal requirements for each license category. With regard to obtaining\nand weighing criminal history record information on each applicant, and\nall non-arbitrary other licensure requirements, the compact committee\nshall adopt licensure requirements comparable, in its judgment, to the\nmost restrictive party state's requirements for such a license;\n  b. to investigate license applicants and, as permitted by federal and\nstate law, to gather information, including criminal history records\nfrom the federal bureau of investigation and from state, local, and\nforeign country law enforcement agencies (including the Royal Canadian\nMounted Police), necessary to decide whether an applicant meets its\nlicense requirements. Such criminal history record information may be\nreceived and reviewed only by the officials on, and employees of, the\ncompact committee, and that information may be used only for the\npurposes of this compact. No such official or employee may disclose or\ndisseminate such criminal history record information to any person or\nentity other than another official on, or employee of, the compact\ncommittee. The compact committee, its employees, or its designee shall\ntake the fingerprints of each license applicant and, pursuant to P.L.\n92-544 or P.L. 100-413, forward the fingerprints to a state\nidentification bureau, the Association of Racing Commissioners,\nInternational (an association of state officials regulating pari-mutuel\nwagering, designated by the attorney general of the United States), or\nanother entity with an equivalent designation, for submission to the\nfederal bureau of investigation or other receiving law enforcement\nagency;\n  c. to issue and renew licenses for participants in live racing who are\nfound by the compact committee to have met its licensure or renewal\nrequirements. The compact committee shall not have the power or\nauthority to deny a license. If it determines that an applicant will not\nbe eligible, the compact committee shall notify the applicant that it\nwill not be able to process his or her licensure or renewal application\nany further. That notification shall not constitute, and shall not be\nconsidered to be, the denial of a license. Although such applicant shall\nhave the right to present further evidence and to be heard by the\ncompact committee, after receiving such notification, the final decision\non issuance or renewal of his or her license shall be made by the\ncompact committee pursuant to its established requirements;\n  d. to enter into contracts and agreements with governmental agencies\nand other persons to provide personal services for its activities, and\nsuch other services as may be necessary;\n  e. to create, appoint, and abolish all those offices, employments, and\npositions (including an executive director) useful to fulfill its\npurposes; to prescribe their powers, duties, and qualifications; to hire\npersons therefor; and to provide for their term, tenure, removal,\ncompensation, and fringe and retirement benefits, and other conditions\nof employment;\n  f. to borrow, accept, and contract for the services of personnel from\nany state, federal, or other governmental agency, or from any other\nperson or entity;\n  g. to acquire, hold, and dispose of any real or personal property by\ngift, purchase, lease, license, and similar means;\n  h. to charge and collect a fee, whether for licensure or renewal, from\neach license applicant; and\n  i. to receive additional funds through gifts, grants, and\nappropriations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>