<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-115-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-115-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="115-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-115-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-115-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-115-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-115-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_115_B">
        <num>115-B</num>
        <heading>Market origin credits</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_115_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sixty percent to thoroughbred racing associations and franchised\ncorporations. Five-sixths shall be allocated to a franchised corporation\nand one-sixth shall be allocated to a thoroughbred racing association.\n  (ii) Forty percent to harness racing associations and corporations.\nAllocations to individual harness racing associations and corporations\nshall be made based on a ratio where the numerator is the association's\nor corporation's total in-state handle on live racing for the previous\ncalendar year as calculated by the commission and the denominator is the\ntotal in-state on live handle for all harness racing associations and\ncorporations for the previous calendar year as calculated by the\ncommission.\n  3. As a condition for any racing association or corporation or\nfranchised corporation to claim any market origin credits allocated to\nit, such racing association or corporation or franchised corporation\nmust make payments for moneys otherwise to be used to pay the regulatory\nfee as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_115_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payment of an amount equal to forty percent of the allocated\ncredits into an account used solely for the purpose of enhancing purses\nat such racing association or corporation or franchised corporation.\nSuch payment shall be made within five days from receipt of notification\nof an allocation by the commission of an allocation of market origin\ncredits;\n  (ii) Payment of an amount equal to twenty percent of the allocated\ncredits to the state's breeding funds. Sixty percent of the payments to\nthe breeding funds shall be allocated to the New York state thoroughbred\nbreeding and development fund corporation established pursuant to\nsection two hundred fifty-two of this chapter, and forty percent to the\nagriculture and New York state horse breeding development fund\nestablished pursuant to section three hundred thirty of this chapter.\nSuch payment shall be made within five days from receipt of notification\nof an allocation by the commission of an allocation of market origin\ncredits.\n  4. The commission shall promulgate any rules and regulations necessary\nfor the administration of the market origin credit.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>