<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1309"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1309"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1309"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1309/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1309/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1309/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1309/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1309">
        <num>1309</num>
        <heading>Severability and preemption</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1309. Severability and preemption. 1. If any clause, sentence,\nsubparagraph, paragraph, subdivision, section, article or other portion\nof this article or the application thereof to any person or\ncircumstances shall be held to be invalid, such holding shall not\naffect, impair or invalidate the remainder of this article or the\napplication of such portion held invalid to any other person or\ncircumstances, but shall be confined in its operation to the clause,\nsentence, paragraph, subparagraph, subdivision, section, article or\nother portion thereof directly involved in such holding or to the person\nor circumstance therein involved.\n  2. If any provision of this article is inconsistent with, in conflict\nwith, or contrary to any other provision of law, such provision of this\narticle shall prevail over such other provision and such other provision\nshall be deemed to be superseded to the extent of such inconsistency or\nconflict. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law to the\ncontrary, no local government unit of this state may enact or enforce\nany ordinance or resolution conflicting with any provision of this\narticle or with any policy of this state expressed or implied herein,\nwhether by exclusion or inclusion. The commission shall have exclusive\njurisdiction over all matters delegated to it or within the scope of its\npowers under the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>