<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-131"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-131"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-06-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131">
        <num>131</num>
        <heading>Gaming inspector general; functions and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131. Gaming inspector general; functions and duties. The gaming\ninspector general shall have the following duties and responsibilities:\n  1. receive and investigate complaints from any source, or upon his or\nher own initiative, concerning allegations of corruption, fraud,\ncriminal activity, conflicts of interest or abuse in the commission;\n  2. determine with respect to such allegations whether disciplinary\naction, civil or criminal prosecution, or further investigation by an\nappropriate federal, state or local agency is warranted, and to assist\nin such investigations;\n  3. prepare and release to the public written reports of such\ninvestigations, as appropriate and to the extent permitted by law,\nsubject to redaction to protect the confidentiality of witnesses. The\nrelease of all or portions of such reports may be deferred to protect\nthe confidentiality of ongoing investigations;\n  4. review and examine periodically the policies and procedures of the\ncommission with regard to the prevention and detection of corruption,\nfraud, criminal activity, conflicts of interest or abuse;\n  5. recommend remedial action to prevent or eliminate corruption,\nfraud, criminal activity, conflicts of interest or abuse in the\ncommission;\n  6. establish programs for training commission officers and employees\nin regard to the prevention and elimination of corruption, fraud,\ncriminal activity, conflicts of interest or abuse in the commission; and\n  7. make an annual report to the governor, the comptroller and the\nlegislature concerning its work during the preceding year. Such report\nshall include but not be limited to the number of cases investigated,\nand the number of complaints received. Such initial report shall be due\nno later than the first day of April two thousand twenty-two, and then\nby the first day of April each year thereafter. Such report shall be\nmade public and published on the website of the office of the state\ninspector general and on the website of the commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>