<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-132"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-132"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-06-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="132"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-132/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-132/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-132/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-132/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_132">
        <num>132</num>
        <heading>Powers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 132. Powers. The gaming inspector general shall have the power to:\n  1. subpoena and enforce the attendance of witnesses;\n  2. administer oaths or affirmations and examine witnesses under oath;\n  3. require the production of any books and papers deemed relevant or\nmaterial to any investigation, examination or review;\n  4. notwithstanding any law to the contrary, examine and copy or remove\ndocuments or records of any kind prepared, maintained or held by the\ncommission;\n  5. require any commission officer or employee to answer questions\nconcerning any matter related to the performance of his or her official\nduties. No statement or other evidence derived therefrom may be used\nagainst such officer or employee in any subsequent criminal prosecution\nother than for perjury or contempt arising from such testimony. The\nrefusal of any officer or employee to answer questions shall be cause\nfor removal from office or employment or other appropriate penalty;\n  6. monitor the implementation by the commission of any recommendations\nmade by the state inspector general; and\n  7. perform any other functions that are necessary or appropriate to\nfulfill the duties and responsibilities of the office.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>