<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1322"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1322"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1322"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1322">
        <num>1322</num>
        <heading>General provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1322. General provisions. 1. It shall be the affirmative\nresponsibility of each applicant or licensee to establish by clear and\nconvincing evidence its individual qualifications, and for a gaming\nfacility license the qualifications of each person who is required to be\nqualified under this article.\n  2. Any applicant, licensee, registrant, or any other person who must\nbe qualified pursuant to this article shall provide all legally required\ninformation and satisfy all lawful requests for information pertaining\nto qualification and in the form specified by regulation. All\napplicants, registrants, and licensees shall waive liability as to the\nstate, and its instrumentalities and agents, for any damages resulting\nfrom any disclosure or publication in any manner, other than a willfully\nunlawful disclosure or publication, of any material or information\nacquired during inquiries, investigations or hearings.\n  3. All applicants, licensees, registrants, intermediary companies, and\nholding companies shall consent to inspections, searches and seizures\nwhile at a gaming facility and the supplying of handwriting exemplars as\nauthorized by this article and regulations promulgated hereunder.\n  4. All applicants, licensees, registrants, and any other person who\nshall be qualified pursuant to this article shall have the continuing\nduty to provide any assistance or information required by the\ncommission, and to cooperate in any inquiry, investigation or hearing\nconducted by the commission. If, upon issuance of a formal request to\nanswer or produce information, evidence or testimony, any applicant,\nlicensee, registrant, or any other person who shall be qualified\npursuant to this article refuses to comply, the application, license,\nregistration or qualification of such person may be denied or revoked.\n  5. Each applicant or person who must be qualified under this article\nshall be photographed and fingerprinted for identification and\ninvestigation purposes in accordance with procedures set forth by\nregulation.\n  6. All licensees, all registrants, and all other persons required to\nbe qualified under this article shall have a duty to inform the\ncommission of any action which they believe would constitute a violation\nof this article. No person who so informs the commission shall be\ndiscriminated against by an applicant, licensee or registrant because of\nthe supplying of such information.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>