<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1324"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1324"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1324"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1324/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1324/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1324/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1324/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1324">
        <num>1324</num>
        <heading>Gaming employee registration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1324__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section eight hundred forty-five-b of the executive\nlaw from the state division of criminal justice services and the federal\nbureau of investigation consistent with applicable state and federal\nlaws, rules and regulations. The registrant shall pay the fee for such\ncriminal history information as established pursuant to article\nthirty-five of the executive law. The state division of criminal justice\nservices shall promptly notify the commission in the event a current or\nprospective licensee, who was the subject of a criminal history\ninformation pursuant to this section, is arrested for a crime or offense\nin this state after the date the check was performed.\n  5. Upon receipt of such criminal history information, the Commission\nshall provide such applicant with a copy of such criminal history\ninformation, together with a copy of article twenty-three-A of the\ncorrection law, and inform such applicant of his or her right to seek\ncorrection of any incorrect information contained in such criminal\nhistory information pursuant to regulations and procedures established\nby the division of criminal justice services. Except as otherwise\nprovided by law, such criminal history information shall be confidential\nand any person who willfully permits the release of such confidential\ncriminal history information to persons not permitted to receive such\ninformation shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>