<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1325"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1325"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1325"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1325/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1325/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1325/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1325/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1325">
        <num>1325</num>
        <heading>Approval, denial and renewal of employee licenses and registrations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1325. Approval, denial and renewal of employee licenses and\nregistrations. 1. Upon the filing of an application for a casino key\nemployee license or gaming employee registration required by this\narticle and after submission of such supplemental information as the\ncommission may require, the commission shall conduct or cause to be\nconducted such investigation into the qualification of the applicant,\nand the commission shall conduct such hearings concerning the\nqualification of the applicant, in accordance with its regulations, as\nmay be necessary to determine qualification for such license.\n  2. After such investigation, the commission may either deny the\napplication or grant a license to an applicant whom it determines to be\nqualified to hold such license.\n  3. The commission shall have the authority to deny any application\npursuant to the provisions of this article following notice and\nopportunity for hearing.\n  4. When the commission grants an application, the commission may limit\nor place such restrictions thereupon as it may deem necessary in the\npublic interest.\n  5. After an application for a casino key employee license is\nsubmitted, final action of the commission shall be taken within ninety\ndays after completion of all hearings and investigations and the receipt\nof all information required by the commission.\n  6. Licenses and registrations of casino key employees and gaming\nemployees issued pursuant to this article shall remain valid for five\nyears unless suspended, revoked or voided pursuant to law. Such licenses\nand registrations may be renewed by the holder thereof upon application,\non a form prescribed by the commission, and payment of the applicable\nfee. Notwithstanding the forgoing, if a gaming employee registrant has\nnot been employed in any position within a gaming facility for a period\nof three years, the registration of that gaming employee shall lapse.\n  8. The commission shall establish by regulation appropriate fees to be\npaid upon the filing of the required applications. Such fees shall be\ndeposited into the commercial gaming revenue fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>