<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1328"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1328"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1328"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1328">
        <num>1328</num>
        <heading>Junket operator licensing</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant for licensure is employed by a gaming facility\nlicensee; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant for licensure has filed a completed application as\nrequired by the commission.\n  6. The commission shall have the authority to immediately suspend,\nlimit or condition any temporary license issued pursuant to this\nsection, pending a hearing on the qualifications of the junket\nrepresentative.\n  7. Unless otherwise terminated, any temporary license issued pursuant\nto this section shall expire twelve months from the date of its\nissuance, and shall be renewable by the commission for one additional\nsix month period.\n  8. Every agreement concerning junkets entered into by a gaming\nfacility licensee and a junket representative or junket enterprise shall\nbe deemed to include a provision for its termination without liability\non the part of the gaming facility licensee, if the commission orders\nthe termination upon the suspension, limitation, conditioning, denial or\nrevocation of the licensure of the junket representative or junket\nenterprise. Failure to expressly include such a condition in the\nagreement shall not constitute a defense in any action brought to\nterminate the agreement.\n  9. A gaming facility licensee shall be responsible for the conduct of\nany junket representative or junket enterprise associated with it and\nfor the terms and conditions of any junket engaged in on its premises,\nregardless of the fact that the junket may involve persons not employed\nby such a gaming facility licensee.\n  10. A gaming facility licensee shall be responsible for any violation\nor deviation from the terms of a junket. Notwithstanding any other\nprovisions of this article, the commission may order restitution to\njunket participants, assess penalties for such violations or deviations,\nprohibit future junkets by the gaming facility licensee, junket\nenterprise or junket representative, and order such further relief as it\ndeems appropriate.\n  11. The commission shall, by regulation, prescribe methods, procedures\nand forms for the delivery and re...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Maintain on file a report describing the operation of any junket\nengaged in on its premises; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Submit to the commission a list of all its employees who are\nacting as junket representatives.\n  12. Each gaming facility licensee, junket representative or junket\nenterprise shall, in accordance with the rules of the commission, file a\nreport with the commission with respect to each list of junket patrons\nor potential junket patrons purchased directly or indirectly by the\ngaming facility licensee, junket representative or enterprise.\n  13. The commission shall have the authority to determine, either by\nregulation, or upon petition by the holder of a gaming facility license,\nthat a type of arrangement otherwise included within the definition of\n"junket" shall not require compliance with any or all of the\nrequirements of this section. In granting exemptions, the commission\nshall consider such factors as the nature, volume and significance of\nthe particular type of arrangement, and whether the exemption would be\nconsistent with the public policies established by this article. In\napplying the provisions of this subdivision, the commission may\ncondition, limit, or restrict any exemption as it may deem appropriate.\n  14. No junket enterprise or junket representative or person acting as\na junket representative may:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Engage in efforts to collect upon checks that have been returned\nby banks without full and final payment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Exercise approval authority with regard to the authorization or\nissuance of credit;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Act on behalf of or under any arrangement with a gaming facility\nlicensee or a gaming patron with regard to the redemption,\nconsolidation, or substitution of the gaming patron's checks awaiting\ndeposit;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Individually receive or retain any fee from a patron for the\nprivilege of participating in a junket; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pay for any services, including transportation, or other items of\nvalue provided to, or for the benefit of, any patron participating in a\njunket.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>