<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1331"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1331"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1331"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1331/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1331/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1331/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1331/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1331">
        <num>1331</num>
        <heading>Operation certificate</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1331. Operation certificate. 1. Notwithstanding the issuance of a\nlicense therefor, no gaming facility may be opened or remain open to the\npublic, and no gaming activity, except for test purposes, may be\nconducted therein, unless and until a valid operation certificate has\nbeen issued to the gaming facility licensee by the commission. Such\ncertificate shall be issued by the executive director upon a\ndetermination that a gaming facility complies in all respects with the\nrequirements of this article and regulations promulgated hereunder, and\nthat the gaming facility is prepared in all respects to receive and\nentertain the public.\n  2. An operation certificate shall remain in force and effect unless\nrevoked, suspended, limited, or otherwise altered by the commission in\naccordance with this article.\n  3. It shall be an express condition of continued operation under this\narticle that a gaming facility licensee shall maintain either\nelectronically or in hard copy at the discretion of the gaming facility\nlicensee, copies of all books, records, and documents pertaining to the\nlicensee's operations and approved hotel in a manner and location\napproved by the commission, provided, however, that the originals of\nsuch books, records and documents, whether in electronic or hard copy\nform, may be maintained at the offices or electronic system of an\naffiliate of the gaming facility licensee, at the discretion of the\ngaming facility licensee. All such books, records and documents shall be\nimmediately available for inspection during all hours of operation in\naccordance with the rules of the commission and shall be maintained for\nsuch period of time as the commission shall require.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>