<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1337"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1337"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1337"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1337/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1337/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1337/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1337/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1337">
        <num>1337</num>
        <heading>Gratuities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1337. Gratuities. 1. It shall be unlawful for any casino key\nemployee or boxman, floorman, or any other gaming employee who shall\nserve in a supervisory position to solicit or accept, and for any other\ngaming employee to solicit, any tip or gratuity from any player or\npatron at the gaming facility where he is employed.\n  2. A dealer may accept tips or gratuities from a patron at the table\nat which such dealer is conducting play, subject to the provisions of\nthis section. All such tips or gratuities shall be immediately deposited\nin a lockbox reserved for that purpose, unless the tip or gratuity is\nauthorized by a patron utilizing an automated wagering system approved\nby the commission. All tips or gratuities shall be accounted for, and\nplaced in a pool for distribution pro rata among the dealers, with the\ndistribution based upon the number of hours each dealer has worked,\nexcept that the commission may, by regulation, permit a separate pool to\nbe established for dealers in the game of poker, or may permit tips or\ngratuities to be retained by individual dealers in the game of poker.\n  3. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\na gaming facility licensee may require that a percentage of the prize\npool offered to participants pursuant to an authorized poker tournament\nbe withheld for distribution to the tournament dealers as tips or\ngratuities as the commission by regulation may approve.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>