<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1340"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1340"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1340"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1340/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1340/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1340/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1340/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1340">
        <num>1340</num>
        <heading>Alcoholic beverages</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1340__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To sell any alcoholic beverage by the glass or other open\nreceptacle including, but not limited to, an original container, for\non-premise consumption within a facility; provided, however, that no\nalcoholic beverage shall be sold or given for consumption; delivered or\notherwise brought to a patron; or consumed at a gaming table unless so\nrequested by the patron.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1340__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To sell any alcoholic beverage by the glass or other open\nreceptacle for on-premise consumption within a gaming facility or Indian\ngaming facility.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1340__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To sell any alcoholic beverage by the glass or other open\nreceptacle or in original containers from a room service location within\nan enclosed room not in a gaming facility or Indian gaming facility;\nprovided, however, that any sale of alcoholic beverages is delivered\nonly to a guest room or to any other room in the gaming facility or\nIndian gaming facility authorized by the commission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1340__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To possess or to store alcoholic beverages in original containers\nintended but not actually exposed for sale at a fixed location on a\ngaming facility or Indian gaming facility premises, not in a gaming\nfacility or Indian gaming facility; and to transfer or deliver such\nalcoholic beverages only to a location approved pursuant to this\nsection; provided, however, that no access to or from a storage location\nshall be permitted except during the normal course of business by\nemployees or agents of the licensee, or by licensed employees or agents\nof wholesalers or distributors licensed pursuant to the alcoholic\nbeverage control law and any applicable rules and regulations; and\nprovided further, however, that no provision of this section shall be\nconstrued to prohibit a casino or Indian gaming facility alcoholic\nbeverage licensee from obtaining an off-site storage license from the\nstate liquor authority.\n  10. The commission may revoke, suspend, refuse to renew or refuse to\ntransfer any casino or Indian gaming facility alcoholic beverage license\nor permit, and may fine or penalize the holder of any alcoholic beverage\nlicense or permit issued under this section for violations of any\nprovision of the alcoholic beverage control law, the rules and\nregulations promulgated by the state liquor authority, and the\nregulations promulgated by the commission.\n  11. Jurisdiction over all alcoholic beverage licenses and permits\npreviously issued with respect to the gaming facility or Indian gaming\nfacility is hereby vested in the commission, which in its discretion\nshall by regulation, rule, or policy promptly provide for the conversion\nthereof into a casino or Indian gaming facility alcoholic beverage\nlicense or permit as provided in this section. This section shall not be\nconstrued to affect the validity of any existing licenses and permits\npreviously issued to an Indian gaming facility by the state liquor\nauthority, or the continuation of any administrativ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1340__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prior to issuing any license under this section, the\ncommission, or its designee, shall consult with the state liquor\nauthority, or its designee, to confirm that such application and such\ngaming facility or Indian gaming facility conforms with all applicable\nprovisions of the alcoholic beverage control law, and all applicable\nrules, regulations, bulletins, orders and advisories promulgated by the\nstate liquor authority;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1340__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prior to commencing enforcement actions against any gaming\nfacility or Indian gaming facility licensed under this section, the\ncommission, or its designee, shall consult with the state liquor\nauthority, or its designee, with respect to the application of the\napplicable provisions of the alcoholic beverage control law, and all\napplicable rules, regulations, bulletins, orders and advisories\npromulgated by the state liquor authority on the alleged conduct of such\nlicensee; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1340__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commission, or its designee, shall consult with the state\nliquor authority, or its designee, on a regular basis, but no less than\nonce every three months, regarding any pending applications and\nenforcement matters.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>