<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1345"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1345"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1345"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1345/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1345/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1345/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1345/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1345">
        <num>1345</num>
        <heading>Excluded person; forfeiture of winnings; other sanctions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1345. Excluded person; forfeiture of winnings; other sanctions. 1. A\nperson who is prohibited from gaming in a licensed gaming facility by\nany order of the executive director, commission or court of competent\njurisdiction, including any person on the self-exclusion list pursuant\nto subdivision one of section one thousand three hundred forty-four of\nthis title, shall not collect, in any manner or proceeding, any winnings\nor recover any losses arising as a result of any prohibited gaming\nactivity.\n  2. For the purposes of this section, any gaming activity in a licensed\ngaming facility that results in a prohibited person obtaining any money\nor thing of value from, or being owed any money or thing of value by,\nthe gaming facility shall be considered, solely for purposes of this\nsection, to be a fully executed gambling transaction.\n  3. In addition to any other penalty provided by law, any money or\nthing of value which has been obtained by, or is owed to, any prohibited\nperson by a licensed gaming facility as a result of wagers made by a\nprohibited person shall be subject to forfeiture following notice to the\nprohibited person and opportunity to be heard. A licensed gaming\nfacility shall inform a prohibited person of the availability of such\nnotice on the commission's website when ejecting the prohibited person\nand seizing any chips, vouchers or other representative of money owed by\na gaming facility to the prohibited person as authorized by this\nsubdivision. All forfeited amounts shall be deposited into the\ncommercial gaming revenue fund.\n  4. In any proceeding brought by the commission against a licensee or\nregistrant for a willful violation of the commission's self-exclusion\nregulations, the commission may order, in addition to any other sanction\nauthorized, an additional fine of double the amount of any money or\nthing of value obtained by the licensee or registrant from any\nself-excluded person. Any money or thing of value so forfeited shall be\ndisposed of in the same manner as any money or thing of value forfeited\npursuant to subdivision three of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>