<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1346"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1346"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1346"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1346/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1346/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1346/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1346/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1346">
        <num>1346</num>
        <heading>Labor peace agreements for certain facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1346__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Gaming facility" means any gaming facility licensed pursuant to\nthis article or a video lottery gaming facility as may be authorized by\nparagraph three of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1346__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section one thousand six hundred\nseventeen-a of the tax law, as amended by section nineteen of the\nchapter of the laws of two thousand thirteen that added this section\nlicensed by the commission. A gaming facility shall not include any\nhorse racing, bingo or charitable games of chance, the state lottery for\neducation, or any gaming facility operating pursuant to the federal\nIndian Gaming Regulatory Act, 25 U.S.C. ยง 2710 et seq. A gaming facility\nshall include any hospitality operation at or related to the gaming\nfacility.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1346__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Labor peace agreement" means an agreement enforceable under 29\nU.S.C. ยง 185</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1346__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that, at a minimum, protects the state's proprietary\ninterests by prohibiting labor organizations and members from engaging\nin picketing, work stoppages, boycotts, and any other economic\ninterference with operation of the relevant gaming facility.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1346__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"License" means any permit, license, franchise or allowance of the\ncommission and shall include any franchisee or permittee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1346__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Proprietary interest" means an economic and non-regulatory\ninterest at risk in the financial success of the gaming facility that\ncould be adversely affected by labor-management conflict, including but\nnot limited to property interests, financial investments and revenue\nsharing.\n  2. The state legislature finds that the gaming industry constitutes a\nvital sector of New York's overall economy and that the state through\nits operation of lotteries and video lottery facilities and through its\nownership of the properties utilized for horse racing by The New York\nRacing Association Inc. has a significant and ongoing economic and\nnon-regulatory interest in the financial viability and competitiveness\nof the gaming industry. The state legislature further finds that the\naward or grant of a license by the commission to operate a gaming\nfacility is a significant state action and that the commission must make\nprudent and efficient decisions to maximize the benefits and minimize\nthe risks of gaming. The state legislature further recognizes that\ncasino gaming industry integration can provide a vital economic engine\nto assist, nurture, develop, and promote regional economic development,\nthe state tourism industry and the growth of jobs in the state.\nAdditionally, the state legislature also finds revenues derived directly\nby the state from such gaming activity will be shared from gross gaming\nreceipts, after payout of prizes but prior to deductions for operational\nexpenses.\n  Therefore, the state legislature finds that the state has a\nsubstantial and compelling proprietary interest in any license awarded\nfor the operation of a gaming facility within the state.\n  3. The commission shall require any applicant for a gaming facility\nlicense who has not yet entered into a labor peace agreement to produce\nan affidavit stating it shall enter into a labor peace agreement with\nlabor organizations that are actively engaged in representing or\nattempting to represe...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>