<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1362"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1362"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1362"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1362/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1362/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1362/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1362/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1362">
        <num>1362</num>
        <heading>Prevention and outreach efforts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1362__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The goals of the plan and procedures and timetables to implement\nthe plan;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1362__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The identification of the individual who will be responsible for\nthe implementation and maintenance of the plan;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1362__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Policies and procedures including the following:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commitment of the applicant and the gaming facility licensee\nto train appropriate employees;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The duties and responsibilities of the employees designated to\nimplement or participate in the plan;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The responsibility of patrons with respect to responsible\ngambling;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures for compliance with the voluntary exclusion program;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures to identify patrons and employees with suspected or\nknown problem gambling behavior, including procedures specific to\nloyalty and other rewards and marketing programs;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures for providing information to individuals regarding the\nvoluntary exclusion program and community, public and private treatment\nservices, gamblers anonymous programs and similar treatment or addiction\ntherapy programs designed to prevent, treat, or monitor problem gamblers\nand to counsel family members;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures for responding to patron and employee requests for\ninformation regarding the voluntary exclusion program and community,\npublic and private treatment services, gamblers anonymous programs and\nsimilar treatment or addiction therapy programs designed to prevent,\ntreat, or monitor compulsive and problem gamblers and to counsel family\nmembers;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provision of printed material to educate patrons and employees\nabout problem gambling and to inform them about the voluntary exclusion\nprogram and treatment services available to problem gamblers and their\nfamilies. The applicant shall provide examples of the materials to be\nused as part of its plan, including, brochures and other printed\nmaterial and a description of how the material will be disseminated;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Advertising and other marketing and outreach to educate the\ngeneral public about the voluntary exclusion program and problem\ngambling;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An employee training program, including training materials to be\nutilized and a plan for periodic reinforcement training and a\ncertification process established by the applicant to verify that each\nemployee has completed the training required by the plan;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures to prevent underage gambling;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Procedures to prevent patrons impaired by drugs or alcohol, or\nboth, from gambling; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1362__subsec_c__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The plan for posting signs within the gaming facility, containing\ninformation on gambling treatment and on the voluntary exclusion\nprogram. The applicant shall provide examples of the language and\ngraphics to be used on the signs as part of its plan;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1362__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A list of community, public and private treatment services,\ngamblers anonymous programs and similar treatment or addiction therapy\nprograms designed to prevent, treat, or monitor problem gamblers and to\ncounsel family members; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1362__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any other information, documents, and policies and procedures that\nthe commission requires.\n  2. Each applicant or gaming facility licensee shall submit any\namendments to the problem gambling plan to the commission for review and\napproval before implementing the amendments.\n  3. Each gaming facility licensee shall submit an annual summary of its\nproblem gambling plan to the commission.\n  4. Each gaming facility licensee shall submit quarterly updates and an\nannual report to the commission of its adherence to the plans and goals\nsubmitted under this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>