<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1401"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1401"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-08-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1401"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1401/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1401/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1401/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-1401/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1401">
        <num>1401</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>entered more than one thousand contests offered by a single\noperator or registrant; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>won more than three prizes valued at one thousand dollars each or\nmore from a single operator or registrant.\n  7. "Horse racing event" shall mean any sport or athletic event\nconducted in New York state subject to the provisions of articles two,\nthree, four, five, six, nine, ten and eleven of this chapter, or any\nsport or athletic event conducted outside of New York state, which if\nconducted in New York state would be subject to the provisions of this\nchapter.\n  8. "Interactive fantasy sports contest" or "contest" shall mean a game\nof skill wherein one or more contestants compete against each other by\nusing their knowledge and understanding of athletic events and athletes\nto select and manage rosters of simulated players whose performance\ndirectly corresponds with the actual performance of human competitors on\nsports teams and in sports events.\n  9. "Interactive fantasy sports gross revenue" shall mean the amount\nequal to the total of all entry fees not attributable to New York state\nprohibited sports events that a registrant collects from all players,\nless the total of all sums not attributable to New York state prohibited\nsports events paid out as winnings to all players, multiplied by the\nresident percentage for New York state; provided, however, that the\ntotal of all sums paid out as winnings to players shall not include the\ncash equivalent value of any merchandise or thing of value awarded as a\nprize.\n  10. "Interactive fantasy sports operator" or "operator" shall mean any\nperson or entity that offers any interactive fantasy sports contest to\nany authorized player through any interactive fantasy sports platform.\n  11. "Interactive fantasy sports platform" or "platform" shall mean the\ncombination of hardware, software, and data networks used to manage,\nadminister, or control contests and any associated entry fees.\n  12. "Interactive fantasy sports registrant" or "registrant" shall mean\nan operator that is registered by the commission...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any member, officer, employee or agent of an operator or\nregistrant;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any spouse, child, brother, sister or parent residing as a member\nof the same household in the principal place of abode of any member,\nofficer, employee or agent of an operator or registrant;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any individual with access to non-public confidential information\nabout contests;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any amateur or professional athlete whose performance may be used\nto determine the outcome of a contest;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any sports agent, team employee, referee, or league official\nassociated with any sport or athletic event on which contests are based;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any individual located in a state where the conduct of contests is\nexpressly prohibited; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1401__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any minor.\n  15. "Prohibited sports event" shall mean any collegiate sport or\nathletic event, any high school sport or athletic event or any horse\nracing event.\n  16. "Resident percentage" shall mean, for each interactive fantasy\nsports contest, the percentage, rounded to the nearest tenth of a\npercent, of the total entry fees collected from players located in New\nYork state, divided by the total entry fees collected from all players\nin interactive fantasy sports contests not prohibited in New York state.\n  17. "Sports event" shall mean any amateur or professional sport or\nathletic event, except a prohibited sports event.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>