<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-205"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-205"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="205"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_205">
        <num>205</num>
        <heading>License for running races and steeplechase meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 205. License for running races and steeplechase meetings. Any\nnon-franchised corporation desiring to obtain the benefits of the\nprovisions of section two hundred three of this article, if proposing to\nconduct a race course or race meeting for running races or\nsteeplechases, may annually apply to the commission for a license to\nconduct running races and race meetings or steeplechases and\nsteeplechase meetings, as the case may be. If, in the judgment of such\ncommission the public interest, convenience or necessity will be served\nthereby and a proper case for the issuance of such license is shown\nconsistent with the purposes of this article and the best interest of\nracing generally, the commission may grant such license, for a term\nwithin the calendar year, which shall specify the dates and period of\ntime during which, and the place where, the licensee may operate. The\nfee for such license shall be one hundred dollars for each racing day,\npayable upon issuance of license. In considering an application for a\nlicense under this section, the commission may give consideration to the\nnumber of licenses already granted and to the location of the tracks\npreviously licensed. Every such license shall contain a condition that\nall running races or race meetings conducted thereunder shall be subject\nto such reasonable rules and regulations from time to time prescribed by\nthe commission, designated as the "rules of racing". Before promulgating\nsuch rules of racing or modifying or abrogating any of them, the\ncommission shall give the jockey club, a corporation organized under the\nlaws of the state of New York, an opportunity to submit recommendations\nrelative to such rules for running races and race meetings, and to the\nnational steeplechase and hunt association, a corporation organized\nunder the laws of the state of New York, an opportunity to submit\nrecommendations relative to such rules for steeplechases and\nsteeplechase meetings, and the commission may adopt, to the extent that\nit deems appropriate, any rules so submitted by either of such\ncorporations or by any other nationally recognized association or\ncorporation that has for its purpose the improvement of the breed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>