<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207">
        <num>207</num>
        <heading>Board of directors of a franchised corporation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_207__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The governor shall nominate a member to serve as chair, subject to\nconfirmation by majority vote of the board of directors. All non-ex\nofficio members shall have equal voting rights.\n  (ii) In the event of a member vacancy occurring by death, resignation\nor otherwise, the respective appointing officer or officers shall\nappoint a successor who shall hold office for the unexpired portion of\nthe term. A vacancy from the members appointed from the present board of\nThe New York Racing Association, Inc., shall be filled by the remaining\nsuch members.\n  * b. The franchised corporation shall establish a compensation\ncommittee to fix salary guidelines, such guidelines to be consistent\nwith an operation of other first class thoroughbred racing operations in\nthe United States; a finance committee, to review annual operating and\ncapital budgets for each of the three racetracks; a nominating\ncommittee, to nominate any new directors to be designated by the\nfranchised corporation to replace its existing directors; and an\nexecutive committee. Each of the compensation, finance, nominating and\nexecutive committees shall include at least one of the directors\nappointed by the governor, and the executive committee shall include at\nleast one of the directors appointed by the temporary president of the\nsenate and at least one of the directors appointed by the speaker of the\nassembly.\n  * NB There are 2 par b's\n  * b. In addition to these voting members, the board shall have two ex\nofficio members to advise on critical economic and equine health\nconcerns of the racing industry, one appointed by the New York\nThoroughbred Breeders Inc., and one appointed by the New York\nthoroughbred horsemen's association (or such other entity as is\ncertified and approved pursuant to section two hundred twenty-eight of\nthis article).\n  * NB There are 2 par b's\n  * c. All directors shall serve at the pleasure of their appointing\nauthority.\n  * NB There are 2 par c's\n  * c. Up...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The governor shall nominate a member to serve as chair for an\ninitial term of three years, who shall serve at the pleasure of the\ngovernor, subject to confirmation by majority vote of the board.\nThereafter, the board shall elect its chair, who shall serve at the\npleasure of the board, from among its members.\n  (ii) The term of voting membership on the New York racing association\nboard shall be three years. Individual appointees shall be limited to\nserving as a voting member the lesser of three terms or nine years.\nNotwithstanding the foregoing, the initial term of one member appointed\nby each of the governor, temporary president of the senate, and speaker\nof the assembly, the member appointed by the New York thoroughbred\nhorsemen's association, and the member appointed by the New York\nThoroughbred Breeders, Inc. shall expire March thirty-first, two\nthousand eighteen; the initial term of the remaining members appointed\nby each of the governor, temporary president of the senate, and speaker\nof the assembly and two members appointed by the New York racing\nassociation reorganization board shall expire on March thirty-first, two\nthousand nineteen; the initial term of three members appointed by the\nNew York racing association reorganization board shall expire on March\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty-one, and the initial term of three\nmembers appointed by the New York racing association reorganization\nboard shall expire on March thirty-first, two thousand twenty-three. The\neight initial members appointed by the New York racing association\nreorganization board shall hold appointment as a voting member for the\ngreater of three terms or nine years.\n  (iii) In the event of a member vacancy occurring by death, resignation\nor otherwise, the respective appointing authority shall appoint a\nsuccessor who shall hold office for the unexpired portion of the term.\nIn the case of vacancies among members appointed by the executive\ncommittee of the New York ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_207__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>over the three years prior, owned or trained horses\nwith a cumulative average of fifteen starts at New York race tracks per\nyear,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_207__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>be a breeder of record registered with the thoroughbred\nbreeding and development fund,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_207__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>be a managing partner in a New York\nstate-based ownership syndicate licensed with the commission, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_207__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nhave a cogent interest in the racing and breeding industry in the state.\nThe provisions of this subparagraph shall not impact any members serving\nas of January first, two thousand twenty-six.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Beginning January first, two thousand twenty-six, all non-publicly\nappointed members must hold a license pursuant to section two hundred\ntwenty of this article.\n  b. The franchised corporation shall establish a compensation committee\nto fix salary guidelines, such guidelines to be consistent with an\noperation of other first class thoroughbred racing operations in the\nUnited States; a finance and audit committee, to review annual operating\nand capital budgets for each of the three racetracks; a nominating and\ngovernance committee, to nominate any new directors to be designated by\nthe franchised corporation to replace its existing directors and be\nresponsible for all issues affecting the governance of the franchised\ncorporation; an equine safety committee to review industry best\npractices to improve the safety of horse racing of the three racetracks;\na racing committee to address all issues related to racing operations;\nand an executive committee. Each of the compensation, finance,\nnominating and executive committees shall include at least one public\nmember from among the directors appointed by the governor.\n  c. Upon the effective date of this paragraph, the structure of the New\nYork racing association board shall be deemed to be incorporated within\nand made part of the certificate of incorporation of the franchised\ncorporation, and no amendment to such certificate of incorporation shall\nbe necessary to give effect to any such provision, and any provision\ncontained within such certificate inconsistent in any manner shall be\nsuperseded by the provisions of this section. Such board shall, however,\nmake appropriate conforming changes to all governing documents of the\nfranchised corporation including but not limited to corporate by-laws.\nFollowing such conforming changes, amendments to the by-laws of the\nfranchised corporation shall be made only by unanimous vote of the\nboard.\n  2. Members of the New York racing association board shall serve\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>