<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-212"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-212"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="212"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_212">
        <num>212</num>
        <heading>Franchise oversight board</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_212__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The local advisory board for the Aqueduct racetrack facility\nshall comprise of fifteen members, nine of whom shall be designees of\nNew York City Queens Community Board Ten, three designees of the\nfranchised corporation and three designees of the video lottery gaming\noperator. At substantial completion of the Belmont project, as\ndetermined by the gaming commission, this board shall be dissolved.\n  (ii) (A) Notwithstanding subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_212__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph, within\nthirty days after the substantial completion of the Belmont project, as\ndetermined by the gaming commission, an Aqueduct Redevelopment Community\nAdvisory Board shall be formed to assess all bids made in response to\nthe request for proposals on developing the Aqueduct property and is\nrequired to hold a public hearing and adopt and submit a written\nrecommendation on each bid to the franchise oversight board within sixty\ndays of receiving such bid. The adoption of such recommendation shall be\nby a public vote which results in approval by a majority of the\nappointed members present during the presence of a quorum. The board\nrecommendation shall be in writing via a form provided by the franchise\noversight board and shall include a description of the application, the\ntime and place of the public hearing on the application, the time and\nplace of the meeting at which the recommendation was adopted and the\nvote by which the recommendation was adopted. The community board may\ninclude in its submission the reasons for the vote and any conditions\nattached to its vote.\n  (B) The Aqueduct Redevelopment Community Advisory Board shall consist\nof six members, one to be appointed by the governor, one to be appointed\nby the mayor of the city of New York, one to be appointed by the senator\nrepresenting the senate district where the Aqueduct property is located,\none to be appointed by the assemblymember representing the assembly\ndistrict where the Aqueduct property is located, one to be appointed by\nthe city councilmember representing the district where the Aqueduct\nproperty is located, and one to be appointed by the borough president\nwhere the Aqueduct property is located.\n  c. The local advisory board for the Belmont racetrack facility shall\ncomprise fifteen members, to be appointed as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_212__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>five members from Nassau county to be appointed by the Nassau\ncounty executive. Four of such members must reside in the hamlet of\nElmont;\n  (ii) two members from the town of Hempstead to be appointed by the\nsupervisor of the town of Hempstead. Both members must reside in the\nhamlet of Elmont;\n  (iii) two members to be appointed by the mayor of the village of\nFloral Park, subject to village board approval;\n  (iv) one member to be appointed by the mayor of the village of South\nFloral Park, subject to village board approval;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_212__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>three members to be appointed by the New York Racing Association,\nInc.; and\n  (vi) two members to be appointed by the New York City Queens Community\nBoard 13.\n  The members of the local advisory boards shall serve for a period of\ntwo years. In the event of a vacancy occurring during a term of\nappointment by reason of death, resignation, disqualification or\notherwise such vacancy shall be filled for the unexpired term in the\nsame manner as the original appointment. The members of the local\nadvisory board shall serve without compensation, except that each member\nshall be allowed the necessary and actual expenses incurred in the\nperformance of his or her duties pursuant to this section.\n  7. The Saratoga local advisory boards in cooperation with the state\nhistoric preservation office and the franchise oversight board shall\ncompile a complete, updated historic resources inventory identifying all\nbuildings and landscape features and their current condition at the\nSaratoga Racecourse. The local advisory board may, at its discretion, in\nthe performance of its responsibilities, seek advice from groups or\nindividuals with relevant expertise.\n  All buildings and landscaped features of historic, architectural or\ncultural significance at the Saratoga Racecourse may be advanced by the\nlocal advisory board for consideration for inclusion in the National and\nState Registers of Historic Places and in local historic districts.\n  8. a. The duties and responsibilities of the franchise oversight board\nshall include, but not be limited to, the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_212__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>represent the interests of the state in all real estate\ndevelopment proposed for Aqueduct racetrack or real estate development\nat Belmont Park racetrack. Any such real estate development shall only\nbe undertaken pursuant to a competitive process approved by the board,\nafter consultation with the applicable local advisory boards and\nconsideration of local zoning and planning regulation, and in a manner\nthat will not adversely impact any historic structure that is included\nin or eligible for inclusion in the National or the State Register of\nHistoric Places, be consistent with any plan approved for such\ncommunity, and shall be subject to unanimous approval of the franchise\noversight board and all statutory and regulatory requirements; provided,\nhowever, that, subject to approval of the franchise oversight board and\nsubject to all statutory and regulatory requirements, the franchised\ncorporation shall have full powers and rights to develop, redevelop,\nrefurbish, renovate or make such other improvements, capital\nexpenditures or otherwise, to the racetracks and the fixtures and\nimprovements thereon consistent with projects specifically identified in\nthe franchised corporation's approved track facility improvement plan.\n  The franchise oversight board shall be guided by the goals of ensuring\nthe continuation of high quality thoroughbred racing at the thoroughbred\nracing facilities located within the state, raising revenue for or in\naid or support of education in this state from video lottery gaming at\nfacilities of the state racing franchise, and maximizing revenue for\ngovernments from pari-mutuel wagering on racing at facilities of the\nstate racing franchise. In consideration of capital expenditure\napproval, the board shall ensure adequate funds are dedicated for\nmaintenance and repair of existing structures at Saratoga racetrack and\nBelmont Park racetrack and for the improvement of onsite backstretch\npersonnel housing and quality of life.\n  ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_212__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>facilitate discussions and voluntary agreements between the\nfranchised corporation and off-track betting corporations to streamline\noperations, decrease operating costs and maximize opportunities\npertaining to costs and revenues, and encourage an exchange of views and\nexperiences from the franchised corporation and the off-track betting\ncorporations to improve the racing product in New York and to realize\nefficiencies;\n  (vi) review and approve all purchasing policies pursuant to paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_212__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision six of section two hundred eight of this article;\n  (vii) review and provide any recommendations on all simulcasting\ncontracts (buy and sell) that are also subject to prior approval of the\ncommission;\n  (viii) act on behalf of the People of the State of New York to enter\ninto any real property transactions in furtherance of the purposes and\nintent of this statute, including, without limitation, one or more\nground leases, for one dollar in consideration annually, for each of\nAqueduct racetrack, Belmont Park and Saratoga racecourse to the\nfranchised corporation, for a term that will extend until the racing\nfranchise expires, is revoked, terminated or ends by any other means\nprovided by law. Such leases shall be executed contemporaneously with\nthe conveyance of the racetracks by the franchised corporation's\npredecessor to the state;\n  (ix) enter into on behalf of the state as licensor, a long term\nlicense agreement with the franchised corporation for the use of the\nsimulcast signal and associated intellectual property rights, for\nconsideration of one dollar annually and for a term that will extend\nuntil the racing franchise expires, is revoked, terminated or ends by\nany other means provided by law. Such license agreement shall be\nexecuted contemporaneously with the conveyance of the franchised\ncorporation's assets associated with the franchise agreement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_212__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conduct running races or steeplechases at racing facilities and\nconduct pari-mutuel betting on the outcome of the same when necessary to\nassure the continuation of the racing and pari-mutuel betting activities\nat such racing facilities (A) in the event that the racing and/or\npari-mutuel betting franchises of the franchised corporation authorized\nby this chapter then holding such franchises have either been terminated\nin the manner provided by law or have been relinquished by such\ncorporation, or such corporation declines to continue conducting race\nmeetings and pari-mutuel betting on the outcome of the same as required\nby such franchises unless such declination is the result of strikes,\nacts of God, or other unavoidable causes not under the control of such\ncorporation, or the corporate existence of such corporation has been\ndissolved in the manner provided by law prior to the end of the term of\nany such franchise and (B) until such time as a new franchise is\ngranted;\n  (xi) on behalf of the People of the State of New York, and, acting in\nsuch capacity as lessor of the racing facilities and real estate, be\nresponsible for payment of all property taxes related to such racing\nfacilities and real estate;\n  (xii) report annually to the governor and the legislature, beginning\nno later than December thirty-first, two thousand eight, stating its\nfindings and recommendations to implement policy and legislative changes\nnecessary to encourage the continuation of high quality thoroughbred\nracing in New York state and to protect the legitimate interests of the\nstate and the thoroughbred racing industry;\n  (xiii) require the franchised corporation to make all records and\ndocuments pertaining to its financial practices, and other documents and\nrecords necessary to carry out its duties, available to the franchise\noversight board within thirty days of a written request;\n  (xiv) examine or cause to be examined by a third party, the books,\npapers, records...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>