<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-217"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-217"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="217"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-217/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-217/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-217/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-217/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_217">
        <num>217</num>
        <heading>Revocation of licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 217. Revocation of licenses. If any corporation to which a license\nshall be granted shall fail or refuse to comply with the provisions of\nthis chapter, or with the terms and conditions of its license, or if for\nany other reason the continuance of such license shall not be deemed\nconducive to the interests of legitimate racing, the commission, upon\nits own initiative or upon complaint of the jockey club, in the case of\nrace courses to be used for running races, or upon the complaint of the\nnational steeplechase and hunt association in the case of race courses\nto be used for steeplechases, shall have the power to cancel and revoke\nsuch license. Written notice of such complaint shall be given to such\ncorporation by the commission within five days after receiving such\ncomplaint, or after determining to take action, which notice shall\nspecify a time and place of hearing thereon. If the commission cancels\nand revokes such license, then all powers exercised under section two\nhundred three of this article by the corporation to which such license\nwas granted shall cease and determine.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>