<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-225"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-225"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225">
        <num>225</num>
        <heading>Registration of race horses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 225. Registration of race horses. The true name, sex and age, and\nalso the pedigree, unless such pedigree is unknown, of every horse,\nmare, gelding, colt or filly shall be registered with the jockey club,\nUnited States trotting association, American quarter horse association,\nthe national steeplechase and hunt association or such other entity as\nthe commission may designate before it shall be eligible to compete in\nany race conducted under a license or franchise of the commission and\nsuch name shall continue to be its true name unless and until the same\nshall be changed according to the rules and regulations of such\norganization. The class to which any such animal belongs for the purpose\nof the entry or competition in any race shall be determined by the\npublic performance thereof in former contests or trials of speed, as\nprescribed by the printed rules of the person, association or\ncorporation sponsoring such race. No horse, mare, gelding, colt or filly\nshall be eligible to compete in any race, unless it is first\nmicrochipped and registered with the jockey club, United States trotting\nassociation, American quarter horse association, the national\nsteeplechase and hunt association or such other entity, as applicable\nand as the commission may designate. The commission may request that all\nmicrochip information be provided and available to the commission as\nnecessary pursuant to this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>