<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-228"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-228"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="228"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-228/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-228/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-228/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-228/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_228">
        <num>228</num>
        <heading>Pension plans for backstretch employees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_228__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it represents more than fifty-one percent of all\nthe owners and trainers using the same facilities and (ii) the\nhorsemen's organization previously approved as qualified by the\ncommission does not represent fifty-one percent of all the owners and\ntrainers using the same facilities. If the commission is satisfied that\nthe documentation submitted with the application of any other horsemen's\norganization is conclusive with respect to subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_228__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of\nthis paragraph, the commission may approve the applicant as the\nqualified recipient organization.\n  In the best interests of racing, upon receipt of such an application,\nthe commission may direct the payments to the previously qualified\nhorsemen's organization to continue uninterrupted, or it may direct the\npayments to be withheld and placed in interest-bearing accounts for a\nperiod not to exceed ninety days, during which time the commission shall\nreview and approve or disapprove the application. Funds held in such\nmanner shall be paid to the organization approved by the commission. In\nno event shall the commission accept more than one such application in\nany calendar year from the same horsemen's organization.\n  The funds authorized to be paid by the commission are to be used\nexclusively for the benefit of those horsemen racing in New York state\nthrough the administrative purposes of such qualified organization,\nbenevolent activities on behalf of backstretch employees, and for the\npromotion of equine research.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>