<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-232"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-232"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="232"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-232/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-232/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-232/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-232/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_232">
        <num>232</num>
        <heading>License to conduct pari-mutuel betting at race meetings for running races or steeplechases</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 232. License to conduct pari-mutuel betting at race meetings for\nrunning races or steeplechases. 1. Any corporation, at the time of\nmaking application to the commission for a license to conduct a race\ncourse or a race meeting for running races or steeplechases, or at such\nsubsequent time as the commission may permit, may apply to such\ncommission for a license to conduct at such race meeting pari-mutuel\nbetting on the races to be run thereat. The commission may prescribe the\nform in which such application shall be made and the information to be\nfurnished by such corporation. If the commission is satisfied from such\napplication, or from other sources of information, that the racetrack of\nsuch corporation for which such application is made has facilities and\nequipment sufficient to accommodate its probable number of patrons, the\ncommission shall issue to such corporation a license to conduct\npari-mutuel betting in the manner and subject to the conditions\nprescribed by this chapter, at the racetrack described in such license\non the days specified in such license.\n  2. The refusal of an application for such license shall be preceded by\nnotice and an opportunity to be heard. In the conduct of such hearing\nthe commission shall not be bound by technical rules of evidence but all\nevidence offered before the commission shall be reduced to writing, and\nsuch evidence together with the exhibits, if any, and the findings of\nthe commission, shall be permanently preserved and shall constitute the\nrecord of the commission in such case. Such hearing may be presided over\nby the chair of the commission or by any member or by an officer of the\ncommission designated by the chair in writing to act as hearing officer\nand such person or persons may issue subpoenas for witnesses and\nadminister oaths to witnesses. The hearing officer, at the conclusion of\nthe hearing shall make findings which, if concurred in by a majority of\nthe commission, shall become the findings of the commission. The action\nof the commission in refusing a license shall be reviewable in the\nsupreme court in the manner provided by the provisions of article\nseventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>