<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-234"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-234"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="234"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_234">
        <num>234</num>
        <heading>Place and manner of conducting pari-mutuel betting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 234. Place and manner of conducting pari-mutuel betting. Any\ncorporation licensed or franchised to conduct pari-mutuel betting at a\nhorse race meeting shall provide a place or places within the race\nmeeting grounds or enclosure at which such licensee or franchisee shall\nconduct the pari-mutuel system of betting by its patrons on the results\nof the horse races at such meeting. Such place or places shall be\nprovided with necessary equipment for issuing or vending pari-mutuel\ntickets, and adding machine equipment and a device capable of accurate\nand speedy determination of the amount of money in each pool and on each\nhorse and the amount of award or dividend to winning patrons and\ndisplaying the same to its patrons. Such place shall also be equipped\nwith automatic or hand-operated machinery for displaying on a mutuel\nindicator in plain view of the public, the total amount of sales\nseparately for straight, place and show on every race and on each horse\nin such race. The machine or mutuel indicator shall also display the\napproximate straight odds on each horse in any race; the value of a\ntwo-dollar winning mutuel ticket, straight, place and show, on the first\nthree horses in any race; the elapsed time of the race; the value of a\ntwo-dollar daily double ticket, if a daily double be conducted; and any\nother information that may be necessary for the guidance of the general\npublic that the commission may require. All such machines and equipment\nmust be approved by the commission and the department of taxation and\nfinance before being used, but the commission shall not require the\ninstallation of any particular make of mechanical or electrical\nequipment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>