<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-241"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-241"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="241"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-241/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-241/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-241/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-241/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_241">
        <num>241</num>
        <heading>Disposition of unpaid money due on account of pari-mutuel tickets not presented</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 241. Disposition of unpaid money due on account of pari-mutuel\ntickets not presented. The sum held by any corporation authorized to\nconduct pari-mutuel betting for payment of outstanding winning\npari-mutuel tickets and for refunding the price of pari-mutuel tickets\nshall be retained by such corporation for such purposes until April\nfirst of the succeeding year; provided, however, that ninety-five per\ncentum of such sum remaining unclaimed as of the last day of February of\nsuch year shall be paid to the department of taxation and finance by\nMarch fifteenth. On April tenth, the balance of such sum remaining\nunclaimed and any other unclaimed amount received in the course of\nconducting pari-mutuel betting shall be paid to the department of\ntaxation and finance. A penalty of five per centum and interest at the\nrate of one per centum per month from the due date to the date of\npayment of the unclaimed balance due March fifteenth or April tenth, as\nthe case may be, shall be payable in case such balance is not paid when\ndue. Such amounts, interest and penalties when collected shall be paid\nby the department of taxation and finance into the general fund of the\nstate treasury.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>