<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-243"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-243"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="243"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-243/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-243/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-243/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-243/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_243">
        <num>243</num>
        <heading>Free or reduced fee passes, cards or badges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 243. Free or reduced fee passes, cards or badges. A corporation\nlicensed or franchised to conduct pari-mutuel betting on races run on\nits racetrack may issue free passes, cards or badges to any qualified\nperson. A qualified person shall include, but need not be limited to,\nofficers and employees of the corporation conducting the race meeting,\nmembers, officers and employees of the commission, members and employees\nof the jockey club, members and employees of the national steeplechase\nand hunt association, members of turf organizations of other states and\nforeign countries, public officers engaged in the performance of their\nduties, persons actually employed and accredited by the press to attend\nsuch meetings, owners, stable managers, trainers, jockeys, jockey\nmanagers, grooms, concessionaires, spouses, domestic partners and\nchildren of owners, trainers and jockeys, other persons whose actual\nduties require their presence at such racetrack, and any other person or\nguest deemed appropriate by such corporation. In addition, free or\nreduced fee passes, cards or badges may be issued to the general public\nor segments of the general public in connection with any promotional\ncampaign or marketing program sponsored by such corporation to increase\nattendance at live race meets. The issuance of free passes, cards or\nbadges shall be under the rules and regulations of the commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>