<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-250"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-250"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="250"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-250/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-250/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-250/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-250/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_250">
        <num>250</num>
        <heading>Power of commission to impose penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 250. Power of commission to impose penalties. The commission, in\naddition to its power to suspend or revoke occupational licenses,\nlicenses to conduct running races and race meetings or steeplechases and\nsteeplechase meetings and licenses to conduct pari-mutuel betting at a\nrace course or race meeting for running races or steeplechases issued by\nthe commission, is authorized to impose civil penalties upon any such\nlicensee or franchisee for a violation of any provision of this chapter\nor the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, not exceeding\nthe amounts set forth in section one hundred sixteen of this chapter,\nwhich penalties shall be paid into the state treasury. Each day upon\nwhich such violation continues may be considered by the commission as a\nseparate violation in assessing the amount of civil penalty to be\nimposed. Any penalty so imposed shall be sued for by the attorney\ngeneral in the name of the people of the state of New York, if so\ndirected by the commission. The amount of the penalty collected by the\ncommission or recovered in any such action, or paid to the commission\nupon a compromise as hereinafter provided, shall be paid by the\ncommission into the state treasury and credited to the general fund. The\ncommission, for cause shown and in its discretion, may extend the time\nfor the payment of such penalty and, by compromise may accept less than\nthe amount of such penalty as imposed in settlement thereof. The powers\ngranted by this section shall not be affected by the circumstances that\nany such license has expired by its terms prior to the imposition of\nsuch penalty.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>