<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-251"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-251"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="251"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-251/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-251/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-251/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-251/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_251">
        <num>251</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_251__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sired by a New York\nstallion and foaled from a mare domiciled in this state; (ii) foaled\nfrom a mare domiciled in this state which mare has been serviced back\nexclusively by a New York stallion in the year of such foaling; or (iii)\non or after January first, nineteen hundred ninety-five foaled from a\nmare domiciled in New York. The fund shall report to the governor and\nthe legislature on or before December fifteenth, nineteen hundred\nninety-nine effects of paragraph (iii) of this subdivision on the New\nYork state breeding industry.\n  * NB Effective until January 1, 2022\n  * 3. "New York-bred." A thoroughbred which is registered in the\nregistry designated and administered by such fund in accordance with\nsuch rules concerning domicile and registration requirements as may be\nestablished by the fund, including that each mare, stallion, and foal be\nmicrochipped and registered pursuant to section two hundred twenty-five\nof this article, and: was on or before December thirty-first, nineteen\nhundred eighty, foaled in this state; or is on or after January first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-one, either:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_251__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sired by a New York stallion\nand foaled from a mare domiciled in this state; (ii) foaled from a mare\ndomiciled in this state which mare has been serviced back exclusively by\na New York stallion in the year of such foaling; or (iii) on or after\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred ninety-five foaled from a mare domiciled\nin New York.\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2022\n  4. "Breeder." The owner of the mare at the time the mare foals a New\nYork-bred.\n  5. "New York stallion." A stallion standing in New York at the time he\nwas bred to the dam of a New York-bred; a stallion must be registered\nwith the fund or its designated agent and must be</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_251__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>owned by a\nresident of this state and standing the entire stud season in this\nstate; or (ii) owned by a resident of another state but standing the\nentire stud season in this state and leased by a resident of this state\nfor a term of not less than one year; or (iii) owned jointly by a\nresident of this state together with a resident of another state and\nstanding the entire stud season in this state and leased by a resident\nof this state for a term of not less than one year. Leases shall be\nfiled with the fund or its designated agent.\n  6. "Stallion owner." The owner of a stallion standing in New York at\nthe time he was bred to the dam of a New York-bred.\n  7. "Races." Races upon which pari-mutuel wagering is conducted at\nthoroughbred race meetings of racing corporations as authorized by the\ncommission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>