<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-254"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-254"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="254"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-254/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-254/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-254/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-254/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_254">
        <num>254</num>
        <heading>Resources of fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_254__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An amount as shall be determined by the fund but not in excess\nof forty-four percent to provide purse moneys exclusively for New\nYork-breds entered in all races, the conditions of which have been\napproved by the fund; provided, however, that the fund shall set aside\nforty percent of the funds allotted under this subdivision to tracks\noperated by corporations licensed or franchised in accordance with the\nprovisions of section two hundred five or section two hundred six of\nthis article except that in addition to the other amounts allotted by\nthe fund under this paragraph, seventy-five percent of fund revenues\nderived from payments received in accordance with subdivision one of\nsection five hundred twenty-seven of this chapter shall be allotted\nexclusively to purses at a track operated by a corporation licensed\nunder the provisions of section two hundred five of this article.\n  (ii) The fund may direct a portion or portions of revenues allocated\nin this paragraph and dedicated to a racing corporation licensed in\naccordance with section two hundred five of this article to pari-mutuel\nraces at such track that are not restricted to New York-breds provided\nthat the revenues so allocated shall be used only to enrich any purses\nawarded to New York-breds finishing first, second, third, fourth or\nfifth in such non-restricted races.\n  * e. An amount as shall be determined by the fund but not in excess of\nsix percent to advance and promote breeding and raising of thoroughbreds\nin this state by the publication and dissemination of information\nrelating thereto, and the encouragement of interest, including among\nyouth, in the breeding and raising of New York-breds, and to advance and\npromote interest generally in agricultural pursuits.\n  * NB Effective until October 28, 2028\n  * e. An amount as shall be determined by the fund but not in excess of\nfive percent to advance and promote breeding and raising of\nthoroughbreds in this state by the publication a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>