<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-256"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-256"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="256"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-256/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-256/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-256/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-256/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_256">
        <num>256</num>
        <heading>Annual report</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 256. Annual report. The fund shall annually make during the month of\nJanuary a report to the governor setting forth in detail:\n  1. Its operations and accomplishments during the preceding year; and\n  2. Its receipts and disbursements during the preceding year.\n  The fund is directed to report annually, on or before January\nthirty-first, to the governor and the legislature, on the state of the\nthoroughbred breeding industry in this state. Such reports shall\ninclude, but not be limited to, the impact of the fund's programs on the\nbreeding and racing aspects of the industry; economic factors affecting\nthe industry such as employment and employment growth, state and local\nbenefits of breeding farms, income and the production of income within\nthis state, economic comparisons with other states; and data relative to\nmares and stallions standing in New York to include such information as\nthe number in New York, racing quality as measured by wins and stakes\nwon and placed and money won, the number of foals and foal racing\nquality as measured by sales value and number of starts, races and money\nwon, the progeny quality, including earnings, and the success of New\nYork-breds nationally.\n  The fund is further directed to incorporate into its reports comments\nfrom spokesmen representing all segments of the industry as well as\nrecommendations on preserving and enhancing the thoroughbred breeding\nindustry in this state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>