<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-318"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-318"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="318"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-318/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-318/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-318/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-318/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_318">
        <num>318</num>
        <heading>Disposition of on-track pari-mutuel pools; harness races</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall pay to the commissioner of taxation and finance\nas a reasonable tax for the privilege of conducting pari-mutuel betting\nat races run at race meetings held by such corporation or association, a\ntax, which is hereby levied, at the rate of one-half of one percent of\nall wagers from total daily on-track pools. Such association or\ncorporation shall receive credit as a reduction of the daily tax by the\nstate for the privilege of conducting pari-mutuel betting of amounts\nequal to four-tenths percent of total daily pools resulting from the\nsimulcast of such association's or corporation's races to licensed\nfacilities operated by regional off-track betting corporations in\naccordance with section one thousand eight of this chapter; provided,\nhowever, that in no event shall total daily credit exceed four-tenths\npercent of the total daily pool of such association or corporation. An\namount equal to fifty percent of such credit shall be used to increase\npurses; provided, however, that for any twelve-month period beginning on\nApril first in nineteen hundred ninety and any year thereafter, each of\nthe applicable rates set forth above shall be increased by one-half of\none percent on all on-track bets of any such racing association or\ncorporation that did not expend an amount equal to at least one-half of\none percent of its on-track bets during the immediately preceding\ncalendar year for enhancements consisting of capital improvements as\ndefined by section three hundred nineteen of this article, repairs to\nits physical plant, structures, and equipment used in its racing or\nwagering operations, as certified by the commission to the commissioner\nof taxation and finance no later than eighty days after the close of\nsuch calendar year, and five special events at each track in each\ncalendar year, not otherwise conducted in the ordinary course of\nbusiness, the purpose of which shall be to encourage, attract and\npromote track attendance and encourage new and ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph in accomplishing the\nobjectives stated therein. Such report shall also specify the amounts of\nsuch retained percentages and breakage used for investments not directly\nrelated to racing activities and such amounts used to declare dividends\nor other profit distributions, additions to capital stock, its sale and\ntransfer and additions to retained earnings. Such reports shall also\ninclude an analysis of any such agreements or proposals to conduct or\notherwise expand wagers authorized under article ten of this chapter and\npresent its conclusions with respect to the conduct of such wagering,\nthe nature of such proposals and agreements, and recommendations to\nensure the future maintenance of the intent of this article and article\nten of this chapter.\n  b.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Of the sums retained by any other licensed harness racing\nassociation or corporation other than those described in paragraph a of\nthis subdivision, the applicable tax rates for regular bets shall be\nsix-tenths of one percent; for multiple bets shall be one and one-tenth\npercent; for exotic bets shall be five and six-tenths percent and for\nsuper exotic bets shall be seven percent, plus fifty percent of the\nbreaks. Effective September first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, for all\nlicensed harness racing associations and corporations that have entered\ninto a contract with their representative horsemen's association on and\nafter such date, such tax shall be one-half of one percent of all\nwagers, plus fifty percent of the breaks.\n  Provided, however, that for any twelve-month period beginning on April\nfirst in nineteen hundred ninety and any year thereafter, each of the\napplicable rates set forth above shall be increased by one-quarter of\none percent on all on-track bets of any such racing association or\ncorporation that did not expend an amount equal to at least one-half of\none percent of its on-track bets during the immediately preceding\ncalendar year for enhancements consisting of capital improvements as\ndefined by section three hundred nineteen of this article, repairs to\nits physical plant, structures, and equipment used in its racing or\nwagering operations, as certified by the commission to the commissioner\nof taxation and finance no later than eighty days after the close of\nsuch calendar year, and five special events at each track in each\ncalendar year, not otherwise conducted in the ordinary course of\nbusiness, the purpose of which shall be to encourage, attract and\npromote track attendance and encourage new and continued patronage,\nwhich events shall be subject to the approval of the commission for\npurposes of this subdivision. In this regard, expenditures by a county\nagricultural society pursuant to section three hundred nineteen of t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such organization represents more than fifty-one percent of all\nthe owners and trainers using the same facilities and (ii) the\nhorsemen's organization previously approved as qualified by the\ncommission does not represent fifty-one percent of all the owners and\ntrainers using the same facilities. If the commission is satisfied that\nthe documentation submitted with the application of any other horsemen's\norganization is conclusive with respect to subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of\nthis paragraph, the commission may approve the applicant as the\nqualified recipient organization.\n  In the best interests of racing, upon receipt of such an application,\nthe commission may direct the payments to the previously qualified\nhorsemen's organization to continue uninterrupted, or it may direct the\npayments to be withheld and placed in interest-bearing accounts for a\nperiod not to exceed ninety days, during which time the commission shall\nreview and approve or disapprove the application. Funds held in such\nmanner shall be paid to the organization approved by the commission. In\nno event shall the commission accept more than one such application in\nany calendar year from the same horsemen's organization.\n  The funds authorized to be paid by the commission are to be used\nexclusively for the benefit of those horsemen racing in New York state\nthrough the administrative purposes of such qualified organization,\nbenevolent activities on behalf of backstretch employees, and for the\npromotion of equine research.\n  c. Of the sums retained by any harness racing association or\ncorporation, an amount equal to one percent of the total pools resulting\nfrom on-track regular, multiple and exotic bets and an amount equal to\nthree percent of the total pools resulting from on-track super exotic\nbets shall be paid to the agriculture and New York state horse breeding\ndevelopment fund.\n  d. Every harness racing association or corporation shall pay to the\ncommission as a regulatory fee, which fee is hereby levied, six-tenths\nof one percent of the total daily on-track pari-mutuel pools of such\nassociation or corporation.\n  2. The state tax levied adjusted for any credits in this section shall\nbe paid to the commissioner of taxation and finance, on the last\nbusiness day of each month and shall cover taxes due for the period from\nthe sixteenth day of the preceding month through the fifteenth day of\nthe current month provided, however, that su...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\npermission to have wagering conducted outside this state on races run by\nsuch association or corporation, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the simulcasting outside this\nstate of races run by such association or corporation, except for such\npermission or such simulcasting as may be granted to an off-track\nbetting operator in the state of Connecticut by a harness racing\nassociation or corporation located in Nassau or Westchester county. Any\nsuch association or corporation so simulcasting to an off-track betting\noperator in the state of Connecticut shall pay to the New York\ncommissioner of taxation and finance a reasonable tax for such\npermission and privilege for such simulcasting, which is hereby levied,\nat the following rates: one and one-tenth per centum of total daily\nregular and multiple bets; three and one-tenth per centum of total daily\nexotic bets; and three and one-half per centum of total daily super\nexotic bets.\n  5. Tax rates in event of failure to maintain pari-mutuel racing\nactivity. a. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section to the\ncontrary, for any calendar year commencing on or after January first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine, in which a harness racing association or\ncorporation does not conduct a minimum number of pari-mutuel programs\nand pari-mutuel races at its facilities equal to at least ninety percent\nof the programs and races so conducted during nineteen hundred\neighty-five or during nineteen hundred eighty-six, whichever is less, in\nlieu of the tax rates set forth in subdivision one of this section the\napplicable pari-mutuel tax rates for such association or corporation\nwith respect to on-track pari-mutuel betting pools during such year\nshall be as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For such an association or corporation authorized to operate in\nWestchester or Nassau county: of total daily on-track pools resulting\nfrom regular bets, three and seventy-five hundredths percent of the\nfirst five hundred thousand dollars comprising such pools and five and\ntwenty-five hundredths percent of the amount in excess of five hundred\nthousand dollars, plus fifty percent of the breaks; of total daily\non-track pools resulting from multiple bets, four and seventy-five\nhundredths percent of the first three hundred thousand dollars\ncomprising such pools and six and twenty-five hundredths percent of the\namount in excess of three hundred thousand dollars, plus fifty percent\nof the breaks; of total daily on-track pools resulting from exotic bets,\neight and seventy-five hundredths percent of the first two hundred\nthousand dollars comprising such pools, and ten and twenty-five\nhundredths percent of the amount in excess of two hundred thousand\ndollars, plus fifty percent of the breaks; and of total daily on-track\npools resulting from super exotic bets, seven percent, plus fifty\npercent of the breaks; and\n  (ii) For any harness racing association or corporation other than one\ndescribed in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph: of total daily on-track\npools resulting from regular bets, one and one-half percent, plus fifty\npercent of the breaks; of total daily on-track pools resulting from\nmultiple bets, two percent, plus fifty percent of the breaks; of total\ndaily on-track pools resulting from exotic bets, six and one-half\npercent, plus fifty percent of the breaks; and of total daily on-track\npools resulting from super exotic bets, seven percent, plus fifty\npercent of the breaks.\n  b. The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to an\nassociation or corporation for any calendar year for which the\ncommission certifies to the commissioner of taxation and finance:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by December fifteenth of the year immediately preceding such year,\nthat such association or corporation has been assigned for such year,\nfrom the programs and races it requested, at least the minimum number of\nprograms and races prescribed in paragraph a of this subdivision, or, if\nfewer than such number were assigned for such year, that the assignment\nof such lesser number was for good cause due to factors beyond the\ncontrol of such association or corporation or because the commission\nfound that it would be uneconomical or impractical for such association\nor corporation to be assigned the prescribed number; and\n  (ii) by January thirty-first of the year immediately subsequent to\nsuch year, that such association or corporation did conduct such number\nof programs and races as were certified pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis paragraph, or if it failed to conduct such number that such failure\nwas for good cause due to factors beyond its control or because the\ncommission found it uneconomical or impractical for such association or\ncorporation to conduct such a number.\n  c. For any calendar year for which the commission does not certify\npursuant to the provisions of subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_318__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph b of this\nsubdivision with respect to an association or corporation, the tax\nimposed by this section shall be computed by substituting the provisions\nof paragraph a of this subdivision for the provisions of paragraph a or\nb, whichever is applicable, of subdivision one of this section and shall\npay the tax so computed to the commissioner of taxation and finance. In\nsuch computation and payment, all other provisions of this section shall\napply as if the provisions of this paragraph and of paragraph a of this\nsubdivision had been incorporated in whole in paragraph a or b,\nwhichever is applicable, of subdivision one of this section.\n  d. For any calendar year for which the commission does not certify\npursuant to the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of paragraph b of this\nsubdivision with respect to an association or corporation, the tax\nrequired to be paid hereunder for such year shall be equal to the\ndifference between the tax imposed pursuant to the provisions of\nparagraph a of this subdivision and the tax imposed pursuant to the\nprovisions of paragraph a or b, whichever is applicable, of subdivision\none of this section, less one-half of such difference in recognition of\npurses that were required to be paid, plus an additional amount equal to\nten percent of such tax in the event of a willful failure to comply with\nthe provisions of subparagraph (ii) of paragraph b of this subdivision\nand such association or corporation shall pay the tax so computed to the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance on or before March fifteenth of the\nfollowing year. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subdivision, in\nthe event that upon appeal from the determination of the commission that\nthe certification provided in paragraph b of this subdivision will not\nbe made, it is finally determined that the commission erred in failing\nto so certify and that any moneys received by the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance under paragraph c of this subdivisio...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>