<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-322"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-322"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="322"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-322/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-322/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_322">
        <num>322</num>
        <heading>Approval of plans of corporation or association</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 322. Approval of plans of corporation or association. The commission\nshall not grant to a corporation or association hereafter formed\npursuant to sections two hundred twenty-two through seven hundred five\nof this chapter, a license to conduct a harness race meeting at which\npari-mutuel betting may be conducted within the state until such\ncorporation or association shall have submitted to the commission a\nstatement of the location of its proposed grounds and racetrack,\ntogether with a plan of such racetrack, and plans of all buildings,\nseating stands and other structures in such form as the commission may\nprescribe, and such plans shall have been approved in writing by the\ncommission. Such plans shall show that its paddock and barn areas can\naccommodate and serve the needs of horses and horse trainers that\nparticipate in live racing at such facility. Alterations or\ndiscontinuance of existing buildings, seating stands and other\nstructures, and the erection of new or additional buildings, seating\nstands or other structures may be made only with the prior written\napproval of the commission and after examination and inspection of the\nplans thereof and the issuance of a permit therefor by the commission.\nThe commission at the expense of the applicant may order such\nengineering examination thereof as the commission may deem necessary.\nThe approval of the certificate of incorporation of such corporation or\nassociation shall not be deemed to vest in it the right to a license to\nconduct harness race meetings at such race course or racetrack unless\nsuch grounds, track, buildings, seating stands and other structures\nshall be completed in accordance with the plans approved by the\ncommission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>