<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-324"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-324"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="324"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-324/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-324/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-324/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-324/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_324">
        <num>324</num>
        <heading>Free or reduced fee passes, cards or badges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 324. Free or reduced fee passes, cards or badges. A corporation or\nassociation licensed to conduct pari-mutuel betting on harness horse\nraces run at its racetrack may issue free passes, cards or badges to any\nqualified person. A qualified person shall include, but need not be\nlimited to, officers and employees of the corporation or association\nconducting the race meeting, members, officers, and employees of the\ncommission, members of harness racing associations of other states and\nforeign countries, public officers engaged in the performance of their\nduties, persons actually employed and accredited by the press to attend\nsuch meetings, owners, stable managers, trainers, drivers,\nconcessionaires, spouses, domestic partners and children of owners,\ntrainers and drivers, other persons whose actual duties require their\npresence at such racetrack, and any other person or guest deemed\nappropriate by such corporation or association. In addition, free or\nreduced fee passes, cards or badges may be issued to the general public\nor segments of the general public in connection with any promotional\ncampaign or marketing program sponsored by such corporation or\nassociation to increase attendance at live race meets. The issuance of\nfree passes, cards or badges shall be under the rules and regulations of\nthe commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>