<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-328"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-328"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="328"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_328">
        <num>328</num>
        <heading>Disposition of unpaid money due on account of pari-mutuel tickets not presented</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 328. Disposition of unpaid money due on account of pari-mutuel\ntickets not presented.  The sum held by any corporation or association\nauthorized to conduct pari-mutuel betting for payment of outstanding\nwinning pari-mutuel tickets and for refunding the price of pari-mutuel\ntickets shall be retained by such corporation or association for such\npurposes until April first of the succeeding year; provided, however,\nthat ninety-five per centum of such sum remaining unclaimed as of the\nlast day of February of such year shall be paid to the state tax\ncommission by March fifteenth. On April tenth, the balance of such sum\nremaining unclaimed and any other unclaimed amount received in the\ncourse of conducting pari-mutuel betting shall be paid to the state tax\ncommission. A penalty of five per centum and interest at the rate of one\nper centum per month from the due date to the date of payment of the\nunclaimed balance due March fifteenth or April tenth, as the case may\nbe, shall be payable in case such balance is not paid when due. Such\namounts, interest and penalties when collected shall be paid by the\nstate tax commission into the general fund of the state treasury.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>