<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-334"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-334"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="334"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-334/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-334/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-334/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-334/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_334">
        <num>334</num>
        <heading>New York-bred harness horse events</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_334__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>owned by a resident of New York state and standing the entire stud\nseason in New York state, or\n  (ii) owned by a resident of a state other than New York but standing\nthe entire stud season in this state and leased by a resident of this\nstate for a term of not less than one year, or\n  (iii) owned jointly by a resident of a state other than New York\ntogether with a resident of this state and standing the entire stud\nseason in this state and leased by a resident of this state for a term\nof not less than one year.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_334__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Starting fees in such colt and filly stake events shall not be\nless than two percent of the amount of the purse therefor and shall be\nadded to purses to be distributed as hereinafter provided.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_334__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Purses, stakes or prizes shall be paid to the winners, second,\nthird, fourth and fifth place horses in the aforesaid colt and filly and\nhorse stake events, in amounts determined by the fund. Purses and prizes\nshall be paid to the winners, second, third, fourth and fifth place\nhorses in overnight events, in amounts to be determined by the harness\ntrack licensees.\n  2. The fund is further authorized and directed in each year, in\ncooperation with each licensee harness track in this state, to provide\nfor the running of stake events conditioned to admit only two year old\nand three year old colts and fillies sired by a stallion owned or leased\nand permanently standing for service at and within this state at the\ntime of the said foal's conception, at each gait of trotting and pacing,\nto be known as "New York sire stakes" and to contribute to the purses,\nstakes or prizes to be awarded in such "New York sire stakes", such sums\nas the fund shall deem advisable. The fund may establi...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_334__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>foals sired by a stallion standing in this\nstate and bred within this state,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_334__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>foals sired by a stallion standing\nin this state and with a mare bred outside this state, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_334__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>foals\nsired by a stallion standing in this state and dropped from a mare who\nwas bred, and resided, in this state for at least one hundred eighty\ndays in the year of conception. The fund shall provide bonus payments to\nthose foals bred within the state that meet other conditions imposed by\nthe fund. The fund may prescribe a starting fee for such "New York-bred\nharness horse stakes" but in no event shall such fee be less than two\nper centum of the estimated purse for each entry. The fee prescribed\nshall be added to the purses awarded.\n  3. Subsequent to the year two thousand fourteen a foal shall be\neligible for the "New York sire stakes" if conceived from a mare bred in\nthe state and sired by a stallion owned by a resident of this state or\nleased to a resident of this state for a period of no less than one year\nand standing for service within the state at the time of the foal's\nconception.\n  4. The fund shall have the power to prescribe rules and regulations to\ndetermine the eligibility of entries in "New York-bred harness horse\nraces" and to effectuate the purposes and requirements set forth in this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>