<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-410"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-410"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410">
        <num>410</num>
        <heading>Power of commission to impose fines and penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 410. Power of commission to impose fines and penalties. The\ncommission, in addition to its powers to suspend or revoke licenses\ngranted by it, is hereby authorized and empowered to impose monetary\nfines upon any corporation, association or person participating in any\nway in any quarter horse race meet at which pari-mutuel betting is\nconducted, other than as a patron, and whether licensed by the\ncommission or not, for a violation of any provision of this chapter or\nthe rules promulgated by the commission pursuant thereto, not exceeding\nthe amounts set forth in section one hundred sixteen of this chapter.\nThe commission is further authorized and empowered to impose monetary\nfines, not exceeding the amounts set forth in section one hundred\nsixteen of this chapter, upon any such corporation, association or\nperson for a violation of any order issued by the commission pursuant to\nthe provisions of this chapter or the rules promulgated by the\ncommission pursuant thereto, provided that a copy of such order shall\nhave been served, either personally or by registered mail, upon the\ncorporation, association or person to whom the same was directed, prior\nto the occurrence of the violation for which such fine is imposed. Such\nfines shall be paid into the treasury of the state. The action of the\ncommission in imposing any monetary fine shall be reviewable in the\nsupreme court in the manner provided by and subject to the provisions of\narticle seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>