<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-430"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-430"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="430"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-430/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-430/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-430/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-430/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_430">
        <num>430</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 430. Definitions. As used in sections four hundred thirty-one\nthrough four hundred thirty-five of this article, the following terms\nshall mean and include:\n  1. "Fund." The New York state quarter horse breeding and development\nfund corporation established by section four hundred thirty-one of this\narticle.\n  2. "Board." The board of directors of the corporation as such board is\nconstituted pursuant to section four hundred thirty-one of this article.\n  3. "New York-bred." A quarter horse foaled in New York state and\nregistered in the registry administered by quarter horse breeding\nassociations in this state designated by the commission.\n  4. "Breeder." The owner of the mare at the time the mare foals a New\nYork-bred.\n  5. "New York stallion." A stallion standing in New York at the time he\nwas bred to the dam of a New York-bred; a stallion must be registered\nwith the fund or its designated agent and must be:\n  a. Owned by a resident of this state and standing the entire stud\nseason in this state; or\n  b. Owned by a resident of another state but standing the entire stud\nseason in this state and leased by a resident of this state for a term\nof not less than ten years; or\n  c. Owned jointly by a resident of this state together with a resident\nof another state and standing the entire stud season in this state and\nleased by a resident of this state for a term of not less than ten\nyears. Leases shall be filed with the fund or its designated agent.\n  6. "Stallion owner." The owner of a stallion standing in New York at\nthe time he was bred to the dam of a New York-bred.\n  7. "Races." Races upon which pari-mutuel wagering is conducted at\nquarter horse race meetings of racing associations or corporations as\nauthorized by the commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>