<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="503"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_503">
        <num>503</num>
        <heading>Powers of regional corporations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 503. Powers of regional corporations.  Subject to the general and\nspecific limitations of sections two hundred twenty-two through seven\nhundred five of this chapter and the authority of the commission\npursuant to articles one and five-a of this chapter, each corporation\nshall have power:\n  1. To sue and be sued;\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;\n  3. To acquire, hold, lease, rent and dispose of personal property for\nits corporate purposes;\n  4. To acquire, in the name of the corporation, by purchase,\ncondemnation, gift, grant or devise or otherwise, and to use, real\nproperty that is necessary or convenient for carrying out its corporate\npurposes; provided that the corporation shall not condemn any real\nproperty without first having obtained the consent of the chief elected\nofficial in the jurisdiction in which such real property is located. All\nreal property acquired by the corporation by condemnation shall be\nacquired in the manner provided by law for the condemnation of real\nproperty in the jurisdiction in which the real property is located;\n  5. To make by-laws for the management and regulation of its affairs;\n  6. To appoint officers, agents, and employees, to prescribe their\nqualifications, and to fix their compensation;\n  7. To make contracts and leases, and to execute all instruments\nnecessary or convenient to accomplish its corporate purposes;\n  8. To construct such buildings, structures and facilities as may be\nnecessary;\n  9. To accept grants, loans and contributions from the United States,\nand the state or any agency or instrumentality of either of them, or any\nparticipating county, or a city, or any person, including gifts or\ntransfers by bequest or otherwise, and to use the same or expend the\nproceeds thereof for its corporate purposes;\n  10. In the manner and subject to the provisions of sections two\nhundred twenty-two through seven hundred five of this chapter, and\nsubject to the rules and regulations of the commission, to establish and\nconduct within the region a system of off-track pari-mutuel betting on\nhorse races, and, if licensed to do so under article three of this\nchapter, conduct harness race meetings;\n  10-a. In the Suffolk region, to install and operate up to two thousand\nvideo lottery gaming terminals at a corporation's facility which is\nlicensed pursuant to section one thousand eight or one thousand nine of\nthis chapter;\n  11. a. To promulgate, amend and repeal such rules and regulations\nconsistent with the provisions of sections two hundred twenty-two\nthrough seven hundred five of this chapter as it may deem necessary or\ndesirable to carry out the purposes of this article. Such rules and\nregulations shall have the force and effect of law;\n  b. No rule or regulation promulgated by a corporation pursuant to the\nprovisions of this subdivision shall be effective until a copy thereof\nis filed with the clerk of each participating county;\n  c. Any violation of any rule or regulation, filed with the county\nclerk of each county in which such corporation operates and designated\nby the letter "R" by resolution of the board of directors of the\ncorporation, shall be a violation and shall be punishable by\nimprisonment for not more than three months, or by a fine of not more\nthan one thousand dollars, or by both such imprisonment and fine. All\nsuch fines collected shall be payable to the county comptroller in the\ncounty in which the violation occurred and shall be paid by such county\ncomptroller into the general fund of such county. Any such rule shall be\neffective, notwithstanding that any act or omission made an offense or\npunishable thereby may be a crime or violation or punishable under any\nother provision of law;\n  12. When licensed to conduct harness race meetings pursuant to article\nthree of this chapter, western regional off-track betting corporation\nshall be authorized to enter into an agreement to make payments in lieu\nof taxes to the Batavia city school district in an amount that is based\nupon the assessed value of Batavia Downs race track as of the first day\nof January, nineteen hundred ninety-eight and to enter into an agreement\nwith the county of Genesee to pay five-tenths of one percent of the\ntotal deposits in pools resulting from the acceptance of simulcast\nwagering at Batavia Downs race track in order to compensate such county\nfor losses that may occur as the result of the closure of branch offices\nin said county.\n  12-a. To enter into, amend, cancel and terminate agreements for the\nperformance among themselves, licensed racing associations and\ncorporations, and multi-jurisdictional account wagering providers, as\ndefined in section one thousand one of this chapter, of their respective\nfunctions, powers and duties on a cooperative or contract basis.\n  13. To perform such other acts and engage in such other activities as\nmay be necessary and proper for exercising its powers and performing its\nduties under this article.\n  14. Nassau regional off-track betting is authorized to enter into and\nperform an agreement pursuant to paragraph four of subdivision a of\nsection sixteen hundred seventeen-a of the tax law to have video lottery\nterminals authorized pursuant to paragraph three of subdivision a of\nsection sixteen hundred seventeen-a of the tax law hosted within the\nAqueduct video lottery terminal facility.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>