<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-509-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-509-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="509-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-509-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-509-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-509-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-509-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_509_A">
        <num>509-A</num>
        <heading>Capital acquisition fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_509_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amounts specified pursuant to subdivision three-a of section\nfive hundred thirty-two of this chapter; and (ii) contributions from the\ncorporation's pari-mutuel wagering pools, subject to the following\nlimitations:\n  a. no contribution shall exceed the amount of one percent of the total\npari-mutuel wagering pools for the quarter in which the contribution is\nmade;\n  b. no contribution shall reduce the amount of quarterly net revenues,\nexclusive of surcharge revenues, to an amount less than fifty percent of\nsuch net revenues; and\n  c. the balance of the fund shall not exceed the lesser of one percent\nof total pari-mutuel wagering pools for the previous twelve months or\nthe undepreciated value of the corporation's offices, facilities and\npremises.\n  2. a. Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation to the\ncontrary, from April nineteenth, two thousand twenty-one to March\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty-two, twenty-three percent of the\nfunds, not to exceed two and one-half million dollars, in the Catskill\noff-track betting corporation's capital acquisition fund and\ntwenty-three percent of the funds, not to exceed four hundred forty\nthousand dollars, in the Capital off-track betting corporation's capital\nacquisition fund established pursuant to this section shall also be\navailable to such off-track betting corporation for the purposes of\nstatutory obligations, payroll, and expenditures necessary to accept\nauthorized wagers.\n  b. Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation to the\ncontrary, from April first, two thousand twenty-two to March\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty-three, twenty-three percent of the\nfunds, not to exceed two and one-half million dollars, in the Catskill\noff-track betting corporation's capital acquisition fund established\npursuant to this section, and twenty-three percent of the funds, not to\nexceed four hundred forty thousand dollars, in the Capital off-track\nbetting corporation's capita...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>