<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-519"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-519"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="519"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-519/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-519/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-519/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-519/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_519">
        <num>519</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 519. Definitions. The following terms shall mean and include:\n  1. "Region." One or more of the following named regions comprised of\nthe counties indicated:\n  a. Suffolk: Suffolk county;\n  b. Nassau: Nassau county;\n  c. New York city: the five counties comprising the city of New York;\n  d. Catskill: Broome, Chemung, Chenango, Delaware, Orange, Rockland,\nSullivan, Tioga, Dutchess, Tompkins, Westchester, Putnam and Ulster\ncounties;\n  e. Capital District: Albany, Clinton, Columbia, Cortland, Essex,\nFranklin, Fulton, Greene, Hamilton, Herkimer, Madison, Montgomery,\nOneida, Otsego, Rensselaer, Saratoga, Schenectady, Schoharie, St.\nLawrence, Warren and Washington counties;\n  f. Central: Lewis and Onondaga counties;\n  g. Western: Allegany, Cattaraugus, Cayuga, Chautauqua, Erie, Genesee,\nJefferson, Livingston, Monroe, Niagara, Ontario, Orleans, Oswego,\nSchuyler, Seneca, Steuben, Wayne, Wyoming and Yates counties;\n  h. Notwithstanding the other provisions of this subdivision, when and\nif the Central regional off-track betting corporation is established, it\nshall include, in addition to the counties listed in paragraph f, the\nfollowing: Cayuga, Chenango, Cortland, Franklin, Herkimer, Jefferson,\nMadison, Oneida, Oswego, Otsego and Tompkins counties.\n  2. "Exotic bet" or "exotic wager." A single bet or wager on three or\nmore horses, evidenced by a single ticket and representing an interest\nin a single betting pool.\n  3. "Multiple bet" or "multiple wager." A single bet or wager on two\nhorses, evidenced by a single ticket and representing an interest in a\nsingle betting pool.\n  4. "Article". As used in this article may also refer to articles five\nand six.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>