<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-520"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-520"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="520"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_520">
        <num>520</num>
        <heading>General jurisdiction</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 520. General jurisdiction. 1. The commission shall have general\njurisdiction over the operation of all off-track betting facilities\nwithin the state. The commission shall issue rules and regulations in\naccordance with the provisions of this article in order to ensure the\naccomplishment of the purposes set out in section five hundred eighteen\nof this article.\n  2. The commission shall own or lease all communication and\ntransmission facilities used to transmit wagering information between\nregions, as provided by and subject to the exceptions in section five\nhundred twenty-five of this article and may establish a data processing\ncenter, within the amounts appropriated therefor, and provide data\nprocessing services to regional corporations, on a transaction fee\nbasis.\n  3. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, the commission\nshall establish such general regulations to limit the access to\noff-track betting establishments of persons not permitted to bet\ntherein, the availability or use of publications, written materials or\ncommunications equipment therein as the commission determines to be in\nthe interest of public order and the furtherance of the objectives of\nthis article and shall prohibit the sale of food and beverages in all\nfacilities where bets may be placed. The commission shall also provide\nfor the methods for the results of races to be communicated to regional\ncorporations and disseminated thereby.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>