<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-521"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-521"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="521"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-521/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-521/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-521/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-521/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_521">
        <num>521</num>
        <heading>Approval of plans of operation; amendments</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_521__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the association or corporation conducting such racing has entered\ninto a written agreement for such telecasts with the New York city\noff-track betting corporation pursuant to section five hundred\ntwenty-seven of this chapter, which agreement shall terminate no later\nthan the thirtieth day of June, nineteen hundred eighty-five,\n  (ii) all expenses incurred in the implementation of such amendment to\nits plan of operation for such telecasting shall be the responsibility\nof the New York city off-track betting corporation, and\n  (iii) the commission shall submit reports to the governor and the\nlegislature evaluating the results of such experiment on the\ncompatibility with the well-being of the horse racing and breeding\nindustries in this state, and its effect on handle and attendance at\noff-track facilities within Richmond county, and including\nrecommendations regarding the future authorization of the telecast of\nlive audio and visual signals into off-track betting facilities; and\n  b. one other application submitted by an off-track betting\ncorporation, other than the New York city off-track betting corporation,\nto amend its plan of operation, pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection, to provide for the display in two existing facilities within\nits region of telecasts of live audio and visual signals of harness\nracing from any harness racing association or corporation within its\nregion; provided however, that\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_521__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the association or corporation conducting such racing has entered\ninto a written agreement for such telecasts with such off-track betting\ncorporation pursuant to section five hundred twenty-seven of this\nchapter, which agreement shall terminate no later than the thirtieth day\nof June, nineteen hundred eighty-five,\n  (ii) all expenses incurred in the implementation of such amendment to\nits plan of operation for such telecasting shall be the responsibility\nof the off-track betting corporation, and\n  (iii) the commission shall submit reports to the governor and the\nlegislature evaluating the results of such experiment on the\ncompatibility with the well-being of the horse racing and breeding\nindustries in this state, and at off-track facilities within its region,\nand including recommendations regarding the future authorization of the\ntelecast of live audio and visual signals into off-track betting\nfacilities.\n  c. provided, however, that such audio and visual telecasts into\napproved facilities shall commence no earlier than sixty days after such\ntelecasts have been approved. During such time, the off-track betting\ncorporation shall provide to the commission daily data, to include but\nnot be limited to, wagers, separately by type of racing and wagers,\nattendance and promotion expenditures of such facilities in such manner\nas the commission may require. Such data shall be used as the\npre-telecast base to evaluate the impact of such telecasts. In addition,\nsuch similar data and information shall also be supplied to the\ncommission during the period that such telecasts are authorized. No\nchange in the types of wagers offered to patrons may be made without\nprior written approval by the commission of at least thirty days in\nadvance of such requested change.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>