<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-523"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-523"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="523"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-523/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-523/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-523/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-523/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_523">
        <num>523</num>
        <heading>General limitations on off-track betting</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_523__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not less than\none percent on regular and multiple wagering and two percent on exotic\nwagers, shall be paid to the track located within the thoroughbred\nspecial betting district running thoroughbred races, and (ii) not less\nthan three-quarters of one percent of regular and multiple wagering and\none and one-quarter percent on exotic wagers shall be paid to the\nharness track operator conducting racing within the region within which\nthe wagers on such out-of-state races are placed.\n  c. If as a result of the authorization granted in paragraph b of this\nsubdivision, the average daily distribution to harness track operators\nfrom regional off-track betting corporations and attributable to the\nconduct of off-track betting on thoroughbred races run concurrently by\nboth an in-state and an out-of-state track operator during the period\nfrom June first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight through May\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-nine and each succeeding\ntwelve-month period thereafter is less than the average daily\ndistribution to such operators from off-track betting corporations and\nattributable to the conduct of racing by a thoroughbred racing\nassociation during the base period of June first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-seven through May thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight,\nsuch operators shall be entitled to a credit against the state tax\nimposed upon its pari-mutuel revenues. The tax credit for any\ntwelve-month period shall be an amount calculated by multiplying the\nshortfall in the average daily distribution by the number of days in\neach twelve-month period that regional off-track betting corporations\nconduct betting on thoroughbred races run concurrently by both an\nin-state and an out-of-state track operator. The commission shall so\ncertify to the department of taxation and finance the amount of credit\napplicable to each harness track operator no later than thirty days\nfollowing the close of each twelve-month period.\n  7. No regiona...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>