<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-528"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-528"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="528"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_528">
        <num>528</num>
        <heading>Agreements involving other states</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 528. Agreements involving other states. 1. The commission shall be\nempowered to conclude agreements with another state or a racing\ncorporation or association in another state, as the case may be, on\nbehalf of any or all regional corporations for the purpose of conducting\noff-track betting on races run in another state, subject to the other\nprovisions of this article.\n  2. No regional corporation shall conclude such an agreement without\nthe express approval of the commission, which shall be withheld upon a\nfinding that such agreement would be contrary to the purposes of this\narticle or upon the commission's determination to act directly, pursuant\nto this section.\n  3. Subdivisions one and two of this section shall apply in like manner\nto any agreements with another state or any agency, subdivision or\nentity thereof concerning off-track pari-mutuel betting conducted in\nanother state on races run in this state. No franchised corporation, nor\nany racing corporation or association licensed by the commission shall\nenter into such an agreement without the commission's express approval.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>