<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-530"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-530"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="530"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_530">
        <num>530</num>
        <heading>Job security for track employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 530. Job security for track employees. Plans of operation of\nregional off-track betting corporations shall include provision for job\nsecurity for employees of racetracks within each region compatible with\nand in furtherance of the objectives of this article and subject to the\napproval of the commission. Job security agreements that may be\nconcluded from time to time after July first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-three between track employee organizations and the New York city\noff-track betting corporation or any other regional off-track betting\ncorporation shall be subject to the approval of the commission and when\napproved shall be deemed a part of the plan of operation of such\ncorporation and any other regional corporation; provided, however, that\nnothing in this article or any other provision of this chapter shall be\nconstrued to require or empower the commission to abrogate job security\nagreements between the New York city off-track betting corporation and\nany track employee organization, in effect on July first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-three and any such contracts shall be deemed to be a\npart of the plan of operation of such corporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>