<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-531"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-531"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="531"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-531/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-531/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-531/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-531/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_531">
        <num>531</num>
        <heading>Reduction of local admissions taxes as a pre-condition of off-track betting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 531. Reduction of local admissions taxes as a pre-condition of\noff-track betting. 1. Notwithstanding article eight of this chapter and\nsubdivision twenty-four of section sixty-four of the town law, no\nlocally imposed taxes on admissions to harness or running races shall be\nin the aggregate more than three percent of such admissions on and after\nthe first day that off-track pari-mutuel betting is conducted or\ncontinues to be conducted in such locality imposing the tax by a\nregional corporation, pursuant to this article, established for the\nregion in which such races are conducted.\n  2. A regional corporation, except for such corporations consisting of\nonly one participating county or one city, shall annually reimburse any\ncity or town within such region for any reduction in admissions tax\nrevenues equal to the difference between such revenues for:\n  a. the twelve months immediately preceding the reduction required by\nthis section, and\n  b. each twelve-month period subsequent to July thirty-first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-eight.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>