<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-602"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-602"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="602"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-602/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-602/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_602">
        <num>602</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 602. Definitions. As used in this article, the following terms shall\nmean and include:\n  1. "Administrative code." The administrative code of the city.\n  2. "Board." The board of directors of the corporation as such board is\nconstituted pursuant to section six hundred three of this article.\n  3. "Bonds" and "notes." Bonds and notes respectively, authorized and\nissued by the corporation pursuant to this article.\n  4. "Branch office." An establishment maintained and operated by the\ncorporation, where off-track, pari-mutuel bets on horse races may be\nplaced in accordance with the terms and conditions of this article and\nthe regulations promulgated pursuant thereto.\n  5. "Charter." The New York city charter.\n  6. "City." The city of New York.\n  8. "Corporation." The New York city off-track betting corporation\nestablished by section six hundred three of this article.\n  9. "Cost of corporation's functions." All costs and expenses incurred\nby the corporation in connection with the performance of the functions\nof the corporation, including, but not limited to, operating expenses of\nthe corporation, the cost of acquiring, constructing or equipping branch\noffices and other facilities and premises of the corporation, and\ninterest and principal on bonds, notes or other obligations of the\ncorporation issued to finance the acquisition, construction or equipment\nof such offices, facilities or premises.\n  10. "Commissioner of finance." The commissioner of finance of the\ncity.\n  11. "Mayor." The mayor of the city.\n  12. "State." The state of New York.\n  13. "Track." The grounds or enclosure within which horse races are\nconducted by any person, corporation or association lawfully authorized\nto hold such races.\n  14. "Site selection board." The site selection board shall be composed\nof the commissioner of general services, the chief executive officer of\nthe urban development corporation, the director of the division of the\nbudget, and a designee of the mayor of the city of New York; and with\nrespect to a branch office located wholly or partly within a borough, of\nthe city, the president or presidents of the borough or boroughs in\nwhich the proposed site is located.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>