<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-606"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-606"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="606"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_606">
        <num>606</num>
        <heading>Personnel administration; pension, retirement and other benefits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 606. Personnel administration; pension, retirement and other\nbenefits.  1. For the purposes of this section, all employees of the New\nYork city off-track betting corporation on or after the effective date\nof the chapter of the laws of two thousand eight which amended this\nsection shall remain employees of such corporation after such effective\ndate.\n  2. The corporation shall administer its personnel pursuant to the\ncivil service law and the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder,\nand classification and compensation schedules of the state department of\ncivil service, and all other applicable provisions of general laws\nrelating to civil service administration. The corporation shall retain\nall personnel, payroll and associated employee records and shall ensure\nthat the New York city employees' retirement system has access to such\nrecords for retirement purposes consistent with current records\nretention requirements.\n  3. Any officer or employee of the corporation who heretofore acquired\nor shall hereafter acquire such position status by transfer and who at\nthe time of such transfer was a member of the New York city employees'\nretirement system shall, with respect to such retirement system,\ncontinue to have the rights, privileges, obligations and status which\nwould have applied to him if he had continued to hold the office or\nposition which entitled him to such membership prior to such transfer.\nEmployment by the corporation shall constitute city-service for the\npurposes of chapter one of title thirteen of the administrative code of\nthe city of New York.\n  4. All employees and officers of the corporation in classes or\npositions whose incumbents, in equivalent classes or positions of the\ncity, are eligible, as of the effective date hereof, to participate in,\nand receive benefits from any city authorized health insurance or\nwelfare benefit program, shall be eligible to participate in, and\nreceive benefits from any such health insurance or welfare benefit\nprogram; provided, however, that the corporation shall reimburse the\ncity or its designee for the actual cost of benefits under this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>