<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-702"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-702"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="702"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_702">
        <num>702</num>
        <heading>Committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 702. Committee. The Harry M. Zweig memorial fund for equine research\ncommittee is established for the purpose of administering the funds. The\ncommittee shall consist of not less than nine and not more than fifteen\nmembers including but not limited to:\n  1. the chair of the commission, or his or her designee;\n  2. the dean of New York state veterinary college at Cornell, or his or\nher designee;\n  3. a member or the executive director of the agriculture and New York\nstate horse breeding development fund to be nominated by such fund;\n  4. a member or the executive director of the New York state\nthoroughbred breeding and development fund to be nominated by such fund;\nand\n  5. other bona fide residents of the state who have a cogent interest\nin the racing and breeding industry in the state of which at least five\nshall be New York breeders, owners, trainers or veterinarians in equine\npractice.\n  The committee as so constituted pursuant to rules and regulations of\nthe commission is hereby continued, and shall establish its own by-laws\nwhich will include a system for electing its own officers and for\nperpetuating its membership, providing for the terms of its members,\ntheir replacement and succession, and such other administrative details\nas it deems necessary to effectuate the purposes of this article. The\ncommission shall review such by-laws and amendments thereto prior to\ntheir implementation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>