<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-810"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-810"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="810"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-810/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-810/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-810/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-810/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_810">
        <num>810</num>
        <heading>Disposition of revenues</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 810. Disposition of revenues. 1. Revenues resulting from the\nimposition of taxes authorized by this article shall be paid into the\ntreasury of the county or city, as the case may be, and shall be\ncredited to and deposited in the general fund of the county or city and,\nunless restricted by local law to a specified purpose or purposes, shall\nbe available for any lawful county or city purpose.\n  2. Where the race meeting grounds or enclosure is situated in two\ncounties, one of which is wholly within a city, then:\n  a. If the tax is imposed by such city, the fiscal officers of such\ncity shall deposit the revenues of such taxes in a special fund and\nshall pay to the county, not located in such city, within sixty days\nafter collection thereof, seventy-five percent of the moneys in such\nspecial fund, for deposit in the general fund of such county as\nhereinbefore provided, less the expenses for the collection of such tax,\nand except that the sum of five thousand dollars shall be retained at\nall times in such special fund for the purpose of making refunds or any\nnecessary adjustments. The fiscal officers of such city shall pay the\nbalance then remaining in such special fund into the general fund of\nsuch city as hereinbefore provided.\n  b. If the tax is not imposed by such city, but is imposed by such\ncounty, the fiscal officers of such county shall deposit the revenues of\nsuch taxes in a special fund and shall pay to such city within sixty\ndays after collection thereof, twenty-five percent of the moneys in such\nspecial fund, for deposit in the general fund of such city as\nhereinbefore provided, less the expenses for the collection of such tax\nand except that the sum of five thousand dollars shall be retained at\nall times in such special fund for the purpose of making refunds or any\nnecessary adjustments. The fiscal officers of such county shall pay the\nbalance remaining in such special fund into the general fund of such\ncounty as hereinbefore provided.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>