<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-901"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-901"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="901"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_901">
        <num>901</num>
        <heading>Reduction in retained commission</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_901__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the New York city region, any facility, located more than five\nmiles from any thoroughbred racetrack operated by a franchised\ncorporation, for which the New York city off-track betting corporation\nrequests such transmissions of such franchised corporation.\n  (ii) for the Nassau region, one facility located at least ten miles\nfrom any thoroughbred racetrack operated by a franchised corporation.\n  (iii) for the Suffolk region, one facility.\n  (iv) for the Catskill and Western regions, six facilities each,\nprovided, however, that no such transmissions are authorized into the\nportion of the Western and Catskill regions in the thoroughbred special\nbetting district on those days that a thoroughbred track is conducting\nracing in such special betting district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_901__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the Capital District region, six facilities, provided,\nhowever, that no such transmissions are authorized into the Capital\nDistrict region on those days that a franchised corporation is\nconducting races at a track located within such region. Nothing in this\nsubparagraph shall prohibit such region and a franchised corporation\nfrom entering into an agreement to provide such transmissions in\nadditional facilities subject to the restrictions in this subparagraph.\n  c. The commission shall approve the request of each such regional\noff-track betting corporation to transmit the call of the race,\nbeginning January first, nineteen hundred seventy-nine, into an\nadditional, like number of facilities as specified in paragraph b of\nthis subdivision and subject to the conditions in such paragraph.\nProvided, however, that nothing shall prohibit such franchised\ncorporation from entering into agreements with such regional off-track\nbetting corporations designating additional facilities within the\nregions of such regional off-track betting corporations that may offer a\n"live call of the race", except that no such transmissions are\nauthorized into the portion of the Western and Catskill regions in the\nthoroughbred special betting district on those days that a thoroughbred\ntrack is conducting racing in such special betting district.\n  d. Notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary in this subdivision,\nduring and only during the period that such franchised corporation shall\nconduct races at a racetrack not within the counties of Suffolk, Nassau\nand the five counties comprising the city of New York, the track\noperator for such franchised corporation shall provide direct\ntransmissions into all of the facilities operated by off-track betting\ncorporations, except those within the Capital District region and any\nfacilities within a thoroughbred special betting district, other than\nthose facilities authorized to accept wagers on races conducted by such\nfran...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>