<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PML">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-905"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-905"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="905"/>
          <FRBRname value="PML"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pml/section-905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_905">
        <num>905</num>
        <heading>Combination of New York wagers with wagers made in other states or foreign countries</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_905__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All New York state and out-of-state and foreign wagers of the same\ntype shall be combined into single pools for calculation.\n  (ii) As many tentative payout prices as there are different retention\nand breakage rates applicable (including the prevailing New York rate)\nshall be calculated on the basis of returning the appropriate rate of\nreturn, less breaks after imposition of each such rate of retention and\nbreaks.\n  (iii) To each such out-of-state or foreign operator shall be allocated\nan amount sufficient for it to pay the appropriate pay-off to holders of\nwinning wagers placed with it together with the applicable retention\namount on its total wagers.\n  (iv) To each New York operator shall be allocated an amount sufficient\nfor it to pay the appropriate pay-off to holders of winning wagers\nplaced with it together with the applicable New York retention amount on\nits total wagers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_905__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The total amount of the combined pool less the combined total of\nall allocations as determined in subparagraphs (iii) and (iv) of this\nparagraph shall be credited to a special breakage account. The amount in\nsuch account giving appropriate weight to rates established for breakage\nshall be allocated as breaks among all operators in the combined pool in\naccordance with the rules and regulations of the commission. Should a\nminus pool eventuate in which the total combined pool is insufficient to\nreimburse each operator for the allocation due to it then the allocation\ndue to each such operator shall be reduced as may be appropriate and\nsuch operator shall be responsible for satisfying its liability from its\nown operating capital.\n  d. No tax or surcharge shall be imposed by this state on any\nout-of-state or foreign wagering operator participating in any combined\npool herein. Nothing in this paragraph, however, shall impair the\nimposition of any tax or charge by this state on the consideration\nreceived from an out-of-state or foreign operator by a New York operator\nfor its consent to wagering on its races, transmitting the simulcast\nthereof, or the agreeing to combination of bets into its pools.\n  e. The operator of the site of the statewide interface shall be\nresponsible for the actual collection or transmittal of funds in\nsettlement of the liabilities of all operators participating in the\ncombined pool.\n  f. Nothing herein shall entitle any operator or person claiming\ntherefrom to participation in any share of the retention or payouts\nallocated to another operator participating in the combined pool.\n  g. Nothing herein shall affect the validity of any surcharge imposed\nupon the winning pay-offs computed herein as may be prescribed by the\nlaws of this state or another state or foreign country.\n  h. Nothing herein shall be construed to authorize or prescribe any act\ncontrary to federal law.\n  3. Combining New York wagers on horse races conduc...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_905__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that if such combination is authorized that all New York state\noperators must participate therein to assure uniform New York odds and\npay-outs;\n  (ii) that if the out-of-state or foreign computation is made on the\nbasis of different retention or breakage rates and (A) such out-of-state\nor foreign laws do not permit New York wagers to be computed in\naccordance with New York retention and breakage rates, that such\nvariation does not exceed twenty percent and shall be allocated pro rata\namong winning wagers in New York state and recipients of such retention\nand breakage rates in New York state, or (B) if such out-of-state or\nforeign laws do permit New York bets to be computed in accordance with\nNew York retention and breakage rates that such rates shall be applied\nand that the out-of-state or foreign operator doing such calculations is\nwilling and able to properly perform such function;\n  (iii) that the out-of-state or foreign rules governing such wagers are\nunderstandable to New York wagerers and in the best judgment of the\ncommission shall not deviate substantially from customary and standard\npari-mutuel practice in general;\n  (iv) that the New York operators are able to perform such transmission\nand computer retrieval functions as may be required;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_905__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that such combination will enhance the best interest of racing\ngenerally; and\n  (vi) such other rules and regulations as may be deemed necessary and\nappropriate by the commission.\n  b. Nothing herein shall be construed to authorize or prescribe any act\ncontrary to federal law.\n  4. In those instances in which the retention rates of the out-of-state\ntrack are different from the retention rates authorized in this section,\ndistribution to each of the entities entitled to receive payment under\nsection five hundred twenty-seven or article ten of this chapter after\npayment of state taxes and regulatory fees shall be adjusted\nproportionately in an appropriate manner to account for higher or lower\nretention rates. For purposes of determining payment on out-of-state\nwagers the retention rate shall be the amount sufficient to pay holders\nof winning wagers plus any payments required to be made to the\nout-of-state track which exceeds two per centum of handle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>