<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1091"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1091"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1091"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1091/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1091/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1091/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1091/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1091">
        <num>1091</num>
        <heading>Mailing rules; holidays; miscellaneous</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1091__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Timely\nmailing.--</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1091__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any return, declaration of estimated tax, claim,\nstatement, notice, petition, or other document required to be filed, or\nany payment required to be made, within a prescribed period or on or\nbefore a prescribed date under authority of any provision of this\narticle, or of article nine, nine-a, nine-b or nine-c, is, after such\nperiod or such date, delivered by United States mail to the tax\ncommission, bureau, office, officer or person with which or with whom\nsuch document is required to be filed, or to which or to whom such\npayment is required to be made, the date of the United States postmark\nstamped on the envelope shall be deemed to be the date of delivery. This\nsubsection shall apply only if the postmark date falls within the\nprescribed period or on or before the prescribed date for the filing of\nsuch document, or for making the payment, including any extension\ngranted for such filing or payment, and only if such document or payment\nwas deposited in the mail, postage ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1091__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A) Any reference in paragraph one of this subsection to the United\nStates mail shall be treated as including a reference to any delivery\nservice designated by the secretary of the treasury of the United States\npursuant to section seventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue\ncode and any reference in paragraph one of this subsection to a postmark\nby the United States mail shall be treated as including a reference to\nany date recorded or marked in the manner described in section\nseventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue code by a designated\ndelivery service. If the commissioner finds that any delivery service\ndesignated by such secretary is inadequate for the needs of the state,\nthe commissioner may withdraw such designation for purposes of this\narticle. The commissioner may also designate additional delivery\nservices meeting the criteria of section seventy-five hundred two of the\ninternal revenue code for purposes of this article, or may withdraw any\nsuch desig...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1091__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Last known address.--For purposes of this article, a taxpayer's\nlast known address shall be the address given in the last return filed\nby it, unless subsequently to the filing of such return the taxpayer\nshall have notified the tax commission of a change of address.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1091__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Last day a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday.--When the last day\nprescribed under authority of this article or article nine, nine-a,\nnine-b or nine-c (including any extension of time) for performing any\nact falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday in the state of New\nYork, the performance of such act shall be considered timely if it is\nperformed on the next succeeding day which is not a Saturday, Sunday or\nlegal holiday.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1091__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certificate; unfiled return.--For purposes of this chapter, the\ncertificate of the tax commission to the effect that a tax has not been\npaid, that a return or declaration of estimated tax has not been filed,\nor that information has not been supplied, as required by or under the\nprovisions of this article or of article nine, nine-a, nine-b or nine-c\nof this chapter, shall be prima facie evidence that such tax has not\nbeen paid, that such return or declaration has not been filed, or that\nsuch information has not been supplied.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1091__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Attorney general; jurisdiction.--The attorney general shall have\nconcurrent jurisdiction with any district attorney in the prosecution of\nany offenses arising under article thirty-seven of this chapter with\nrespect to the taxes to which this article applies.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>