<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1103"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1103">
        <num>1103</num>
        <heading>Prepayment of sales tax on cigarettes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1103__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every cigarette\nagent shall pay, as a prepayment on account of the taxes imposed by this\narticle and pursuant to the authority of article twenty-nine of this\nchapter, a tax on cigarettes possessed for sale or use in this state and\nto which an agent is required to affix cigarette tax stamps under\narticle twenty of this chapter, at the time that the agent is required\nto purchase and affix such stamps (or as otherwise prescribed by the\ncommissioner pursuant to such article twenty) and the provisions of such\narticle twenty in relation to the use of stamps to evidence payment of\nthe tax imposed by such article twenty shall be applicable to the\nprepayment imposed by this section, except no tax shall be required to\nbe prepaid on cigarettes sold under circumstances that this state is\nwithout power to impose such prepayment or sold to the United States or\nsold to or by a voluntary unincorporated organization of the armed\nforces of the United States operating a place for the sale o...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1103__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The tax imposed by this section shall be paid at the same time and\nin the same manner as the tax imposed by such article twenty with\nrespect to cigarettes. The commissioner may, in the commissioner's\ndiscretion, permit an agent to pay the tax imposed under this section at\nthe same time that the agent pays for cigarette tax stamps under article\ntwenty of this chapter and may require any such agent to file with the\ndepartment a bond issued by a surety company approved by the\nsuperintendent of financial services as to solvency and responsibility\nand authorized to transact business in the state or other security\nacceptable to the commissioner, in such amount as the commissioner may\nfix, to secure the payment of any sums due from such agent pursuant to\nthis section. If securities are deposited as security under this\nsubdivision, such securities shall be kept in the custody of the\ncommissioner and may be sold by the commissioner if it becomes necessary\nto do so in order to reco...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1103__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person other than an agent shall prepay the tax imposed by\nthis section at the same time and in the same manner as the use tax\nimposed by section four hundred seventy-one-a of this chapter. The\ncommissioner may require any compensating use tax imposed by section\neleven hundred ten and pursuant to the authority of article twenty-nine\nof this chapter to be paid at such time after allowing for the credit\nprovided by subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred twenty-one of this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1103__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of the prepayment for cigarettes imposed by this\nsection shall be computed pursuant to the provisions of subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof section eleven hundred eleven of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the taxes required\nto be prepaid pursuant to this section shall be administered and\ncollected in a like manner as the taxes imposed by sections eleven\nhundred five and eleven hundred ten of this article. All the provisions\nof this article relating to or applicable to the administration,\ncollection and disposition of the taxes imposed by such sections shall\napply to the tax required to be prepaid under this section so far as\nsuch provisions can be made applicable to such prepayments of tax with\nsuch limitations as set forth in this article and such modifications as\nmay be necessary in order to adapt such language to the tax so imposed;\nprovided, however, that the provisions of paragraph one of subdivision\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred thirty-seven of this article shall not be\napplicable to such tax required to be prepaid under this section. Such\nprovisions shall apply with the same force and effect as if the language\nof those provisions had been set forth in full in this section except to\nthe extent that any provision is either inconsistent with a provision of\nthis section or is not relevant to the tax required to be prepaid by\nthis section. For purposes of this section, any reference in this\narticle to the tax or taxes imposed by this article shall be deemed to\nrefer to the tax required to be prepaid pursuant to this section unless\na different meaning is clearly required.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this article shall be construed to require the payment\nof the tax required to be prepaid pursuant to this section more than\nonce upon cigarettes possessed for sale or used within the state. When\nthe prepaid tax imposed pursuant to this section is paid, it shall have\nbeen so paid on account of the taxes imposed by this article and\npursuant to the authority of article twenty-nine of this chapter with\nrespect to the retail sale or the use of cigarettes. Nothing in this\nsection shall modify or affect the taxes imposed by sections eleven\nhundred five and eleven hundred ten of this article as applied to\nreceipts from the sale, or to the use, of such cigarettes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1103__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Deposit and disposition of revenue.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1103__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Consistent with sections\neleven hundred forty-eight of this article and twelve hundred sixty-one\nof this chapter, the taxes required to be prepaid pursuant to this\nsection and interest and penalties thereon received by the commissioner,\nafter deducting the amount which the commissioner shall determine to be\nnecessary for reasonable costs of the commissioner in administering,\ncollecting, and distributing such taxes, shall be deposited daily with\nsuch responsible banks, banking houses or trust companies, as may be\ndesignated by the comptroller, to the credit of the comptroller. Of the\ntotal revenue collected or received under this section, the comptroller\nshall retain in the comptroller's hands such amount as the commissioner\nmay determine to be necessary for refunds under this article and\npursuant to the authority of article twenty-nine of this chapter.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1103__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On or before the twelfth day of each month, after reserving such\namount for such refunds and such costs, the commissioner shall determine\nthe amount of all revenues so received during the prior month as a\nresult of the taxes, interest and penalties so imposed and, in addition,\non or before the last day of June and December the commissioner shall\ndetermine in like manner the amount of such moneys received during and\nincluding the first twenty-five days of said months. The commissioner\nshall determine the proportion of revenues attributable to receipts for\nthe period for which the determination is made pursuant to the preceding\nsentence from taxes on sales and uses of property and services and rent\nand amusement charges imposed by this article and pursuant to the\nauthority of article twenty-nine of this chapter and administered by the\ncommissioner which is payable to each jurisdiction determined without\nregard to this section. The amount of revenues so determined pursuant to...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>