<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1202-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1202_D">
        <num>1202-D</num>
        <heading>Hotel or motel taxes in Oneida county</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1202-d. Hotel or motel taxes in Oneida county. (1) Notwithstanding\nany other provisions of law to the contrary, the county of Oneida is\nhereby authorized and empowered to adopt and amend local laws imposing\nin such county a tax, in addition to any other tax authorized and\nimposed pursuant to this article, such as the legislature has or would\nhave the power and authority to impose upon persons occupying hotel or\nmotel rooms in such county. The rates of such tax shall be five percent\nof the per diem rental rate for each room provided, however, such tax\nshall not be applicable to a permanent resident of such hotel or motel.\nFor the purposes of this section the term "permanent resident" shall\nmean a person occupying any room or rooms in a hotel or motel for at\nleast thirty consecutive days, also provided that the county of Oneida\nmay provide in its local law imposing such hotel and motel occupancy tax\nthat such tax shall not be applicable to a hotel or motel having\ntwenty-five rooms or less.\n  (2) Such tax may be collected and administered by the county treasurer\nor other fiscal officers of Oneida county by such means and in such\nmanner as other taxes which are now collected and administered by such\nofficers or as otherwise may be provided by such local law.\n  (3) Such local laws may provide that any tax imposed shall be paid by\nthe person liable therefor to the owner of the hotel or motel room\noccupied or to the person entitled to be paid the rent or charge for the\nhotel or motel room occupied for and on account of the county of Oneida\nimposing the tax and that such owner or person entitled to be paid the\nrent or charge shall be liable for the collection and payment of the\ntax; and that such owner or person entitled to be paid the rent or\ncharge shall have the same right in respect to collecting the tax from\nthe person occupying the hotel or motel room, or in respect to\nnonpayment of the tax by the person occupying the hotel or motel room,\nas if the tax were a part of the rent or charge and payable at the same\ntime as the rent or charge; provided, however, that the county treasurer\nor other fiscal officers of the county, specified in such local law,\nshall be joined as a party in any action or proceeding brought to\ncollect the tax by the owner or by the person entitled to be paid the\nrent or charge.\n  (4) Such local laws may provide for the filing of returns and the\npayment of the tax on a monthly basis or on the basis of any longer or\nshorter period of time.\n  (5) This act shall not authorize the imposition of such tax upon any\nof the following:\n  a. The state of New York, or any public corporation (including a\npublic corporation created pursuant to agreement or compact with another\nstate or the dominion of Canada), improvement district or other\npolitical subdivision of the state;\n  b. The United States of America, insofar as it is immune from\ntaxation;\n  c. Any corporation or association, or trust, or community chest, fund\nor foundation organized and operated exclusively for religious,\ncharitable or educational purposes, or for the prevention of cruelty to\nchildren or animals, and no part of the net earnings of which inures to\nthe benefit of any private shareholder or individual and no substantial\npart of the activities of which is carrying on propaganda, or otherwise\nattempting to influence legislation; provided, however, that nothing in\nthis paragraph shall include an organization operated for the primary\npurpose of carrying on a trade or business for profit, whether or not\nall of its profits are payable to one or more organizations described in\nthis paragraph.\n  (6) Any final determination of the amount of any tax payable hereunder\nshall be reviewable for error, illegality or unconstitutionality or any\nother reason whatsoever by a proceeding under article seventy-eight of\nthe civil practice law and rules if application therefor is made to the\nsupreme court within thirty days after the giving of the notice of such\nfinal determination, provided, however, that any such proceeding under\narticle seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules shall not be\ninstituted unless:\n  a. The amount of any tax sought to be reviewed, with such interest and\npenalties thereon as may be provided for by local law or regulation,\nshall be first deposited and there is filed an undertaking, issued by a\nsurety company authorized to transmit business in this state and\napproved by the superintendent of financial services of this state as to\nsolvency and responsibility, in such amount as a justice of the supreme\ncourt shall approve to the effect that if such proceeding be dismissed\nor the tax confirmed the petitioner will pay all costs and charges which\nmay accrue in the prosecution of such proceeding; or\n  b. At the option of the petitioner such undertaking may be in a sum\nsufficient to cover the taxes, interests and penalties stated in such\ndetermination plus the costs and charges which may accrue against it in\nthe prosecution of the proceeding, in which event the petitioner shall\nnot be required to pay such taxes, interest or penalties as a condition\nprecedent to the application.\n  (7) Where any tax imposed hereunder shall have been erroneously,\nillegally or unconstitutionally collected and application for the refund\nthereof duly made to the proper fiscal officer or officers, and such\nofficer or officers shall have made a determination denying such refund,\nsuch determination shall be reviewable by a proceeding under article\nseventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, provided, however,\nthat such proceeding is instituted within thirty days after the giving\nof the notice of such denial, that a final determination of tax due was\nnot previously made, and that an undertaking is filed with the proper\nfiscal officer or officers in such amount and with such sureties as a\njustice of the supreme court shall approve to the effect that if such\nproceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed, the petitioner will pay\nall costs and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of such\nproceeding.\n  (8) Except in the case of a wilfully false or fraudulent return with\nintent to evade the tax, no assessment of additional tax shall be made\nafter the expiration of more than three years from the date of the\nfiling of a return, provided, however, that where no return has been\nfiled as provided by law the tax may be assessed at any time.\n  (9) Revenues resulting from the imposition of tax authorized by this\nsection shall be paid into the treasury of the county of Oneida and\nshall be credited to and deposited in the Oneida county trust and agency\nfund; the net collections therefrom shall thereafter be allocated by the\ncounty legislature of Oneida and shall be used for the promotion of\ntourism development, economic development, and other directly related\nand supporting activities by a not-for-profit and/or a public benefit\ncorporation under contract with the county. Promotion of tourism and\nconventions being specifically defined as the retaining of staff for the\npurpose of placing and purchasing of advertising promoting the county,\nand engaging in such other efforts as are designed to induce tourist and\nconvention attraction to Oneida county.\n  (10) Each enactment of a local law may provide for the imposition of a\nhotel or motel tax for a period of time no longer than three years from\nthe date of its enactment. Nothing in this section shall prohibit the\nadoption and enactment of local laws, pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection, upon the expiration of any other local law adopted pursuant to\nthis section.\n  (11) If any provision of this act or the application thereof to any\nperson or circumstance shall be held invalid, the remainder of this act\nand the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances\nshall not be affected thereby.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>