<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1210-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1210-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1210-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1210-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1210-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1210-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1210-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1210_F">
        <num>1210-F</num>
        <heading>Sales and compensating use tax for purposes of the Suffolk county water quality restoration fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the taxes\nimposed by section twelve hundred ten, section twelve hundred ten-A, or\nany other provision of this article, the county of Suffolk is hereby\nauthorized and empowered to adopt and amend a local law, ordinance or\nresolution, subject to a mandatory referendum, in accordance with the\nprovisions set forth in section twenty-three of the municipal home rule\nlaw, imposing within the territorial limits of said county an additional\nsales and compensating use tax at the rate of one-eighth of one percent\nfor the period beginning March first, two thousand twenty-four and\nending February twenty-ninth, two thousand sixty, which tax shall be\nidentical to the tax imposed by said county pursuant to section twelve\nhundred ten of this article. Provided, however, that such local law,\nordinance or resolution shall not take effect unless such county\ncomplies with the provisions of subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210_F__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210_F__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\ntwelve hundred ten of this subpart and provides notice to the\ncommissioner in accordance with the provisions of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210_F__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsuch section of the approval of such resolution by the electors. Except\nas hereinafter provided, all provisions of this article, including the\ndefinition and exemption provisions and the provisions relating to the\nadministration, collection and distribution by the commissioner, shall\napply for purposes of the tax imposed by this section in the same manner\nand with the same force and effect as if the language of this article\nhad been incorporated in full in this section and had expressly referred\nto the tax imposed by this section; provided, however, that any\nprovision relating to a maximum rate shall be calculated without\nreference to the additional sales and compensating use tax herein\nauthorized. For purposes of part IV of this article, relating to the\ndisposition of revenues resulting from taxes collected and administered\nby the commissioner, the additional sales and compensating use tax\nherein provided shall be deemed to be imposed under the authority of\nsection twelve hundred ten of this article and all provisions relating\nto the deposit, administration and disposition of taxes, penalties and\ninterest relating to a tax imposed by a county under the authority of\nsection twelve hundred ten of this article shall, except as otherwise\nspecifically provided in this section, apply to the additional sales and\ncompensating use tax imposed pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this article to the\ncontrary, the net collections from the tax imposed pursuant to\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section for the period beginning March first,\ntwo thousand twenty-four and ending February twenty-ninth, two thousand\nsixty shall, upon payment to the county of Suffolk, be deposited in a\nspecial fund, to be designated as the water quality restoration fund to\nbe created by said county therefor separate and apart from any other\nfunds and accounts of the county. Moneys in such fund shall be deposited\nand secured in the manner provided by section ten of the general\nmunicipal law and in no event shall moneys deposited be transferred to\nany other account. In addition to the net collections from the tax,\ndeposits into the fund may include revenues of Suffolk county from\nwhatever source and may include the acceptance of gifts. Pending\nexpenditure from such fund, moneys therein may be invested in the manner\nprovided in section eleven of the general municipal law. Any interest\nearned or capital gain realized on the moneys so deposited or invested\nshall accrue to and become part of such fund. Moneys in said fund may be\nappropriated from and transferred to or expended in any fiscal year only\nfor the purposes authorized by subdivision eleven of section two hundred\nfifty-six-b of the county law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>