<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1212-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1212-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-08-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1212-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1212-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1212-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1212-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1212-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1212_A">
        <num>1212-A</num>
        <heading>Certain taxes of cities of one million or more administered by commissioner of taxation and finance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any city in this state\nhaving a population of one million or more, acting through its local\nlegislative body, is hereby authorized and empowered to adopt and amend\nlocal laws imposing in any such city:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a tax on receipts from every\nsale of the service of providing parking, garaging or storing for motor\nvehicles by persons operating a garage (other than a garage which is\npart of premises occupied solely as a private one or two family\ndwelling), parking lot or other place of business engaged in providing\nparking, garaging or storing for motor vehicles, in any county within\nsuch city with a population density in excess of fifty thousand persons\nper square mile, at the rate of eight per centum, on receipts from every\nsale of such services, except receipts from the sale of such services to\nan individual resident of such county when such services are rendered on\na monthly or longer-term basis at the principal location for the\nparking, garaging or storing of a motor vehicle owned or leased (but\nonly in the case of a lease for a term of one year or more) by such\nindividual resident. The population of a county shall be determined by\nreference to the latest federal census.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of the tax authorized by paragraph one of this\nsubdivision, the following terms shall mean:\n  (A) "Individual resident." A natural person who maintains in the\ncounty in which such tax is authorized to be imposed a permanent place\nof abode which is such person's primary residence.\n  (B) "Motor vehicle." A motor vehicle which is registered pursuant to\nthe vehicle and traffic law at the address of the primary residence\nreferred to in clause (A) of this subparagraph, or which is registered\npursuant to the vehicle and traffic law and leased to an individual\nresident at the address of the primary residence referred to in clause\n(A) of this subparagraph, and which is not used in carrying on any\ntrade, business or commercial activity.\n  (C) A "lease for a term of one year or more" shall not include any\nlease the term of which is less than one year, irrespective of the fact\nthat the cumulative period for which such lease may be in effect is one\nyear or more as the result of the right to exercise an option to renew\nor other like provision.\n  (ii) Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, for\npurposes of implementing the exemption of individual residents from the\ntax authorized by this paragraph, the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance shall, subject to such terms and conditions as it may consider\nnecessary, delegate to the commissioner of finance of any city imposing\nsuch tax the power and authority to develop and administer reasonable\nand necessary procedures, including the use of exemption certificates\nfor presentation to vendors, for determining entitlement to exemption\nfrom such tax, and to prescribe, subject to the approval of the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance, rules and regulations necessary\nand appropriate in carrying out such responsibilities.\n  (iii) Any person who, in violation of any provision of law enacted\npursuant to the authorization contained in this paragraph or any rule or\nregulation promul...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a tax, at the same uniform rate, but at a rate not to exceed four\nand one-half per centum, in multiples of one-half of one per centum, on\nthe receipts from every sale of the following services: beauty,\nbarbering, hair restoring, manicuring, pedicuring, electrolysis, massage\nservices and similar services, and every sale of services by weight\ncontrol salons, health salons, gymnasiums, turkish and sauna bath and\nsimilar establishments and every charge for the use of such facilities,\nwhether or not any tangible personal property is transferred in\nconjunction therewith; but excluding services rendered by a physician,\nosteopath, dentist, nurse, physiotherapist, chiropractor, podiatrist,\noptometrist, ophthalmic dispenser or a person performing similar\nservices licensed under title VIII of the education law, as amended, and\nexcluding such services when performed on pets and other animals.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a tax, at the same uniform rate, but at a rate not to exceed four\nand one-half per centum, in multiples of one-half of one per centum, on\nthe receipts from every sale of any or all of the following services in\nwhole or in part: credit rating, credit reporting, credit adjustment and\ncollection services, including, but not limited to, those services\nprovided by mercantile and consumer credit rating or reporting bureaus\nor agencies and credit adjustment or collection bureaus or agencies,\nwhether rendered in written or oral form or in any other manner, except\nto the extent otherwise taxable under article twenty-eight of this\nchapter; notwithstanding the foregoing, collection services shall not\ninclude those services performed by a law office or a law and collection\noffice, the maintenance or conduct of which constitutes the practice of\nlaw, if the services are performed by an attorney at law who has been\nduly licensed and admitted to practice law in this state. The local law\n...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All provisions set forth in article twenty-eight of this\nchapter applicable to the taxes imposed under section eleven hundred\nfive, including the definition and exemption provisions of such article,\nshall apply in respect to a tax imposed under the authority of\nsubdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, except as to rate and except as\notherwise provided herein. A sale of tangible personal property to a\nperson for use by him in performing a service subject to the tax imposed\nunder the authority of paragraph two or three of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsection shall not be deemed a purchase for resale for purposes of the\ntaxes imposed by article twenty-eight or pursuant to the authority of\nthis article.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>However, with respect to a tax imposed under the authority of\nparagraph three of subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section a refund or credit\nequal to the amount of the sale or compensating use tax imposed by\nsection eleven hundred seven of this chapter and paid on the sale or use\nof tangible personal property which is later used by such purchaser in\nperforming a service subject to tax under such paragraph shall be\nallowed such purchaser against the tax imposed pursuant to such\nparagraph and collected by such person on the sale of such service if\nsuch property has become a physical component part of the property upon\nwhich the service is performed or has been transferred to the purchaser\nof the service in conjunction with the performance of the service\nsubject to tax.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any tax imposed under the authority of subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsection shall be paid with respect to receipts from all sales of\nservices on or after the effective date of such tax although rendered or\nagreed to be rendered under a prior contract. Where a service is sold on\na monthly, quarterly, yearly or other term basis, the charge for such\nservice shall be subject to the tax imposed pursuant to the authority of\nsuch subdivision to the extent that such charge is applicable to any\nperiod on or after the date such tax becomes effective, and such charge\nshall be apportioned on the basis of the ratio of the number of days\nfalling within such period to the total number of days in the full term\nor period.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Wages, salaries and other compensation paid by an employer to an\nemployee for performing as an employee the services described in\nsubdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section are not receipts subject to the taxes\nimposed under such subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All taxes imposed pursuant to subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section\nshall be administered and collected by the commissioner, as provided in\nsubpart B of part III, and shall be distributed by the commissioner as\nprovided in part IV of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tax so imposed pursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall be in addition\nto any other tax which a city may impose or may be imposing pursuant to\nthis article or any other law, and may be so imposed notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provisions of this article or of any other law and\nnotwithstanding that the city may impose or may be imposing the taxes\nauthorized by section twelve hundred ten at the maximum rate authorized\ntherefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A local law imposing a tax pursuant to this section, increasing or\ndecreasing the rate of such tax, or repealing or suspending such tax\nmust go into effect only on one of the following dates: March first,\nJune first, September first or December first. No such local law shall\nbe effective unless a certified copy of such local law is mailed by\nregistered or certified mail to the commissioner at the commissioner's\noffice in Albany at least ninety days prior to the date it is to become\neffective. However, the commissioner may waive and reduce such\nninety-day minimum notice requirement to a mailing of such certified\ncopy by registered or certified mail within a period of not less than\nthirty days prior to such effective date if the commissioner deems such\naction to be consistent with the commissioner's duties under section\ntwelve hundred fifty of this article and the commissioner acts by\nresolution.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certified copies of any local law described in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1212_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis section shall also be filed with the city clerk, the secretary of\nstate and the state comptroller within five days after the date it is\nenacted. Certified copies of any other local law enacted pursuant to\nthis section shall be filed with the commissioner, the city clerk, the\nsecretary of state and the state comptroller within five days after the\ndate it is enacted.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>