<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1262-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1262_S">
        <num>1262-S</num>
        <heading>Disposition of net collections from the additional one-quarter of one percent rate of sales and compensating use taxes in the county of H...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1262-s. Disposition of net collections from the additional\none-quarter of one percent rate of sales and compensating use taxes in\nthe county of Herkimer. Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law,\nif the county of Herkimer imposes the additional one-quarter of one\npercent rate of sales and compensating use taxes authorized by section\ntwelve hundred ten-E of this article for all or any portion of the\nperiod beginning December first, two thousand seven and ending November\nthirtieth, two thousand twenty-seven, the county shall use all net\ncollections from such additional one-quarter of one percent rate to pay\nthe county's expenses for the construction of additional correctional\nfacilities. The net collections from the additional rate imposed\npursuant to section twelve hundred ten-E of this article shall be\ndeposited in a special fund to be created by such county separate and\napart from any other funds and accounts of the county. Any and all\nremaining net collections from such additional tax, after the expenses\nof such construction are paid, shall be deposited by the county of\nHerkimer in the general fund of such county for any county purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>