<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1311"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1311">
        <num>1311</num>
        <heading>Enforcement with other taxes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1311__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If there is assessed a tax\nunder a city income tax imposed pursuant to the authority of this\narticle and there is also assessed a tax or taxes against the same\ntaxpayer pursuant to article twenty-two or articles twenty-two and\ntwenty-three of this chapter or under a local law enacted pursuant to\nthe authority of article two-E of the general city law and payment of a\nsingle amount is required under the provisions of this article, such\npayment shall be deemed to have been made with respect to the taxes so\nassessed in proportion to the amounts of such taxes due, including tax,\npenalties, interest and additions to tax.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1311__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the state tax commission takes action under such article\ntwenty-two or articles twenty-two and twenty-three or under a local law\nenacted pursuant to the authority of article two-E of the general city\nlaw with respect to the enforcement and collection of the tax or taxes\nassessed under such articles the state tax commission shall, wherever\npossible, accompany such action with a similar action under similar\nenforcement and collection provisions of such city income tax.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1311__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any moneys collected as a result of such joint action shall be\ndeemed to have been collected in proportion to the amounts due,\nincluding tax, penalties, interest and additions to tax, under article\ntwenty-two or articles twenty-two and twenty-three of this chapter and\nsuch city income tax.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1311__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever the state tax commission takes any action with respect to\na deficiency of income tax under article twenty-two or articles\ntwenty-two and twenty-three of this chapter or under a local law enacted\npursuant to the authority of article two-E of the general city law,\nother than the action set forth in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1311__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, it\nmay in its discretion accompany such action with a similar action under\nsuch city income tax.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>