<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1449-EEEEE"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1449-EEEEE"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1449-EEEEE"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1449-EEEEE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1449-EEEEE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1449-EEEEE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1449-EEEEE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1449_EEEEE">
        <num>1449-EEEEE</num>
        <heading>Exemptions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state of New York, or any of its agencies, instrumentalities,\npolitical subdivisions, or public corporations (including a public\ncorporation created pursuant to agreement or compact with another state\nor the Dominion of Canada).\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The United Nations, the United States of America and any of its\nagencies and instrumentalities.\n  The exemption of such governmental bodies or persons shall not,\nhowever, relieve a grantee from them of liability for the tax.\n  2. The tax shall not apply to any of the following conveyances:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances to the United Nations, the United States of America,\nthe state of New York, or any of their instrumentalities, agencies or\npolitical subdivisions (or any public corporation, including a public\ncorporation created pursuant to agreement or compact with another state\nor the Dominion of Canada);\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances which are or were used to secure a debt or other\nobligation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances which, without additional consideration, confirm,\ncorrect, modify or supplement a prior conveyance;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances of real property without consideration and otherwise\nthan in connection with a sale, including conveyances conveying realty\nas bona fide gifts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances given in connection with a tax sale;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances to effectuate a mere change of identity or form of\nownership or organization where there is no change in beneficial\nownership, other than conveyances to a cooperative housing corporation\nof the real property comprising the cooperative dwelling or dwellings;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances which consist of a deed of partition;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances given pursuant to the federal bankruptcy act;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances of real property which consist of the execution of a\ncontract to sell real property without the use or occupancy of such\nproperty or the granting of an option to purchase real property without\nthe use or occupancy of such property; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1449_EEEEE__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conveyances of an option or contract to purchase real property\nwith the use or occupancy of such property where the consideration is\nless than two hundred thousand dollars and such property was used solely\nby the grantor as his personal residence and consists of a one, two or\nthree-family house, an individual residential condominium unit or the\nsale of stock in a cooperative housing corporation in connection with\nthe grant or transfer of a proprietary leasehold covering an individual\nresidential cooperative unit.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>