<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1604"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1604">
        <num>1604</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the division</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1604. Powers and duties of the division. a. In addition to the\npowers and duties provided in other sections of this article, the\ndivision shall have the power and it shall be its duty to operate and\nadminister the lottery within the state including any joint,\nmulti-jurisdiction, and out-of-state lottery in cooperation with a\ngovernment-authorized lottery of one or more other jurisdictions, and to\npromulgate rules and regulations governing the establishment and\noperation thereof, including but not limited to the following:\n  1. The type of lottery to be conducted.\n  2. The price or prices of a ticket or tickets in the lottery.\n  3. The numbers and sizes of the prizes on the winning tickets.\n  4. The manner of selecting the winning tickets.\n  5. The frequency of the drawings or selections of winning tickets.\n  6. Without limit as to number, the type or types of locations at which\ntickets may be sold.\n  7. The method to be used in selling tickets.\n  8. The use of vending machines or mechanical devices of any kind.\n  9. The compensation in such manner and amounts and subject to such\nlimitations as the division may determine to licensed sellers of lottery\ntickets, but only where the division finds that such compensation is\nnecessary to assure adequate availability of lottery tickets, and that\nthe public convenience will be served thereby.\n  10. The development of an internal security plan.\n  b. The division is authorized to license agents to sell tickets for\nthe state lottery. The division may require a bond from any licensed\nagent, in an amount to be determined by the division. Every licensed\nagent shall prominently display his license, or a copy thereof, as may\nbe determined by rules and regulations of the division, in each place of\nbusiness or activity where lottery tickets are sold.\n  c. (1) The commission shall make regular reports to the commissioner,\nwhich reports shall include a full and complete statement of lottery\nrevenues, prize disbursements and other expenses, and any other\ninformation the commissioner may require. (2) The commission shall make\nan annual report to the governor and the legislature, which shall\ninclude a summary of lottery revenues, prize disbursements and other\nexpenses for the year preceding such report. (3) The commission shall,\nby January thirty-first of each year, provide the commissioner with a\nlist of the lottery prize amounts, names and social security numbers of\nthe winners of New York state lottery and video lottery gaming\nindividual prizes in excess of one million dollars in the previous\ncalendar year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>