<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1607"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1607"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1607"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1607">
        <num>1607</num>
        <heading>Suspension and revocation of licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1607. Suspension and revocation of licenses. The division may\nsuspend or revoke, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing\npursuant to the state administrative procedure act, any license issued\npursuant to this article. Such license may, however, be temporarily\nsuspended by the division without prior notice, pending any prosecution,\ninvestigation or hearing. A license may be suspended or revoked by the\ndivision for one or more of the following reasons:\n  a. Failure to account for lottery tickets received or the proceeds of\nthe sale of lottery tickets or to file a bond if required by the\ndivision or to comply with instructions of the division concerning the\nlicensed activity;\n  b. Conviction of any offense as defined in the penal law, or any\nfelony under the laws of the United States or under the laws of the\nstate of New York or any other state or foreign jurisdiction or any\ncrime relating to gaming activities;\n  c. Failure to file any return or report, to keep records or to pay any\ntax required by any article of this chapter;\n  d. Fraud, deceit, misrepresentation or conduct prejudicial to public\nconfidence in the state lottery;\n  e. With respect to a lottery sales agent, the number of lottery\ntickets sold by the lottery sales agent is insufficient to meet\nadministrative costs and public convenience is adequately served by\nother licensees;\n  f. A material change, since issuance of the license, with respect to\nany matters required to be considered by the division under subdivision\nd or e of section sixteen hundred five of this article.\n  g. Conviction for misuse of food stamps pursuant to section one\nhundred forty-seven of the social services law.\n  h. A violation of article thirteen-F of the public health law as\nprovided in this subdivision:\n  1. A license shall be suspended for a period of one year upon\nnotification to the division by the commissioner of health of a lottery\nsales agent's accumulation of three or more points pursuant to\nsubdivision three of section thirteen hundred ninety-nine-ee of the\npublic health law.\n  2. A license shall be revoked for one year upon notification to the\ndivision by the commissioner of health of a lottery sales agent's fourth\nviolation of article thirteen-F of the public health law within a three\nyear period.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>