<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1612"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1612"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1612"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1612/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1612/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1612/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1612/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1612">
        <num>1612</num>
        <heading>Disposition of revenues</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the licensee does not hold a license issued pursuant to the\nalcoholic beverage control law to sell alcoholic beverages for\nconsumption on the premises, then the premises must have a minimum\nsquare footage greater than two thousand five hundred square feet;\n  (ii) notwithstanding the foregoing provisions, television equipment\nthat automatically displays the results of such drawings may be\ninstalled and used without regard to the square footage if such premises\nare used as:\n  (I) a commercial bowling establishment, or\n  (II) a facility authorized under the racing, pari-mutuel wagering and\nbreeding law to accept pari-mutuel wagers;\n  (B) the rules for the operation of such game shall be as prescribed by\nregulations promulgated and adopted by the division, provided however,\nthat such rules shall provide that no person under the age of twenty-one\nmay participate in such games on the premises of a licensee who holds a\nlicense issued pursuant to the alcoholic beverage control law to sell\nalcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises; and, provided,\nfurther, that such regulations may be revised on an emergency basis not\nlater than ninety days after the enactment of this paragraph in order to\nconform such regulations to the requirements of this paragraph; or\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>sixty-four and one-fourth percent of the total amount for which\ntickets have been sold for the "Instant Cash" game in which the\nparticipant purchases a preprinted ticket on which dollar amounts or\nsymbols are concealed on the face or the back of such ticket, provided\nhowever up to five new games may be offered during the fiscal year,\nseventy-four and one-fourth percent of the total amount for which\ntickets have been sold for such five games in which the participant\npurchases a preprinted ticket on which dollar amounts or symbols are\nconcealed on the face or the back of such ticket; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fifty-five percent of the total amount for which tickets have been\nsold for any joint, multi-jurisdiction, and out-of-state lottery except\nas otherwise provided in paragraph one of subdivision b of this section\nfor any joint, multi-jurisdiction, out-of-state video lottery gaming; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fifty percent of the total amount for which tickets have been sold\nfor games known as: (A) the "Daily Numbers Game" or "Win 4", discrete\ngames in which the participants select no more than three or four of\ntheir own numbers to match with three or four numbers drawn by the\ncommission for purposes of determining winners of such games, (B) "Pick\n10", offered no more than twice daily, in which participants select from\na specified field of numbers a subset of ten numbers to match against a\nsubset of numbers to be drawn by the commission from such field of\nnumbers for the purpose of determining winners of such game, (C) "Take\n5", offered no more than twice daily, in which participants select from\na specified field of numbers a subset of five numbers to match against a\nsubset of five numbers to be drawn by the commission from such field of\nnumbers for purposes of determining winners of such game; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>forty percent of the total amount for which tickets have been sold\nfor: (A) "Lotto", offered no more than twice daily, a discrete game in\nwhich all participants select a specific subset of numbers to match a\nspecific subset of numbers, as prescribed by rules and regulations\npromulgated and adopted by the commission, from a larger specific field\nof numbers, as also prescribed by such rules and regulations and (B)\nwith the exception of the game described in paragraph one of this\nsubdivision, such other state-operated lottery games that the commission\nmay introduce, offered no more than twice daily, commencing on or after\nforty-five days following the official publication of the rules and\nregulations for such game.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the commission shall make a report on the revenues derived from\nthe additional lottery drawings pursuant to paragraphs four and five of\nthis subdivision and shall submit such report to the governor, the\nspeaker of the assembly, and the temporary president of the senate by\nthe first day of March two thousand twenty-two.\n  The moneys in the lottery prize account shall be paid out of such\naccount on the audit and warrant of the comptroller on vouchers\ncertified or approved by the director or his or her duly designated\nofficial.\n  Prize money derived from ticket sales receipts of a particular game\nand deposited in the lottery prize account in accordance with the\npercentages set forth above may be used to pay prizes in such game.\nBalances in the lottery prize account identified by individual games may\nbe carried over from one fiscal year to the next to ensure proper payout\nof games.\n  b. 1. Notwithstanding section one hundred twenty-one of the state\nfinance law, on or before...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>less ten percent of the total revenue wagered after\npayout for prizes to be retained by the division for operation,\nadministration, and procurement purposes;\n  (ii) less a vendor's fee the amount of which is to be paid for serving\nas a lottery agent to the track operator of a vendor track or the\noperator of any other video lottery gaming facility authorized pursuant\nto section sixteen hundred seventeen-a of this article. The amount of\nthe vendor's fee shall be calculated as follows:\n  (A) when a vendor track is located within development zone one as\ndefined by section thirteen hundred ten of the racing, pari-mutuel\nwagering and breeding law, at a rate of thirty-nine and one-half percent\nof the total revenue wagered at the vendor track after payout for prizes\npursuant to this chapter;\n  (B) when a vendor track is located within zone two as defined by\nsection thirteen hundred ten of the racing, pari-mutuel wagering and\nbreeding law, the rate of the total revenue wagered at the vendor track\nafter payout for prizes pursuant to this chapter shall be as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>forty-three and one-half percent for a vendor track located more\nthan fifteen miles but less than fifty miles from a destination resort\ngaming facility authorized pursuant to article thirteen of the racing,\npari-mutuel wagering and breeding law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>forty-nine percent for a vendor track located within fifteen miles\nof a destination resort gaming facility authorized pursuant to article\nthirteen of the racing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fifty-one percent for vendor track located more than fifteen miles\nbut less than fifty miles from a Native American class III gaming\nfacility as defined in 25 U.S.C. ยง2703</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fifty-six percent for a vendor track located within fifteen miles\nof a Native American class III gaming facility as defined in 25 U.S.C\nยง2703</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>forty-nine percent for a video lottery gaming facility authorized\npursuant to paragraph five of subdivision a of section sixteen hundred\nseventeen-a of this article;\n  (B-1) Notwithstanding subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, for the\nperiod commencing on April first, two thousand nineteen and ending on\nMarch thirty-first, two thousand twenty, for a vendor track that is\nlocated within Ontario County, such vendor fee shall be thirty-seven and\none-half percent of the total revenue wagered at the vendor track after\npayout for prizes pursuant to this chapter;\n  (B-2) Notwithstanding subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, for the\nperiod commencing on April first, two thousand nineteen and ending on\nMarch thirty-first two thousand twenty, for a vendor track that is\nlocated within Saratoga County, such vendor fee shall be thirty-nine and\none-half percent of the total revenue wagered at the vendor track after\npayout for prizes pursuant to this chapter;\n  (C) when a video lottery fac...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, at a rate of\nfifty-six percent of the total revenue wagered at the vendor track after\npayout for prizes pursuant to this chapter; provided, however, that the\nfollowing additional provisions shall apply to such vendor track:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>From the vendor fee amount equivalent to fifty-six percent of the\ntotal revenue wagered at the vendor track after payout for prizes\npursuant to this clause, a portion equivalent to five percent of the\ntotal revenue wagered at the vendor track after payout for prizes shall\nbe defined as and hereinafter be referred to as the "additional vendor\nfee".\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such additional vendor fee shall be accounted for separately by\nthe vendor track and shall be used exclusively for the following\npurposes, in proportions determined annually by such vendor track in\naccordance with a plan submitted to the gaming commission pursuant to\nsubclause four of this clause:\n  (A) reducing the costs paid by non-executive and non-managerial\nemployees of such vendor track for healthcare coverage offered by such\nvendor track;\n  (B) increasing salaries, hourly wages, or benefits paid to\nnon-executive and non-managerial employees of such vendor track, or\nfunding increases in the number of full-time equivalent non-executive\nand non-managerial employees; and\n  (C) supplementing distributions payable to participating counties or\nmunicipalities as required under existing law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Additional vendor fee revenue utilized pursuant to this clause\nshall not be included in any calculation used to determine amounts\npayable pursuant to subclause two of this clause or payments required\nunder subclause two of this clause to the appropriate breeding fund\nestablished pursuant to article three of the racing, pari-mutuel\nwagering and breeding law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A) Such vendor track shall annually submit a plan to the\ncommission, no later than sixty days prior to the beginning of its\nfiscal year, detailing the allocation and use of the additional vendor\nfee revenue among the purposes specified in subclause two of this clause\nfor the upcoming fiscal year. Such plan shall include specific\nprojections for cost reductions in employee healthcare, increases in\nemployee compensation specifying the job titles or categories benefiting\ntherefrom, and supplemental amounts for local distributions.\n  (B) Such vendor track shall submit a plan to the commission, no later\nthan sixty days after the effective date of this clause, detailing the\nallocation and use of such additional vendor fee among the purposes\nspecified in subclause two of this clause for the remainder of fiscal\nyear two thousand twenty-five. Such plan shall include specific\nprojections for cost reductions in employee healthcare, increases in\nemployee compensation specifying the ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such vendor track shall also submit an annual report to the gaming\ncommission, the governor, the temporary president of the senate, and the\nspeaker of the assembly, no later than ninety days after the end of each\nfiscal year, detailing the actual allocation and use of such additional\nvendor fee during the preceding fiscal year. Such report shall specify\nthe amounts applied to each purpose outlined in subclause two of this\nclause, provide data demonstrating the impact on employee healthcare\ncosts and compensation including the specific job titles or categories\nthat received increased compensation pursuant to item (B) of subclause\ntwo of this clause, detail the supplemental distributions made to\nlocalities, compare actual use to the plan, and provide justification\nfor any significant variances.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A) The additional vendor fee shall only be used to supplement\namounts previously allocated or appropriated by the corporation for the\npurposes stated in subclause two of this clause and may not be used to\nreplace or backfill such amounts.\n  (B) The gaming commission shall have the authority to audit the use of\nsuch additional vendor fee by such vendor track. If the gaming\ncommission determines, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing,\nthat such funds have been used for purposes other than those authorized\nin subclause two of this clause or inconsistent with the plan, including\na failure to benefit non-executive and non-managerial employees as\nrequired by item (B) of subclause two of this clause, the gaming\ncommission may impose monetary penalties pursuant to its authority under\nthe racing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law and may require that\nan amount equivalent to any funds used in a manner inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this clause shall be expended fo...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing contained in this clause shall affect any existing\ncollective bargaining agreement or the obligation of such vendor track\nto negotiate terms and conditions of employment with any certified\nemployee representative.\n  * NB Repealed April 1, 2030\n  (iii) less any additional vendor's fees. Additional vendor's fees\nshall be calculated as follows:\n  (A) when a vendor track is located within region one and is located\nwithin Orange county or region two of development zone two, as such zone\nis defined in section thirteen hundred ten of the racing, pari-mutuel\nwagering and breeding law, or is located within region six of such\ndevelopment zone two and is located within Ontario county, the\nadditional vendor fee received by the vendor track shall be calculated\npursuant to subclause one of this clause; provided, however, such\nadditional vendor fee shall not exceed ten percent.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional vendor fee is a percentage of the total revenue\nwagered at the vendor track after payout for prizes pursuant to this\nchapter. That percentage is calculated by subtracting the effective tax\nrate on all taxable gross gaming revenue paid by a gaming facility\nwithin the same region as the vendor track from the percentage that is\nninety percent less than the percentage of the vendor track's vendor\nfee. For purposes of this clause, Seneca and Wayne counties shall be\ndeemed to be located within region six of development zone two.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1612__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional vendor fee paid pursuant to this clause shall\ncommence with the state fiscal year beginning on April first, two\nthousand nineteen and shall be paid to a vendor track no later than\nninety days after the close of the fiscal year. The additional vendor\nfee authorized by this clause shall only be applied to revenue wagered\nat a vendor track while a gaming facility in the same region as that\nvendor track is open and operating pursuant to an operation certificate\nissued pursuant to section thirteen hundred thirty-one of the racing,\npari-mutuel wagering and breeding law.\n  * (B) for a vendor track that is located within Oneida county, within\nfifteen miles of a Native American class III gaming facility, such\nadditional vendor fee shall be six and four-tenths percent of the total\nrevenue wagered at the vendor after payout for prizes pursuant to this\nchapter. The vendor track shall forfeit this additional vendor fee for\nany time period that the vendor track does not ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, any\noperators of a vendor track or the operators of any other video lottery\ngaming facility eligible to receive a capital award as of December\nthirty-first, two thousand eighteen shall deposit from their vendor fee\ninto a segregated account an amount equal to four percent of the first\nsixty-two million five hundred thousand dollars of revenue wagered at\nthe vendor track after payout for prizes pursuant to this chapter to be\nused exclusively for capital investments, except for Aqueduct, which\nshall deposit an amount equal to four percent of all revenue wagered at\nthe video lottery gaming facility after payout for prizes pursuant to\nthis chapter into a segregated account for capital investments.\n  (ii) Vendor tracks and video lottery gaming facilities shall be\npermitted to withdraw funds for projects approved by the commission to\nimprove the facilities of the vendor track or video lottery gaming\nfacility which enhance or maintain the video lottery gaming facility\nincluding, but not limited to hotels, other lodging facilities,\nentertainment facilities, retail facilities, dining facilities, events\narenas, parking garages and other improvements and amenities customary\nto a gaming facility, provided, however, the vendor tracks and video\nlottery gaming facilities shall be permitted to withdraw funds for\nunreimbursed capital awards approved prior to the effective date of this\nsubparagraph.\n  (iii) Any proceeds from the divestiture of any assets acquired through\nthese capital funds or any prior capital award must be deposited into\nthis segregated account, provided that if the vendor track or video\nlottery gaming facility ceases use of such asset for gaming purposes or\ntransfers the asset to a related party, such vendor track or video\nlottery gaming facility shall deposit an amount equal to the fair market\nvalue of that asset into the account.\n  (iv) In the event a vendor track or video lottery...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The comptroller or his legally authorized representative is\nauthorized to audit any and all expenditures made out of these\nsegregated capital accounts.\n  (vi) Notwithstanding subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>through</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph,\na vendor track located in Ontario county may withdraw up to two million\ndollars from this account for the purpose of constructing a turf course\nat the vendor track and may withdraw up to six million dollars in\ncalendar year two thousand nineteen for the purpose of covering ongoing\noperating expenses.\n  (vii) Notwithstanding subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>through (vi) of this\nparagraph, a vendor track located within Saratoga county may withdraw up\nto three million dollars in calendar year two thousand nineteen for the\npurpose of covering ongoing operating expenses.\n  (viii) Any balance remaining in the capital award account of a vendor\ntrack or operator or any other video lottery gaming facility as of March\nthirty-first, two thousand nineteen shall be transferred for deposit\ninto a segregated account established by this subparagraph.\n  1-b. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, free play\nallowance credits authorized by the division pursuant to subdivision i\nof section sixteen hundred seventeen-a of this article shall not be\nincluded in the calculation of the total amount wagered on video lottery\ngames, the total amount wagered after payout of prizes, the vendor fees\npayable to the operators of video lottery gaming facilities, fees\npayable to the division's video lottery gaming equipment contractors, or\nracing support payments.\n  1-c. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the\noperator of a vendor track or the operator of any other video lottery\ngaming facility shall fund a marketing and promotion program out of the\nvendor's fee. Each operator shall submit an annual marketing plan for\nthe review and approval of the commission and any other required\ndocuments detailing promotional activities as prescribed by the\ncommission. The commission shall have the right to reject any\nadvertisement or promotion that does not properly represent the mission\nor interests of the lottery or its programs.\n  2. As consideration for the operation of a video lottery gaming\nfacility, the division, shall cause the investment in the racing\nindustry of a portion of the vendor fee received pursuant to paragraph\none of this subdivision in the manner set forth in this subdivision.\nWith the exception of Aqueduct racetrack, a video lottery gaming\nfacility authorized pursuant to paragraph ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nparagraph a of subdivision eight of section two hundred twelve of the\nracing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law, the state, pursuant to an\nagreement with the video lottery gaming operator to operate a video\nlottery terminal facility at Aqueduct, may authorize, as part of such\nagreement or in conjunction with such agreement at the time it is\nexecuted, additional development at the Aqueduct racing facility. The\nselection will be made in consultation with the franchised corporation,\nbut is not subject to such corporation's approval. The franchised\ncorporation shall not be eligible to compete to operate or to operate a\nvideo lottery terminal facility at Aqueduct. The state will use its best\nefforts to ensure that the video lottery terminal facility at Aqueduct\nis opened as soon as is practicable and will, if practicable, pursue the\nconstruction of a temporary video lottery terminal facility at Aqueduct\nsubject to staying within an agreed budget for such video lottery\nterminal facility and subject to such temporary facility not having an\nadverse impact on opening of the permanent facility at Aqueduct. To\nfacilitate the opening of the video lottery gaming facility at Aqueduct\nas soon as is practicable, the division of the lottery may extend the\nterm of any existing contract related to the video lottery system.\n  f. As consideration for the operation of the video lottery gaming\nfacility at Aqueduct racetrack, the division shall cause the investment\nin the racing industry of the following percentages of the vendor fee to\nbe deposited or paid, as follows:\n  1. Six and one-half percent of the total wagered after payout of\nprizes for the first year of operation of video lottery gaming at\nAqueduct racetrack, seven percent of the total wagered after payout of\nprizes for the second year of operation, and seven and one-half percent\nof the total wagered after payout of prizes for the third year of\noperation and thereafter, for the purpose of enha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Four percent of the total revenue wagered after payout of\nprizes to be deposited into an account of the franchised corporation\nestablished pursuant to section two hundred six of the racing,\npari-mutuel wagering and breeding law to be used for capital\nexpenditures in maintaining and upgrading Aqueduct racetrack, Belmont\nPark racetrack and Saratoga race course. Capital expenditures may\ninclude funding the construction of and initially equipping a\nstate-based equine drug testing and research laboratory to be used\npursuant to subdivision seven of section nine hundred two of the racing,\npari-mutuel wagering and breeding law.\n  (ii) Notwithstanding subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph, in the event\nthe state provides funds to the franchised corporation for the\nrenovation of Belmont Park racetrack, out of the amount payable to the\nfranchised corporation for capital expenditures pursuant to subparagraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph during any state fiscal year, an amount pursuant\nto the repayment agreement between the state and the franchised\ncorporation shall instead be deposited into the miscellaneous capital\nprojects fund, New York racing capital improvement fund as required to\nrepay the state for funds provided for the renovation of Belmont Park\nracetrack. Any amount payable to the franchised corporation in any state\nfiscal year for capital expenditures pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis paragraph in excess of the amount pursuant to the repayment\nagreement between the state and the franchised corporation shall be\ndeposited pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph. Once the state\nhas been fully reimbursed for the costs related to the renovation of\nBelmont Park racetrack, this subparagraph shall no longer apply and\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall apply.\n  4. Three percent of the total revenue wagered after payout for prizes\nto be deposited into an account of the franchised corporation\nestablished pursuant to section two hundred six of the racing,\npari-mutuel wagering and breeding law to be used for general\nthoroughbred racing operations at Aqueduct racetrack, Belmont Park\nracetrack and Saratoga race course.\n  5. Paragraphs one, two, three and four of this subdivision shall be\nknown collectively as the "racing support payments".\n  f-1. As consideration for operation of video lottery gaming facility\nlocated in the county of Nassau or Suffolk and operated by a corporation\nestablished pursuant to section five hundred two of the racing,\npari-mutuel wagering and breeding law, the division shall cause the\ninvestment in the racing industry of the following percentages of the\nvendor fee to be deposited or paid as follows:\n  1. Two and three tenths percent of the total wagered after payout of\nprizes for the purpose of enhancing purses at Aqueduct racetrack,\nBelmont Park racetrack and Saratoga race course, provided, however, that\nany amount that is in excess of the amount necessary to maintain purse\nsupport from video lottery gaming at Aqueduct racetrack, Belmont Park\nracetrack and Saratoga race course at the same level realized in two\nthousand thirteen, to be adjusted by the consumer price index for all\nurban consumers, as published annually by the United States department\nof labor, bureau of labor statistics, shall instead be returned to the\ncommission.\n  2. five tenths percent of the total wagered after payout of prizes for\nthe appropriate breeding fund for the manner of racing at Aqueduct\nracetrack, Belmont Park racetrack and Saratoga race course, provided,\nhowever, that any amount that is in excess of the amount necessary to\nmaintain payments from video lottery gaming at Aqueduct racetrack at the\nsame level realized in two thousand thirteen, to be adjusted by t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one and three tenths percent of the total revenue wagered after\npayout of prizes to be deposited into an account of the franchised\ncorporation established pursuant to section two hundred six of the\nracing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law to be used for capital\nexpenditures in maintaining and upgrading Aqueduct racetrack, Belmont\nPark racetrack and Saratoga race course, provided, however, that any\namount that is in excess of the amount necessary to maintain payments\nfor capital expenditures from video lottery gaming at Aqueduct racetrack\nat the same level realized in two thousand thirteen, to be adjusted by\nthe consumer price index for all urban consumers, as published annually\nby the United States department of labor, bureau of labor statistics,\nshall instead be returned to the commission.\n  (ii) Notwithstanding subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph, in the event\nthe state provides funds to the franchised corporation for the\nrenovation of Belmont Park racetrack, and in the event the amount\ndeposited pursuant to subparagraph (ii) of paragraph three of\nsubdivision f of this section is insufficient to make the required\nrepayment pursuant to such subparagraph during any state fiscal year, an\namount payable to the franchised corporation for capital expenditures\npursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall instead be\ndeposited into the miscellaneous capital projects fund, New York racing\ncapital improvement fund to the extent necessary, when combined with the\namount set forth in subparagraph (ii) of paragraph three of subdivision\nf of this section, to make any required repayment of funds provided by\nthe state related to the renovation of Belmont Park racetrack during\nsuch fiscal year. Any amount payable to the franchised corporation in\nany state fiscal year for capital expenditures pursuant to subparagraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph in excess of the amount pursuant to the repayment\nagreement between the state and the franchised corporation shall be\ndeposited pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph. Once the state\nhas been fully reimbursed for such costs related to the renovation of\nBelmont Park racetrack, this subparagraph shall no longer apply and\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall apply.\n  4. Nine tenths percent of the total revenue wagered after payout for\nprizes to be deposited into an account of the franchised corporation\nestablished pursuant to section two hundred six of the racing,\npari-mutuel wagering and breeding law to be used for general\nthoroughbred racing operations at Aqueduct racetrack, Belmont Park\nracetrack and Saratoga race course, provided, however, that any amount\nthat is in excess of the amount necessary to maintain payments for\ngeneral thoroughbred racing operations from video lottery gaming at\nAqueduct racetrack at the same level realized in two thousand thirteen,\nto be adjusted by the consumer price index for all urban consumers, as\npublished annually by the United States department of labor, bureau of\nlabor statistics, shall instead be returned to the commission.\n  g. In the event the state elects to construct a video lottery terminal\nfacility at the Aqueduct racetrack, all video lottery terminal revenues\npayable to the video lottery gaming operator at the Aqueduct racetrack\nremaining after payment of the racing support payments shall first be\nused to repay the state's advances for</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>confirmation of the chapter\neleven plan of reorganization and cash advances for the franchised\ncorporation's operations following confirmation of the chapter eleven\nplan of reorganization and (ii) the amount expended by the state to\nconstruct such video lottery terminal facility at Aqueduct racetrack\npursuant to an agreement with the state. Subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1612__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of\nthis paragraph shall be defined as the state advance amount and the\namounts payable to the division of the lottery.\n  h. As consideration for the operation of a video lottery gaming\nfacility located in Orange county, the division shall cause the\ninvestment in the racing industry at the following amount from the\nvendor fee to be paid as follows:\n  As amount to the horsemen for purses at a licensed racetrack in\nSullivan county in an amount equal to eight and three-quarters percent\nof the total revenue wagered at the video lottery gaming facility, after\npay out for prizes. The facility located in Orange county, as defined in\nparagraph five of subdivision a of section sixteen hundred seventeen-a\nof this article shall pay to the horsemen at a licensed racetrack at\nYonkers racetrack an amount to maintain purses for such horsemen at the\nsame dollar levels realized in two thousand eighteen, to be adjusted by\nthe consumer price index for all urban consumers, as published annually\nby the United States department of labor bureau of labor statistics. In\naddition, one and one-quarter percent of total revenue wagered at the\nvideo lottery gaming facility after pay out for prizes, received\npursuant to clause (B) of subparagraph (ii) of paragraph one of\nsubdivision b of this section, shall be distributed to the appropriate\nbreeding fund for the manner of racing conducted by such track. In no\ncircumstance shall net proceeds of the lottery, including the proceeds\nfrom video lottery gaming, be used for the payment of non-lottery\nexpenses of the gaming commission, administrative or otherwise.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>