<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1613"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1613"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1613"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1613/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1613/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1613/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1613/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1613">
        <num>1613</num>
        <heading>Certification of prize winners; payment of prizes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the claimant has filed a perfected claim therefor;\n  (ii) the perfected claim is for a first prize in excess of five\nmillion dollars;\n  (iii) at least one year has elapsed since the date of the drawing for\nwhich the prize is claimed;\n  (iv) no other perfected claim has been filed therefor; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the perfected claim has been authenticated by the division.\n  2. For purposes of this section, a "perfected claim" shall consist of\na written request that the prize be awarded and paid to the claimant,\naccompanied by:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a "Players Copy" of a claim validation report showing that the\noriginal winning lottery ticket was produced by the on-line lottery\ncomputer system at the same time and place as the validation of a\nprevious first-prize claim in the "Daily Numbers" game;\n  (ii) "Lotto" play cards bearing the same number combinations as were\nplayed at such time and place immediately before or immediately\nfollowing the validation of such "Daily Numbers" first prize claim;\n  (iii) a written statement from the licensed lottery sales agent\nstating that the agent believes the missing ticket was sold to the\nclaimant;\n  (iv) a verified written statement explaining the circumstances under\nwhich the winning ticket was lost; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a filing fee of one hundred dollars.\n  3. Within thirty days of the receipt of a perfected claim, the\ndivision shall attempt to authenticate it by comparing it to the records\nof the division, including electronic information provided by its\non-line service provider. A perfected claim may be deemed\n"authenticated" if:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the "Players Copy" and "Lotto" play cards included therewith\ncorrespond to the records of the division; and\n  (ii) none of the information included in the perfected claim is\ncontradicted by the records of the division.\n  4. The director may promulgate rules and regulations to implement the\nprovisions of this subdivision.\n  d. 1. The right of any person to receive payments under a prize that\nis paid in installments over time by the division may be voluntarily\nassigned, in whole or in part, if the assignment is made to a person or\nentity designated pursuant to an order of the supreme court of the\ncounty where the assigning prize winner resides or where the\nheadquarters of the division is located. A court may issue an order\napproving a voluntary assignment and directing the division to make\nprize payments in whole or in part to the designated assignee, if the\ncourt finds that all of the following conditions have been met:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The assignment is in writing, is executed by the assignor, and is,\nby its terms, subject to the laws of this state.\n  (ii) The purchase price being paid for the payments being assigned\nrepresents a present value of the payments being assigned, discounted at\nan annual rate that does not exceed ten percentage points over the Wall\nStreet Journal prime rate published on the business day prior to the\ndate of execution of the contract.\n  (iii) The contract of assignment expressly states that the assignor\nhas three business days after the contract was signed to cancel the\nassignment.\n  (iv) The assignor provides a sworn affidavit attesting that he or she:\n  (A) Is of sound mind, is in full command of his or her faculties, and\nis not acting under duress;\n  (B) Has been advised regarding the assignment by his or her own\nindependent legal counsel, who is unrelated to and is not being\ncompensated by the assignee or any of the assignee's affiliates, and has\nreceived independent financial or tax advice concerning the effects of\nthe assignment from a lawyer or other professional who is unrelated to\nand is not being compensated by the assignee or any of the assignee's\naffiliates;\n  (C) Understands that he or she will not receive the prize payments or\nportions thereof for the years assigned;\n  (D) Understands and agrees that, with regard to the assigned payments,\nthe division and its officials and employees will have no further\nliability or responsibility to make the assigned payments to him or her;\n  (E) Has been provided with a one-page written disclosure statement\nsetting forth, in bold type of not less than fourteen points, the\npayments being assigned, by amounts and payment dates; the purchase\nprice being paid; the rate of discount to present value, assuming daily\ncompounding and funding on the contract date; and the amount, if any, of\nany origination or closing fees that will be charged to him or her; and\n  (F) Was advised in writing, at the tim...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Written notice of the proposed assignment and any court hearing\nconcerning the proposed assignment is provided to the division's counsel\nat least thirty days prior to any court hearing. The division is not\nrequired to appear in or be named as a party to any such action seeking\njudicial confirmation of an assignment under this subdivision, but may\nintervene as of right in any such proceeding.\n  2. A certified copy of a court order approving a voluntary assignment\nmust be provided to the division no later than thirty days before the\ndate on which the payment is to be made.\n  3. A court order obtained pursuant to this section, together with all\nsuch prior orders, shall not require the division to divide any single\nprize payment among more than three different persons. Nothing in this\nsection shall prohibit substituting assignees as long as there are no\nmore than three assignees at any one time for any one-prize payment.\n  4. If a husband and wife are co-owners of a prize, any assignment of\nthe prize must be made jointly.\n  5. A voluntary assignment may not include portions of payments that\nare subject to offset on account of a defaulted or delinquent child\nsupport obligation, non-wage garnishment, or criminal restitution\nobligation or on account of a debt owed to a state agency. Each court\norder issued under paragraph one of this subdivision shall provide that\nany delinquent child support or criminal restitution obligations of the\nassigning prize winner and any debts owed to a state agency by the\nassigning prize winner, as of the date of the court order, shall be set\noff by the division first against remaining payments or portions thereof\ndue the prize winner and then against payments due the assignee.\n  6. The division and its respective officials and employees shall be\ndischarged of all liability upon payment of an assigned prize under this\nsubdivision. The assignor and assignee shall hold harmless and indemnify\nthe division, the state of...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A summary of assignee contacts with the winner;\n  (ii) A summary of any law suits, claims, and other legal actions from\nlottery winners regarding conduct of the assignee or its agents;\n  (iii) A statement that the assignee is in good standing in its state\nof domicile and with any other licensing or regulatory agency as may be\nrequired in the conduct of its business;\n  (iv) A brief business history of the assignee;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1613__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement describing the nature of the business of the assignee;\nand\n  (vi) A statement of the assignee's privacy and non-harassment policies\nand express affirmation that the assignee has followed those policies in\nNew York.\n  10. The assignee shall notify the division of its business location\nand mailing address for payment purposes during the entire course of the\nassignment. The division shall be discharged of all further liability\nupon payment of a prize pursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>