<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="171-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_171_D">
        <num>171-D</num>
        <heading>Certain overpayments credited against defaulted governmental education loans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the procedure under which the New York state higher education\nservices corporation shall notify the commissioner of a default in\nrepayment of a governmental education loan, such procedure to specify\nwhen the commissioner shall be notified and the content of such\nnotification;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the minimum amount outstanding on a default in repayment of a\ngovernmental education loan against which the commissioner shall,\npursuant to this section, credit an overpayment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the procedure for reimbursement of the commissioner by the New\nYork state higher education services corporation for the full cost of\ncarrying out the procedures authorized by this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such other matters as the parties to such agreement shall deem\nnecessary to carry out the provisions of this section; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the procedure for reimbursement of the comptroller by the New York\nstate higher education services corporation for overpayment and interest\nthereon which has been credited against the amount of default in\nrepayment of a governmental education loan owed by a taxpayer filing a\njoint return, but which has been refunded by the comptroller, pursuant\nto paragraph six of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section six hundred fifty-one of\nthis chapter, to a spouse not liable for the amount of default in\nrepayment of a governmental education loan owed by such taxpayer.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_D__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In calculating the amount of an overpayment and interest\nthereon which shall be credited against the amount of a default in\nrepayment of a governmental education loan owed by a taxpayer, the\ncommissioner shall first credit the overpayment and interest thereon\nagainst any:\n  (A) liability of such taxpayer in respect of any tax imposed by this\nchapter;\n  (B) liability of such taxpayer for any tax imposed pursuant to the\nauthority of this chapter or any other law if such tax is administered\nby the tax commission;\n  (C) estimated tax for the succeeding taxable year if such taxpayer\nclaims such overpayment or a portion thereof as a credit against\nestimated tax for such succeeding taxable year pursuant to subsection\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section six hundred eighty-six of this chapter or subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof section 11-1786 of the administrative code of the city of New York\nfor any tax imposed pursuant to the authority of this chapter or any\nother law if such tax is administered by the tax commission; and\n  (D) past-due support owed by the taxpayer pursuant to section one\nhundred seventy-one-c of this article.\n  (E) the amount of a default in repayment of a state university loan or\ncity university loan pursuant to section one hundred seventy-one-e of\nthis article.\n  (F) the amount of a past-due legally enforceable debt owed to a state\nagency pursuant to section one hundred seventy-one-f of this article.\n  (G) the amount of a city of New York tax warrant judgment debt owed to\nthe city of New York pursuant to section one hundred seventy-one-l of\nthis article.\n  (ii) Only the balance remaining, after such overpayment and the\ninterest thereon has been credited as described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, shall be certified as an overpayment plus any interest to\nbe credited against the amount of a default in repayment of a\ngovernmental education loan, with the remainder to be refunded to the\ntaxpayer.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_D__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The tax commission shall certify to the comptroller the total\namount of the overpayment and the interest on such overpayment, the\namount of such overpayment and the interest on such amount to be\ncredited against the amount of the default in repayment of a\ngovernmental education loan and the balance of such overpayment and\ninterest to be refunded to the taxpayer.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_D__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall notify the taxpayer making the overpayment,\nin writing, of the amount of such overpayment and the interest thereon\ncertified to the comptroller as the amount to be credited against the\namount of a default in repayment of a governmental education loan. Such\nnotice shall include notification to any other person who may have filed\na joint return with the taxpayer of the steps such other person may take\nin order to secure his or her proper share of the refund.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_D__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>From the time the state tax commission is notified by the New York\nstate higher education services corporation of an individual's, estate's\nor trust's default in repayment of a governmental education loan under\nthe agreement provided for in this section, the state tax commission and\nthe department shall be relieved from all liability to such individual,\nestate or trust, their assigns, successors, heirs or representatives for\nthe amount of an overpayment and interest on such amount certified to\nthe comptroller to be credited against the amount of default in\nrepayment of a governmental education loan and such individual, estate\nor trust shall have no right to commence a court action or proceeding or\nto any other legal recourse against the state tax commission or the\ndepartment to recover such overpayment or such interest certified to the\ncomptroller to be credited against the amount of default in repayment of\na governmental education loan. Provided, however, nothing herein s...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_D__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The tax commission shall promulgate such rules and regulations as\nit deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>