<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-R"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-R"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="171-R"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_171_R">
        <num>171-R</num>
        <heading>Brownfield credit report</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_R__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, in\nconsultation with the commissioner of environmental conservation, must\npublish a brownfield credit report annually by January thirty-first. The\nfirst report must be published by January thirty-first, two thousand\nnine.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The brownfield credit report must contain the following\ninformation about the credits claimed under sections twenty-one,\ntwenty-two and twenty-three of this chapter during the previous calendar\nyear:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_R__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name of each taxpayer claiming a credit; provided however, if\nthe taxpayer claims a credit because the taxpayer is a member of a\nlimited liability company, a partner in a partnership or a shareholder\nin a subchapter S corporation, the name of each limited liability\ncompany, partnership or subchapter S corporation earning any of those\ncredits must be included in the report instead of information about the\ntaxpayer claiming the credit;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_R__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount of each credit earned by each taxpayer; provided\nhowever, if the taxpayer claims a credit because the taxpayer is a\nmember of a limited liability company, a partner in a partnership or a\nshareholder in a subchapter S corporation, the amount of credit earned\nby each entity must be included in the report instead of information\nabout the taxpayer claiming the credit;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_R__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>information identifying the project for which a certificate of\ncompletion was issued and the credit claimed under section twenty-one,\ntwenty-two or twenty-three of this chapter, including the name of the\nproject and municipality, including the county, in which the project is\nlocated; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_R__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the number of credits by each credit type and the amount of such\ncredits granted, claimed and earned on a brownfield site, statewide and\ndepartment of environmental conservation region basis; and of those, the\nnumber of credits and the average amount of such credits allowed to\ntaxpayers in each county, brownfield opportunity area designated\npursuant to section nine hundred seventy-r of the general municipal law\nand in each environmental zone as defined in subdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\ntwenty-one of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171_R__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>copies of all reports received from developers pursuant to section\none hundred seventy-one-s of this article or, in the commissioner's\ndiscretion, a summary of the contents of such reports.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_R__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The information included in the brownfield credit report will be\nbased on the information filed with the department during the previous\ncalendar year, to the extent that it is practicable to use that\ninformation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_R__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such report shall also contain any other information received from\nthe commissioner of environmental conservation with regard to such\ncredits, and any other statistical information that such commissioner\ndeems to be useful in analyzing the effects of the program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171_R__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of\nenvironmental conservation, shall publish by January thirty-first, two\nthousand sixteen a supplemental brownfield credit report containing the\ninformation required by this section about the credits claimed for the\nyears two thousand five, two thousand six, and two thousand seven.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>