<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-174-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-174-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="174-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-174-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-174-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-174-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-174-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_174_B">
        <num>174-B</num>
        <heading>Limitation on the time to collect tax liabilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section six hundred ninety or subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection one thousand ninety of this chapter, unless the commissioner\nassesses the liability under either such subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>. When there is a\nright to a hearing with respect to a notice and demand for a tax\nliability, the first date a warrant could be filed means the day that\nopportunity for a hearing or review has been exhausted.\n  2. This section shall apply to any tax that is administered by the\ncommissioner. Any reference to "tax" in this section shall be deemed\nalso to refer to special assessments, fees, interest, additions to tax,\npenalties and other impositions that are administered by the\ncommissioner.\n  3. When, before the expiration of the time prescribed in this section\nto enforce the collection of tax, both the commissioner and the taxpayer\nhave consented in writing to its collection after such time, the tax\nliability shall not be extinguished and the tax may be collected at any\ntime prior to the expiration of the period agreed upon. The period so\nagreed upon may be extended by any subsequent agreement in writing made\nbefore the expiration of the period previously agreed upon.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall supplement or be in addition\nto the procedures relating to collection or administration provided with\nrespect to any tax covered by this section. Where a provision of this\nsection is inconsistent with any such provision with respect to such\ntax, the provisions of this section shall apply. For purposes of\nsubsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section six hundred ninety-two and subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_174_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection one thousand ninety-two of this chapter, if the commissioner\ndoes not file a warrant within six years of assessment, the time\nlimitations in this section shall not apply and the tax liability is\nextinguished. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the\ncommissioner from accepting any payment for a tax liability made\nvoluntarily by a taxpayer after the time to collect such liability has\nexpired and the liability is extinguished. When a warrant is filed, the\ncommissioner may include a date on that warrant indicating when such\nwarrant expires and tax liability is extinguished.\n  5. If a tax liability could have been first warranted before the\neffective date of this section, such liability shall not be enforceable\nand shall be extinguished after twenty years from the first date the\nwarrant could have been filed by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>