<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="187-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_187_Q">
        <num>187-Q</num>
        <heading>Utility COVID-19 debt relief credit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_187_Q__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section one\nthousand eighty-eight of this chapter notwithstanding, no interest shall\nbe paid thereon.\n  3. Certification. No amount of waived customer debt may be the basis\nfor the credit herein unless such amount is certified by the public\nservice commission as provided herein. After consulting with the\ncommissioner, the public service commission shall establish procedures\nfor determining the amount of waived customer debt that may be used as a\nbasis for the tax credit allowed by this section. Such procedures shall\ninclude provisions describing the application process, application due\ndates, the documentation that will be provided by taxpayers to\nsubstantiate the amount of customer debt that was waived by such\ntaxpayers, the process by which the public service commission shall\ncertify to a taxpayer and to the commissioner the amount of waived\ncustomer debt that qualifies for the credit, and such other provisions\nas deemed necessary and appropriate.\n  4. Timing of credit. The credit allowed by this section shall be\nclaimed in the taxable year in which the public service commission\ncertifies the amount of customer debt waived by the taxpayer that\nqualifies for the credit allowed by this section.\n  5. Credit recapture. If the certification made by the public service\ncommission under subdivision three of this section is revoked by the\npublic service commission, the amount of credit described in this\nsection and claimed by the taxpayer prior to that revocation shall be\nadded back to the tax in the taxable year in which such revocation\nbecomes final.\n  6. Information sharing. Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter,\nemployees and officers of the public service commission and the\ndepartment shall be allowed and are directed to share and exchange\ninformation regarding the credits allowed, or claimed, pursuant to this\nsection, and the taxpayers who are applying for credits or who are\nclaiming credits, including information contained i...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>