<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-N*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-N*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="187-N*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-N*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-N*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-N*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-N*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_187_N*2">
        <num>187-N*2</num>
        <heading>Fuel cell electric generating equipment expenditures credit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_187_N*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Qualified fuel cell electric generating equipment expenditures are\nthe costs, incurred on or after July first, two thousand five,\nassociated with the purchase of on-site electricity generation units\nutilizing proton exchange membrane fuel cells, providing a rated\nbaseload capacity of no less than one kilowatt of electricity and no\nmore than one hundred kilowatts of electricity, which are located in\nthis state at the time the qualified fuel cell electric generating\nequipment is placed in service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_187_N*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Qualified fuel cell electric generating equipment expenditures\nshall also include costs, incurred on or after July first, two thousand\nfive, for materials, labor for on-site preparation, assembly and\noriginal installation, engineering services, designs and plans directly\nrelated to construction or installation and utility compliance costs.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_187_N*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such qualified expenditures shall not include interest or other\nfinance charges.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_187_N*2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amount of any federal, state or local grant received by the\ntaxpayer, which was used for the purchase and/or installation of such\nequipment and which was not included in the federal gross income of the\ntaxpayer, shall not be included in the amount of such qualified\nexpenditures.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_187_N*2__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Application of credit. In no event shall the credit under this\nsection be allowed in an amount which will reduce the tax payable to\nless than the applicable minimum tax fixed by section one hundred\neighty-three of this article. If, however, the amount of credit\nallowable under this section for any taxable year reduces the tax to\nsuch amount, any amount of credit not deductible in such taxable year\nmay be carried over to the following year or years and may be deducted\nfrom the taxpayer's tax for such year or years.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 187-n's\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>