<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-192"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-192"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="192"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-192/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-192/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-192/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-192/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_192">
        <num>192</num>
        <heading>Reports of corporations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_192__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as hereinafter provided in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_192__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, every insurance corporation liable to pay a tax under\nsection one hundred eighty-seven of this chapter shall, on or before\nMarch first, June first, September first and December first in each\nyear, make a written report to the tax commission and to the\nsuperintendent of financial services covering the quarter year ending on\nthe last day of the third month preceding that in which the report is\nrequired to be filed, in such form and containing such information as\nthe tax commission may deem necessary for the determination of the tax\ndue for each such quarter year. There shall also be filed with the tax\ncommission and with the superintendent of financial services, on or\nbefore March fifteenth of each year, a statement which will reconcile\nthe net taxable premiums shown in the quarterly reports, made pursuant\nto this section, for the preceding calendar year, with the total gross\nand net premiums shown in the annual statement of the insurance\ncorporation filed with said superintendent of financial services for\nsuch year pursuant to section three hundred seven of the insurance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_192__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every insurance corporation liable to pay a tax under subdivisions\nsix and eight of section one hundred eighty-seven of this chapter shall,\non or before the fifteenth day of March, make and file a written report\nwith the tax commission and with the superintendent of financial\nservices, covering the preceding calendar year, in such form and\ncontaining such information as the tax commission may deem necessary for\nthe determination of the tax imposed by said subdivisions, and such\ncalendar year shall be deemed the taxable year within the meaning of\nthis section and of said subdivisions, provided, however that insurance\ncorporations liable to pay tax under subdivision eight of section one\nhundred eighty-seven shall be required to make the reports required\nherein only on the fifteenth day of March in the years nineteen hundred\nsixty-five through and including nineteen hundred seventy-six.\n  5. Notwithstanding the provisions of section two hundred two of this\narticle, the commissioner shall provide the statements and other\nrequired information requested on tax reports under section four hundred\neight of the business corporation law to the secretary of state for\nfiling. Such provision may also include a copy or image of that portion\nof the report solely pertinent to such information to the extent\nfeasible. The commissioner may also provide information on\nnoncompliance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>