<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-194"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-194"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="194"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-194/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-194/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-194/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-194/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_194">
        <num>194</num>
        <heading>Further requirements as to reports of corporations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_194__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section seventy-seven hundred one\nof the internal revenue code (including a limited liability company), a\npublicly traded partnership treated as a corporation for purposes of the\ninternal revenue code pursuant to section seventy-seven hundred four\nthereof and any business conducted by a trustee or trustees wherein\ninterest or ownership is evidenced by certificates or other written\ninstruments, such certification shall be made by any person duly\nauthorized so to act on behalf of such association, publicly traded\npartnership, limited liability company or business. The fact that an\nindividual's name is signed on a certification attached to a report\nshall be prima facie evidence that such individual is authorized to\ncertify the report on behalf of the taxpayer. Such reports shall contain\nany other data, information or matter which the commissioner may require\nto be included therein, and it may prescribe the form in which such\nreports shall be made.  When so prescribed such forms shall be used in\nmaking the report. The commissioner may require at any time a further or\nsupplemental report under this article, which shall contain information\nand data upon such matters as the commissioner may specify.  Reports\nshall be preserved for five years, and thereafter until the commissioner\norders them to be destroyed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>