<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-209-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-209-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-209-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-209-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-209-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-209-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_O">
        <num>209-O</num>
        <heading>Retired and rescued standardbred race horse aftercare</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 209-O. Retired and rescued standardbred race horse aftercare.\nEffective for any tax year commencing on or after the effective date of\nthis section, a taxpayer in any taxable year may elect to contribute to\nthe agriculture and New York horse breeding and development fund\nestablished pursuant to section three hundred thirty of the racing,\npari-mutuel wagering and breeding law, for the purpose of funding the\noperation of retired race horse aftercare facilities. Any contributions\nmade to the agriculture and New York state horse breeding development\nfund pursuant to this section shall be deposited into a dedicated\naccount managed by the fund, which shall solely be used for funding the\noperation of retired race horse aftercare facilities, with a preference\nfor those organizations that are accredited horse retirement and rescue\nprograms. Such contribution shall be in any whole dollar amount and\nshall not reduce the amount of the state tax owed by such taxpayer. The\ncommissioner shall include space on the corporate income tax return to\nenable a taxpayer to make such contribution. Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of law, all revenues collected pursuant to this section shall\nbe credited to the New York state standardbred retirement race horse and\naftercare fund and shall be used only for those purposes enumerated in\nparagraph j of subdivision one of section three hundred thirty-two of\nthe racing, pari-mutuel wagering and breeding law.\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2022\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>