<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="211"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_211">
        <num>211</num>
        <heading>Reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section seventy-seven hundred one of the internal revenue\ncode, a publicly traded partnership treated as a corporation for\npurposes of the internal revenue code pursuant to section seventy-seven\nhundred four thereof and any business conducted by a trustee or trustees\nwherein interest or ownership is evidenced by certificates or other\nwritten instruments such certification shall be made by any person duly\nauthorized so to act on behalf of such association, publicly traded\npartnership or business. The fact that an individual's name is signed on\na certification of the report shall be prima facie evidence that such\nindividual is authorized to sign and certify the report on behalf of the\ncorporation. Blank forms of reports shall be furnished by the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance, on application, but failure to\nsecure such a blank shall not release any corporation from the\nobligation of making any report required by this article.\n  2-a. The commissioner may prescribe regulations and instructions\nrequiring returns of information to be made and filed in conjunction\nwith the reports required to be filed pursuant to this article, relating\nto payments made to shareholders owning, directly or indirectly,\nindividually or in the aggregate, more than fifty percent of the issued\ncapital stock of the taxpayer, where such payments are treated as\npayments of interest in the computation of entire net income reported on\nsuch reports.\n  3. If the amount of taxable income for any year of any taxpayer\n(including any taxpayer which has elected to be taxed under subchapter s\nof chapter one of the internal revenue code), as returned to the United\nStates treasury department is changed or corrected by the commissioner\nof internal revenue or other officer of the United States or other\ncompetent authority, or where a renegotiation of a contract or\nsubcontract with the United States results in a change in taxable\nincome, such taxpayer shall report such changed...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any taxpayer\nconducts its activity or business under any agreement, arrangement or\nunderstanding in such manner as either directly or indirectly to benefit\nits members or stockholders, or any of them, or any person or persons\ndirectly or indirectly interested in such activity or business, by\nentering into any transaction at more or less than a fair price which,\nbut for such agreement, arrangement or understanding, might have been\npaid or received therefor, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any taxpayer, a substantial portion of\nwhose capital stock is owned either directly or indirectly by another\ncorporation, enters into any transaction with such other corporation on\nsuch terms as to create an improper loss or net income, the commissioner\nmay include in the entire net income of the taxpayer the fair profits\nwhich, but for such agreement, arrangement or understanding, the\ntaxpayer might have derived from such transaction. Where any taxpayer\nowns, directly or indirectly, more than fifty percent of the capital\nstock of another corporation subject to tax under section fifteen\nhundred two-a of this chapter and fifty percent or less of whose gross\nreceipts for the taxable year consist of premiums, the commissioner may\ninclude in the entire net income of the taxpayer, as a deemed\ndistribution, the amount of the net income of the other corporation that\nis in excess of its net premium income.\n  6. An action may be brought at any time by the attorney-general at the\ninstance of the tax commission, in the name of the state, to compel the\nfiling of reports due under this article.\n  7. Reports shall be preserved for five years, and thereafter until the\ntax commission orders them to be destroyed.\n  8.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except in accordance with proper judicial order or as otherwise\nprovided by law, it shall be unlawful for any tax commissioner, any\nofficer or employee of the department, or any person who, pursuant to\nthis section, is permitted to inspect any report, or to whom any\ninformation contained in any report is furnished, or any person engaged\nor retained by such department on an independent contract basis, or any\nperson who in any manner may acquire knowledge of the contents of a\nreport filed pursuant to this article, to divulge or make known in any\nmanner the amount of income or any particulars set forth or disclosed in\nany report under this article. The officers charged with the custody of\nsuch reports shall not be required to produce any of them or evidence of\nanything contained in them in any action or proceeding in any court,\nexcept on behalf of the state or the commissioner in an action or\nproceeding under the provisions of this chapter or in any other action\nor proceeding involving the collection of a tax due under this chapter\nto which the state or the commissioner is a party or a claimant, or on\nbehalf of any party to any action or proceeding under the provisions of\nthis article when the reports or facts shown thereby are directly\ninvolved in such action or proceeding, in any of which events the court\nmay require the production of, and may admit in evidence, so much of\nsaid reports or of the facts shown thereby as are pertinent to the\naction or proceeding, and no more. The commissioner may, nevertheless,\npublish a copy or a summary of any determination or decision rendered\nafter the formal hearing provided for in section one thousand\neighty-nine of this chapter. Nothing herein shall be construed to\nprohibit the delivery to a corporation or its duly authorized\nrepresentative of a copy of any report filed by it, nor to prohibit the\npublication of statistics so classified as to prevent the identification\nof particular reports and the item...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any officer or employee of the state who willfully violates\nthe provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall be dismissed\nfrom office and be incapable of holding any public office in this state\nfor a period of five years thereafter.\n  (ii) Cross-reference: For criminal penalties, see article thirty-seven\nof this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provisions of this subdivision, the tax\ncommission may permit the secretary of the treasury of the United States\nor his delegates, or the proper officer of any other state charged with\ntax administration, or the authorized representative of either such\nofficer, to inspect the reports filed under this article, or may furnish\nto such officer or his authorized representative an abstract of any such\nreport or supply information concerning an item contained in any such\nreport, or disclosed by an investigation of tax liability under this\narticle, but such permission shall be granted or such information\nfurnished to such officer or his representative only if the laws of the\nUnited States or of such other state, as the case may be, grant\nsubstantially similar privileges to the commission or officer of this\nstate charged with the administration of the tax imposed by this article\nand such information is to be used for tax purposes only; and provided\nfurther the commissioner of taxation and finance may furnish to the\nsecretary of the treasury of the United States or his delegates such\nreports filed under this article and other tax information, as he may\nconsider proper, for use in court actions or proceedings under the\ninternal revenue code, whether civil or criminal, where a written\nrequest therefor has been made to the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance by the secretary of the treasury or his delegates provided the\nlaws of the United States grant substantially similar powers to the\nsecretary of the treasury or his delegates. Where the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance has so authorized use of reports or other tax\ninformation in such actions or proceedings, officers and employees of\nthe department of taxation and finance may testify in such actions or\nproceedings in respect to such reports or other tax information; and\nprovided further that such commission may furnish any municipality with\nsuch information contained in the ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision eight of this\nsection, the commissioner and the comptroller shall enter into an\nagreement pursuant to which the commissioner shall, upon request,\nprovide the comptroller with a report, not more frequently than\nannually, with respect to corporations or other entities which have\nfiled a business corporation franchise tax report under this article for\nany taxable year within ten calendar years prior to the report to the\ncomptroller made pursuant to this subdivision, providing the following\ninformation, to the extent that such information is readily available\nfrom the department's system for identifying taxpayer indicative data:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>business name and legal name, if different;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>business address and mailing address;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>federal employer identification number;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>date entered into business.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each report to the comptroller made pursuant to this subdivision\nshall list each corporation or other entity with respect to which such\nreport is made according to the total assets reported for the end of the\nyear on its most recent available business corporation franchise tax\nreport, in descending order. Such reports to the comptroller shall not\ndisclose the actual amount of total assets reported on such business\ncorporation franchise tax reports.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The information provided to the comptroller pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be used only for administration and enforcement of the\nabandoned property law. The comptroller may redisclose the information\nprovided under this subdivision only to the extent necessary for\nenforcement or administration of the abandoned property law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The reports to the comptroller required under this subdivision\nshall be submitted by electronic means or in some other format which is\nmutually acceptable to the comptroller and the commissioner. The written\nagreement with the comptroller shall set forth the procedures for\nproviding the information the commissioner is allowed to disclose\npursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding article six of the public officers law or any\nother provision of law, the reports to be furnished to the comptroller\npursuant to this subdivision shall not be open to the public for\ninspection.\n  14. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision eight of this\nsection, the commissioner may disclose to a taxpayer or a taxpayer's\nrelated member, as defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision nine of\nsection two hundred eight of this article, information relating to any\nroyalty payments paid, incurred or received by such taxpayer or related\nmember to or from the other, including the treatment of such payments by\nthe taxpayer or the related member in any report or return transmitted\nto the commissioner under this chapter.\n  15. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision eight of this\nsection, the commissioner shall provide the statements and other\nrequired information requested on tax reports under section four hundred\neight of the business corporation law to the secretary of state for\nfiling. Such provision may also include a copy or image of that portion\nof the report solely pertinent to such information to the extent\nfeasible. The commissioner any also provide information on\nnoncompliance.\n  16.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision eight of this\nsection, upon written request from the chairperson of the committee on\nways and means of the United States House of Representatives, the\nchairperson of the committee on finance of the United States Senate, or\nthe chairperson of the joint committee on taxation of the United States\nCongress, the commissioner shall furnish such committee with any current\nor prior year reports specified in such request that were filed under\nthis article by the president of the United States, vice-president of\nthe United States, member of the United States Congress representing New\nYork state, or any person who served in or was employed by the executive\nbranch of the government of the United States on the executive staff of\nthe president, in the executive office of the president, or in an acting\nor confirmed capacity in a position subject to confirmation by the\nUnited States senate; or, in New York state: a statewide elected\nofficial, as defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section\nseventy-three-a of the public officers law; a state officer or employee,\nas defined in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsuch section seventy-three-a; a political party chairperson, as defined\nin paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of such section seventy-three-a; a\nlocal elected official, as defined in subdivisions one and two of\nsection eight hundred ten of the general municipal law; a person\nappointed, pursuant to law, to serve due to vacancy or otherwise in the\nposition of a local elected official, as defined in subdivisions one and\ntwo of section eight hundred ten of the general municipal law; a member\nof the state legislature; or a judge or justice of the unified court\nsystem, or filed by a partnership, firm, association, corporation,\njoint-stock company, trust or similar entity directly or indirectly\ncontrolled by any individual listed in this paragraph, whether by\ncontract, through ownership or control of a majority interest in such\nentity, or otherwise, or filed by a partnership, firm, association,\ncorporation, joint-stock company, trust or similar entity of which any\nindividual listed in this paragraph holds ten percent or more of the\nvoting securities of such entity; provided however that, prior to\nfurnishing any report, the commissioner shall redact any copy of a\nfederal return (or portion thereof) attached to, or any information on a\nfederal return that is reflected on, such report, and any social\nsecurity numbers, account numbers and residential address information.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No reports shall be furnished pursuant to this subdivision unless\nthe chairperson of the requesting committee certifies in writing that\nsuch reports have been requested related to, and in furtherance of, a\nlegitimate task of the Congress, that the requesting committee has made\na written request to the United States secretary of the treasury for\nrelated federal reports or report information, pursuant to 26 U.S.C.\nSection 6103</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, and that if such requested reports are inspected by\nand/or submitted to another committee, to the United States House of\nRepresentatives, or to the United States Senate, then such inspection\nand/or submission shall occur in a manner consistent with federal law as\ninformed by the requirements and procedures established in 26 U.S.C.\nSection 6103</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>