<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-R"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-R"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="253-R"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_253_R">
        <num>253-R</num>
        <heading>Recording tax imposed by the county of Schenectady</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_253_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section two hundred fifty-five of this article.\n  Except as otherwise provided in this section, all the provisions of\nthis article relating to or applicable to the administration and\ncollection of the taxes imposed by such subdivision shall apply to the\ntaxes imposed under the authority of this section with such\nmodifications as may be necessary to adapt such language to the tax so\nauthorized. Such provisions shall apply with the same force and effect\nas if those provisions had been set forth in full in this section except\nto the extent that any provision is either inconsistent with a provision\nof this section or not relevant to the tax authorized by this section.\nFor purposes of this section, any reference in this article to the tax\nor taxes imposed by this article shall be deemed to refer to a tax\nimposed pursuant to this section, and any reference to the phrase\n"within this state" shall be read as "within Schenectady county", unless\na different meaning is clearly required.\n  3. Where the real property covered by the mortgage subject to the tax\nimposed pursuant to the authority of this section is situated in this\nstate but within and without the county imposing such tax, the amount of\nsuch tax due and payable to such county shall be determined in a manner\nsimilar to that prescribed in the opening paragraph of section two\nhundred sixty of this article which concerns real property situated in\ntwo or more counties. Where such property is situated both within such\ncounty and without the state, the amount due and payable to such county\nshall be determined in the manner prescribed in the second undesignated\nparagraph of such section two hundred sixty which concerns property\nsituated within and without the state. Where real property is situated\nwithin and without the county imposing such tax, the recording officer\nof the jurisdiction in which the mortgage is first recorded shall be\nrequired to collect the taxes imposed p...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>