<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-271-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-271-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="271-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-271-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-271-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-271-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-271-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_271_A">
        <num>271-A</num>
        <heading>Sale of stamps</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 271-a. Sale of stamps. No person, firm, company, association or\ncorporation other than a corporation organized under the banking law of\nthis state or under the national bank act of the United States, or a\nduly authorized agent of the tax commission, shall sell or expose for\nsale, traffic in, trade, barter or exchange any stamp issued pursuant to\nthis article, without first obtaining from the tax commission its\nwritten consent to sell, traffic in, trade, barter or exchange such\nstamps, except that in connection with a sale of or agreement to sell\nstock a broker or agent of the principal making such sale or agreement\nto sell may supply and affix the stamp or stamps required by this\narticle. No persons shall sell or expose for sale any stamp so purchased\nor acquired for a sum less than the face value thereof without the\nwritten consent of the tax commission. Any person lawfully in possession\nof unused stamps of the issue then in effect may request the tax\ncommission for its consent to redeem the same. He shall present to the\ntax commission, if so required, a sworn statement setting forth the name\nand address of the owner and the party desiring to redeem said stamps,\nhow, when and from whom the same were acquired and such other pertinent\nand relevant information as the tax commission may require. Thereupon\nthe tax commission may authorize the redemption of such stamps through\nits fiscal agent appointed for the sale of stock transfer stamps. Upon\nthe failure or refusal of the tax commission to give such authority the\nsame may be enforced by mandamus. Any person violating any of the\nprovisions of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon\nconviction thereof shall be punishable by a fine of not less than five\nhundred nor more than one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment for not\nmore than six months, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the\ndiscretion of the court.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>