<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-282"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-282"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="282"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-282/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-282/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-282/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-282/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_282">
        <num>282</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>who or which imports or causes to\nbe imported into the state, for use, distribution, storage or sale\nwithin the state, any Diesel motor fuel; (ii) who or which produces,\nrefines, manufactures or compounds Diesel motor fuel within the state;\n(iii) who or which makes a sale or use of Diesel motor fuel in this\nstate other than: (A) a retail sale not in bulk or (B) the self-use of\nDiesel motor fuel which has been the subject of a retail sale to such\nperson; (iv) who or which is registered by the department as a\ndistributor of kero-jet fuel pursuant to the provisions of subdivision\ntwo of section two hundred eighty-two-a of this article. For the\npurposes of this article when used with respect to Diesel motor fuel, a\n"retail sale not in bulk" means the making or offering to make any sale\nof Diesel motor fuel to a consumer of such fuel which is delivered\ndirectly into a motor vehicle for use in the operation of such vehicle.\nA "retail sale in bulk" means the making or offering to make any sale of\nDiesel motor fuel to a consumer which is other than a "retail sale not\nin bulk". Motor fuel or Diesel motor fuel brought into the state in the\nordinary fuel tank connecting with the engine of a motor vehicle,\naeroplane, motor boat or other conveyance propelled by the use of such\nmotor fuel or Diesel motor fuel, and to be used only in the operation\nthereof, shall not be deemed imported within the meaning of this\narticle, if not removed from such tank except as used in the propulsion\nof such engine.\n  2. "Motor fuel" means gasoline, benzol, reformulated blend stock for\noxygenate blending, conventional blend stock for oxygenate blending,\nE85, fuel grade ethanol that meets the ASTM International active\nstandards specifications D4806 or D4814 or other product which is\nsuitable for use in operation of a motor vehicle engine.\n  3. "Motor vehicle" means any vehicle propelled by any power other than\nmuscular, except boats, road building machinery, power shovels...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and the regulations thereunder, as may be\namended from time to time.\n  19. "Qualified Indian" means a person duly enrolled on the tribal\nrolls of one of the Indian nations or tribes. In the case of the Cayuga\nIndian Nation of New York, such term shall include enrolled members of\nsuch nation when such enrolled members purchase motor fuel on any Seneca\nreservation.\n  20. "Qualified reservation" means</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lands held by an Indian nation\nor tribe that is located within the reservation of that nation or tribe\nin the state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lands within the state over which an Indian nation or tribe\nexercises governmental power and that are either</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>held by the Indian\nnation or tribe subject to restrictions by the United States against\nalienation, or (ii) held in trust by the United States for the benefit\nof such Indian nation or tribe;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lands held by the Shinnecock Tribe or the Poospatuck (Unkechauge)\nNation within their respective reservations; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any land that falls within paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, and which may be sold and replaced with other land in\naccordance with an Indian nation's or tribe's land claims settlement\nagreement with the state of New York, shall nevertheless be deemed to be\nsubject to restriction by the United States against alienation.\n  21. "Reservation motor fuel seller" means a seller of motor fuel or\nDiesel motor fuel which is an Indian nation or tribe, one or more\nmembers of such tribe, or an entity wholly owned by either or both,\nwhich sells motor fuel within the boundaries of a qualified reservation.\n  * 22. "E85" means a fuel blend consisting of ethanol and motor fuel,\nwhich meets the ASTM International active standard D5798 for fuel\nethanol.\n  * NB Repealed September 1, 2026\n  * 23. "B20" means a mixture consisting by volume of twenty percent\nbiodiesel and the remainder of which is diesel motor fuel. "Biodiesel"\nshall mean either "qualified biodiesel" or "unqualified biodiesel."\n"Qualified biodiesel" means a diesel motor fuel substitute produced from\nnonpetroleum renewable resources that meets the registration\nrequirements for fuels and fuel additives established by the\nEnvironmental Protection Agency under section 211 of the Clean Air Act\n(42 U.S.C. 7545) and that meets the ASTM International active standard\nD6751 for biodiesel fuel. "Unqualified biodiesel" means a diesel motor\nfuel substitute produced from nonpetroleum renewable resources that does\nnot meet the ASTM International active standard D6751 for biodiesel\nfuel.\n  * NB Repealed September 1, 2026\n  * 24. "CNG" means fuel comprised primarily of methane, stored in\neither a gaseous or liquid state, suitable for use and consumption in\nthe engine of a motor vehicle.\n  * NB Repealed September 1, 2026\n  * 25. "Hydrogen" means fuel comprised primarily of molecular hydrogen,\nstored in either a gaseous or liquid state, suitable for use and\nconsumption in the engine of a motor vehicle.\n  * NB Repealed September 1, 2026\n  26. "Publ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_282__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is not a distributor of motor fuel;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_282__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nmakes a sale of motor fuel in this state other than a retail sale not in\nbulk; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_282__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A) makes any purchases of motor fuel for resale within the\nregion set forth in subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or (ii) of paragraph one of\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred eleven of this chapter; or (B)\nmakes any sales of motor fuel, other than retail sales not in bulk,\nwithin the region set forth in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or (ii) of paragraph one\nof subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_282__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred eleven of this chapter. For\nthe purposes of this article when used with respect to motor fuel, a\n"retail sale not in bulk" means the making or offering to make any sale\nof motor fuel to a consumer of such fuel which is delivered directly\ninto a motor vehicle for use in the operation of such vehicle. A "retail\nsale in bulk" means the making or offering to make any sale of motor\nfuel to a consumer which is other than a "retail sale not in bulk".\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>