<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-423"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-423"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="423"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-423/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-423/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-423/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-423/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_423">
        <num>423</num>
        <heading>Cancellation of registration of distributors</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 423. Cancellation of registration of distributors. The registration\nof any distributor may be cancelled by the commissioner upon its failure\nto file a bond or other security when required, and the registration of\na distributor may be cancelled by the commissioner upon its failure to\ncomply with any of the provisions of this article or any reasonable\nrequirement, rule or regulation adopted pursuant to this article by the\ndepartment of taxation and finance or by the commissioner. All the\nprovisions of subdivisions four through six and eight through ten of\nsection two hundred eighty-three of this chapter relating to\nregistration of distributors of motor fuel shall be applicable to the\nregistration of distributors under this article with the same force and\neffect as if the language of those subdivisions had been incorporated in\nfull in this section and had expressly referred to the registration of\ndistributors under this article and the tax imposed by this article,\nwith such modification as may be necessary in order to adapt the\nlanguage of such provisions to the provisions of this article, provided,\nspecifically, that the term "motor fuel" shall be read as "alcoholic\nbeverages". Provided, however, a registration shall be cancelled\nimmediately, upon cancellation or revocation for cause of a license\nunder the alcoholic beverage control law. A distributor shall\nimmediately inform the department in writing of any change in its name\nor address, and a corporate distributor shall immediately inform the\ndepartment, in writing, of any change in its name, or in its officers or\ndirectors, or their residence addresses.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>