<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-445"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-445"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="445"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-445/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-445/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-445/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-445/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_445">
        <num>445</num>
        <heading>Local taxes on beer and liquor by a city of one million or more</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_445__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Twelve cents per gallon upon beers and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_445__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Twenty-six and four-tenths cents per liter on the liquors\ndescribed in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_445__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section four hundred\ntwenty-four, when sold or used in such city.\n  Such local law shall provide that if prior to the date upon which the\ntaxes go into effect, a contract of sale of any beer or other alcoholic\nbeverages described above was made, and delivery thereof pursuant to\nsuch contract is made within the city imposing such taxes on or after\nthe effective date thereof, the vendor shall be deemed a distributor,\nand such beer and other alcoholic beverages shall be deemed to be sold,\nand shall be subject to the tax at the time of such delivery.\n  2. Every local law imposing taxes pursuant to the authority of\nsubdivision one shall also impose upon each person, other than a\ndistributor within the meaning of such local law, who, on the date the\ntaxes imposed pursuant to the authority of such subdivision become\neffective, owns and possesses for the purposes of sale beer, or other\nalcoholic beverages described in subdivision one, a floor tax at the\nrates applicable under subdivision one upon such beer in excess of one\nhundred gallons and upon such other alcoholic beverages in excess of\nfour hundred liters. Such floor tax shall be due and payable on the\ntwentieth day of the month succeeding the month in which the taxes\nbecome effective.\n  3. All the provisions of this article shall apply to the taxes\nauthorized by subdivision one of this section and the provisions of\nsection four hundred twenty, four hundred twenty-six, four hundred\ntwenty-nine through four hundred thirty-four, four hundred thirty-six\nand four hundred thirty-seven shall apply to the tax authorized by\nsubdivision two thereof, so far as such article or sections can be made\napplicable to the taxes authorized by this section with such limitations\nas set forth in this section and such modifications as may be necessary\nin order to adapt such language to the local taxes authorized by this\nsection. Provided, however, in every case where the words "this state"\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>