<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-470"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-470"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-10-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="470"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-470/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-470/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-470/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-470/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_470">
        <num>470</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sells cigarettes or tobacco\nproducts to retail dealers or other persons for purposes of resale, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>owns, operates or maintains one or more cigarette or tobacco product\nvending machines in, at or upon premises owned or occupied by any other\nperson, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sells cigarettes or tobacco products to an Indian nation\nor tribe or to a reservation cigarette seller on a qualified\nreservation.\n  9. "Retail dealer." Any person other than a wholesale dealer engaged\nin selling cigarettes or tobacco products. For purposes of section four\nhundred eighty-a of this article and section eleven hundred thirty-four\nof this chapter, such term shall include for each such person engaged in\nselling cigarettes or tobacco products all "persons required to collect\ntax," as defined in subdivision one of section eleven hundred thirty-one\nof this chapter.\n  10. "Package." The individual package, box or other container in or\nfrom which retail sales of cigarettes are normally made or intended to\nbe made.\n  11. "Agent." Any person licensed by the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance to purchase and affix adhesive or meter stamps on packages of\ncigarettes under this article.\n  12. "Distributor." Any person who imports or causes to be imported\ninto this state any tobacco product (in excess of fifty cigars or one\npound of tobacco) for sale, or who manufactures any tobacco product in\nthis state, and any person within or without the state who is authorized\nby the commissioner of taxation and finance to make returns and pay the\ntax on tobacco products sold, shipped or delivered by him to any person\nin the state.\n  13. "Unstamped or unlawfully stamped packages of cigarettes." A\npackage of cigarettes which bears no tax stamp, or which bears a tax\nstamp of another state or taxing jurisdiction is considered to be an\nunstamped package of cigarettes. A package of cigarettes bearing a\ncounterfeit New York state or a counterfeit joint state and New York\ncity tax stamp is an unlawfully stamped package of cigarettes.\n  14. "Indian nation or tribe." One of the following New York state\nIndian nations or tribes: Cayuga Nation, Oneida Nation of New York,\nOnondaga Nation, Poospatuck or Unkechauge Nation, Saint Regis Mohawk\nTribe, Seneca Na...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Lands held by an Indian nation or\ntribe that is located within the reservation of that nation or tribe in\nthe state;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Lands within the state over which an Indian nation or tribe\nexercises governmental power and that are either</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>held by the Indian\nnation or tribe subject to restrictions by the United States against\nalienation, or (ii) held in trust by the United States for the benefit\nof such Indian nation or tribe;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Lands held by the Shinnecock Tribe or the Poospatuck (Unkechauge)\nNation within their respective reservations; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any land that falls within paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, and which may be sold and replaced with other land in\naccordance with an Indian nation's or tribe's land claims settlement\nagreement with the state of New York, shall nevertheless be deemed to be\nsubject to restriction by the United States against alienation.\n  17. "Reservation cigarette seller." A seller of cigarettes which is an\nIndian nation or tribe, one or more members of such tribe, or an entity\nwholly owned by either or both, which sells cigarettes within the\nboundaries of a qualified reservation.\n  18. "Snuff." Any finely cut, ground, or powdered tobacco that is not\nintended to be smoked.\n  19. "Cigar." Any roll of tobacco wrapped in leaf tobacco or in any\nsubstance containing tobacco (other than any roll of tobacco that is a\ncigarette as defined in subdivision one of this section). "Cigar" shall\ninclude, except where expressly excluded, any little cigar.\n  20. "Research tobacco product." A tobacco product or cigarette that is\nlabeled as a research tobacco product, manufactured for use in research\nfor health, scientific, or similar experimental purposes, is exclusively\nused for such purposes by an accredited college, university or hospital,\nor a researcher affiliated with an accredited college, university or\nhospital, and is not offered for sale or sold to consumers for any\npurpose.\n  21. "Affiliated person." Persons are affiliated persons with respect\nto each other where one of such persons has an ownership interest of\nmore than five percent, whether direct or indirect, in the other, or\nwhere an ownership interest of more than five percent, whether direct or\nindirect, is held in each of such persons by another person, or by a\ngroup of other persons that are affiliated persons with respect to each\nother.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>