<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-506"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-506"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="506"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_506">
        <num>506</num>
        <heading>Payment of tax</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 506. Payment of tax. 1. At the time of filing a return, as required\nby this article, each carrier shall pay to the tax commission the tax\nimposed by this article for the period covered by such return. Such tax\nshall be due and payable at the time of filing the return or, if a\nreturn is not filed when due, on the last day on which the return is\nrequired to be filed.  The tax commission may grant a reasonable\nextension of time for paying the tax whenever good cause exists.\n  2. The fees, taxes, penalties and interest accruing under this article\nshall constitute a lien upon all motor vehicles and vehicular units\nwhich are owned by such carrier or of which he has the lawful use or\ncontrol. The lien shall attach at the time of operation of any such\nmotor vehicle or vehicular unit within this state and shall remain\neffective until the fees, taxes, penalties and interest are paid, or the\nmotor vehicle or vehicular unit is sold for the payment thereof.  Such\nliens shall be paramount to all prior liens or encumbrances of any\ncharacter and to the rights of any holder of the legal title in or to\nany such motor vehicle or vehicular unit, provided, however, that:\n  a. No lien for any additional tax assessed pursuant to this article\nshall be enforceable against any motor vehicle or vehicular unit which\nprior to such assessment had been transferred in good faith to a bona\nfide transferee for value.\n  b. The lien of such tax shall be subject to the lien of any\nindebtedness secured by a chattel mortgage or conditional sales\nagreement existing against such motor vehicle or vehicular unit previous\nto the time when such tax became a lien, if:\n  (1) Such indebtedness was incurred in good faith to secure a portion\nof the purchase price of such motor vehicle or vehicular unit, and\n  (2) Such indebtedness is secured by a chattel mortgage or conditional\nsales agreement duly filed as required by law, and\n  (3) Such chattel mortgage or conditional sales agreement was not\ngiven, directly or indirectly, to any officer or stockholder of the\ncorporation owning or having the lawful use or control of such motor\nvehicle or vehicular unit, whether as a purchase money mortgage or\notherwise.\n  The lien of such tax shall be enforceable, however, as to any equity\nafter the encumbrance of such chattel mortgage or conditional sales\nagreement. In the event a motor vehicle or vehicular unit subject to\nsuch tax lien is repossessed by a chattel mortgagee or a conditional\nvendor such motor vehicle or vehicular unit shall not be sold at public\nor private sale unless at least five days notice of the time and place\nof such sale is served by registered mail upon the tax commission in\nAlbany.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>