<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-515"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-515"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="515"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-515/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-515/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-515/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-515/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_515">
        <num>515</num>
        <heading>Disposition of revenues</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 515. Disposition of revenues. All taxes, interest, penalties and\nfees collected or received pursuant to this article shall be deposited\ndaily in one account with such responsible banks, banking houses or\ntrust companies as may be designated by the comptroller, and to the\ncredit of the comptroller on account of the dedicated highway and bridge\ntrust fund established pursuant to section eighty-nine-b of the state\nfinance law. Such an account may be established in one or more of such\ndepositories and such deposits shall be kept separate and apart from all\nother moneys in the possession of the comptroller. The comptroller shall\nrequire adequate security from all such depositories.\n  Of the revenues so deposited, the comptroller shall retain in his\nhands such amount as the commissioner of taxation and finance may\ndetermine to be necessary for refunds or reimbursements of the taxes\ncollected or received pursuant to this article to which taxpayers shall\nbe entitled under the provisions of this article, out of which amount\nthe comptroller shall pay any refunds or reimbursements of the taxes\ncollected or received pursuant to this article to which taxpayers shall\nbe entitled under such provisions. The comptroller, after reserving the\namount to pay such refunds or reimbursements, shall, on or before the\nlast day of each month, pay the balance of the revenue so deposited\nduring such month into the dedicated highway and bridge trust fund\nestablished pursuant to section eighty-nine-b of the state finance law.\n  Notwithstanding the foregoing or any other law to the contrary, the\ncomptroller shall deposit all monies collected on account of the\nregistration fees imposed pursuant to section five hundred two-a and\nsubdivision eight of section five hundred nine of this article into the\nhighway use tax administration account established pursuant to section\nninety-nine-y of the state finance law. The monies deposited in such\naccount shall be available to the commissioner for the costs of issuing\nthe certificates of registration and highway use tax decals required by\nthis article and for any other costs of administering the provisions of\nsections five hundred two, five hundred two-a and five hundred nine of\nthis article. Any moneys not used in a given year shall be returned to\nsuch account and be added to the total funds available for disbursement\nin the succeeding year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>