<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-691"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-691"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="691"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-691/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-691/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-691/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-691/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_691">
        <num>691</num>
        <heading>Mailing rules; holidays; miscellaneous</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_691__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Timely\nmailing.--</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_691__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any return, claim, statement, notice, petition, or\nother document required to be filed, or any payment required to be made,\nwithin a prescribed period or on or before a prescribed date under\nauthority of any provision of this article is, after such period or such\ndate, delivered by United States mail to the tax commission, bureau,\noffice, officer or person with which or with whom such document is\nrequired to be filed, or to which or to whom such payment is required to\nbe made, the date of the United States postmark stamped on the envelope\nshall be deemed to be the date of delivery. This subsection shall apply\nonly if the postmark date falls within the prescribed period or on or\nbefore the prescribed date for the filing of such document, or for\nmaking the payment, including any extension granted for such filing or\npayment, and only if such document or payment was deposited in the mail,\npostage prepaid, properly addressed to the tax commission, bureau,\noffice, officer or...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_691__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A) Any reference in paragraph one of this subsection to the United\nStates mail shall be treated as including a reference to any delivery\nservice designated by the secretary of the treasury of the United States\npursuant to section seventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue\ncode and any reference in paragraph one of this subsection to a postmark\nby the United States mail shall be treated as including a reference to\nany date recorded or marked in the manner described in section\nseventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue code by a designated\ndelivery service.  If the commissioner finds that any delivery service\ndesignated by such secretary is inadequate for the needs of the state,\nthe commissioner may withdraw such designation for purposes of this\narticle.  The commissioner may also designate additional delivery\nservices meeting the criteria of section seventy-five hundred two of the\ninternal revenue code for purposes of this article, or may withdraw any\nsuch des...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_691__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Last known address.--For purposes of this article, a taxpayer's\nlast known address shall be the address given in the last return filed\nby him, unless subsequently to the filing of such return the taxpayer\nshall have notified the tax commission of a change of address.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_691__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Last day a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday.--When the last day\nprescribed under authority of this article (including any extension of\ntime) for performing any act falls on Saturday, Sunday, or a legal\nholiday in the state of New York, the performance of such act shall be\nconsidered timely if it is performed on the next succeeding day which is\nnot a Saturday, Sunday or a legal holiday.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_691__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certificate; unfiled return.--For purposes of this chapter, the\ncertificate of the tax commission to the effect that a tax has not been\npaid, that a return has not been filed, or that information has not been\nsupplied, as required by or under the provisions of this article, shall\nbe prima facie evidence that such tax has not been paid, that such\nreturn has not been filed, or that such information has not been\nsupplied.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_691__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Attorney general; jurisdiction.--The attorney general shall have\nconcurrent jurisdiction with any district attorney in the prosecution of\nany offenses arising under article thirty-seven of this chapter with\nrespect to the tax imposed under this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_691__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Voter registration forms.--The commissioner of taxation and\nfinance shall from time to time distribute mail voter registration\nforms, designed by the state board of elections, that conform to the\nrequirements of subdivision five of section 5-210 of the election law.\nOne such registration form shall be included by the commissioner in each\npacket of forms and instructions that the commissioner distributes to\nresidents who may be required to file a return pursuant to section six\nhundred fifty-one of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>