<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1038"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1038"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-06-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1038"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1038/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1038/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1038/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1038/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1038">
        <num>1038</num>
        <heading>Violations, penalties and procedures</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may impose a civil penalty upon a model\nmanagement company, model management group, or client that has been\ndeemed to have violated this article, for three thousand dollars for the\ninitial violation, and for five thousand dollars for a second or\nsubsequent violation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The order imposing such civil penalty may be served personally or\nby certified mail in accordance with section thirty-three of this\nchapter.  Such order shall be in writing and shall describe the nature\nof the violation, including reference to the provisions of subdivisions\none, two and three of this section alleged to have been violated.\n  4. An order issued under this section shall be final and not subject\nto review by any court or agency unless a review is had pursuant to\nsection one hundred one of this chapter. Provided that no proceeding for\nadministrative or judicial review as provided in this chapter shall then\nbe pending and the time for initiation of such proceeding shall have\nexpired, the commissioner may file with the county clerk of the county\nwhere the person against whom the penalty has been imposed has a place\nof business the order of the commissioner or the decision of the\nindustrial board of appeals containing the amount of the civil penalty.\nThe filing of such order or decision shall have the full force and\neffect of a judgment duly docketed in the office of such clerk. The\norder or decision may be enforced by and in the name of the commissioner\nin the same manner, and with like effect, as that prescribed by the\ncivil practice law and rules for the enforcement of a money judgment.\n  5. If any model management company has failed to comply within twenty\ndays of an order by the commissioner to register or renew registration,\nthe commissioner may seek to enjoin such unlawful activity, pursuant to\nthe civil practice law and rules.\n  6. The attorney general may bring and maintain an action in a court of\ncompetent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this article when\nthe attorney general has determined there is reasonable cause to believe\nthat a model management company, model management group, or client has\nengaged in repeated fraudulent or illegal acts or otherwise demonstrates\npersistent fraud or illegality in the carr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A model who is aggrieved by a violation of this article may\nfile a complaint with the commissioner within six years after the acts\nalleged to have violated this article occurred. The commissioner shall\nprescribe the form of the complaint, which shall include, at a minimum:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name and mailing address of the model and of the person or\nentity alleged to have violated this article;\n  (ii) a statement detailing the terms of the model's contract,\nincluding a copy of such contract if available;\n  (iii) the model's occupation;\n  (iv) a statement detailing the alleged violations of this article; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a signed affirmation that all facts alleged in the complaint are\ntrue.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receiving a complaint alleging a violation of this\narticle, the commissioner shall send the person or entity named in the\ncomplaint a written notice of complaint. The commissioner shall send\nsuch notice by certified mail in accordance with section thirty-three of\nthe labor law and shall bear the cost of sending such notice.\n  (ii) Notice shall include:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1038__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a copy of the complaint;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1038__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>materials of remedies available to the model for the violations of\nsaid article by the person or entity named in the complaint;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1038__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>materials informing the person or entity that twenty days after\nreceiving the notice of complaint, the person or entity identified in\nthe complaint must answer; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1038__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>materials informing the person or entity that failure to respond\nto the complaint will create a rebuttable presumption in any civil\naction commenced pursuant to this article that such person or entity\ncommitted the violations alleged in the complaint.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The response shall include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a written statement that the model has been paid in full and proof\nof such payment;\n  (ii) a written statement that the model has not been paid in full and\nthe reasons for the failure to provide such payment; or\n  (iii) a written statement and any proof responding to the violations\nalleged in the complaint.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1038__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receiving the written response, the commissioner shall\nsend the model a copy of:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1038__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the response;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1038__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any enclosures submitted to the commissioner with the response;\nand\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1038__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any other information about the status of the complaint.\n  (ii) If the commissioner receives no response from the person or\nentity alleged to have violated this article to the notice of complaint\nwithin the time provided by this subdivision, then there shall be a\ndetermination that such person or entity committed the violations\nalleged in the complaint. The commissioner shall mail a notice of\nnon-response to both the model and the person or entity named in the\ncomplaint by regular mail and shall include with such notice proof that\nthe commissioner previously mailed the notice of complaint to the person\nor entity named in the complaint by certified mail.\n  8. An aggrieved model may bring and maintain an action in a court of\ncompetent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of sections one\nthousand thirty-four and one thousand thirty-five of this article. A\nmodel management company or model management group that violates these\nsections shall be liable for actual damages to a...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>