<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="130"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_130">
        <num>130</num>
        <heading>Employment of minors under fourteen years of age</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 130. Employment of minors under fourteen years of age. 1. No minor\nunder fourteen years of age shall be employed in or in connection with\nany trade, business, or service, except as otherwise provided in this\nsection.\n  2. Exceptions: Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit\nthe employment of:\n  a. A minor under fourteen years of age as a child performer in\ncompliance with section 35.01 of the arts and cultural affairs law and\narticle four-A of this chapter.\n  b. A minor under fourteen years of age as a child model in compliance\nwith section 35.05 of the arts and cultural affairs law.\n  * c. A minor eleven years of age as a newspaper carrier in compliance\nwith section thirty-two hundred twenty-eight of the education law.\n  * NB Repealed May 9, 2027\n  d. A minor twelve or thirteen years of age by his parents or\nguardians, either on the home farm or at other outdoor work not\nconnected with or for any trade, business, or service, when attendance\nupon instruction is not required by the education law.\n  e. A minor over twelve years of age who presents a farm work permit,\nin assisting in the hand work harvest of berries, fruits and vegetables,\nfor a period of four hours in any work day when attendance upon\ninstruction is not required by the education law between the hours of\nnine o'clock in the forenoon and four o'clock in the afternoon between\nthe first day after Labor Day through and the twentieth day of June, and\nseven o'clock in the forenoon and seven o'clock in the evening between\nthe twenty-first day of June and Labor day of the same calendar year,\nand the minor is accompanied by a parent or has presented the written\nconsent of a parent or party with whom he or she resides to the\nemployer.\n  f. A minor pursuant to section seven hundred fifty-eight-a or 353.6 of\nthe family court act.\n  g. A minor twelve or thirteen years of age who assists a parent, aunt,\nuncle, grandparent or guardian in the sale of produce of a farm that is\nowned or leased by the minor's parent, aunt, uncle, grandparent or\nguardian, at a farm stand or farmer's market stand that is owned or\nleased by the minor's parent, aunt, uncle, grandparent or guardian, at\ntimes when school is not in session and the minor is accompanied by the\nparent or guardian or has presented the written consent of the parent or\nguardian.\n  h. A minor twelve or thirteen years of age as a bridge caddie at a\nbridge tournament when attendance upon instruction is not required by\nthe education law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>