<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-144"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-144"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="144"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-144/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-144/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-144/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-144/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_144">
        <num>144</num>
        <heading>Posting of hours</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 144. Posting of hours. 1.  The employer shall make a schedule for\nall minors employed by the employer, setting forth the hours of\nbeginning and stopping and the time allowed for meals, which shall be\nkept conspicuously posted in each establishment where such persons are\nemployed.\n  A change in the schedule of hours worked by minors pursuant to the\nprovisions of this chapter shall be allowed provided that the posted\nschedule reflects the change.  Nothing herein shall be construed so as\nto affect the limitations on hours worked by such minors as set forth\nelsewhere in this chapter.\n  2. The presence of any person subject to this article at any hours\nother than those stated in the above notice, or the failure to post such\nnotice, shall constitute prima facie evidence of a violation of this\narticle.\n  3. Where a person is employed in two or more establishments on the\nsame day or week, the total time of employment shall not exceed that\nallowed per day or week in a single establishment.\n  4. Exception. If the commissioner finds that because of the nature of\nthe work in a factory it is practically impossible to fix the hours of\nwork weekly in advance, he may upon an application stating facts showing\nthe necessity therefor, grant a permit dispensing with the poster\nrequired by this section. In every factory operating under such a\npermit, a time book shall be kept in a form approved by the commissioner\nshowing the name and addresses of all employees subject to this\nsubdivision and the hours worked by each of them on each day.  No person\nshall knowingly make or suffer to be made a false entry in any such time\nbook. Such time book shall be kept for a period of six years and shall\nbe available upon request of the commissioner at the place of\nemployment. The permit shall be posted conspicuously in the factory, and\nthe commissioner may revoke the permit for failure to comply with the\nprovisions of this subdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>