<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-165"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-165"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="165"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-165/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-165/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-165/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-165/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_165">
        <num>165</num>
        <heading>Steam and other railroads</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 165. Steam and other railroads. 1. No person or corporation\noperating a steam or electric surface, subway or elevated railroad of\nthirty miles or more in length, wholly or partly within this state,\nexcept where the mileage system of running trains is in operation, shall\npermit or require a conductor, engineer, fireman, trainman, motorman or\nassistant motorman, engaged in or connected with the movement of any\ntrain on such railroad, to be or remain on duty for a longer period than\nsixteen consecutive hours.  Whenever any such employee shall have been\ncontinuously on duty for sixteen hours he shall not be required or\npermitted again to go on duty until he has had at least ten consecutive\nhours off duty. No such employee who has been on duty sixteen hours in\nthe aggregate in any twenty-four hour period shall be required or\npermitted to continue or again go on duty without having had at least\neight consecutive hours off duty.\n  2. This section shall not apply to any such employee when he is\nprevented from reaching his terminal by casualty occurring after he has\nstarted on his trip or by accident to or unexpected delay of trains\nscheduled to make connection with the train on which he is serving, or\nwhen he is engaged in interstate commerce.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>