<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="202-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_202_F">
        <num>202-F</num>
        <heading>Protection of hotel and motel employees against fire hazards in employee housing facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 202-f. Protection of hotel and motel employees against fire hazards\nin employee housing facilities. Notwithstanding any other provision of\nlaw, the board of standards and appeals shall issue a temporary rule\ngoverning fire hazards in housing facilities for hotel and motel\nemployees, to become effective on the first day of June, nineteen\nhundred seventy-three. Such temporary rule shall contain such national\nconsensus standards or standards of any governmental agency in the state\nrelating to housing facilities as the board deems necessary for the\nprotection of the lives, health and safety of hotel and motel employees.\nNotice of the adoption of such temporary rule shall be published in ten\nnewspapers throughout the state and such temporary rule shall be filed\nwith the secretary of state. Such temporary rule shall remain in effect\nuntil superseded by a safety and health standard promulgated in\naccordance with the procedure prescribed in article twelve of this\nchapter or until the first day of June, nineteen hundred seventy-four,\nwhichever occurs first, provided however, that nothing in this section\nshall prevent any other agency of the state or subdivision thereof from\nenforcing a public health and safety standard promulgated pursuant to\nsection two hundred twenty-five of the public health law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>