<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="202-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_202_B">
        <num>202-B</num>
        <heading>Leave for organ or bone marrow donation granted to state employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 202-b. Leave for organ or bone marrow donation granted to state\nemployees.  1. Any employee of the state of New York shall be allowed up\nto seven days paid leave to undergo a medical procedure to donate bone\nmarrow and up to thirty days paid leave to serve as an organ donor,\nprovided, however, that an employee of the state of New York shall\nprovide his or her employer with not less than fourteen days prior\nwritten notice of an intention to utilize such leave, unless there\nexists a medical emergency, attested to by a physician, which would\nrequire the employee to participate in the medical procedure or organ\ndonation for which the leave is sought within the fourteen day\nnotification period. Such leave shall be in addition to any other sick\nor annual leave allowed. The employer may require verification by a\nphysician for the purpose and length of each leave requested by the\nemployee to donate bone marrow.\n  2. An employer shall not retaliate against an employee for requesting\nor obtaining a leave of absence as provided by this section for the\npurpose of undergoing a medical procedure to donate bone marrow or serve\nas an organ donor.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not prevent an employer from\nproviding leave for bone marrow or organ donations in addition to leave\nallowed under any other provision of law. The provisions of this section\nshall not affect an employee's rights with respect to any other employee\nbenefit otherwise provided by law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>