<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="203"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Washrooms, washing facilities and waterclosets for elevator employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 203. Washrooms, washing facilities and waterclosets for elevator\nemployees. There shall be provided and maintained for the use of all\npersons employed in operating freight or passenger elevators adequate\nand convenient washrooms or washing facilities and a sufficient number\nof suitable and convenient waterclosets. Where the elevator is used in\nor in connection with a factory or mercantile establishment, the\nprovisions of sections two hundred and ninety-three and two hundred and\nninety-five shall apply to wash-rooms, washing facilities and\nwaterclosets for employees mentioned in this section; and where the\nelevator is used in any other building or place, the provisions of such\nsections three hundred and seventy-eight and three hundred and\neighty-one shall apply to washrooms, washing facilities and waterclosets\nfor employees engaged in the care, custody or operation of an elevator\nin such building or place. For the purpose of so applying the sections\nlast referred to, the term "mercantile establishment" as therein used\nshall be deemed to mean and include a building in which the elevator is\nlocated or with which it connects.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>