<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_F">
        <num>21-F</num>
        <heading>Job transition plan for certain climate risk-related and energy transition projects</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 21-f. Job transition plan for certain climate risk-related and\nenergy transition projects. 1. The commissioner, in consultation with\nlabor organizations, shall develop a comprehensive plan to transition,\ntrain, or retrain employees that are impacted by climate risk-related\nand energy transition projects funded from the New York climate action\nfund climate investment account established pursuant to section\nninety-nine-qq of the state finance law. This plan shall include a\nmethod of allowing displaced and transitioning workers, including\naffected labor organizations, to notify the commissioner of the loss of\nemployment, their previous title, and previous wage rates including\nwhether they previously received medical benefits, retirement benefits,\nand/or other benefits. The plan shall require employers to notify the\ncommissioner of workers laid off or discharged due to climate\nrisk-related and energy transition projects funded from the New York\nclimate action fund climate investment account established pursuant to\nsection ninety-nine-qq of the state finance law.\n  2. Funding shall be made available for worker transition and\nretraining, which shall include funding as provided by subdivision\ntwenty-seven-d of section one thousand five of the public authorities\nlaw.\n  3. The commissioner shall create a program pursuant to which, where\napplicable and feasible, newly created job opportunities shall be\noffered to a pool of transitioning workers who have lost their\nemployment or will be losing their employment in the energy sector due\nto climate risk-related and energy transition projects funded from the\nNew York climate action fund climate investment account established\npursuant to section ninety-nine-qq of the state finance law. Such\nprogram shall include a method for the commissioner to communicate names\nand contact information for displaced or transitioning workers to public\nentities that may have job opportunities for such workers every ninety\ndays.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>