<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220_H">
        <num>220-H</num>
        <heading>Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) construction safety and health course</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 220-h. Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA)\nconstruction safety and health course. The advertised specifications for\nevery contract for the construction, reconstruction, maintenance and/or\nrepair of public work to which the state or a municipality is a party,\nwhere the total cost of all work to be performed under the contract is\nat least two hundred fifty thousand dollars, shall contain a provision\nrequiring that all laborers, workers, and mechanics employed in the\nperformance of the contract on the public work site, either by the\ncontractor, sub-contractor or other person doing or contracting to do\nthe whole or a part of the work contemplated by the contract, shall be\ncertified prior to performing any work on the project as having\nsuccessfully completed a course in construction safety and health\napproved by the United States department of labor's occupational safety\nand health administration that is at least ten hours in duration.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>