<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="224-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_224_E">
        <num>224-E</num>
        <heading>Wage requirements for certain broadband projects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fiscal officer shall report to the governor, the temporary\npresident of the senate, and the speaker of the assembly by July first,\ntwo thousand twenty-three and annually thereafter, on the participation\nof minority and women-owned business enterprises undertaking covered\nbroadband projects subject to the provisions of this section as well as\nthe diversity practices of contractors and subcontractors employing\nworkers on such projects.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such reports shall include aggregated data on the utilization and\nparticipation of minority and women-owned business enterprises, the\nemployment of minorities and women in construction-related jobs on such\nprojects, and the commitment of contractors and subcontractors on such\nprojects to adopting practices and policies that promote diversity\nwithin the workforce. The reports shall also examine the compliance of\ncontractors and subcontractors with other equal employment opportunity\nrequirements and anti-discrimination laws, in addition to any other\nemployment practices deemed pertinent by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fiscal officer may require any owner or developer to disclose\ninformation on the participation of minority and women-owned business\nenterprises and the diversity practices of contractors and\nsubcontractors involved in the performance of any covered broadband\nproject. It shall be the duty of the fiscal officer to consult and to\nshare such information in order to effectuate the requirements of this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>