<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="224-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_224_C">
        <num>224-C</num>
        <heading>Public subsidy board</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the minimum threshold percentage of public funds set forth in\nsubdivision one of section two hundred twenty-four-a of this article,\nbut no lower than that which is set forth in such subdivision;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the minimum dollar threshold of projects set forth in subdivision\none of section two hundred twenty-four-a of this article, but no lower\nthan that which is set forth in such subdivision;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>construction work excluded as a covered project, as set forth in\nsubparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, (ii) and (iii) of paragraph c of subdivision four of\nsection two hundred twenty-four-a of this article;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the definition of construction for purposes of section two hundred\ntwenty-four-a of this article; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>particular instances of benefits, monies or credits as to whether\nor not they should constitute public funds.\n  4. Prior to making any recommendation intended to apply to all\nprojects, the board shall hold a public hearing. The board shall\nannounce each public hearing at least fifteen days in advance. The\nannouncement shall contain an agenda of the topics the board will\ndiscuss. At each hearing, the board may hear testimony and/or review\nwritten documents from any interested stakeholders related to the\nplanned agenda of the meeting.  The board shall make any such\nrecommendations in writing. In making its recommendations, the board\nshall examine the impact of such thresholds and circumstances on private\ndevelopment in light of available public subsidies, existing labor\nmarket conditions, prevailing wage and supplement practices, and shall\nconsider the extent to which adjustments to such thresholds and\ncircumstances could ameliorate adverse impacts, if any, or expand\nopportunities for prevailing wage and supplement standards on publicly\nsubsidized private construction projects in any region or regions of the\nstate.\n  5. The board shall be empowered to issue binding determinations to any\npublic entity, or any private or not-for-profit owner or developer as to\nany particular matter related to an existing or potential covered\nproject. In such instances the board shall make a determination based\nupon documents, or testimony, or both in its sole discretion. Any such\nproceedings shall be confidential, except that publication of such\ndecisions shall be made available on the department's website, subject\nto redaction or confidentiality as the board shall deem warranted in\naccordance with any applicable federal or state statutory or regulatory\nrequirement governing confidentiality and personal privacy.\n  6. Any recommendation rendered by the board pursuant to this section\nshall be subject to the provisions of article seventy-eight of the civil\npra...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>