<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-09-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="224-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_224_D">
        <num>224-D</num>
        <heading>Wage requirements for certain renewable energy systems</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a renewable energy system, as such term is defined in section\nsixty-six-p of the public service law, with a capacity of one or more\nmegawatts alternating current and which involves the procurement of\nrenewable energy credits by a public entity, or a company or corporation\nprovided in subdivisions twenty-three and twenty-four of section two of\nthe public service law, or a third party acting on behalf and for the\nbenefit of a public entity;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any "thermal energy network" as defined\nby subdivision twenty-nine of section two of the public service law;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nany offshore wind supply chain project, including but not limited to\nport infrastructure, primary component manufacturing, finished component\nmanufacturing, subassembly manufacturing, subcomponent manufacturing, or\nraw material producers, or a combination thereof receiving direct\nfunding from the New York state energy research and development\nauthority pursuant to an award under a New York state energy research\nand development authority solicitation; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a "major utility\ntransmission facility" as such term is defined by section one hundred\ntwenty of the public service law.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of section two hundred twenty-four-a\nof this article, a covered renewable energy system shall be subject to\nprevailing wage requirements in accordance with sections two hundred\ntwenty and two hundred twenty-b of this article. Provided that a\nrenewable energy system defined in section sixty-six-p of the public\nservice law which is not considered to be covered by this section, may\nstill otherwise be considered a "covered project" pursuant to section\ntwo hundred twenty-four-a of this article if it meets such definition.\n  3. For purposes of this section, a covered renewable energy system\nshall exclude construction work performed under a pre-hire collective\nbargaining agreement between an owner or contractor and a bona fide\nbuilding and construction trade labor organization which has established\nitself, and/or its affiliates, as the collective bargaining\nrepresentative for all persons who will perform work on such a project,\nand which provides that only contractors and subcontractors who sign a\npre-negotiated agreement with the labor organization can perform work on\nsuch a project provided, however, this subdivision shall not apply to\nany covered renewable energy systems defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_224_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of this section.\n  4. For purposes of this section, the "fiscal officer" shall be deemed\nto be the commissioner. The enforcement of any covered renewable energy\nsystem pursuant to this section shall be subject to the requirements of\nsections two hundred twenty, two hundred twenty-a, two hundred twenty-b,\ntwo hundred twenty-three, two hundred twenty-four-b, and two hundred\ntwenty-seven of this chapter and within the jurisdiction of the fiscal\nofficer; provided, however, nothing contained in this section shall be\ndeemed to construe any covered renewable energy system as otherwise\nbeing considered public work pursuant to this article.\n  5. The fiscal officer may issue rules and regulations governing the\nprovisions of this section. Violations of this section shall be grounds\nfor determinations and orders pursuant to section two hundred twenty-b\nof this article.\n  6. Each owner and developer subject to the requirements of this\nsection shall comply with the objectives and goals of certified minority\nand women-owned business enterprises pursuant to article fifteen-A of\nthe executive law and certified service-disabled veteran-owned\nbusinesses pursuant to article three of the veterans' services law. The\ndepartment in consultation with the commissioner of the division of\nminority and women's business development and the director of the\ndivision of service-disabled veterans' business development shall make\ntraining and resources available to assist minority and women-owned\nbusiness enterprises and service-disabled veteran-owned business\nenterprises on covered renewable energy systems to achieve and maintain\ncompliance with prevailing wage requirements. The department shall make\nsuch training and resources available online and shall afford minority\nand women-owned business enterprises and service-disabled veteran-owned\nbusiness enterprises an opportunity to submit comments on such training.\n  7. a. The fiscal officer shall report...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>