<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-225-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-225-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="225-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-225-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-225-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-225-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-225-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_225_A">
        <num>225-A</num>
        <heading>General requirements making applicable certain provisions of article eight and providing for enforcement thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 225-a. General requirements making applicable certain provisions of\narticle eight and providing for enforcement thereof.  All work of every\nkind to which the preceding section is applicable shall hereafter be\nsubject to application of all the provisions of sections two hundred and\ntwenty, two hundred and twenty-one and two hundred and twenty-two of\narticle eight of this chapter. Every contract hereafter entered into for\nsuch elimination work shall require compliance with the regulations of\nsuch sections. If the fiscal officer as defined herein finds that in the\nperformance of any such elimination work that any person contracting\nwith the state, a municipal corporation, board, any commission appointed\npursuant to law, their agent or other person carrying on such work to\nwhich state funds are applied for payment fails to comply with or evades\nthe provisions of this section, he shall present evidence of such\nnon-compliance or evasion to the officer, department, board or\ncommission having charge of such work for enforcement.  Wherein such\nevidence indicates a non-compliance or evasion on the part of a\nsub-contractor, the contractor shall be responsible for such\nnon-compliance or evasion. It shall be the duty of any officer,\ndepartment, board or commission in charge of the construction of such\ngrade crossing elimination contracts to enforce the provisions of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>