<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-264"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-264"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="264"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-264/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-264/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-264/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-264/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_264">
        <num>264</num>
        <heading>Fireproof building</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 264. Fireproof building. "Fireproof building" means a building\nconforming to the following requirements:\n  1. All exterior walls shall be constructed of brick, or stone, or\nconcrete, or cinder block, or concrete block, or tile, or terra cotta or\nsuch other material as shall be specified in the rules of the board. The\nboard shall determine and specify in its rules such requirements as it\ndeems necessary for the construction of exterior walls.\n  2. All floors and roofs shall be built of brick, or cinder block, or\nconcrete block, or tile, or terra cotta, or reinforced concrete\nsupported by steel or reinforced concrete beams and girders. The board\nshall determine and specify in its rules such other materials, the\nmanner of construction of floors and roofs and such other requirements\nas may be deemed necessary to carry into effect the intent of this\nchapter.\n  3. All structural metal shall be encased in fireproof material, of\nsuch thickness as shall be specified in the rules of the board.\n  4. All vertical openings leading from one floor to another, except one\ncreated by a mezzanine floor, shall be enclosed by fireproof or\nfire-resisting materials in a manner conforming to rules adopted by the\nboard.\n  5. All stairways, landings, hallways, floor surfaces, furring,\nceilings, partitions, sash, trim, window frames, doors and other\ninterior finish, shall be constructed of incombustible material; but\nnothing in this section shall prevent the use of such combustible\nmaterials as the board shall determine and specify in its rules. Such\nrules shall also specify the circumstances or conditions under which\ncombustible flooring, trim, acoustical material, insulating material or\nother interior finish may be used or applied to floors, walls,\npartitions or ceilings of fireproof buildings.\n  6. All windows shall be fire windows except:\n  a. In buildings less than seventy feet in height erected after October\nfirst, nineteen hundred and thirteen, where the windows are located more\nthan thirty feet from another building or open on a court or space more\nthan thirty feet wide;\n  b. In buildings less than one hundred and fifty feet in height erected\nbefore October first, nineteen hundred and thirteen, where the windows\nare located more than thirty feet from another building.\n  c. Fire windows may be provided with plate glass not less than\none-fourth of an inch in thickness, no light of which shall exceed seven\nhundred and twenty square inches in area.\n  (1) If the windows are located more than thirty feet horizontally or\nfifty feet vertically from the nearest opening in the wall of another\nbuilding.\n  (2) If the windows are located more than fifty feet in a vertical\ndirection above the roof of a building within a horizontal distance of\nthirty feet of the wall in which the said windows are located.\n  7. Partitions. All partitions in the interior of fireproof buildings\nshall be of incombustible material. Nothing in this section shall\nprevent the use, in a building equipped with automatic sprinklers, of\nsubdividing partitions of wood, or of wood and glass, in spaces used\nsolely for office or show-room purposes, provided, however, that where\nsuch spaces are contiguous to any room or rooms in which manufacturing\nis carried on, such spaces shall be separated from such room or rooms by\na dividing partition which, including doors, is constructed of\nincombustible material.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>