<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-06-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_E">
        <num>27-E</num>
        <heading>Prevention of retail workplace violence</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>outline a list of factors or situations in the workplace that\nmight place retail employees at risk of workplace violence, including\nbut not limited to:\n  (A) working late night or early morning hours;\n  (B) exchanging money with the public;\n  (C) working alone or in small numbers; and\n  (D) uncontrolled access to the workplace;\n  (ii) outline methods that employers may use to prevent incidents of\nworkplace violence, including but not limited to establishing and\nimplementing reporting systems for incidents of workplace violence;\n  (iii) include information concerning the federal and state statutory\nprovisions concerning violence against retail workers and remedies\navailable to victims of violence in the workplace and a statement that\nthere may be applicable local laws; and\n  (iv) clearly state that retaliation against individuals who complain\nof workplace violence or the presence of factors or situations in the\nworkplace that might place retail employees at risk of workplace\nviolence, or who testify or assist in any proceeding under the law is\nunlawful.\n  b. Every employer shall adopt the model retail workplace violence\nprevention policy promulgated pursuant to this subdivision, or establish\na workplace violence prevention policy that equals or exceeds the\nminimum standards provided by such model retail workplace violence\nprevention policy. Such retail workplace violence prevention policy\nshall be provided to all employees in writing upon hire and annually\nthereafter pursuant to paragraph a of subdivision four of this section.\n  3. Employee information and training. a. The department, in\nconsultation with relevant groups as deemed necessary by the department,\nshall produce a model workplace violence prevention training program.\nEvery employer shall utilize the model workplace violence prevention\ntraining program pursuant to this subdivision or establish a workplace\nviolence prevention training program that equals or exceeds the minimum\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>information on the requirements of this section;\n  (ii) examples of measures retail employees can use to protect\nthemselves when faced with workplace violence from customers or other\ncoworkers;\n  (iii) de-escalation tactics;\n  (iv) active shooter drills;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_E__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>emergency procedures; and\n  (vi) instruction on the use of security alarms or buttons, and other\nrelated emergency devices.\n  b. The department shall include information in such model workplace\nviolence prevention training program addressing conduct by supervisors\nand any additional responsibilities for such supervisors, including ways\nto address workplace specific emergency procedures, and training on\nareas of previous security problems.\n  c. As part of this training, every employer shall communicate to each\nemployee a site-specific list of emergency exits and meeting places in\ncase of emergency. Such workplace violence prevention training shall be\nprovided to all retail employees upon hire and on an annual basis\nthereafter. Employers covered under this section employing fewer than\nfifty retail employees shall provide such workplace violence prevention\ntraining upon hire and once every two years thereafter.\n  4. Notice of policy. a. Every employer shall provide their retail\nemployees, in writing in English and in the language identified by each\nemployee as the primary language of such employee, at the time of hiring\nand at every annual workplace violence prevention training provided\npursuant to subdivision three of this section, a notice containing such\nemployer's retail workplace violence prevention policy and the\ninformation presented at such employer's workplace violence prevention\ntraining program.\n  b. The commissioner shall prepare templates of the model retail\nworkplace violence prevention policy created and published pursuant to\nsubdivision two of this section and the model workplace violence\nprevention training program produced pursuant to subdivision three of\nthis section. The commissioner shall determine, in their discretion,\nwhich languages to provide in addition to English, based on the twelve\nmost common non-English languages spoken by limited-English proficient\nindividuals in the state, based on the data in the most rece...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>