<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-270"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-270"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="270"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-270/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-270/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-270/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-270/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_270">
        <num>270</num>
        <heading>Construction of buildings erected after October first, nineteen hundred and thirteen</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_270__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>continuously to the street, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_270__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to a fireproof passageway independent of other exits from the\nbuilding opening on a road or street, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_270__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to an open area affording\nunobstructed passage to a road or street, except that unobstructed\naccess to exits on the floor immediately below may be accepted for\nstairways from a mezzanine floor unless otherwise specified by the board\nin its rules. Provision shall be made for the adequate lighting of all\nstairways, ramps and passageways by artificial light. Where more than\ntwo stairways are provided in a building, not more than two may lead\nthrough a common fireproof passage to a street. Required stairways\nterminating at a floor below roof shall be connected at floor at which\nsuch stairs terminate through a fireproof passage to at least one other\nrequired stairway.\n  5. Doors and doorways. All doors at required exits or that lead to\nrequired exits shall open outwardly. The width of the fireproof\npassageways and exit doorways including stops, leading to the street at\nthe grade level shall be not less than the aggregate required width of\nall stairways and ramps leading to them. The aggregate capacity of all\nother required exit doorways shall be calculated on the basis of\ntwenty-two inches for each fifty persons or fraction thereof to be\nserved by such doorways, but no such doorway shall be less than\nthirty-six inches in width.\n  The provisions of this section shall not apply to a building, in a\ncity having a population of more than one million, used exclusively by\none employer and in which not more than one-tenth of all the persons\nemployed therein are engaged in work for a factory and which, except for\nsuch factory work, would be classified as a mercantile establishment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>