<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-274"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-274"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="274"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-274/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-274/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-274/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-274/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_274">
        <num>274</num>
        <heading>Fire-escapes erected before October first, nineteen hundred and thirteen</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 274. Fire-escapes erected before October first, nineteen hundred and\nthirteen. All outside fire-escapes erected before October first,\nnineteen hundred and thirteen, and serving as required exits under the\nprovisions of section two hundred and seventy-one shall conform to the\nfollowing requirements:\n  1. There shall be balconies on each floor of the building connected\nwith stairways placed at an angle of not more than sixty degrees.\n  2. A stairway shall lead from the top floor balcony to the roof,\nexcept when the fire-escapes are erected on the front of the building.\n  3. A stairway not less than twenty-two inches wide shall lead from the\nlowest balcony to a safe landing place beneath, which stairway shall\nremain down permanently or swing up and down by counterbalancing\nweights.\n  4. A safe and unobstructed exit shall be provided to the street from\nthe foot of such fire-escapes as required in subdivision nine of section\ntwo hundred and seventy-three.\n  5. Steps shall connect the sill of every opening leading to the\nfire-escapes with the floor wherever such sill is more than three feet\nabove the floor level.\n  6. All openings leading to the fire-escapes shall be provided with\nfireproof windows or fire doors.\n  7. All windows opening upon the course of the fire-escape shall be\nfireproof windows.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>