<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-276"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-276"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="276"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-276/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-276/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-276/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-276/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_276">
        <num>276</num>
        <heading>Inspection of buildings and approval of plans</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 276. Inspection of buildings and approval of plans. 1.  Inspection\nof buildings. The officer of any city, village or town having power to\ninspect buildings therein to determine their conformity to the\nrequirements of law or ordinance governing their construction shall,\nwhenever requested by the commissioner, inspect any factory building\ntherein and certify to the commissioner whether such building conforms\nto the requirements of this chapter and the rules of the board. Such\ncertificate shall be presumptive evidence of the truth of the matters\ntherein stated.\n  2. Approval of plans. Before constructing or altering a building to be\nused for a factory, the plans and specifications therefor may be\nsubmitted to the commissioner in such form as he may require. If they\ncomply with the requirements of this chapter and the rules of the board,\nthe commissioner shall issue his certificate approving the same. No\npermit for the construction of any building or structure, which is\nrequired to conform to the structural requirements of the labor law or\nthe rules adopted thereunder shall be issued by an enforcing authority\nin any city or village of this state except as provided by chapter five\nhundred and three of the laws of nineteen hundred sixteen as amended,\nuntil the plans have been approved by the commissioner.  Nothing herein\nshall prohibit any local authority from issuing a temporary permit for\nexcavation and foundations and such temporary permit also shall issue\nupon notice from the department of labor of the receipt of a request for\na variation as provided for in section thirty of this chapter. Such\ncertificate shall be presumptive evidence of the truth of the matters\ntherein stated.\n  3. Certificate of compliance. After such construction or alteration\nshall be completed, the commissioner shall ascertain by inspection\nwhether the building conforms substantially to the requirements of this\nchapter and the rules of the board. If the commissioner finds that it\ndoes so conform he shall issue his certificate to that effect. No\nbuilding or structure hereafter erected, or altered, which is required\nto conform to the structural requirements of the labor law or the rules\nadopted thereunder, shall be used or occupied without such certificate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>