<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-278"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-278"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="278"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-278/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-278/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-278/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-278/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_278">
        <num>278</num>
        <heading>Limitation of number of occupants</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 278. Limitation of number of occupants. The number of persons who\nmay be employed in a factory building or portion thereof shall be\nlimited to such number as can safely escape from the building by the\nexits provided in the building and shall not exceed the following:\n  1. In a building erected after October first, nineteen hundred and\nthirteen, fourteen persons for every full twenty-two inches in width of\nstairway provided for such floor and conforming to the requirements for\nrequired exits, except as to extension to the roof.  No allowance shall\nbe made for any excess in width of less than twenty-two inches.\n  2. In a building erected before October first, nineteen hundred\nthirteen, fourteen persons for every eighteen inches in width of\nstairway provided for such floor and conforming to the requirements for\nrequired exits except as to extension to the roof. For any excess in\nwidth of less than eighteen inches, a proportionate increase in the\nnumber of occupants shall be allowed. If a stairway has winders a\ndeduction of ten per centum shall be made in computing the capacity of\nsuch stairway.\n  3. On any floor which is more than ten feet from the one immediately\nbeneath, the number "fourteen" allowed in subdivisions one and two may\nbe increased respectively by one person for every sixteen inches over\nten feet between the two floors provided such stairways conform to the\nrequirements for required exits except as to extension to the roof.\n  4. In addition to the number of persons allowed in subdivisions one,\ntwo and three, so many persons may be employed on any floor as can\noccupy the stair halls, allowing five square feet of unobstructed floor\nspace per person where the stairways and stair halls are enclosed by\npartitions as required by sections two hundred and seventy and two\nhundred and seventy-one.\n  5. The number of persons permitted to be employed on any floor under\nsubdivisions one, two, three and four may be increased one hundred per\ncentum where there is maintained throughout the building an automatic\nsprinkler system conforming to the requirements of section two hundred\neighty and to the rules of the board and where, if required by\nsubdivisions one and two of section two hundred seventy-nine, a fire\nalarm signal system is maintained and fire drills are conducted.\n  6. On any floor at which a horizontal exit is provided so many persons\nmay be employed as can occupy the smaller of the spaces on either side\nof the fireproof partitions or fire walls, or as can occupy the floor of\nan adjacent building which is connected with such floor by openings in\nthe wall or walls between the buildings or by exterior balconies or\nbridges in addition to the occupants of such connected floor in such\nadjacent building, allowing five square feet of unobstructed floor space\nper person. Openings constituting required exit doorways, or if such\nexits are balconies or bridges, the openings leading thereto shall be of\nsufficient aggregate width to allow eighteen inches in width of openings\nfor each fifty persons or fraction thereof employed on such floor in the\ncase of factory buildings erected before October first, nineteen hundred\nand thirteen, and twenty-two inches in the case of factory buildings\nerected after that date.\n  7. Where a floor is occupied by more than one tenant, the commission\nmay prescribe how many of the persons allowed to occupy such floor under\nthe provisions of this section may occupy the space of each tenant.\n  8. In every factory building the commissioner shall cause to be posted\nin a conspicuous place in every stairhall and workroom, notices\nspecifying the number of persons that may occupy each floor thereof in\naccordance with the provisions of this section. If any floor is occupied\nby more than one tenant, such notices shall be posted in the space\noccupied by each tenant, and shall state the number of persons that may\noccupy such space. Every such notice shall bear the date when posted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>