<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-354"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-354"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="354"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_354">
        <num>354</num>
        <heading>Conditions of manufacture</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 354. Conditions of manufacture. 1. No person other than a person\nresident therein shall carry on industrial homework on any article in a\nhome except as otherwise provided for under section three hundred\nfifty-one, subdivision two, paragraph b.\n  2. No person shall carry on industrial homework except in accordance\nwith this article.\n  3. No child shall be employed in manufacture in a home except in\naccordance with articles four and five of this chapter.\n  4. No employer having an employer's permit shall deliver or cause to\nbe delivered or received any articles for or as a result of homework\nmanufacture unless he shall keep in such form and forward to the\ncommissioner at such intervals as he may by regulation prescribe and on\nsuch blanks as he may provide, a complete and accurate list of all\npersons engaged in industrial homework on materials furnished or\ndistributed by him, of all places where such persons work, of all\nmaterials furnished and distributed to such persons described as the\ncommissioner may require, of all goods which such persons have\nmanufactured and of the wages paid to each industrial homeworker, and\nunless he shall attach to all materials delivered for homework\nmanufacture a label bearing his name and address or place of business\nlegibly written or printed in English.\n  5. No person shall do industrial homework, except in a home in which\nhe resides, and unless his name is on a homeworker's certificate issued\nby the commissioner and permitting industrial homework to be done in\nsuch home, and unless such certificate is exposed clearly in the home in\nwhich industrial homework is being done.\n  6. No article of food, no dolls or dolls' clothing and no stuffed\nanimals or other stuffed toys used in the same way as dolls shall be\nmanufactured for a factory, either directly or through a contractor or\nfor an employer, in a home.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>