<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-453"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-453"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="453"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_453">
        <num>453</num>
        <heading>Storage</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 453. Storage. No person shall store explosives except in a magazine\nconstructed, located and certified in accordance with the provisions of\nthis article and the regulations promulgated pursuant to this article.\nThe magazine certificate shall be attached to the magazine on the inside\nof each such magazine. No person shall store more than three hundred\nthousand pounds of explosives in any one magazine at any time.\nExplosives not stored in compliance with this section shall be deemed to\npresent a danger to the public, including but not limited to, emergency\nresponders and other persons lawfully frequenting the area and as such,\nare subject to seizure and destruction pursuant to subdivision five of\nsection four hundred sixty of this article.\n  This section shall not apply to explosives while being legally blasted\nor while legally in the custody of a common carrier awaiting shipment or\ndelivery to a consignee during the time permitted by federal law; nor to\nthe storage of such limited amount of sporting or smokeless powders as\nmay be permitted by the regulations promulgated pursuant to this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>