<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-517"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-517"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="517"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-517/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-517/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-517/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-517/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_517">
        <num>517</num>
        <heading>Remuneration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amount of any payment made to, or on behalf of, any employee\nor any of his dependents under a plan or system established by an\nemployer which makes provision for his employees generally, or for such\nemployees and their dependents, or for a class or classes of his\nemployees, or for a class or classes of such employees and their\ndependents, including any amount paid by an employer for insurance or\nannuities, or into a fund, to provide for any such payment, on account\nof retirement, or sickness or accident disability, or medical or\nhospitalization expenses in connection with sickness or accident\ndisability, or death.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payment by an employer without deduction from the remuneration of\nthe employee of the tax imposed upon an employee under the federal\ninsurance contributions act.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any payment made to an employee, including any amount paid by an\nemployer for insurance or annuities, or into a fund, to provide for any\nsuch payment, on account of retirement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any payment on account of sickness or accident disability, or\nmedical or hospitalization expenses in connection with sickness or\naccident disability, made by an employer to, or on behalf of, an\nemployee after the expiration of six calendar months following the last\ncalendar month in which the employee worked for such employer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any payment made to, or on behalf of, an employee or his\nbeneficiary from or to a trust described in section four hundred one</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof the federal internal revenue code which is exempt from tax under\nsection five hundred one</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of such code at the time of such payment\nunless such payment is made to an employee of the trust as remuneration\nfor services rendered as such employee and not as a beneficiary of the\ntrust, or under or to an annuity plan which, at the time of such\npayment, meets the requirements of section four hundred one</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_517__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_517__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_517__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_517__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of such code.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation paid in any medium other than cash to an employee for\nservice not in the course of the employer's trade or business.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any payment, other than vacation or sick pay, made to an employee\nafter the month in which he attains the age of sixty-five, if he did not\nwork for the employer in the period for which such payment is made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Dismissal payments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_517__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any payment made by an employer who is not liable for\ncontributions under this article or for payments in lieu of\ncontributions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>