<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-538"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-538"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-08-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="538"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-538/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-538/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-538/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-538/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_538">
        <num>538</num>
        <heading>Representation and witness fees and other expenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No fee shall be charged in any\nproceeding under this article by the commissioner, by the appeal board\nor by any court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any proceeding under this article a party may be represented by\nan agent, but no fees for services rendered by such agent shall be\nallowable unless such agent is registered with the appeal board or is an\nattorney.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Claims of representatives for services rendered to a claimant in\nconnection with any claim arising under this article shall not be\nenforceable unless approved by the appeal board and shall in no event\nexceed the benefit allowed, except as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision. In approving any fee requested by a representative pursuant\nto this section, the appeal board shall consider the following factors:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total benefit allowed; (ii) the time spent in providing\nrepresentation; (iii) the legal and factual complexities involved; and\n(iv) such other factors as the appeal board may deem relevant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any fee which may be allowed by the appeal board\nfor services rendered to the claimant, an attorney representing a\nclaimant shall be entitled to a fee not to exceed the sum of five\nhundred dollars and necessary printing and other disbursements in each\nof the following cases:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_538__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On an appeal from a decision of the appeal\nboard in favor of the claimant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_538__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On a motion for leave to appeal to\nthe court of appeals from a decision of the appellate division of the\nsupreme court which relates to a decision of the appeal board in favor\nof the claimant.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_538__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On an appeal to the court of appeals from a\ndecision of the appellate division of the supreme court which relates to\na decision of the appeal board in favor of the claimant. When a claimant\ntakes such appeal, the court shall allow a fee and disbursements only if\nit finds the appeal to have been meritorious.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall appoint an attorney to represent the claimant if\nhe is unrepresented in each of the cases described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nhereof, except when the claimant takes an appeal to the court of\nappeals. Fees and disbursements provided in such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall be\nfixed by the court in which the appeal is taken or the motion for leave\nto appeal is made. Such fees and disbursements shall be paid by the\ncommissioner as part of the expenses incurred in the administration of\nthis article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person, firm, or corporation who shall exact or receive any\nremuneration or gratuity for any services rendered to or on behalf of a\nclaimant except as allowed by this section and in an amount approved by\nthe board or a court shall be guilty of a misdemeanor. The appeal board\nshall order the restitution of any fee paid by a claimant to a\nrepresentative to the extent that it exceeds the amount authorized by\nthis section.\n  2. Fees of witnesses and other expenses. Fees of witnesses and other\nexpenses, except representation services, involved in proceedings under\nthis article shall be paid at a rate to be established by regulation of\nthe commissioner except that such fees and other expenses involved in\nproceedings before referees and the appeal board shall be paid at a rate\nto be established by regulation of this board. Such fees or other\nexpenses shall be treated as expenses under this article.\n  3. Representatives; lists. *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The appeal board shall establish the\nqualifications and procedures for the registration of agents authorized\nto represent claimants in connection with any claims arising under this\narticle. An agent shall be registered as authorized to represent\nclaimants by providing the appeal board with his name, business address\nand telephone number and by posting a bond with the appeal board in the\namount of five hundred dollars for the benefit of claimants charged fees\nby said representative in excess of those approved pursuant to this\nsection and with respect to which restitution has been ordered pursuant\nto paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this section. An agent shall be\nregistered as authorized to represent an employer by providing the\nappeal board with a letter of authorization from the employer. No agent\nmay be registered who knowingly violates paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\none of this section.\n  * NB Expires December 31, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An attorney who is available to represent claimants may notify the\nappeal board by providing his name, business address and telephone\nnumber.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_538__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The appeal board shall maintain lists of authorized agents and\nattorneys who are available to represent claimants and shall make such\nlists available to claimants on request.\n  * NB Expires December 31, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>