<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-560"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-560"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="560"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-560/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-560/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-560/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-560/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_560">
        <num>560</num>
        <heading>Terms of coverage</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_560__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In conformity with subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_560__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection thirty-three hundred five of the federal unemployment tax act,\nany instrumentality of the United States, except such as are wholly or\npartially owned by the United States, or exempt from tax imposed by\nsection thirty-three hundred one of said act by virtue of any provision\nof law, which specifically refers to such section, or the corresponding\nsection of prior law, in granting such exemption, shall be subject to\nall the provisions of this article, except as provided in section\nfifty-two hundred forty of the revised statutes of the United States, as\namended and modified by subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_560__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section thirty-three hundred\nfive of said act. If in any year this state shall not be certified under\nsection thirty-three hundred four of said act, any contributions\nrequired under this article from any such instrumentality of the United\nStates with respect to such year, including penalty and interest\ncollected with respect thereto, if any, shall be refunded without\ninterest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_560__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In conformity with subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_560__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section thirty-three hundred\nfive of the federal unemployment tax act, the commissioner is authorized\nto transmit a copy of any return or report of a national banking\nassociation relative to the association's employees, their remuneration\nand services, to the comptroller of the currency and to request the said\ncomptroller of the currency to cause an examination of the correctness\nof such return or report to be made at the time of the next succeeding\nexamination of such association, and thereupon to transmit to the\ncommissioner a complete statement of his findings respecting the\naccuracy of such returns or reports.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_560__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This subdivision applies to national banking associations and any\nother federal instrumentalities which would be immune from contributions\nrequired under this article without authorization by subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_560__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection thirty-three hundred five of the federal unemployment tax act.\n  5. Primary liability for contributions. Whenever one employer\ncontracts with a second employer for any work which is part of the first\nemployer's usual trade, occupation, profession or enterprise, the first\nemployer shall be liable for any contributions otherwise payable by the\nsecond employer, based upon wages paid in respect to such work, unless\nthe second employer is free to do business with anyone who may wish to\ncontract with him. Contributions so paid by the first employer on behalf\nof the second employer shall be deemed paid by the second employer. If\nthe first employer fails to pay, on the date prescribed by the\ncommissioner, contributions due on wages paid by the second employer,\nthe commissioner may collect such deficiency from the second employer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>