<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-602-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-602-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-10-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="602-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-602-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-602-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-602-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-602-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_602_A">
        <num>602-A</num>
        <heading>Outreach</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 602-a. Outreach. 1. The commissioner shall have the obligation and\nduty of providing informational materials regarding shared work program\neligibility. Such materials shall be made available on the department's\nwebsite and provided to each employer within the state annually through\nsuch means as the commissioner deems appropriate.\n  2. The department shall conduct outreach to employers within the state\nfor purposes of providing information regarding the benefits of shared\nwork programs, including by remote and in-person information sessions,\ncorrespondence, assistance in completing an application for approval of\na shared work program, and such other means as the commissioner may deem\nappropriate. The department shall consult and coordinate with the\ndepartment of economic development, small business development centers\nand any other relevant agency, department, office, division, board,\nbureau, commission or authority.\n  3. The department shall report to the governor, the temporary\npresident of the senate and the speaker of the assembly on any and all\noutreach efforts made pursuant to this section on an annual basis\nbeginning one year after the effective date of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>