<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-605-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-605-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-10-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="605-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-605-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-605-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-605-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-605-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_605_A">
        <num>605-A</num>
        <heading>Shared work program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 605-a. Shared work program. 1. Any group of employees who may\nreasonably be expected to experience an employment loss as a consequence\nof a reduction in workforce or have experienced employment loss as a\nconsequence of a reduction in workforce may petition in writing the\nemployer of such group of employees to apply to participate in a shared\nwork program pursuant to this article for purposes of avoiding such\nreduction in workforce or for purposes of re-hiring any former employee\nor employees of the employer that were laid off due to a reduction in\nworkforce. Such employer shall, no later than seven days after such\npetition has been made, respond in writing to such group of employees.\nSuch response shall state the decision of the employer to apply or not\nto apply to participate in a shared work program, and the reason for\ndeciding to apply or not to apply to participate in a shared work\nprogram, and if the employer did apply, the outcome of the application,\nif available.\n  2. No employer or their agent, or person acting as or on behalf of a\nhiring entity, or the officer or agent of any corporation, partnership,\nor limited liability company, shall discriminate, retaliate against, or\ntake adverse action against any employee for exercising the rights\nafforded to them under this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>