<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-624"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-624"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="624"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_624">
        <num>624</num>
        <heading>Appeals to courts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 624. Appeals to courts. Within thirty days after the mailing or\npersonal delivery of notice of a decision by the appeal board, the\ncommissioner or any other party affected thereby who appeared at the\nappeal before the board may appeal questions of law involved in such\ndecision to the appellate division of the supreme court, third\ndepartment. The board may also, in its discretion, certify to such court\nquestions of law involved in its decisions.  Such appeals and the\nquestions so certified shall be heard in a summary manner and shall have\nprecedence over all other civil cases in such court except cases arising\nunder the workmen's compensation law. The commissioner shall be\nrepresented in court by the attorney-general without additional\ncompensation. An appeal may be taken from the decision of such court to\nthe court of appeals in the same manner and subject to the same\nlimitations, not inconsistent herewith, as is provided for in civil\naction. It shall not be necessary to file exception to the rulings of\nthe appeal board. No bond shall be required to be filed upon an appeal\nto the appellate division or to the court of appeals, except as\nhereinafter provided. Upon final determination of an appeal, the appeal\nboard shall enter an order in accordance with such determination.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>