<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-677"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-677"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="677"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-677/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-677/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-677/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-677/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_677">
        <num>677</num>
        <heading>Appeals from compliance orders</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 677. Appeals from compliance orders.  Within sixty days after the\nissuance by the commissioner of an order to comply with any provision of\nthis article or with any minimum wage regulation promulgated thereunder,\nany person aggrieved may appeal questions of law and fact involved in\nsuch order to the board of standards and appeals by filing with said\nboard a written petition in accordance with such rules as the board\nshall prescribe, provided, however, that no such appeal shall bring\nunder review any minimum wage regulation promulgated under this article.\nThe provisions of subdivision two of section six hundred seventy-six\nrelating to appeals from determinations of the board and the provisions\nof subdivisions three through seven of section six hundred seventy-six\nshall apply to appeals such as herein provided. Unless an appeal such as\nherein provided is taken within the prescribed time, the findings of\nfact and conclusions of law contained in such order to comply shall be\nfinal and binding and no board or court shall have jurisdiction to\nreview such order, or finding or conclusion contained therein, or to\nrestrain or interfere with its enforcement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>