<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-692"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-692"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="692"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-692/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-692/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-692/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-692/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_692">
        <num>692</num>
        <heading>Statement of job conditions; records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 692. Statement of job conditions; records. 1. Every licensed\nemployment agency under the jurisdiction of the commissioner and engaged\nin the job placement of domestic workers or household employees shall\nprovide to each applicant for employment as a domestic worker or\nhousehold employee a written statement, in a form approved by the\ncommissioner, of the job conditions of each potential employment\nposition to which the agency recommends that the applicant apply. Each\nsuch statement shall fully and accurately describe the nature and terms\nof employment, including the name and address of the person to whom the\napplicant is to apply for such employment, the name and address of the\nperson authorizing the hiring for such position, wages, hours of work,\nthe kind of services to be performed and agency fee.\n  2. Every employment agency engaged in the job placement of domestic\nworkers or household employees shall keep on file in its principal place\nof business for a period of three years a duplicate copy of the written\nstatement of job conditions required by subdivision one of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>