<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-704-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-704-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="704-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-704-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-704-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-704-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-704-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_704_B">
        <num>704-B</num>
        <heading>Unfair labor practices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 704-b. Unfair labor practices. 1. It shall be an unfair labor\npractice for a farm laborer or an employee organization representing\nfarm laborers to strike any agricultural employer. The term "strike"\nshall mean, for the purposes of this section, any strike or other\nconcerted stoppage of work or slowdown by farm laborers.\n  2. It shall be an unfair labor practice for an agricultural employer\nto:\n  a. lockout its laborers. The term "lockout" shall mean, for the\npurposes of this section, a refusal by an agricultural employer to\npermit farm laborers to work as a result of a dispute with such farm\nlaborers or employee organization representing such farm laborers that\naffects wages, hours and other terms and conditions of employment of\nsuch farm laborers, provided, however, that a lockout shall not include\na termination of employment for good cause that does not involve such\nlaborers exercising any rights guaranteed by this article;\n  b. refuse to continue all the terms of an expired agreement until a\nnew agreement is negotiated;\n  c. discourage union organization or to discourage an employee from\nparticipating in a union organizing drive, engaging in protected\nconcerted activity, or otherwise exercising the rights guaranteed under\nthis article.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall be construed as to bar any proceeding\nbrought pursuant to section seven hundred four or seven hundred five of\nthis article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>