<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-807"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-807"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="807"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_807">
        <num>807</num>
        <heading>Injunctions issued in labor disputes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That unlawful acts have or a breach of any contract not contrary\nto public policy has been threatened or committed and that such acts or\nbreach will be executed or continued unless restrained;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That substantial and irreparable injury to complainant's property\nwill follow unless the relief requested is granted;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That as to each item of relief granted greater injury will be\ninflicted upon complainant by the denial thereof than will be inflicted\nupon defendants by the granting thereof;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That complainant has no adequate remedy at law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That the public officers charged with the duty to protect\ncomplainant's property have failed or are unable to furnish adequate\nprotection; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That no item of relief granted prohibits directly or indirectly\nany person or persons from doing, whether singly or in concert, any of\nthe following acts:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Ceasing or refusing to perform any work or to remain in any\nrelation of employment;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Becoming or remaining a member of any labor organization or of any\nemployer organization, regardless of any agreement, undertaking or\npromise;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Paying or giving to, or withholding from, any person any strike or\nunemployment benefits or insurance or other moneys or things of value;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>By all lawful means aiding any person who is being proceeded\nagainst in, or is prosecuting any action or suit in any court of the\nUnited States or of any state;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Giving publicity to and obtaining or communicating information\nregarding the existence of, or the facts involved in, any dispute,\nwhether by advertising, speaking, picketing, patrolling any public\nstreet or any place where any person or persons may lawfully be, or by\nany other method not involving fraud, violence or breach of the peace;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Ceasing to patronize or to employ any person or persons;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Assembling peaceably to do or to organize to do any of the acts\nheretofore specified or to promote lawful interests;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Advising or notifying any person or persons of any intention to do\nany of the acts heretofore specified;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Agreeing with other persons to do or not to do any of the acts\nheretofore specified;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Advising, urging or inducing without fraud, violence or threat\nthereof, others to do the acts heretofore specified;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_807__subsec_f__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Doing in concert of any or all of the acts heretofore specified\non the ground that the persons engaged therein constitute an unlawful\ncombination or conspiracy or on any other grounds whatsoever.\n  2. Such hearings shall be held only after a verified complaint\nspecifying in detail the time, place and the nature of the acts\ncomplained of and the names of the persons alleged to have committed the\nsame or participated therein have been served and after due and personal\nnotice, in such manner as the court shall direct, has been given to all\nknown persons against whom relief is sought and also to the public\nofficers charged with the duty to protect the complainant's property.\nThe hearing shall consist of the taking of testimony in open court with\nopportunity for cross-examination and testimony in opposition thereto,\nif offered, and no affidavits shall be received in support of any of the\nallegations of the complaint.\n  Provided, however, that a court or a judge thereof may iss...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is a labor dispute which directly and immediately involves:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The production on a farm of milk, fruits, berries, vegetables or\nother farm produce; or\n  (ii) The shipment of any such product from the farm where it was\nproduced; or\n  (iii) The first storage of any such product after shipment from the\nfarm where it was produced; or\n  (iv) The first processing by canning or freezing of fruits, berries or\nvegetables; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The plaintiff is a producer of such product; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such product is in a perishable condition; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The verified complaint and other testimony submitted by the\nplaintiff, under oath, if sustained, would be sufficient not only to\njustify the court in issuing a temporary injunction upon a hearing after\nnotice in accordance with the provisions of this section, but also to\nshow that the plaintiff will be irreparably damaged unless a restraining\norder is issued; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court or judge, before issuing the restraining order, makes a\ndecision to be filed in the record of the case in which he finds\nspecifically that each of the facts called for by subdivision one above\nof this section has been established prima facie by the weight of the\nevidence submitted in support of the application for the restraining\norder and in opposition thereto.\n  Any such restraining order shall be effective for no longer than five\ndays and shall become void and not be subject to renewal at the\nexpiration of said five days.\n  3. No temporary injunction or restraining order shall be issued except\non condition that plaintiff shall first file a minimum undertaking of\none thousand dollars. Where an injunction or restraining order is sought\nagainst more than a single individual, the court on the hearing shall\nmake a finding of the number of individuals sought to be enjoined and\nthe undertaking shall be increased by the sum of twenty dollars for each\nadditional member of a local or national body sought to be enjoined. The\nmaximum undertaking which may be required shall not exceed ten thousand\ndollars. The undertaking shall be sufficient to recompense those\nenjoined for any loss, expense or damage caused by the improvident or\nimproper issuance of such injunction, including all reasonable costs\n(together with reasonable attorney's fees), and expense against the\ngranting of any injunctive relief sought in the same proceeding and\nsubsequently denied by the court. The undertaking herein mentioned shall\nconstitute an agreement on the part of the plaintiff and the surety upon\nwhich a judgment may be entered in the same action or proceeding against\nsaid plaintiff and surety. The filing of the undertaking shall be deemed\nan appearance by the surety for that purpose. But nothing herein\ncontained shall deprive any party having a claim or cause of action\nunder or upon such undertaking from electing to pursue his ordinary\nremedy by suit at law o...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the doing of such acts by\npersons who are officers, members or agents of any such association or\norganization, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>actual participation in, or actual authorization\nof, such acts, or ratification of such acts after actual knowledge\nthereof by such association or organization.\n  7. Every temporary injunction and restraining order shall by its terms\nexpire within such time after entry as the court or judge may fix, not\nto exceed ten days, unless the plaintiff is ready by the expiration of\nthat period to proceed to trial and shall pay the necessary calendar and\ntrial fees.\n  8. No permanent injunction shall remain in force for more than six\nmonths from the date on which the judgment is signed, provided, however,\nthat the duration of the injunction may be extended for another six\nmonths, if after a further hearing initiated and conducted in the same\nmanner as the original hearing the court shall determine that the\ninjunction shall be continued or modified in accordance with the\nfindings of facts on the subsequent hearing.\n  9. Whenever any court or judge or judges thereof shall issue or deny\nany temporary injunction in a case involving or growing out of a labor\ndispute the stenographer shall furnish to the clerk within ten days the\noriginal transcript of the minutes after fees therefor have been paid.\nImmediately upon receiving such minutes the clerk shall cause notice of\nthat fact to be sent to the attorney for the appellant, or to the\nappellant if he has not appeared by attorney. The appellant or his\nattorney shall then procure the case to be settled on written notice of\nat least three days to the clerk and to the attorney for the respondent\nor to the respondent if he has not appeared by attorney, returnable\nbefore the justice who tried the case. The clerk must thereupon make a\nreturn to the appellate court, which must contain the summons,\npleadings, evidence and judgment or final order and all other necessary\npapers and proceedings and have annexed thereto the opinion of the\ncourt, if any, and the notice of appeal. The justice before whom the\ncase was...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A case shall be held to involve or to grow out of a labor dispute\nwhen the case involves persons who are engaged in the same industry,\ntrade, craft or occupation, or who are employees of one employer; or who\nare members of the same or an affiliated organization of employers or\nemployees; whether such dispute is between one or more employers or\nassociations of employers and one or more employees or associations of\nemployees; between one or more employers or associations of employers\nand one or more employers or associations of employers; or between one\nor more employees or associations of employees and one or more employees\nor associations of employees; or when the case involves any conflicting\nor competing interests in a "labor dispute" (as hereinafter defined) of\n"persons participating or interested" therein (as hereinafter defined).\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person or association shall be held to be a person participating\nor interested in a labor dispute if relief is sought against him or it\nand if he or it is engaged in the industry, trade, craft or occupation\nin which such dispute occurs, or is a member, officer or agent of any\nassociation of employers or employees engaged in such industry, trade,\ncraft or occupation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_807__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term "labor dispute" includes any controversy concerning terms\nor conditions of employment, or concerning the association or\nrepresentation of persons in negotiating, fixing, maintaining, changing\nor seeking to arrange terms or conditions of employment, or concerning\nemployment relations, or any other controversy arising out of the\nrespective interests of employer and employee, regardless of whether or\nnot the disputants stand in the relation of employer and employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>