<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-815"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-815"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="815"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_815">
        <num>815</num>
        <heading>Suggested standards for apprenticeship agreements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 815. Suggested standards for apprenticeship agreements.  Suggested\nstandards for apprenticeship agreements are as follows:\n  1. A statement of the trade or craft to be taught and the required\nhours for completion of apprenticeship which shall be not less than four\nthousand hours of reasonably continuous employment.\n  2. A statement of the processes in the trade or craft divisions in\nwhich the apprentice is to be taught and the approximate amount of time\nto be spent at each process.\n  3. A statement of the number of hours to be spent by the apprentice in\nwork and the number of hours to be spent in related and supplemental\ninstruction which instruction shall be not less than one hundred\nforty-four hours per year when available, such availability to be\ndetermined by the commissioner of education.\n  4. A statement that apprentices shall be not less than sixteen years\nof age.\n  5. Provision that apprentices shall be selected on the basis of\nqualifications alone, as determined by objective criteria which permit\nreview, and without any direct or indirect limitation, specification or\ndiscrimination as to race, creed, color, age, sex or national origin.\n  6. A statement of the progressively increasing scale of wages to be\npaid the apprentice.\n  7. Provision for a period of probation during which the industrial\ncommissioner shall be directed to terminate an apprenticeship agreement\nat the request in writing of any party thereto. After the probationary\nperiod the industrial commissioner shall be empowered to terminate the\nregistration of an apprentice upon agreement of the parties.\n  8. Provision that the services of the industrial commissioner may be\nutilized for consultation regarding the settlement of differences\narising out of the apprenticeship agreement where such differences\ncannot be adjusted locally or in accordance with the established trade\nprocedure.\n  9. Provision that if an employer is unable to fulfill his obligation\nunder the apprenticeship agreement he may transfer such obligation to\nanother employer.\n  10. Such additional standards as may be prescribed in accordance with\nthe provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>