<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-821"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-821"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="821"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-821/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-821/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-821/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-821/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_821">
        <num>821</num>
        <heading>State training courses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 821. State training courses. The commissioner may provide for career\nand related, institutional and on-the-job training courses as described\nin section five hundred ninety-nine of this chapter and for the\nadministration of public work projects for recipients of public\nassistance, and may contract for these purposes with public and private\nagencies including public and private institutions of learning,\nemployers or other appropriate organizations. He shall select for and\nrefer to such training courses unemployed and under-employed persons who\nwould meet the conditions for approval as specified in section five\nhundred ninety-nine of this chapter. He shall select and refer to public\nwork projects all public assistance recipients registered at employment\noffices of the department who are neither referred thereby for\nemployment in the regular economy or for career training, nor assigned\nto public works projects by social welfare officials. The commissioner\nmay provide for such payments, either in advance or by way of\nreimbursement, from funds made available to carry out the purposes of\nthis article, as he deems necessary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>