<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-840"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-840"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="840"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-840/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-840/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-840/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-840/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_840">
        <num>840</num>
        <heading>State level activities, rapid response</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on site intervention within forty-eight hours of notification of\neither a plant closing or a substantial layoff;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provision of emergency basic readjustment services as needed;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>promotion of labor-management cooperation through the initiation,\nwith the department of economic development, where appropriate, of\nlabor-management committees;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>development, with the department of economic development, of an\nearly warning system;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>dissemination of information on dislocated worker services\navailable under title III of the federal Job Training Partnership Act\n(P.L. 97-300) and other appropriate services funded by the federal,\nstate, and local governments;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provision of technical assistance to substate grantees;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>receipt of notifications of layoffs and closings and provision to\nsubstate grantees of such information as soon as possible to assure the\nmaximum local response;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>coordination between rapid response activities and the\nunemployment insurance system and the job training partnership system,\nstate and local economic development activities and the regional\neducation centers of the state education department; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_840__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>notification of appropriate state agency staff and coordination\nwith the activities of central, local or regional staff of the\ndepartments of labor, economic development and education to facilitate\nadditional on-site contact with employer and employee representatives\nwithin a short period of time, preferably forty-eight hours, after\nbecoming aware of a current or projected permanent closure or\nsubstantial layoff in order to provide information on and facilitate\naccess to available public programs and services.\n  3. The commissioner may, under exceptional circumstances, authorize\nthe designated dislocated worker unit to provide rapid response services\nwhen the employment loss is for less than twenty-five employees, is not\nat a single site of employment or does not take place during a single\nthirty day period. For purposes of this subdivision, exceptional\ncircumstances include those situations which would have a major impact\non the community or communities in which they occur.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>