<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-841"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-841"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="841"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-841/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-841/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-841/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-841/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_841">
        <num>841</num>
        <heading>Regional and demonstration projects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_841__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state unit shall conduct statewide projects and\ndemonstration programs to address the needs of distressed industries and\nto provide for projects that would lead to the development of innovative\nstrategies to meet the needs of dislocated workers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_841__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such projects shall emphasize retraining, and include counseling\nand assessment components.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_841__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Funding for such projects shall be allocated through a contract\nprocess subject to the state plan and in coordination with the substate\ngrantees affected.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_841__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Funding for projects and programs shall be made available in\nannual rounds, by December thirty-first of each fiscal year beginning in\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine.  The department shall, by rule, establish\na solicitation and award evaluation process for funds made available for\nthis purpose. Such rules shall specify the criteria by which the\ndepartment shall evaluate proposals and determine which shall receive\nfunding. The evaluation process shall consider the ability of the\nprovider to accomplish the proposal based on past performance,\nadministrative capability and fiscal responsibility, the innovativeness\nof the proposal, the expected improvement in the delivery of services\nwithin the area served by the substate grantee, the extent to which\nelements of the proposal may be replicated in other service areas within\nthe state, and such other factors as the commissioner shall, by rule,\nprescribe.\n  2. Regional projects.  The state unit shall provide extended\nretraining and basic readjustment services directly through the\ndepartment, through awards to substate grantees or through awards by the\ndepartment to service providers. Substate grantees shall have preference\nin receiving such grants. Such grants shall be made available from funds\nallocated to the state pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_841__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of\nsection eight hundred forty-seven of this article and shall be subject\nto such requirements as are imposed by section eight hundred forty-seven\nof this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>