<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-843"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-843"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="843"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-843/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-843/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-843/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-843/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_843">
        <num>843</num>
        <heading>Employer specific skills training</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>describe the amount and purposes\nfor which funding is requested;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>describe the training services to be\nprovided, including the duration of training and the estimated training\ncost per recipient;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>show evidence that the proposed training program\nwill provide appropriate assistance to recipients;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>describe other\nfunding sources which may be used for such training;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>describe the\nsteps the provider will take to avoid duplication of training available\nthrough existing resources;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>describe the provider's coordination\nwith programs and activities funded through the job training partnership\nact or other state resources; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such other information as may be\nrequired by the commissioner of education. No grant shall exceed fifty\npercent of total program cost.\n  4. Evaluation of grant applications. The commissioner of education\nshall make grant awards based on evaluation of the following criteria,\nat a minimum:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provider's past effectiveness in delivering\ntraining programs based on demonstrated performance;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ability to\nprovide participants with the skills necessary to fill available jobs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the administrative capability to operate such a training program;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>cost of the proposed program;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>where appropriate, evidence that\nthe provider has made provisions for coordination with other services\navailable from the department of economic development, the department of\nlabor, such other state agencies as may be relevant, and local grantees;\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such other factors as the commissioner of education shall deem\nappropriate.\n  5. In the event of a plant closing or substantial layoff as defined in\nsubdivisions ten and sixteen of section eight hundred thirty-five of\nthis article, the state education department shall participate in rapid\nresponse activity and make available appropriate resources for training\ninterventions through the regional education centers for economic\ndevelopment.\n  6. In developing projects in response to training needs for dislocated\nworkers or additional dislocated workers, the commissioner of education\nshall approve and fund from this article, only employer specific\ntraining projects that have been certified in writing by the substate\ngrantee as consistent with the area's substate plan after formal\nconsultation with the state education department.\n  7. Funds available under this paragraph shall be allocated to each\nregion based on a formula which includes the relative number of\nunemployed individuals within each region and available plant closing\nand substantial layoff data published by the department under the\npermanent mass layoff and plant closing statistical series. However,\nafter March first of each fiscal year, the commissioner of education, in\na manner consistent with applicable federal law and regulations, shall\nreapportion any amount of any allocation otherwise due to a region if he\nor she determines that such amount cannot be obligated within such\nregion. Such reapportionment shall be distributed in a manner consistent\nwith the purposes of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>