<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-882"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-882"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="882"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-882/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-882/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-882/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-882/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_882">
        <num>882</num>
        <heading>Penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 882. Penalties. 1. Civil penalty. Any employer who fails to comply\nwith the provisions of this article shall be liable for a civil penalty\nnot to exceed ten thousand dollars in addition to any other damages for\nwhich an employer may be liable pursuant to any other provision of law.\nThe attorney general may bring an action in the supreme court against\nany person or persons alleged to have violated the provisions of this\narticle. In any such action the supreme court shall have jurisdiction to\nrestrain violations of this article and to levy appropriate penalties.\nAny penalty assessed for the violation of any of the provisions of this\narticle shall be payable to the commissioner of health to be utilized\nfor the purposes of environmental health pursuant to section forty-eight\nhundred two of the public health law.\n  2. Criminal penalty. Any person who willfully and intentionally\nviolates the provisions of this article is guilty of a misdemeanor and\nupon conviction shall be punished, for a first offense, by a fine of not\nmore than five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than\nthirty days or by both such fine and imprisonment; for a subsequent\noffense by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars, or by\nimprisonment for not more than ninety days, or by both such fine and\nimprisonment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>