<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-902"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-902"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="902"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-902/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-902/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-902/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-902/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_902">
        <num>902</num>
        <heading>Licensing and certification requirements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 902. Licensing and certification requirements. 1. It shall be\nunlawful for any contractor to engage in an asbestos project unless such\ncontractor has a valid asbestos handling license issued by the\ncommissioner. Such license will not be issued without evidence of\nsuccessful completion by the contractor, or a supervisor designated to\nact as the contractor's agent, of an approved asbestos safety program\nwhich is, at the least, equivalent to the U.S. Environmental Protection\nAgency Model Accreditation Plan (40 CFR Part 763) and the submission of\nany additional information which the commissioner may require.\n  2. A copy of a valid asbestos handling license or other proof of the\nissuance of a valid asbestos handling license granted to the contractor\nwho will be undertaking the asbestos project must be submitted by the\nbidder in a form acceptable to the commissioner prior to the award of\nany public works contract all or part of which involves an asbestos\nproject.\n  3. A copy of a valid asbestos handling license must be conspicuously\ndisplayed at the work site on an asbestos project.\n  4. It shall be unlawful for any contractor to engage in or to permit a\nperson employed by the contractor, including but not limited to\nhandlers, project designers, inspectors and management planners, to\nengage in work on an asbestos project or to supervise persons engaging\nin work on an asbestos project unless each such person and supervisor\nhas a valid asbestos handling certificate. Such certificate will not be\nissued without evidence of successful completion by each such person of\nan approved asbestos safety program and the submission of any additional\ninformation which the commissioner may require.\n  5. Any person employed on an asbestos project or the supervisor of any\nperson engaged in work on an asbestos project or any other person who is\notherwise required by law or regulation to obtain an asbestos handler's\ncertificate shall have in his or her possession at all times during the\nwork on the project a copy of the asbestos handling certificate issued\nto the person by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>