<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="903"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_903">
        <num>903</num>
        <heading>License and certification procedure</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 903. License and certification procedure.  1. All applications for\nasbestos handling licenses or certificates shall be submitted in writing\non forms furnished by the commissioner and shall contain such\ninformation which the commissioner may require. An application for an\nasbestos handling license shall contain a statement by the asbestos\ncontractor or its duly authorized representative, which shall be\nsubscribed by the asbestos contractor or its duly authorized\nrepresentative and affirmed as true under penalties of perjury, that all\npersons employed by the asbestos contractor on any asbestos project\nwhose duties involve the removal, encapsulation, enclosure, repair or\ndisturbance of asbestos, or any handling of asbestos material that may\nresult in the release of asbestos fiber or the supervision thereof,\nshall have valid asbestos handling certificates and that the asbestos\ncontractor will abide by all the rules and regulations promulgated\npursuant to this article. The commissioner shall have the authority to\ndeny the issuance or renewal of a license or certificate for good cause\nshown, including the serious violation of state, federal or local laws\nby the applicant or by any substantially owned-affiliated entity of the\napplicant with regard to the conduct of any job involving asbestos or\nasbestos material, or for any serious violation or violations that\nresulted in a suspended or revoked license or certificate during the\nprevious five years.\n  2. The fee for an asbestos handling license shall be five hundred\ndollars, which shall accompany each license application.\n  3. The renewal fee for an asbestos handling license shall be three\nhundred dollars, which shall accompany each license renewal application.\n  4. An asbestos handling license shall be valid for a period of one\nyear from the date of issuance and may be renewed on conditions set by\nthe commissioner related to additional training.\n  5. The fee for an asbestos handling certificate shall be assessed in\naccordance with the following and shall accompany each certificate\napplication.\n                                                          Application\n   Schedule: Asbestos Handling Certificate Category          Fee\n   Management Planner                                       $150\n   Project Designer                                          150\n   Inspector                                                 100\n   Air Monitor                                                75\n   Supervisor                                                 75\n   Asbestos Handler                                           50\n   Operation and Maintenance                                  50\n   Restricted Handler                                         50\n  6. The renewal fee for any annual asbestos handling certificate shall\nbe equal to the application fee set forth herein, and shall accompany\neach certificate renewal application.\n  7. An asbestos handling certificate shall be valid for a period of one\nyear from date of issuance and may be renewed on conditions set by the\ncommissioner related to additional training.\n  8. Within thirty days of the receipt of the application and fee for\nany license or certificate issued under this section, the commissioner\nshall either issue the license or certificate or deny the license or\ncertificate setting forth the reason for such denial in writing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>