<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-904"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-904"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="904"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-904/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-904/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-904/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-904/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_904">
        <num>904</num>
        <heading>Notice and recordkeeping requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_904__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pursuant\nto a plan adopted pursuant to article fifteen of the general municipal\nlaw;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_904__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pursuant to a plan adopted pursuant to article eighteen-C of\nthe general municipal law; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_904__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by or on behalf of a land bank\noperating pursuant to article sixteen of the not-for-profit corporation\nlaw.\n  3. Upon the expiration, revocation or non-renewal of an asbestos\nhandling license, or at any other time at the request of the\ncommissioner, any records required to be kept pursuant to this section\nshall be given to the commissioner.\n  4. A contractor shall post or otherwise provide for written\nnotification to residential and business occupants of a building ten\ndays prior to the commencement of work on any asbestos project in the\nbuilding or, if the work is scheduled to begin less than ten days after\nthe execution of the contract, at least three days prior to the\ncommencement of work, or if emergency conditions make it impossible to\nprovide ten days notice or three days notice as applicable, as soon as\npracticable after identification of the project. The notification shall\nbe made in such a manner and shall contain such information as is\nreasonably necessary to advise such occupants of any asbestos project in\nthe building, according to regulations promulgated by the commissioner.\nIf posted, such notice shall remain in place until completion of the\nproject. It shall be a violation of this chapter for any person to\ninterfere with the obligations of a contractor under this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>