<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-906"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-906"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="906"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_906">
        <num>906</num>
        <heading>Regulations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 906. Regulations. The commissioner shall promulgate such rules and\nregulations as shall be necessary and proper to effectuate the purposes\nand provisions of this article and to comply with the requirements of\nthe Federal Asbestos Hazard Emergency Response Act and any other\napplicable federal standards. Such regulations shall include but not be\nlimited to (1) standards for asbestos projects including methods of\nremoving, encapsulating, enclosing or disturbing friable asbestos and\nstandards for any handling of asbestos material which may result in the\ncreation of friable asbestos or any handling of asbestos material that\nmay result in the release of asbestos fibers, as shall be necessary to\nprotect the public health and safety and shall include regulations which\nwill permit such disturbance that results from actions that are\nnecessary to abate an emergency which poses an immediate threat to\nsafety or the public health; (2) standards for asbestos projects and\nin-plant operations setting licensing and certification requirements;\nand (3) standards for asbestos projects and in-plant operations setting\ngoal air monitoring and clearance requirements, including those\nnecessary to insure that asbestos work is properly designated as an\nin-plant operation as defined in subdivision twelve of section nine\nhundred one of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>