<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-946"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-946"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="946"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-946/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-946/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-946/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-946/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_946">
        <num>946</num>
        <heading>Minimum work standards for the conduct of mold remediation by licensed persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 946. Minimum work standards for the conduct of mold remediation by\nlicensed persons. 1. A mold remediation licensee shall prepare a mold\nremediation work plan that is specific to each project, fulfills all the\nrequirements of the mold remediation plan developed by the mold\nassessment licensee as provided to the client and provides specific\ninstructions and/or standard operating procedures for how a mold\nremediation project will be performed. The mold remediation licensee\nshall provide the mold remediation work plan to the client before site\npreparation work begins.\n  2. If a mold assessment licensee specifies in the mold remediation\nplan that personal protection equipment (PPE) is required for the\nproject, the mold remediation licensee shall provide the specified PPE\nto all employees who engage in remediation activities and who will, or\nare anticipated to, disturb or remove mold contamination. The\ncontainment, when constructed as described in the remediation work plan\nand under normal conditions of use, must prevent the spread of mold to\nareas outside the containment.\n  3. Signs advising that a mold remediation project is in progress shall\nbe displayed at all accessible entrances to remediation areas.\n  4. No person shall remove or dismantle any containment structures or\nmaterials from a project site prior to receipt by the mold remediation\nlicensee overseeing the project of a notice from a mold assessment\nlicensee that the project has achieved clearance as described in section\nnine hundred forty-seven of this title.\n  5. Disinfectants, biocides and antimicrobial coatings may be used only\nif their use is specified in a mold remediation plan, if they are\nregistered by the United States Environmental Protection Agency for the\nintended use and if the use is consistent with the manufacturer's\nlabeling instructions. If a plan specifies the use of such a product but\ndoes not specify the brand or type of product, a mold remediation\nlicensee may select the brand or type of product to be used. A decision\nby a mold assessment or remediation licensee to use such a product must\ntake into account the potential for occupant sensitivities and possible\nadverse reactions to chemicals that have the potential to be off-gassed\nfrom surfaces coated with the product.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>