<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-950"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-950"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="950"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-950/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-950/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-950/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-950/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_950">
        <num>950</num>
        <heading>Application</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hoisting and lowering mechanisms equipped with a car or platform\nwhich moves between two or more landings. This equipment includes, but\nis not limited to elevators, platform lifts, and non-residential\nstairway chair lifts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>power driven stairways and walkways for carrying persons between\nlandings. This equipment includes, but is not limited to, escalators and\nmoving walks;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hoisting and lowering mechanisms equipped with a car, which serves\ntwo or more landings and is restricted to the carrying of material by\nits limited size or limited access to the car. This equipment includes,\nbut is not limited to, dumbwaiters, material lifts, and dumbwaiters with\nautomatic transfer devices as defined in section nine hundred fifty-one\nof this article; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>automatic guided transit vehicles on guideways with an exclusive\nright-of-way. This equipment includes, but is not limited to, automated\npeople movers.\n  2. The following equipment is not covered by this article:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>personnel and material hoists;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>manlifts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>mobile scaffolds, towers, and platforms;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>powered platforms and equipment for exterior and interior\nmaintenance;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>conveyor and related equipment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>cranes, derricks, hoists, hooks, jacks, and slings;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>industrial trucks;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>portable equipment, except for portable escalators;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>tiering and piling machines used to move materials to and from\nstorage located and operating entirely within one story;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>equipment for feeding or positioning materials including, but not\nlimited to, machine tools and printing presses;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>skip or furnace hoists;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>wharf ramps;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>railroad car lifts or dumpers;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>stairway chairlifts for private residences; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_950__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>line jacks, false cars, shafters, moving platforms, and similar\nequipment used for installing an elevator by a contractor licensed in\nthis state.\n  3. The licensing provisions of this article shall not apply to the\nowners or lessees of private residences who design, construct, install,\nalter, repair, service, or maintain conveyances that are located or will\nbe located in such owner or lessee's private residence. However, any\nperson hired to design, construct, install, alter, repair, service,\nmaintain, or perform any other work related to such conveyances must\ncomply with the provisions of this article.\n  4. No license shall be required for the removal or dismantling of\nconveyances.\n  5. No license shall be required for the outfitting, removal,\nrefinishing, or replacement of interior finishes, including wall panels,\ndrop ceilings, handrails and flooring, removal or replacement of\ninterior lighting, recladding of doors, transoms and front return\npanels, finishing, or ornamental work on car operating panels.\n  6. The provisions of this article and the rules adopted pursuant\nthereto shall be the minimum standard required and shall supersede any\nspecial law or local ordinance inconsistent therewith, and no local\nordinance inconsistent therewith shall be adopted, but nothing herein\ncontained shall prevent the enactment by local law or ordinance of\nadditional requirements and restrictions.\n  7. Any municipal corporation may waive licensing fees for any\nindividual seeking an elevator license, or its equivalent, offered by\nsuch municipal corporation if such individual holds an elevator\nmechanic's license pursuant to this article; provided, however, that any\nelevator mechanic's license, or its equivalent, offered by a municipal\ncorporation shall not be inconsistent with the requirements of this\narticle and nothing herein shall prevent the enactment by local law or\nordinance of additional requirements.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>