<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-956"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-956"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="956"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-956/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-956/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-956/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-956/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_956">
        <num>956</num>
        <heading>New York state elevator safety and standards advisory board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 956. New York state elevator safety and standards advisory board. 1.\nAn elevator safety and standards advisory board is hereby created, to\nconsist of thirteen members. The governor shall appoint seven members,\nthe temporary president of the senate shall appoint three members, and\nthe speaker of the assembly shall appoint three members. The appointees\nto the board shall be representatives of elevator manufacturers,\nbuilding owners or managers, elevator industry construction workers,\nelevator servicing companies, elevator industry associations, elevator\nmechanics, or fire marshals. The board shall meet on an as needed basis\nto advise the commissioner on the implementation of this article. The\nboard shall elect a chairperson to serve for the term of their\nappointment to the board.\n  2. The members appointed pursuant to this section shall serve at the\npleasure of the authority appointing such member. The members shall\nserve without salary or compensation, but shall be reimbursed for\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.\n  3. The board may consult with engineering authorities and\norganizations concerned with standard safety codes, rules and\nregulations governing the maintenance, servicing, construction,\nalteration, installation, and inspection of conveyances and the\nadequate, reasonable, and necessary qualifications of elevator\nmechanics, contractors, and inspectors.\n  4. The board shall have the authority to administer, oversee, and\napprove examinations for the purpose of qualifying applicants pursuant\nto subdivision six of section nine hundred fifty-four of this article.\nIn exercising this authority, the board shall, in its discretion,\ndetermine the criteria and standards for examinations to satisfy the\nrequirements of this subdivision, such as the mechanic examination of\nthe national elevator industry educational program, or an equivalent\nexamination recognized by the board, which shall satisfy the\nrequirements of this subdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>