<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-958"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-958"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="958"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-958/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-958/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-958/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-958/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_958">
        <num>958</num>
        <heading>Inspection of elevators and conveyances</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 958. Inspection of elevators and conveyances. Except in a city with\na population of one million or more, it shall be the responsibility of\nthe owner of all elevators and other conveyances subject to this article\nto ensure that such equipment conforms to the following inspection and\ntesting requirements:\n  1. New or altered conveyances shall be inspected and tested in\naccordance with the American Society of Mechanical Engineers safety code\nfor elevators and escalators version A17.1/CSA B-44, section 8.10.\n  2. Existing conveyances shall be inspected and tested in accordance\nwith the American Society of Mechanical Engineers safety code for\nelevators and escalators version A17.1/CSA B-44, section 8.11.\n  3. Inspections and tests of conveyances required under this section\nshall be conducted to ensure the conveyances are operated and maintained\nin accordance with applicable code requirements for such conveyances as\nadopted or determined by the department.\n  4. It shall be the responsibility of the owner of all conveyances to\nensure that the inspections and tests required pursuant to this section\nare performed in compliance with the applicable code requirements for\nsuch conveyances as adopted or determined by the department.\n  5. All work required for inspections and the associated tests of\nelevators and other conveyances shall be performed by a licensed\nelevator mechanic and shall be physically witnessed by a licensed\nelevator inspector to ensure compliance with applicable code\nrequirements for such conveyances as adopted or determined by the\ndepartment.\n  6. All inspections of elevators and other conveyances shall be\nperformed by a licensed elevator inspector to ensure compliance with\napplicable code requirements for such conveyances as adopted or\ndetermined by the department.\n  7. When any tests on elevators or other conveyances are performed\npursuant to this section and such tests are required to be witnessed by\na licensed elevator inspector in accordance with this section or\napplicable industry codes or standards incorporated herein, such\ninspections shall be conducted by a licensed elevator inspector who is\nemployed by the state and who shall be physically present during the\ntests to witness such tests to ensure they are properly administered and\nto verify test results.\n  8. Subsequent to any inspection, the licensed elevator inspector shall\nsupply the property owner and the department with a written inspection\nreport verifying code compliance or describing any code violations\nfound. It shall be the responsibility of the department to verify\ncompliance with the requirements of this chapter and applicable code\nrequirements, as adopted or required by the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>