<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVR">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVR"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_D">
        <num>50-D</num>
        <heading>Personnel records of court officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-d. Personnel records of court officers. 1. As used in this\nsection, "personnel records of court officers" means all personnel\nrecords of court officers as defined in paragraph a of subdivision\ntwenty-one of section 2.10 of the criminal procedure law, used to\nevaluate performance toward continued employment or promotion, and under\nthe control of the office of court administration.\n  2. Personnel records of court officers shall be disclosed in a court\naction pursuant to the relevant provisions of the criminal procedure\nlaw, the civil practice law and rules, or any other provision of law\ngoverning such disclosure only after the court has notified the subject\nof such record that such record may be disclosed in a court action and\nthe court has given the subject of such record an opportunity to be\nheard on the question of whether the records sought are relevant and\nmaterial in the action before the court. If, after such hearing, the\ncourt determines that only a portion of such records are relevant and\nmaterial in the action before it, it shall make those parts of the\nrecord found to be relevant and material available to the persons so\nrequesting.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any grand jury or\nany agency of government which requires the records described in\nsubdivision one of this section in the furtherance of their official\nduties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>