<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVR">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVR"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-50-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_E">
        <num>50-E</num>
        <heading>Personnel records of bridge and tunnel officers, sergeants and lieutenants</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-e. Personnel records of bridge and tunnel officers, sergeants and\nlieutenants. 1. As used in this section, "personnel records of bridge\nand tunnel officers, sergeants and lieutenants" means all personnel\nrecords of bridge and tunnel officers, sergeants and lieutenants as\ndefined in subdivision twenty of section 2.10 of the criminal procedure\nlaw, used to evaluate performance toward continued employment or\npromotion, and under the control of the Triborough bridge and tunnel\nauthority.\n  2. Personnel records of bridge and tunnel officers, sergeants and\nlieutenants shall be disclosed in a court action pursuant to the\nrelevant provisions of the criminal procedure law, the civil practice\nlaw and rules, or any other provision of law governing such disclosure\nonly after the court has notified the subject of such record that such\nrecord may be disclosed in a court action and the court has given the\nsubject of such record an opportunity to be heard on the question of\nwhether the records sought are relevant and material in the action\nbefore the court. If, after such hearing, the court determines that only\na portion of such records are relevant and material in the action before\nit, it shall make those parts of the record found to be relevant and\nmaterial available to the persons so requesting.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any grand jury or\nany agency of government which requires the records described in\nsubdivision one of this section in the furtherance of their official\nduties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>