<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVR">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-52-C*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-52-C*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-05-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="52-C*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVR"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-52-C*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-52-C*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-52-C*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-52-C*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52_C*2">
        <num>52-C*2</num>
        <heading>Employers engaged in electronic monitoring; prior notice required</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_52_C*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any employer who monitors or otherwise intercepts telephone\nconversations or transmissions, electronic mail or transmissions, or\ninternet access or usage of or by an employee by any electronic device\nor system, including but not limited to the use of a computer,\ntelephone, wire, radio, or electromagnetic, photoelectronic or\nphoto-optical systems, shall give prior written notice upon hiring to\nall employees who are subject to electronic monitoring. The notice\nrequired by this subdivision shall be in writing, in an electronic\nrecord, or in another electronic form and acknowledged by the employee\neither in writing or electronically. Each employer shall also post the\nnotice of electronic monitoring in a conspicuous place which is readily\navailable for viewing by its employees who are subject to electronic\nmonitoring.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52_C*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of written notice required by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_52_C*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, an employee shall be advised that any and all telephone\nconversations or transmissions, electronic mail or transmissions, or\ninternet access or usage by an employee by any electronic device or\nsystem, including but not limited to the use of a computer, telephone,\nwire, radio or electromagnetic, photoelectronic or photo-optical systems\nmay be subject to monitoring at any and all times and by any lawful\nmeans.\n  3. The attorney general may enforce the provisions of this section.\nAny employer found to be in violation of this section shall be subject\nto a maximum civil penalty of five hundred dollars for the first\noffense, one thousand dollars for the second offense and three thousand\ndollars for the third and each subsequent offense.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall not apply to processes that\nare designed to manage the type or volume of incoming or outgoing\nelectronic mail or telephone voice mail or internet usage, that are not\ntargeted to monitor or intercept the electronic mail or telephone voice\nmail or internet usage of a particular individual, and that are\nperformed solely for the purpose of computer system maintenance and/or\nprotection.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 52-c's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>