<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVR">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-72"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-72"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVR"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-72/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-72/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-72/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-72/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72">
        <num>72</num>
        <heading>Term of imprisonment of civil prisoner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 72. Term of imprisonment of civil prisoner. No person shall be\nimprisoned within the prison walls of any jail for a longer period than\nthree months under an execution or any other mandate against the person\nto enforce the recovery of a sum of money less than five hundred dollars\nin amount or under a commitment upon a fine for contempt of court in the\nnonpayment of alimony, maintenance, distributive awards or special\nrelief in matrimonial actions or counsel fees in a divorce case where\nthe amount so to be paid is less than the sum of five hundred dollars;\nand where the amount in either of said cases is five hundred dollars or\nover, such imprisonment shall not continue for a longer period than six\nmonths. It shall be the duty of the sheriff in whose custody any such\nperson is held to discharge such person at the expiration of said\nrespective periods without any formal application being made therefor.\nNo person shall be imprisoned within the jail liberties of any jail for\na longer period than six months upon any execution or other mandate\nagainst the person to enforce the recovery of a sum of five hundred\ndollars or over or for a longer period than three months where the\namount is less than five hundred dollars, and no action shall be\ncommenced against the sheriff upon a bond given for the jail liberties\nby such person. In computing the term of imprisonment time spent within\nthe prison walls of any jail and time spent within the jail liberties\nshall be included. Notwithstanding such a discharge in either of the\nabove cases, the judgment creditor in the execution, or the person at\nwhose instance the said mandate was issued, has the same remedy against\nthe property of the person imprisoned which he or she had before such\nexecution or mandate was issued; but the prisoner shall not be again\nimprisoned upon a like process issued in the same action or arrested in\nany action upon any judgment under which the same may have been granted.\nExcept in a case hereinbefore specified nothing in this section shall\naffect a commitment for contempt of court.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>