<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVR">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-73"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-73"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="73"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVR"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-73/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-73/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-73/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-73/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_73">
        <num>73</num>
        <heading>Code of fair procedure for investigating agencies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Agency". A standing or select committee of either house of the\nlegislature or a joint committee of both houses; a duly authorized\nsubcommittee of any such legislative committee; the commissioner of\ninvestigation acting pursuant to section eleven of the executive law; a\ncommissioner appointed by the governor acting pursuant to section six of\nthe executive law; the attorney general acting pursuant to subdivision\neight of section sixty-three of the executive law; any temporary state\ncommission or any duly authorized subcommittee thereof which has the\npower to require testimony or the production of evidence by subpoena or\nother compulsory process in an investigation being conducted by it; and\nany standing or select committee, or subcommittee thereof, of the\nconstitutional convention to be held in the year nineteen hundred\nsixty-seven.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Hearing". Any hearing in the course of an investigatory\nproceeding (other than a preliminary conference or interview at which no\ntestimony is taken under oath) conducted before an agency at which\ntestimony or the production of other evidence may be compelled by\nsubpoena or other compulsory process.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Public hearing". Any hearing open to the public, or any hearing,\nor such part thereof, as to which testimony or other evidence is made\navailable or disseminated to the public by the agency.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Private hearing". Any hearing other than a public hearing.\n  2. No person may be required to appear at a hearing or to testify at a\nhearing unless there has been personally served upon him prior to the\ntime when he is required to appear, a copy of this section, and a\ngeneral statement of the subject of the investigation. A copy of the\nresolution, statute, order or other provision of law authorizing the\ninvestigation shall be furnished by the agency upon request therefor by\nthe person summoned.\n  3. A witness summoned to a hearing shall have the right to be\naccompanied by counsel, who shall be permitted to advise the witness of\nhis rights, subject to reasonable limitations to prevent obstruction of\nor interference with the orderly conduct of the hearing. Counsel for any\nwitness who testifies at a public hearing may submit proposed questions\nto be asked of the witness relevant to the matters upon which the\nwitness has been questioned and the agency shall ask the witness such of\nthe questions as it may deem appropriate to its inquiry.\n  4. A complete and accurate record shall be kept of each public hearing\nand a witness shall be entitled to receive a copy of his testimony at\nsuch hearing at his own expense. Where testimony which a witness has\ngiven at a private hearing becomes relevant in a criminal proceeding in\nwhich the witness is a defendant, or in any subsequent hearing in which\nthe witness is summoned to testify, the witness shall be entitled to a\ncopy of such testimony, at his own expense, provided the same is\navailable, and provided further that the furnishing of such copy will\nnot prejudice the public safety or security.\n  5. A witness who testifies at any hearing shall have the right at the\nconclusion of his examination to file a brief sworn statement relevant\nto his testimony for incorporation in the record of the investigatory\nproceeding.\n  6. Any person whose name is mentioned or who is specifically\nidentified and who believe...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>