<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVR">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="79-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVR"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_79_J">
        <num>79-J</num>
        <heading>Confidentiality of records in multi-state information system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 79-j. Confidentiality of records in multi-state information system.\n1. An ongoing research and demonstration project called the multi-state\ninformation system for psychiatric patients located at Rockland state\nhospital in Rockland county has been developed by a number of\ncooperating states and is designed to provide a computer-based system\nfor records and statistics of mental health patients in those states.\nThe records stored by the multi-state information system are intended\nalso for research and demonstration purposes concerning (1) the\nfeasibility of computer-based record systems improving the quality of\nmedical information available to clinicians treating psychiatric\npatients and (2) the quality of aggregate statistics to aid in planning,\noperating and monitoring psychiatric services. Such records are not\nintended to substitute for or replace original records retained in the\ncooperating mental health facilities and agencies. In order to protect\nthe privacy of the information stored in such records which relates to\npatients in facilities outside of the state of New York, it is necessary\nand desirable that such records be declared confidential and not subject\nto examination in the courts or by agencies of this state.\n  2. The records and information concerning patients in mental health\nand related facilities located outside of the state of New York and\ncurrently or hereafter stored in the multi-state information system for\npsychiatric patients maintained at Rockland state hospital in the county\nof Rockland are not public records. Such records and information shall\nbe confidential and shall not be subject to subpoena in any court or\nbefore any tribunal or administrative agency. Such records and\ninformation shall not be open for inspection by nor otherwise available\nto any agency or individual other than the agency or facility submitting\nthe records or information and the technical staff of the multi-state\ninformation system except that the commissioner of mental hygiene shall\nhave the power to conduct an annual review of the operation of the\ninformation system in order to assure its proper and lawful operation in\nthe interest of the agencies and facilities contributing records and\ninformation to such system. Aggregate statistics drawn from the records\nstored, with all personal identification removed, may be released by the\nsystem for research and planning purposes.\n  3. Nothing in this act shall affect existing law with respect to the\nrecords of patients now or formerly treated in facilities in this state.\nThe records stored in the multi-state information system described in\nsubdivision two shall not be considered records of the department of\nmental hygiene.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>