<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVR">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-05-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="79-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVR"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvr/section-79-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_79_Q">
        <num>79-Q</num>
        <heading>Collection of gender or sex designation information by state agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 79-q. Collection of gender or sex designation information by state\nagencies. 1. All New York state agencies that collect demographic\ninformation about a person's gender or sex shall make available to the\nperson at the point of data collection an option to mark their gender or\nsex as "x".\n  2. Where applicable federal law requires a state agency to collect sex\nor gender data as either "m" or "f", the state agency shall create a\nseparate field for state purposes so that a person has the option to\nmark their gender or sex as "x" to be collected by the state.\n  3. All state agencies shall update any applicable physical and online\nforms or data systems by January first, two thousand twenty-three,\nexcept the department of labor, the office of children and family\nservices, the office of temporary and disability assistance and the\ndivision of criminal justice services, which shall update any applicable\nforms or data systems by January first, two thousand twenty-four.\n  4. A state agency that cannot comply with the requirements of this\nsection shall, at least sixty days before the applicable deadline, post\npublicly on its website a written progress report that describes with\nspecificity the steps the agency has taken to comply with this section,\nthe impediments that prevented compliance, the efforts undertaken by the\nagency to come into compliance, and an estimated time frame for\ncompliance. The written report shall be updated every six months from\nthe date of the original posting.\n  5. By January first, two thousand twenty-five, the governor shall post\non a publicly available website and submit to the temporary president of\nthe senate and the speaker of the assembly a written report listing\nevery agency that has not yet complied with this section. Such report\nshall include the latest progress reports for each non-compliant agency.\nSuch annual report shall be updated every year by January first;\nprovided that once all agencies have complied with the requirements of\nthis section, the governor shall post on a publicly available website\nand submit to the temporary president of the senate and the speaker of\nthe assembly a certification of compliance with this section, and no\nfurther annual report shall be required.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>