<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1027-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1027-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-11-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1027-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1027-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1027-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1027-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1027-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1027_A">
        <num>1027-A</num>
        <heading>Placement of siblings; contact with siblings</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1027_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a\nsocial services official removes a child pursuant to this part, such\nofficial shall place such child with his or her minor siblings or\nhalf-siblings who have been or are being remanded to or placed in the\ncare and custody of such official unless, in the judgment of such\nofficial, such placement is contrary to the best interests of the\nchildren. Placement with siblings or half-siblings shall be\npresumptively in the child's best interests unless such placement would\nbe contrary to the child's health, safety, or welfare. If such placement\nis not immediately available at the time of the removal of the child,\nsuch official shall provide or arrange for the provision of such\nplacement within thirty days.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1027_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If placement of a child removed pursuant to this part together\nwith his or her minor siblings is not in the best interests of the\nchild, the social services official shall arrange appropriate and\nregular contact by the child with his or her minor siblings and\nhalf-siblings unless such contact would not be in the child's and the\nsiblings' best interests.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1027_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a child removed pursuant to this part is not placed together or\nafforded regular contact with his or her siblings, the child, through\nhis or her attorney or through a parent on his or her behalf, may move\nfor an order regarding placement or contact. The motion shall be served\nupon:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1027_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the respondent in the proceeding under this article; (ii) the\nlocal social services official having the care of the child; (iii) other\npersons having care, custody and control of the child, if any; (iv) the\nparents or other persons having care, custody and control of the\nsiblings to be visited or with whom contact is sought;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1027_A__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any\nnon-respondent parent in the proceeding under this article; (vi) such\nsibling himself or herself if ten years of age or older; and (vii) such\nsibling's attorney, if any. For purposes of this section, "siblings"\nshall include half-siblings and those who would be deemed siblings or\nhalf-siblings but for the termination of parental rights or death of a\nparent. The court may order that the child be placed together with or\nhave regular contact with his or her siblings if the court determines it\nto be in the best interests of the child and his or her siblings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>