<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1047"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1047"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1047"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1047/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1047/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1047/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1047/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1047">
        <num>1047</num>
        <heading>Sequence of hearings</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1047__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon completion of the fact-finding\nhearing, the dispositional hearing may commence immediately after the\nrequired findings are made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1047__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Reports prepared by the probation service or a duly authorized\nassociation, agency, society or institution for use by the court at any\ntime for the making of an order of disposition shall be deemed\nconfidential information furnished to the court which the court shall\nmake available for inspection and copying by all counsel. The court may,\nin its discretion, withhold from disclosure, a part or parts of the\nreports which are not relevant to a proper disposition, or sources of\ninformation which have been obtained on a promise of confidentiality, or\nany other portion thereof, disclosure of which would not be in the\ninterests of justice or in the best interests of the child. In all cases\nwhere a part or parts of the reports are not disclosed, the court shall\nstate for the record that a part or parts of the reports have been\nexcepted and the reasons for its action.  The action of the court\nexcepting information from disclosure shall be subject to review on\nappeal from the order of disposition. Such reports may not be furnished\nto the court prior to the completion of a fact-finding hearing, but may\nbe used in a dispositional hearing.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>