<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1052-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1052-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1052-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1052-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1052-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1052-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1052-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1052_C">
        <num>1052-C</num>
        <heading>Duty to report investigations to locate non-respondent parents or relatives</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1052-c. Duty to report investigations to locate non-respondent\nparents or relatives. Upon a determination by the court to enter an\norder of disposition placing the child in accordance with section one\nthousand fifty-five of this part, the court shall immediately require\nthe local social services district to report to the court the results of\nany investigation to locate any non-respondent parent or relatives of\nthe child, including all of the child's grandparents, all suitable\nrelatives identified by any respondent parent and any non-respondent\nparent and all relatives identified by a child over the age of five as\nrelatives who play or have played a significant positive role in the\nchild's life, as required pursuant to section one thousand seventeen of\nthe article.  Such report shall include whether any non-respondent\nparent has expressed an interest in seeking custody of the child or\nwhether any relative who has been located has expressed an interest in\nbecoming a foster parent for the child or in seeking custody or care of\nthe child.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>