<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1057"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1057"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-06-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1057"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1057/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1057/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1057/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1057/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1057">
        <num>1057</num>
        <heading>Release of the child to the respondent or respondents; supervision of the respondent or respondents</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1057__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may release the child to the respondent or respondents\nfor a period of up to one year, which may be extended pursuant to\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1057__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1057__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In conjunction with an order releasing a child under this section\nor an order under paragraph (ii), (iii) or (iv) of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1057__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection one thousand fifty-two of this part, the court may place the\nrespondent or respondents under supervision of a child protective agency\nor of a social services official or duly authorized agency. An order of\nsupervision entered under this section shall set forth the terms and\nconditions of such supervision that the respondent or respondents must\nmeet and the actions that the child protective agency, social services\nofficial or duly authorized agency must take to exercise such\nsupervision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1057__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided for herein, in any order issued pursuant to\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1057__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1057__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, the court may require the child\nprotective agency to make progress reports to the court, the parties,\nand the child's attorney on the implementation of such order. Where the\norder of disposition is issued upon the consent of the parties and the\nchild's attorney, such agency shall report to the court, the parties and\nthe child's attorney no later than ninety days after the issuance of the\norder and no later than sixty days prior to the expiration of the order,\nunless the court determines that the facts and circumstances of the case\ndo not require such report to be made. Uniform statewide rules of court\nshall define permissible terms and conditions of supervision of the\nrespondent or respondents under this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1057__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The duration of any period of release of the child to the\nrespondent or respondents or supervision of the respondent or\nrespondents or both shall be for an initial period of no more than one\nyear. The court may at the expiration of that period, upon a hearing and\nfor good cause shown, extend such release or supervision or both for a\nperiod of up to one year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>