<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1075"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1075"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1075"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1075/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1075/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1075/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1075/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1075">
        <num>1075</num>
        <heading>Special duties of attorney for the child</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1075. Special duties of attorney for the child. In addition to all\nother duties and responsibilities necessary to the representation of a\nchild who is the subject of a proceeding under this article, an attorney\nfor a child shall upon receipt of a report from a child protective\nagency pursuant to sections one thousand thirty-nine, one thousand\nthirty-nine-a, one thousand fifty-two-a, one thousand fifty-three, one\nthousand fifty-four, one thousand fifty-five, one thousand fifty-seven\nand one thousand fifty-eight, review the information contained therein\nand make a determination as to whether there is reasonable cause to\nsuspect that the child is at risk of further abuse or neglect or that\nthere has been a substantive violation of a court order. Where the\nattorney for the child makes such a determination, the attorney shall\napply to the court for appropriate relief pursuant to section one\nthousand sixty-one. Nothing contained in this section shall relieve a\nchild protective agency or social services official of its duties\npursuant to this act or the social services law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>