<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1121"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1121"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1121"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1121">
        <num>1121</num>
        <heading>Special procedures</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided for herein, counsel for the appellant shall,\nno later than ten days after filing the notice of appeal, request\npreparation of the transcript of the proceeding appealed therefrom.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Counsel assigned or appointed pursuant to article eleven of the\ncivil practice law and rules or section eleven hundred twenty of this\nact shall, no later than ten days after receipt of notice of such\nappointment, request preparation of the transcript of the proceeding\nappealed from.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In any case where counsel is assigned or appointed pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision subsequent to the filing of the notice\nof appeal, such counsel shall, within ten days of such assignment or\nappointment, request preparation of the transcript of the proceeding\nappealed from.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where the appellant is seeking relief to proceed as a poor person\npursuant to article eleven of the civil practice law and rules, the\ntranscript of the proceeding appealed from shall be requested within ten\ndays of the order determining the motion.\n  7. Such transcript shall be completed within thirty days from the\nreceipt of the request of the appellant. Where such transcript is not\ncompleted within such time period, the court reporter or director of the\ntranscription service responsible for the preparation of the transcript\nshall notify the administrative judge of the appropriate judicial\ndistrict. Such administrative judge shall establish procedures to\neffectuate the timely preparation of such transcript. The appellate\ndivisions may establish additional procedures to effectuate the timely\npreparation of transcripts.\n  The appellate division shall establish procedures to ensure the\nexpeditious filing and service of the appellant's brief, the answering\nbrief and any reply brief, which may include scheduling orders. The\nappellant shall perfect the appeal within sixty days of receipt of the\ntranscript of the proceeding appealed from or within any different time\nthat the appellate division has by rule prescribed for perfecting such\nappeals under subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1121__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule five thousand five hundred thirty\nof the civil practice law and rules or as otherwise specified by the\nappellate division. Such sixty day or other prescribed period may be\nextended by the appellate division for good cause shown upon written\napplication to the appellate division showing merit to the appeal and a\nreasonable ground for an extension of time. Upon the granting of such an\nextension of time the appellate division shall issue new specific\ndeadlines by which the appellant's brief, the answering brief and any\nreply brief must be filed and served.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>