<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1122"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1122"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1122"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-1122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1122">
        <num>1122</num>
        <heading>Filing of papers on appeal to the appellate division by electronic means</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1122__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule twenty-one hundred three of the civil practice\nlaw and rules. Provided however, such rules shall not require an\nunrepresented party or any attorney who furnishes a certificate\nspecified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1122__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or (ii) of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1122__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section two\nhundred fourteen of this chapter to take or perfect an appeal by\nelectronic means. Provided further, however, before promulgating any\nsuch rules, the appellate division in each judicial department shall\nconsult with the chief administrator of the courts and shall provide an\nopportunity for review and comment by all those who are or would be\naffected including city, state, county and women's bar associations;\ninstitutional legal service providers; not-for-profit legal service\nproviders; attorneys assigned pursuant to article eighteen-B of the\ncounty law; unaffiliated attorneys who regularly appear in proceedings\nthat are or have been affected by the programs that have been\nimplemented or who may be affected by promulgation of rules concerning\nthe use of the electronic filing program in the appellate division of\nany judicial department; and any other persons in whose county a program\nhas been implemented in any of the courts therein as deemed to be\nappropriate by any appellate division. To the extent practicable, rules\npromulgated by the appellate division in each judicial department\npursuant to this section shall be uniform.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>