<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-131"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-131"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131">
        <num>131</num>
        <heading>Number of judges</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in each county in which there was a separate office or offices of\njudge of the children's court authorized by law on the thirty-first day\nof August nineteen hundred sixty-two, the number of judges of the family\ncourt for such county shall be equal to the number of offices so\nauthorized except those authorized by certificate filed pursuant to\nsubdivision two of section four of the children's court act of the state\nof New York subsequent to March first, nineteen hundred sixty-two; and,\neffective May fifteenth, nineteen hundred sixty-three, there shall be a\nseparate office of judge of the family court for the county of Niagara;\nand, effective May fifteenth, nineteen hundred sixty-three, there shall\nbe a separate office of judge of the family court for the county of\nUlster; and, effective January first, nineteen hundred sixty-four, there\nshall be a separate office of judge of the family court for the county\nof St. Lawrence; and, effective January first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-five, there shall be a separate office of judge of the family\ncourt for the county of Chautauqua; and, effective January first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-seven, there shall be a separate office of judge\nof the family court for the county of Oneida; and, effective January\nfirst, nineteen hundred sixty-five, there shall be a separate office of\njudge of the family court for the county of Jefferson; and, effective\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred sixty-six, there shall be a separate\noffice of judge of the family court for the county of Rockland:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the other counties except the counties of Chautauqua, Jefferson\nand Oneida, a judge of the county court shall act as and discharge the\nduties of judge of the family court;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the counties of Chautauqua, Jefferson and Oneida, upon the\nexpiration of the term of office of the special county judge who was\ncontinued as a judge of the family court pursuant to section one hundred\nthirty-two of this act, or if there was no special county judge in\noffice on the effective date of this act, a judge of the county court of\neach such county shall act as and discharge the duties of judge of the\nfamily court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Nassau there shall be nine family court judges\nand the number of such judges now existing in said county is hereby\nincreased accordingly.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Monroe there shall be six family court judges and\nthe number of such judges now existing in said county is hereby\nincreased accordingly; in the county of Erie there shall be six family\ncourt judges and the number of such judges now existing in said county\nis hereby increased accordingly. In the county of Albany there shall be\na total of three family court judges and the number of such judges now\nexisting in such county is hereby increased accordingly.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Onondaga there shall be three additional family\ncourt judges and the number of such judges now existing in such county\nis hereby increased accordingly. The compensation of each such\nadditional family court judge shall be the same as the compensation of\nexisting family court judges in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be a separate office of judge of the family court for\nthe counties of Oswego and Sullivan and the compensation payable for\neach such separate office of judge of the family court shall be\ntwenty-five thousand dollars per annum. In the county of Saratoga there\nshall be two additional family court judges and the number of such\njudges now existing in such county is hereby increased accordingly. The\ncompensation of such additional family court judge shall be the same as\nthe compensation of the existing family court judge in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Westchester there shall be three additional\nfamily court judges and the number of such judges now existing is hereby\nincreased accordingly. The compensation of each additional family court\njudge shall be the same as the existing family court judge in such\ncounty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Schenectady there shall be one additional family\ncourt judge and the number of such judges now existing is hereby\nincreased accordingly. The compensation of the additional family court\njudge shall be the same as the existing family court judge in such\ncounty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Genesee there shall be one additional family\ncourt judge and the number of such judges now existing is hereby\nincreased accordingly. The compensation of the additional family court\njudge shall be the same as the existing family court judge in such\ncounty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Rockland there shall be one additional family\ncourt judge and the number of such judges now existing is hereby\nincreased accordingly. The compensation of the additional family court\njudge shall be the same as the existing family court judge in such\ncounty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Dutchess there shall be two additional family\ncourt judges and the number of such judges now existing is hereby\nincreased accordingly. The compensation of the additional family court\njudges shall be the same as the compensation paid to each of the\nexisting family court judges in such county pursuant to section two\nhundred twenty-one-e of the judiciary law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Niagara there shall be one additional family\ncourt judge and the number of such judges now existing is hereby\nincreased accordingly. The compensation of the additional family court\njudge shall be the same as the existing family court judge in such\ncounty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Ulster there shall be one additional family court\njudge and the number of such judges now existing is hereby increased\naccordingly. The compensation of the additional family court judge shall\nbe the same as the existing family court judge in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Oneida there shall be two additional family court\njudges making a total of three family court judges in such county. The\nnumber of such judges now existing in such county is hereby increased\naccordingly. The compensation of the additional family court judges\nshall be the same as the compensation of the existing family court judge\nin such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_p">
          <num>(p)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Suffolk there shall be four additional family\ncourt judges making a total of ten family court judges in such county.\nThe number of such judges now existing in such county is hereby\nincreased accordingly. The compensation of each such family court judge\nshall be the same as the compensation of existing family court judges in\nsuch county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_q">
          <num>(q)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Rensselaer, there shall be one additional family\ncourt judge and the number of judges now existing is hereby increased\naccordingly. The compensation of the additional family court judge shall\nbe the same as the existing family court judge in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_r">
          <num>(r)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Orange there shall be three additional family\ncourt judges, making a total of four family court judges, and the number\nof such judges now existing is hereby increased accordingly. The\ncompensation of each such additional family court judge shall be the\nsame as the compensation paid to each of the existing family court\njudges in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the county of Broome there shall be a total of three family\ncourt judges and the number of such judges now existing is hereby\nincreased accordingly. The compensation of such additional family court\njudge shall be the same as the compensation paid to each of the existing\nfamily court judges in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_t">
          <num>(t)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be a separate office of judge of the family court for\nthe county of Clinton and the compensation payable for such separate\noffice of judge of the family court shall be the same as the\ncompensation payable to the judge of the county court of Clinton county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_u">
          <num>(u)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be an additional family court judge for each of the\nfollowing counties: Albany, Broome, Chautauqua, Franklin, Nassau,\nOneida, Oswego, Schenectady, Suffolk, Ulster and Westchester. The\ncompensation of each such additional family court judge shall be the\nsame as the compensation paid to each existing family court judge in the\ncounty for which it is established or, if there is no separately-elected\nfamily court judge in such county, the same as the compensation paid to\na judge of the county court in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be an additional family court judge for each of the\nfollowing counties: Delaware, Dutchess, Erie, Monroe, and Warren. The\ncompensation of each such additional family court judge shall be the\nsame as the compensation paid to each existing family court judge in the\ncounty for which it is established or, if there is no separately-elected\nfamily court judge in such county, the same as the compensation paid to\na judge of the county court in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_w">
          <num>(w)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be an additional family court judge for each of the\nfollowing counties: Albany, Chemung, Erie, Monroe, Niagara, Oneida,\nOnondaga, St. Lawrence, Suffolk, and Westchester. The compensation of\neach such additional family court judge shall be the same as the\ncompensation paid to each existing family court judge in such county or,\nif there is no separately-elected family court judge in such county, the\nsame as the compensation paid to a judge of the county court in such\ncounty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_131__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be an additional family court judge for each of the\nfollowing counties: Cayuga, Chenango, Cortland, Erie, Jefferson,\nRensselaer, Rockland and Westchester. Moreover, there shall be two\nadditional family court judges from the county of Suffolk and there\nshall be two additional family court judges from the county of Nassau.\nThe compensation of each such additional family court judge shall be the\nsame as the compensation paid to each existing family court judge in\nsuch county or, if there is no separately-elected family court judge in\nsuch county, the same as the compensation paid to a judge of the county\ncourt in such county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>