<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-169"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-169"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-07-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="169"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-169/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-169/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-169/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-169/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_169">
        <num>169</num>
        <heading>Translation and interpretation of orders of protection</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_169__subsec_t">
          <num>(t)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision two of section two hundred twelve of the judiciary law,\nensure that a court order of protection and temporary order of\nprotection issued by the court under article three, four, five, six,\nseven, eight or ten of this act, is translated in writing into the\nappropriate language for a party to a proceeding where the court has\nappointed an interpreter. The office of court administration shall\nensure that the standard language of the office of court administration\norder of protection and temporary order of protection forms shall be\ntranslated in writing in the languages most frequently used in the\ncourts of each judicial department in accordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_169__subsec_t">
          <num>(t)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision two of section two hundred twelve of the judiciary law. A\ncopy of the written translation shall be given to each party in the\nproceeding, along with the original order or temporary order of\nprotection issued in English. A copy of this written translation shall\nalso be included as part of the record of the proceeding. The court\nshall read the essential terms and conditions of the order aloud on the\nrecord and direct the court appointed interpreter to interpret the same\nterms and conditions. Such written translation or interpretation shall\nnot affect the validity or enforceability of the order. In every case a\nparty to a proceeding shall be provided with an English copy of any\ncourt order of protection or temporary order of protection issued. The\nauthority provided herein shall be in addition to and shall not be\ndeemed to diminish or reduce any rights of the parties under existing\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>