<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-176"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-176"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="176"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_176">
        <num>176</num>
        <heading>Inter-county probation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 176. Inter-county probation. 1. Transfer of probation supervision.\nWhere a person placed on probation resides in another jurisdiction\nwithin the state at the time of the order of disposition, the family\ncourt which placed him or her on probation may, and, in the case of\norders of probation issued under article three or seven of this act,\nshall transfer probation supervision to the probation department in the\njurisdiction in which the person resides. Where, after a probation\ndisposition is pronounced, a probationer relocates to another\njurisdiction within the state, the family court which placed him or her\non probation may, and, in the case of orders of probation issued under\narticle three or seven of this act, shall transfer probation supervision\nto the probation department in the jurisdiction of the probationer's new\nresidence. Upon completion of a transfer of probation supervision as\nauthorized pursuant to this subdivision, the probation department in the\nreceiving jurisdiction shall assume all powers and duties of the\nprobation department in the jurisdiction of the family court which\nplaced the probationer on probation. Any transfer under this subdivision\nmust be in accordance with rules adopted by the commissioner of the\ndivision of criminal justice services.\n  2. For all cases brought under article three or seven of this act,\nwhere probation supervision has been transferred under subdivision one\nof this section, the family court in the receiving jurisdiction shall\nhear any proceedings to enforce or modify the order of probation, unless\nthe receiving family court determines that there is good cause to return\nthe proceeding to the sending family court for adjudication, in which\ncase the proceeding shall be returned to the sending family court for\nadjudication.\n  3. For the purpose of this section, "jurisdiction" shall mean a county\nor the city of New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>