<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-232"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-232"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="232"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-232/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-232/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-232/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-232/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_232">
        <num>232</num>
        <heading>Jurisdiction over children with physical disabilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_232__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The\nfamily court has jurisdiction over children with physical disabilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_232__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Child with physical disabilities" means a person under twenty-one\nyears of age who, by reason of a physical disability, whether congenital\nor acquired by accident, injury or disease, is or may be expected to be\ntotally or partially incapacitated for education or for remunerative\noccupation, as provided in the education law, or has a physical\ndisability, as provided in section two thousand five hundred eighty-one\nof the public health law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_232__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_232__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever a parent or other person who has been ordered to\ncontribute to the cost of medical service authorized pursuant to section\ntwo thousand five hundred eighty-two of the public health law refuses to\nor fails to make such contribution, the health commissioner or the\nmedical director of the program for children with physical disabilities,\nas the case may be, may institute a proceeding in the family court to\ncompel such contribution. In any case where an order has been granted\npursuant to section 556-18.0 or section 17-121 of the administrative\ncode of the city of New York the department of health, under the\nconditions specified in such section, may institute a proceeding in the\nfamily court to compel the parents of a child for whom care, treatment,\nappliances or devices have been ordered pursuant to such section, or\nother persons legally chargeable with the support of such child, to\ncontribute such portion of the expense of such care, treatment,\nappliances or devices a...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_232__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A parent or other person who has been ordered by the commissioner\nof health of a county or part-county health district, the medical\ndirector of a county program for children with physical disabilities, or\nthe department of health of the city of New York, to contribute to the\ncost of medical service authorized under section two thousand five\nhundred eighty-two of the public health law, may petition the family\ncourt to review such order and determine the extent, if any, of his\nfinancial liability. In any such proceeding, the court may by order\nrequire such parent or other person to pay part or all of the expense of\nsuch service in a lump sum or in such weekly or monthly installments as\nthe court may decide.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>