<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-306.2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-306.2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="306.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-306.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-306.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-306.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-306.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_306_2">
        <num>306.2</num>
        <heading>Fingerprinting; duties of the division of criminal justice services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 306.2. Fingerprinting; duties of the division of criminal justice\nservices. 1. Upon receipt of fingerprints taken pursuant to section\n306.1, the division of criminal justice services shall retain such\nfingerprints distinctly identifiable from adult criminal records except\nas provided in section 354.1, and shall not release such fingerprints to\na federal depository or to any person except as authorized by this act.\nThe division shall promulgate regulations to protect the confidentiality\nof such fingerprints and related information and to prevent access\nthereto, by, and the distribution thereof to, persons not authorized by\nlaw.\n  2. Upon receipt of such fingerprints, the division of criminal justice\nservices shall classify them and search its records for information\nconcerning an adjudication or pending matter involving the person\narrested. The division shall promptly transmit to such forwarding\nofficer or agency a report containing any information on file with\nrespect to such person's previous adjudications and pending matters or a\nreport stating that the person arrested has no previous record according\nto its files.  Notwithstanding the foregoing, where the division has not\nreceived disposition information within two years of an arrest, the\ndivision shall, until such information or up-to-date status information\nis received, withhold the record of that arrest and any related activity\nin disseminating criminal history information.\n  3. Upon receipt of a report of the division of criminal justice\nservices pursuant to this section, the recipient office or agency must\npromptly transmit two copies of such report to the family court in which\nthe proceeding may be originated and two copies thereof to the\npresentment agency who shall furnish a copy thereof to counsel for the\nrespondent.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>