<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-307.2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-307.2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="307.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-307.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-307.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-307.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-307.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_307_2">
        <num>307.2</num>
        <heading>Appearance ticket procedures</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 307.2. Appearance ticket procedures. 1. If a child fails to appear\non the return date specified on a family court appearance ticket, the\nprobation service may refer the matter forthwith to the appropriate\npresentment agency or may, in its discretion, attempt to secure the\nattendance of the child. Upon exercise of its discretion, probation\nservices shall take appropriate action under law including, but not\nlimited to, written notification to the child and parent or other person\nlegally responsible for his care or telephone communications with the\nchild and parent or other person legally responsible for his care.\nEfforts to secure the attendance of the child shall not extend beyond\nseven days subsequent to such return date and the probation service must\nrefer the matter to the appropriate presentment agency within such\nperiod. Upon referral, the presentment agency may take whatever action\nit deems appropriate, including the filing of a petition pursuant to\nsection 311.1.\n  2. If the complainant fails to appear on the return date specified on\nsuch appearance ticket, the probation service may, in its discretion,\nattempt to secure his voluntary attendance. Upon exercise of its\ndiscretion, probation services may take appropriate action under law\nincluding, but not limited to, written notification to the complainant\nor telephone communications with the complainant. Efforts to secure the\nvoluntary attendance of such person shall not extend beyond seven days\nsubsequent to such return date and the probation service shall refer the\nmatter to the appropriate presentment agency within such period. Upon\nreferral, the presentment agency may take whatever action it deems\nappropriate, including the issuance of a subpoena or the filing of a\npetition pursuant to section 311.1.\n  3. If a petition is filed subsequent to the issuance of an appearance\nticket the appearance ticket shall be made part of the probation service\nfile.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>