<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-312.2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-312.2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="312.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-312.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-312.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-312.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-312.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_312_2">
        <num>312.2</num>
        <heading>Issuance of a warrant</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_312_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a summons cannot be served; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_312_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such person has refused to obey a summons or family court\nappearance ticket; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_312_2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the respondent or other person is likely to leave the\njurisdiction; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_312_2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a summons, in the court's opinion, would be ineffectual; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_312_2__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a respondent has failed to appear.\n  2. Upon issuance of a warrant due to the respondent's failure to\nappear for a scheduled court date, the court shall adjourn the matter to\na date certain within thirty days for a report on the efforts made to\nsecure the respondent's appearance in court. The court may order that\nthe person legally responsible for the respondent's care or, if such\nlegally responsible person is not available, a person with whom the\nrespondent resides, appear on the adjourned date. Upon receiving the\nreport, for good cause, the court may order further reports and may\nrequire further appearances of the person legally responsible for the\nrespondent's care or, if such person legally responsible is not\navailable, a person with whom the respondent resides. Upon receiving the\ninitial or any subsequent report, the court shall set forth in writing\nits findings of fact as to the efforts, if any, made up to that date to\nsecure the respondent's appearance in court.\n  3. A juvenile who is arrested pursuant to a warrant issued under this\nsection must forthwith and with all reasonable speed be taken directly\nto the family court located in the county in which the warrant had been\nissued, or, when the family court is not in session, to the most\naccessible magistrate, if any, designated by the appellate division of\nthe supreme court in the applicable department. If a juvenile is brought\nbefore an accessible magistrate, the magistrate shall set a date for the\njuvenile to appear in the family court in the county in which the\nwarrant had been issued, which shall be no later than the next day the\ncourt is in session if the magistrate orders the juvenile to be detained\nand within ten court days if the magistrate orders the juvenile to be\nreleased. In determining whether the juvenile should be released, with\nor without conditions, or detained, the magistrate shall apply the\ncriterion and issue the findings required by section 320.5 of this\nartic...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>