<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-315.3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-315.3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="315.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-315.3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-315.3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-315.3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-315.3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_315_3">
        <num>315.3</num>
        <heading>Adjournment in contemplation of dismissal</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_315_3__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 19.07 of the mental hygiene law. The court\nmay, as a condition of an adjournment in contemplation of dismissal\norder, in cases where the record indicates that the respondent is an\neligible person as defined in section four hundred fifty-eight-l of the\nsocial services law and has allegedly committed an eligible offense as\ndefined in such section, direct the respondent to attend and complete an\neducation reform program established pursuant to section four hundred\nfifty-eight-l of the social services law. Upon ex parte motion by the\npresentment agency, or upon the court's own motion, made at the time the\norder is issued or at any time during its duration, the court may\nrestore the matter to the calendar. If the proceeding is not restored,\nthe petition is, at the expiration of the order, deemed to have been\ndismissed by the court in furtherance of justice.\n  2. Rules of court shall define the permissible terms and conditions\nwhich may be included in an order that the proceeding be adjourned in\ncontemplation of dismissal; such permissible terms and conditions may\ninclude supervision by the probation service, a requirement that the\nrespondent cooperate with a mental health, social services or other\nappropriate community facility or agency to which the respondent may be\nreferred and a requirement that the respondent comply with such other\nreasonable conditions as the court shall determine to be necessary or\nappropriate to ameliorate the conduct which gave rise to the filing of\nthe petition or to prevent placement with the commissioner of social\nservices or the division for youth.\n  3. An order adjourning a petition in contemplation of dismissal may be\nissued upon motion of the presentment agency, the court itself, or the\nrespondent. Upon issuing such an order, the court must set forth its\nreasons therefor upon the record.\n  4. Where an order of fact-finding that includes solely a violation as\ndefined in subdivision three of section 1...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>