<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-325.1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-325.1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="325.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-325.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-325.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-325.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-325.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_325_1">
        <num>325.1</num>
        <heading>The probable-cause hearing; time</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 325.1. The probable-cause hearing; time. 1. At the initial\nappearance, if the respondent denies a charge contained in the petition\nand the court determines that the respondent shall be detained for more\nthan three days pending a fact-finding hearing, the court shall schedule\na probable-cause hearing to determine the issues specified in section\n325.3 of this part.\n  2. Such probable-cause hearing shall be held within three days\nfollowing the initial appearance or within four days following the\nfiling of a petition, whichever occurs sooner.\n  3. For good cause shown, the court may adjourn the hearing for no more\nthan an additional three court days.\n  4. The respondent may waive the probable-cause hearing, but the fact\nthat the respondent is not ready for a fact-finding hearing shall not be\ndeemed such a waiver.\n  5. Where the petition consists of an order of removal pursuant to\narticle seven hundred twenty-five of the criminal procedure law, unless\nthe removal was pursuant to subdivision three of section 725.05 of such\nlaw and the respondent was not afforded a probable cause hearing\npursuant to subdivision three of section 722.20 of such law, the\npetition shall be deemed to be based upon a determination that probable\ncause exists to believe the respondent is a juvenile delinquent and the\nrespondent shall not be entitled to any further inquiry on the subject\nof whether probable cause exists. After the filing of any such petition\nthe court must, however, exercise independent, de novo discretion with\nrespect to release or detention as set forth in section 320.5 of this\npart.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>