<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="331.5"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_331_5">
        <num>331.5</num>
        <heading>Discovery; protective orders, continuing duty to disclose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 331.5. Discovery; protective orders, continuing duty to disclose. 1.\nThe court may, upon motion of either party, or of any affected person,\nor upon determination of a motion of either party for an order of\ndiscovery, or upon its own initiative, issue a protective order denying,\nlimiting, conditioning, delaying or regulating discovery for good cause,\nincluding constitutional limitations, danger to the integrity of\nphysical evidence or a substantial risk of physical harm, intimidation,\neconomic reprisal, bribery or unjustified annoyance or embarrassment to\nany person or an adverse effect upon the legitimate needs of law\nenforcement, including the protection of the confidentiality of\ninformants, or any other factor or set of factors which outweighs the\nusefulness of the discovery.\n  2. An order limiting, conditioning, delaying or regulating discovery\nmay, among other things, require that any material copied or derived\ntherefrom be maintained in the exclusive possession of the attorney for\nthe discovering party and be used for the exclusive purpose of preparing\nfor the defense or presentment of the action.\n  3. A motion for a protective order shall suspend discovery of the\nparticular matter in dispute.\n  4. If, after complying with the provisions of sections 331.2 through\n331.7 or an order pursuant thereto, a party finds, either before or\nduring the fact-finding hearing, additional material subject to\ndiscovery or covered by such order, he shall promptly comply with the\ndemand or order, refuse to comply with the demand where refusal is\nauthorized, or apply for a protective order pursuant to this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>