<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.7"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.7"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="331.7"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-331.7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_331_7">
        <num>331.7</num>
        <heading>Discovery; demand and motion procedure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_331_7__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a demand to produce shall be made within seven days after the\nconclusion of the initial appearance or prior to the commencement of the\nfact-finding hearing, whichever occurs sooner, unless the court grants\nan extension for good cause shown;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_331_7__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a refusal to comply with a demand to produce shall be made within\nfive days of the service of the demand to produce, but for good cause\nmay be made thereafter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_331_7__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>absent a refusal to comply with a demand to produce, compliance\nwith such demand shall be made within seven days of the service of the\ndemand or as soon thereafter as practicable. The court, however, may\norder compliance within a shorter period of time.\n  2. If the respondent is not in detention:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_331_7__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a demand to produce shall be made within fifteen days after the\nconclusion of the initial appearance unless extended for good cause\nshown, but in no event later than the commencement of the fact-finding\nhearing;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_331_7__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a refusal to comply with a demand to produce shall be made within\nfifteen days of the service of the demand to produce, but for good cause\nmay be made thereafter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_331_7__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>absent a refusal to comply with a demand to produce, compliance\nwith such demand shall be made within fifteen days of the service of the\ndemand or as soon thereafter as practicable.\n  3. If the respondent is not in detention, a motion by the presentment\nagency for discovery shall be made within thirty days after the\nconclusion of the initial appearance, but for good cause shown may be\nmade at any time before commencement of the fact-finding hearing. If the\nrespondent is in detention such motion shall be made within fourteen\ndays after the conclusion of the initial appearance or prior to the\ncommencement of the fact-finding hearing, whichever occurs sooner.\n  4. A motion by a respondent for discovery shall be made as prescribed\nin section 332.2.\n  5. Where the interests of justice so require, the court may permit a\nparty to a motion for an order of discovery or a protective order, or\nother affected person, to submit papers or to testify ex parte or in\ncamera. Any such papers and transcripts of such testimony shall be\nsealed, but shall constitute a part of the record on appeal. If\npractical, a judge who receives papers or testimony in camera shall\nrefer the case to a different judge of the same court to preside at the\nfact-finding hearing.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>