<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-335.2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-335.2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="335.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-335.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-335.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-335.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-335.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_335_2">
        <num>335.2</num>
        <heading>Notice of alibi</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_335_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe place or places where the respondent claims to have been at the time\nin question, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_335_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the names, the residential addresses, the places of\nemployment and the addresses thereof of every such alibi witness upon\nwhom he intends to rely. For good cause shown, the court may extend the\nperiod for service of the notice.\n  2. Within a reasonable time after receipt of the respondent's witness\nlist but not later than ten days before the fact-finding hearing, the\npresentment agency must serve upon the respondent and file a copy\nthereof with the court, a list of witnesses such agency proposes to\noffer in rebuttal to discredit the respondent's alibi at the trial\ntogether with the residential addresses, the places of employment and\nthe addresses thereof of any such rebuttal witnesses. A witness who will\ntestify that the respondent was at the scene of the crime is not such an\nalibi rebuttal witness. For good cause shown, the court may extend the\nperiod for service.\n  3. If at the trial the respondent calls such an alibi witness without\nhaving served the demanded notice of alibi, or if having served such a\nnotice he calls a witness not specified therein, the court may exclude\nany testimony of such witness relating to the alibi defense. The court\nmay in its discretion receive such testimony, but before doing so, it\nmust, upon application of the presentment agency, grant a reasonable\nadjournment.\n  4. Similarly, if the presentment agency fails to serve and file a list\nof any rebuttal witnesses, the provisions of subdivision three shall\nreciprocally apply.\n  5. Both the respondent and the presentment agency shall be under a\ncontinuing duty to promptly disclose the names and addresses of\nadditional witnesses which come to the attention of either party\nsubsequent to filing his witness list as provided in this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>