<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-344.2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-344.2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-11-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="344.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-344.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-344.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-344.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-344.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_344_2">
        <num>344.2</num>
        <heading>Rules of evidence; statements of respondent; corroboration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_344_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by any person by the use or threatened use of physical force upon\nthe respondent or another person, or by means of any other improper\nconduct or undue pressure which impaired the respondent's physical or\nmental condition to the extent of undermining his ability to make a\nchoice whether or not to make a statement; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_344_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by a public servant engaged in law enforcement activity or by a\nperson then acting under his direction or in cooperation with him:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_344_2__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by means of any promise or statement of fact, which promise or\nstatement creates a substantial risk that the respondent might falsely\nincriminate himself; or\n  (ii) in violation of such rights as the respondent may derive from the\nconstitution of this state or of the United States; or\n  (iii) in violation of section 305.2.\n  3. Where a respondent is subject to interrogation by a public servant\nat a facility specified in subdivision four of section 305.2 of this\narticle, the entire custodial interrogation, including the giving of any\nrequired advice of the rights of the individual being questioned, and\nthe waiver of any rights by the individual, shall be recorded and\ngoverned in a manner consistent with standards established by rule of\nthe division of criminal justice services pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_344_2__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of section 60.45 of the criminal procedure law. The\ninterrogation shall be recorded in a manner such that the persons in the\nrecording are identifiable and the speech is intelligible. A copy of the\nrecording shall be subject to discovery pursuant to section 331.2 of\nthis article.\n  4. A child may not be found to be delinquent based on the commission\nof any crime solely upon evidence of a confession or admission made by\nhim without additional proof that the crime charged has been committed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>