<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-345.1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-345.1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="345.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-345.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-345.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-345.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-345.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_345_1">
        <num>345.1</num>
        <heading>Orders</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 345.1. Orders. 1. If the allegations of a petition or specific\ncounts of a petition concerning the commission of a crime or crimes are\nestablished, the court shall enter an appropriate order and schedule a\ndispositional hearing pursuant to section 350.1. The order shall specify\nthe count or counts of the petition upon which such order is based and\nthe section or sections of the penal law or other law under which the\nact or acts so stated would constitute a crime if committed by an adult.\nIf the respondent or respondents are found to have committed a\ndesignated felony act, the order shall so state.\n  2. If the allegations of a petition or specific counts of a petition\nunder this article are not established, the court shall enter an order\ndismissing the petition or specific counts therein.\n  3. Where an order of fact-finding that includes solely a violation as\ndefined in subdivision three of section 10.00 of the penal law committed\nby a juvenile sixteen years of age or, commencing on October first, two\nthousand nineteen, seventeen years of age, has been entered pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section, there shall be a rebuttable presumption\nthat the court shall refer the case to the probation service for\nadjustment services in accordance with section 320.6 of this article,\ndismiss the case pursuant to subdivision two of section 352.1 of this\narticle or adjourn the case in contemplation of dismissal pursuant to\nsection 315.3 of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>