<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-355.3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-355.3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="355.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-355.3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-355.3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-355.3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-355.3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_355_3">
        <num>355.3</num>
        <heading>Extension of placement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_355_3__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that where appropriate, and where consistent with the need for the\nprotection of the community, reasonable efforts were made to make it\npossible for the respondent to safely return to his or her home;\n  (ii) in the case of a respondent who has attained the age of sixteen,\nthe services needed, if any, to assist the child to make the transition\nfrom foster care to independent living; and\n  (iii) in the case of a child placed outside New York state, whether\nthe out-of-state placement continues to be appropriate and in the best\ninterests of the child.\n  5. Pending final determination of a petition to extend such placement\nfiled in accordance with the provisions of this section, the court may,\non its own motion or at the request of the petitioner or respondent,\nenter one or more temporary orders extending a period of placement for a\nperiod not to exceed thirty days upon satisfactory proof showing\nprobable cause for continuing such placement and that each temporary\norder is necessary. The court may order additional temporary extensions,\nnot to exceed a total of fifteen days, if the court is unable to\nconclude the hearing within the thirty day temporary extension period.\nIn no event shall the aggregate number of days in extentions granted or\nordered under this subdivision total more than forty-five days. The\npetition shall be dismissed if a decision is not rendered within the\nperiod of placement or any temporary extension thereof.\n  6. Successive extensions of placement under this section may be\ngranted, but no placement may be made or continued beyond the\nrespondent's eighteenth birthday without his or her consent and in no\nevent past his or her twenty-first birthday except as provided for in\nsubdivision four of section 353.5 of this part.\n  7. A youth who was formerly a respondent pursuant to this article may\nbe eligible to file a motion pursuant to article ten-B of this act and\nmay be subsequently placed into foster care, in a supervised set...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>