<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-380.1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-380.1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-05-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="380.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-380.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-380.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-380.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-380.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_380_1">
        <num>380.1</num>
        <heading>Nature and effect of adjudication</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 380.1. Nature and effect of adjudication. 1. No adjudication under\nthis article may be denominated a conviction and no person adjudicated a\njuvenile delinquent shall be denominated a criminal by reason of such\nadjudication.\n  2. No adjudication under this article shall operate as a forfeiture of\nany right or privilege or disqualify any person from holding any public\noffice or receiving any license granted by public authority. Such\nadjudication shall not operate as a disqualification of any person to\npursue or engage in any lawful activity, occupation, profession or\ncalling.\n  3. Except where specifically required by statute, no person shall be\nrequired to divulge information pertaining to the arrest of the\nrespondent or any subsequent proceeding under this article; provided,\nhowever, whenever a person adjudicated a juvenile delinquent has been\nplaced with the office of children and family services pursuant to\nsection 353.3 of this article, and is thereafter enrolled as a student\nin a public or private elementary or secondary school, the court that\nhas adjudicated such person shall provide notification of such\nadjudication to the designated educational official of the school in\nwhich such person is enrolled as a student. Such notification shall be\nused by the designated educational official only for purposes related to\nthe execution of the student's educational plan, where applicable,\nsuccessful school adjustment and reentry into the community. Such\nnotification shall be kept separate and apart from such student's school\nrecords and shall be accessible only by the designated educational\nofficial. Such notification shall not be part of such student's\npermanent school record and shall not be appended to or included in any\ndocumentation regarding such student and shall be destroyed at such time\nas such student is no longer enrolled in the school district. At no time\nshall such notification be used for any purpose other than those\nspecified in this subdivision.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, where a finding of\njuvenile delinquency has been entered, upon request, the records\npertaining to such case shall be made available to the commissioner of\nmental health or the commissioner of developmental disabilities, as\nappropriate; the case review panel; and the attorney general pursuant to\nsection 10.05 of the mental hygiene law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>