<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-385.1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-385.1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="385.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-385.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-385.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-385.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-385.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_385_1">
        <num>385.1</num>
        <heading>Reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 385.1. Reports. 1. In addition to reports filed pursuant to section\ntwo hundred thirteen, the chief administrator of the courts shall\ninclude in its annual report to the legislature and the governor\ninformation, by county, showing the total number of delinquency cases\nfiled under this article, the precise crime or crimes charged in such\npetitions by penal law section, the number of respondents included in\nsuch petitions, the number of cases heard in the designated felony\nparts, the age of the alleged victim by crime, the length of time and\nnumber of adjournments between the filing of a petition and the\nconclusion of the fact-finding process, the number of cases dismissed by\nthe court, the number withdrawn, the number admitted to in whole or in\npart, the number of contested fact-finding hearings and their result,\nthe precise crime, if any, found to have been committed, the length of\ntime and number of adjournments between the fact-finding hearing and the\nconclusion of the dispositional hearing and the final precise\ndisposition of such cases. Designated felony cases shall be separately\nreported by each event or fact enumerated in this section. Cases removed\nfrom criminal courts shall also be separately reported by each event and\nfact enumerated in this section.\n  2. The office of probation and correctional alternatives shall include\nin its annual report to the legislature and the governor information, by\ncounty, showing the total number of delinquency cases adjusted prior to\nfiling.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>