<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-422"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-422"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="422"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-422/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-422/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-422/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-422/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_422">
        <num>422</num>
        <heading>Persons who may originate proceedings</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_422__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A husband, wife,\nchild, or relative in need of public assistance or care may originate a\nproceeding under this article to compel a person chargeable with the\nsupport to support the petitioner as required by law. A social services\nofficial may originate a proceeding under this article if so authorized\nby section one hundred and two of the social services law. The\ncommissioner of mental health may originate a proceeding under this\narticle when authorized by article forty-three of the mental hygiene\nlaw. A parent or guardian, of a child, or other person in loco parentis,\nor a representative of an incorporated charitable or philanthropic\nsociety having a legitimate interest in the petitioner, or, when the\npetitioner is unable because of his physical or mental condition to file\na petition, a guardian ad litem, or a committee, conservator, next\nfriend or other person appointed by the court, may file a petition in\nbehalf of a dependent relative.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_422__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any party to a decree of divorce, separation, or annulment may\noriginate a proceeding to enforce or modify a decree of the supreme\ncourt or a court of competent jurisdiction, not of the state of New\nYork, as is provided in part six of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>