<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-443"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-443"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="443"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-443/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-443/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-443/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-443/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_443">
        <num>443</num>
        <heading>Order of support by parent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 443. Order of support by parent. If the court finds after a hearing\nthat a parent is chargeable under section four hundred thirteen of this\nact with the support of his or her child and is possessed of sufficient\nmeans or able to earn such means, the court shall make an order\nrequiring the parent to pay weekly or at other fixed periods a fair and\nreasonable sum for or towards the support of such child. Where permitted\nunder federal law and where the record of the proceedings contains such\ninformation, the court shall also require the social security number of\nsuch parent to be affixed to such order; provided, however, that no such\norder shall be invalid because of the omission of such number. Where the\nrecord of the proceedings contains such information, such order shall\nalso include on its face the name and address of the employer, if any,\nof the person chargeable with support provided, however, that failure to\ncomply with this requirement shall not invalidate such order. Where the\norder of child support or combined child and spouse support is made on\nbehalf of persons in receipt of public assistance or in receipt of\nservices pursuant to section one hundred eleven-g of the social services\nlaw, the court shall require each party to provide, and update upon any\nchange, the following information to the court by reporting such change\nto the support collection unit designated by the appropriate social\nservices district: social security number, residential and mailing\naddresses, telephone number, driver's license number; and name, address\nand telephone number of the parties' employers.  Due process\nrequirements for notice and service of process for subsequent hearings\nare met, with respect to such party, upon sending written notice by\nfirst class mail to the most recent residential address on record with\nthe support collection unit; or by sending by first class mail written\nnotice to the most recent employer address on record with the support\ncollection unit, if a true copy thereof also is sent by first class mail\nto the most recent residential address on record with the support\ncollection unit.  Any such order issued on or after the first day of\nOctober, nineteen hundred ninety-nine shall also include, where\navailable, the social security number of each child on whose behalf\nsupport has been ordered.  Failure to report such changes shall subject\nthe parent to the provisions of section four hundred fifty-four of this\nact.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>