<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-466"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-466"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="466"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-466/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-466/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-466/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-466/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_466">
        <num>466</num>
        <heading>Effect of granting of support in action for divorce, separation or annulment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_466__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The supreme court may provide in an order or decree\ngranting temporary or permanent support or maintenance in an action for\ndivorce, separation or annulment that only the family court may\nentertain an application to enforce or, upon a showing to the family\ncourt that there has been a subsequent change of circumstance and that\nmodification is required, to modify such order or decree. If the supreme\ncourt so provides, the family court shall entertain such an application\nand any disposition by the family court of the application is an order\nof the family court appealable only under article eleven of this act.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_466__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The supreme court may provide in an order or decree granting\nalimony, maintenance or support in an action for divorce, separation or\nannulment that the order or decree may be enforced or modified only in\nthe supreme court. If the supreme court so provides, the family court\nmay not entertain an application to enforce or modify an order or decree\nof the supreme court involving the parties to the action.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_466__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the supreme court enters an order or decree granting alimony,\nmaintenance or support in an action for divorce, separation or annulment\nand if the supreme court does not exercise the authority given under\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_466__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_466__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section; or if a court of competent\njurisdiction not of the state of New York shall enter an order or decree\ngranting alimony, maintenance or support in any such action, the family\ncourt may\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_466__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>entertain an application to enforce the order or decree granting\nalimony or maintenance, or\n  (ii) entertain an application to modify the order or decree granting\nalimony or maintenance on the ground that there has been a subsequent\nchange of circumstances and that modification is required.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>