<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-545"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-545"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="545"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-545/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-545/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-545/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-545/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_545">
        <num>545</num>
        <heading>Order of support by parents</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_545__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection fifty-two hundred forty-one of the civil practice law and rules.\nThe court shall direct such parent to make his or her residence known at\nall times should he or she move from the address last known to the court\nby reporting such change to the support collection unit designated by\nthe appropriate social services district. The order shall contain the\nsocial security numbers of the named parents. The order may also direct\neach parent to pay an amount as the court may determine and apportion\nfor the support of the child prior to the making of the order of\nfiliation, and may direct each parent to pay an amount as the court may\ndetermine and apportion for the funeral expenses if the child has died.\nThe necessary expenses incurred by or for the mother in connection with\nher confinement and recovery and such expenses in connection with the\npregnancy of the mother shall be deemed cash medical support, and the\ncourt shall determine the obligation of either or both parents to\ncontribute to the cost thereof pursuant to subparagraph five of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_545__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section four hundred thirteen of\nthis act. In addition, the court shall make provisions for health\ninsurance benefits in accordance with the requirements of section four\nhundred sixteen of this act.\n  2. The court, in its discretion, taking into consideration the means\nof the father and his ability to pay and the needs of the child, may\ndirect the payment of a reasonable sum or periodic sums to the mother as\nreimbursement for the needs of the child accruing from the date of the\nbirth of the child to the date of the application for an order of\nfiliation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>