<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-205"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-205"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-01-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="580-205"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_580_205">
        <num>580-205</num>
        <heading>Continuing exclusive jurisdiction to modify child support order</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_205__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state that has issued a child support\norder consistent with the law of this state has and shall exercise\ncontinuing, exclusive jurisdiction to modify its child support order if\nthe order is the controlling order and:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_205__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>at the time of the filing of a request for modification this state\nis the residence of the obligor, the individual obligee or the child for\nwhose benefit the support order is issued; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_205__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>even if this state is not the residence of the obligor, the\nindividual obligee or the child for whose benefit the support order is\nissued, the parties consent in a record or in open court that the\ntribunal of this state may continue to exercise jurisdiction to modify\nits order.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_205__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state that has issued a child support order\nconsistent with the law of this state may not exercise continuing,\nexclusive jurisdiction to modify the order if:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_205__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>all of the parties who are individuals file consent in a record\nwith the tribunal of this state that a tribunal of another state that\nhas jurisdiction over at least one of the parties who is an individual\nor that is located in the state of residence of the child may modify the\norder and assume continuing, exclusive jurisdiction; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_205__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>its order is not the controlling order.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_205__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a tribunal of another state has issued a child support order\npursuant to the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act or a law\nsubstantially similar to that act which modifies a child support order\nof a tribunal of this state, tribunals of this state shall recognize the\ncontinuing, exclusive jurisdiction of the tribunal of the other state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_205__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state that lacks continuing, exclusive\njurisdiction to modify a child support order may serve as an initiating\ntribunal to request a tribunal of another state to modify a support\norder issued in that state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_205__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A temporary support order issued ex parte or pending resolution of\na jurisdictional conflict does not create continuing, exclusive\njurisdiction in the issuing tribunal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>