<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-01-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="580-207"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_580_207">
        <num>580-207</num>
        <heading>Determination of controlling child support order</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a\nproceeding is brought under this article and only one tribunal has\nissued a child support order, the order of that tribunal controls and\nmust be recognized.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a proceeding is brought under this article, and two or more\nchild support orders have been issued by tribunals of this state,\nanother state or a foreign country with regard to the same obligor and\nsame child, a tribunal of this state having personal jurisdiction over\nboth the obligor and individual obligee shall apply the following rules\nand by order shall determine which order controls and must be\nrecognized:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If only one of the tribunals would have continuing, exclusive\njurisdiction under this article, the order of that tribunal controls.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If more than one of the tribunals would have continuing, exclusive\njurisdiction under this article:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an order issued by a tribunal in the current home state of the\nchild controls; or\n  (ii) if an order has not been issued in the current home state of the\nchild, the order most recently issued controls.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_207__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If none of the tribunals would have continuing, exclusive\njurisdiction under this article, the tribunal of this state shall issue\na child support order, which controls.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If two or more child support orders have been issued for the same\nobligor and same child, upon request of a party who is an individual or\nthat is a support enforcement agency, a tribunal of this state having\npersonal jurisdiction over both the obligor and the obligee who is an\nindividual shall determine which order controls under subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis section. The request may be filed with a registration for\nenforcement or registration for modification pursuant to part six of\nthis article, or may be filed as a separate proceeding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A request to determine which is the controlling order must be\naccompanied by a copy of every child support order in effect and the\napplicable record of payments. The requesting party shall give notice of\nthe request to each party whose rights may be affected by the\ndetermination.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The tribunal that issued the controlling order under subdivision\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section has continuing jurisdiction to the\nextent provided in section 580-205 or 580-206 of this part.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A tribunal of this state that determines by order which is the\ncontrolling order under paragraph one or two of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, or that issues a new controlling order\nunder paragraph three of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, shall state in\nthat order:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the basis upon which the tribunal made its determination;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount of prospective support, if any; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_207__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the total amount of consolidated arrears and accrued interest, if\nany, under all of the orders after all payments made are credited as\nprovided by section 580-209 of this part.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within thirty days after issuance of an order determining which is\nthe controlling order, the party obtaining the order shall file a\ncertified copy of it in each tribunal that issued or registered an\nearlier order of child support. A party or support enforcement agency\nobtaining the order that fails to file a certified copy is subject to\nappropriate sanctions by a tribunal in which the issue of failure to\nfile arises. The failure to file does not affect the validity or\nenforceability of the controlling order.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_207__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An order that has been determined to be the controlling order, or\na judgment for consolidated arrears of support and interest, if any,\nmade pursuant to this section must be recognized in proceedings under\nthis article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>