<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-01-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="580-102"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-580-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_580_102">
        <num>580-102</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>which has been declared under the law of the United States to be a\nforeign reciprocating country;\n  (ii) which has established a reciprocal arrangement for child support\nwith this state as provided in section 580-308 of this article;\n  (iii) which has enacted a law or established procedures for the\nissuance and enforcement of support orders which are substantially\nsimilar to the procedures under this article; or\n  (iv) in which the Convention is in force with respect to the United\nStates.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Foreign support order" means a support order of a foreign\ntribunal.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Foreign tribunal" means a court, administrative agency or\nquasi-judicial entity of a foreign country which is authorized to\nestablish, enforce or modify support orders, or to determine parentage\nof a child. The term includes a competent authority under the\nConvention.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Home state" means the state or foreign country in which a child\nlived with a parent or a person acting as parent for at least six\nconsecutive months immediately preceding the time of filing of a\npetition or comparable pleading for support and, if a child is less than\nsix months old, the state or foreign country in which the child lived\nfrom birth with any of them. A period of temporary absence of any of\nthem is counted as part of the six-month or other period.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Income" includes earnings or other periodic entitlements to money\nfrom any source and any other property subject to withholding for\nsupport as defined by section five thousand two hundred forty-one of the\ncivil practice law and rules.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Income withholding order" means an order or other legal process\ndirected to an obligor's employer, an income payor as defined by section\nfive thousand two hundred forty-one or five thousand two hundred\nforty-two of the civil practice law and rules, or other debtor to\nwithhold support from the income of the obligor.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Initiating tribunal" means the tribunal of a state or foreign\ncountry from which a petition or comparable pleading is forwarded or in\nwhich a petition or comparable pleading is filed for forwarding to\nanother state or foreign country.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Issuing foreign country" means the foreign country in which a\ntribunal issues a support order or a judgment determining parentage of a\nchild.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Issuing state" means the state in which a tribunal issues a\nsupport order or a judgment determining parentage of a child.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Issuing tribunal" means the tribunal of a state or foreign\ncountry that issues a support order or a judgment determining parentage\nof a child.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Law" includes decisional and statutory law and rules and\nregulations having the force of law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Obligee" means:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an individual to whom a duty of support is or is alleged to be\nowed or in whose favor a support order or a judgment determining\nparentage of a child has been issued;\n  (ii) a foreign country, state or political subdivision of a state to\nwhich the rights under a duty of support or support order have been\nassigned or which has independent claims based on financial assistance\nprovided to an individual obligee in place of child support;\n  (iii) an individual seeking a judgment determining parentage of the\nindividual's child; or\n  (iv) a person that is a creditor in a proceeding under part seven of\nthis article.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_17">
            <num>(17)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Obligor" means an individual, or the estate of a decedent that:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>owes or is alleged to owe a duty of support;\n  (ii) is alleged but has not been adjudicated to be a parent of a\nchild;\n  (iii) is liable under a support order; or\n  (iv) is a debtor in a proceeding under part seven of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_18">
            <num>(18)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Outside this state" means a location in another state or a\ncountry other than the United States, whether or not the country is a\nforeign country.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_19">
            <num>(19)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Person" means an individual, corporation, business trust,\nestate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association,\njoint venture, public corporation, government or governmental\nsubdivision, agency or instrumentality, or any other legal or commercial\nentity.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_20">
            <num>(20)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Record" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium\nor that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in\nperceivable form.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_21">
            <num>(21)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Register" means to file in a tribunal of this state a support\norder or judgment determining parentage of a child issued in another\nstate or a foreign country.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_22">
            <num>(22)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Registering tribunal" means a tribunal in which a support order\nor judgment determining parentage of a child is registered.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_23">
            <num>(23)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Responding state" means a state in which a petition or\ncomparable pleading for support or to determine parentage of a child is\nfiled or to which a petition or comparable pleading is forwarded for\nfiling from another state or a foreign country.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_24">
            <num>(24)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Responding tribunal" means the authorized tribunal in a\nresponding state or foreign country.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_25">
            <num>(25)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Spousal-support order" means a support order for a spouse or\nformer spouse of the obligor.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_26">
            <num>(26)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"State" means a state of the United States, the District of\nColumbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any\nterritory or insular possession under the jurisdiction of the United\nStates. The term includes an Indian nation or tribe.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i__subsec_27">
            <num>(27)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Support enforcement agency" means a public official,\ngovernmental entity or private agency authorized to:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_102__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>seek enforcement of support orders or laws relating to the duty of\nsupport;\n  (ii) seek establishment or modification of child support;\n  (iii) request determination of parentage of a child;\n  (iv) attempt to locate obligors or their assets; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_580_102__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>request determination of the controlling child support order.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_v__subsec_28">
            <num>(28)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Support order" means a judgment, decree, order, decision or\ndirective, whether temporary, final or subject to modification, issued\nin a state or foreign country for the benefit of a child, a spouse or a\nformer spouse, which provides for monetary support, health care,\narrearages, retroactive support or reimbursement for financial\nassistance provided to an individual obligee in place of child support.\nThe term may include related costs and fees, interest, income\nwithholding, automatic adjustment, reasonable attorney's fees and other\nrelief.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_580_102__subsec_v__subsec_29">
            <num>(29)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Tribunal" means a court, administrative agency, or\nquasi-judicial entity authorized to establish, enforce, or modify\nsupport orders or to determine parentage of a child.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>