<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-205"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-205"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="581-205"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_581_205">
        <num>581-205</num>
        <heading>Inspection of records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 581-205. Inspection of records. Court records relating to\nproceedings under this article shall be sealed, provided, however, that\nthe office of temporary and disability assistance, a child support unit\nof a social services district or a child support agency of another state\nproviding child support services pursuant to title IV-d of the federal\nsocial security act, when a party to a related support proceeding and to\nthe extent necessary to provide child support services or for the\nadministration of the program pursuant to title IV-d of the federal\nsocial security act, may obtain a copy of a judgment of parentage. The\nparties to the proceeding and the child shall have the right to inspect\nand make copies of the entire court record, including, but not limited\nto, the name of the person acting as surrogate and any known donor.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the county clerk or the\nclerk of the supreme, surrogate's or family court shall not display the\nsurname of the child or parties in any caption, document, index, minutes\nor other record available to the public, whether filed in hard copy or\nelectronically.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>