<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-502"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-502"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="581-502"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_581_502">
        <num>581-502</num>
        <heading>Compensation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_502__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation may be paid to a donor or\nperson acting as surrogate based on medical risks, physical discomfort,\ninconvenience and the responsibilities they are undertaking in\nconnection with their participation in the assisted reproduction. Under\nno circumstances may compensation be paid to purchase gametes or embryos\nor for the release of a parental interest in a child.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_502__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The compensation, if any, paid to a donor or person acting as\nsurrogate must be reasonable and negotiated in good faith between the\nparties. Base compensation paid to a person acting as surrogate shall\nnot exceed the duration of the pregnancy and recuperative period of\neight weeks after the birth of any resulting child. Supplemental\ncompensation for any medical procedure associated with complications\nfrom the pregnancy or delivery as confirmed by a health care\npractitioner, and any associated lost wages, may be, but are not\nrequired to be, paid after the recuperative period and until twelve\nmonths after the birth of the child, a stillbirth, a miscarriage\nresulting in termination of the pregnancy, or termination of the\npregnancy.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_502__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation may not be conditioned upon the purported quality or\ngenome-related traits of the gametes or embryos.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_502__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation may not be conditioned on actual genotypic or\nphenotypic characteristics of the donor or donors or of any resulting\nchildren.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_502__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation to any embryo donor shall be limited to storage fees,\ntransportation costs and attorneys' fees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>