<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-03-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="581-604"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-581-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_581_604">
        <num>581-604</num>
        <heading>Health insurance and medical costs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 581-604. Health insurance and medical costs. A person acting as\nsurrogate has the right to have a comprehensive health insurance policy\nthat covers preconception care, prenatal care, major medical treatments,\nhospitalization and behavioral care for a term that extends throughout\nthe duration of the expected pregnancy and for twelve months after the\nbirth of the child, a stillbirth, a miscarriage resulting in termination\nof pregnancy, or termination of the pregnancy, to be paid for by the\nintended parent or parents. The intended parent or parents shall also\npay for or reimburse the person acting as surrogate for all co-payments,\ndeductibles and any other out-of-pocket medical costs associated with\npregnancy, childbirth, or postnatal care that accrue through twelve\nmonths after the birth of the child, a stillbirth, a miscarriage, or the\ntermination of the pregnancy. A person acting as a surrogate who is\nreceiving no compensation may waive the right to have the intended\nparent or parents make such payments or reimbursements.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>