<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-636"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-636"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="636"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-636/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-636/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-636/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-636/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_636">
        <num>636</num>
        <heading>Originating a proceeding to restore parental rights; service and venue</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_636__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A proceeding to modify the disposition in order to\nrestore parental rights may be originated by the filing of a petition by\nthe child's attorney, by the agency or individual to whom guardianship\nand custody of the child had been committed or by the respondent or\nrespondents in the termination of parental rights proceeding. The\npetition shall be served upon the child's attorney, the agency or\nindividual to whom guardianship and custody of the child had been\ncommitted and the respondent or respondents in the termination of\nparental rights proceeding, as well as the attorney or attorneys who\nrepresented the respondent or respondents in the termination of parental\nrights proceeding. A certified copy of the order committing guardianship\nand custody shall be attached to the petition.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_636__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the filing of a petition under this part, the court may cause\na summons to be issued to the child, the agency or individual to whom\nguardianship and custody of the child had been committed and the\nrespondent or respondents in the termination of parental rights\nproceeding. The summons shall be served in accordance with section six\nhundred seventeen of this article, accompanied by a copy of the petition\nand the certified order of commitment sought to be modified.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_636__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The petition shall be filed before the court that exercised\njurisdiction over the most recent permanency proceeding involving the\nchild and shall be assigned, wherever practicable, to the family court\njudge who presided over that proceeding or the proceeding to terminate\nparental rights.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_636__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Wherever practicable, the child shall be represented by the same\nattorney that represented the child in the most recent permanency\nproceeding and the parent or parents shall be represented by the same\nattorney or attorneys who represented the parent or parents in the\ntermination of parental rights proceeding. Where this is not\npracticable, or where the court grants a request by the attorney or\nattorneys to be relieved, the court shall immediately assign a new\nattorney or attorneys, as applicable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>