<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-671"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-671"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="671"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-671/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-671/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-671/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-671/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_671">
        <num>671</num>
        <heading>Issuance of warrant; certificate of warrant</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court may\nissue a warrant, directing that the respondent be arrested, brought\nbefore the court, when a petition is presented to the court under\nsections six hundred fourteen, six hundred fifty-one, six hundred\nfifty-four, six hundred fifty-five and six hundred fifty-six of this\narticle or section three hundred eighty-four-b of the social services\nlaw and it appears that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the summons cannot be served; or\n  (ii) the respondent has failed to obey the summons; or\n  (iii) the respondent is likely to leave the jurisdiction; or\n  (iv) a summons, in the court's opinion, would be ineffectual; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the safety of the petitioner or child is endangered; or\n  (vi) a respondent on bail or on parole has failed to appear.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The petitioner may not serve a warrant upon the respondent unless\nthe court itself grants such permission upon the application of the\npetitioner. The clerk of the court may issue to the petitioner or to the\nrepresentative of an incorporated charitable or philanthropic society\nhaving a legitimate interest in the family a certificate stating that a\nwarrant for the respondent has been issued by the court. The\npresentation of such certificate by said petitioner or representative to\nany peace officer, acting pursuant to his special duties, or police\nofficer authorizes him to arrest the respondent and take him to court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A certificate of warrant expires ninety days from the date of\nissue but may be renewed from time to time by the clerk of the court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_671__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Rules of court shall provide that a record of all unserved\nwarrants be kept and that periodic reports concerning unserved warrants\nbe made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>