<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-812"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-812"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="812"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_812">
        <num>812</num>
        <heading>Procedures for family offense proceedings</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons related by consanguinity or affinity;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons legally married to one another;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons formerly married to one another regardless of whether they\nstill reside in the same household;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons who have a child in common regardless of whether such\npersons have been married or have lived together at any time;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons who are not related by consanguinity or affinity and who\nare or have been in an intimate relationship regardless of whether such\npersons have lived together at any time. Factors the court may consider\nin determining whether a relationship is an "intimate relationship"\ninclude but are not limited to: the nature or type of relationship,\nregardless of whether the relationship is sexual in nature; the\nfrequency of interaction between the persons; and the duration of the\nrelationship. Neither a casual acquaintance nor ordinary fraternization\nbetween two individuals in business or social contexts shall be deemed\nto constitute an "intimate relationship"; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons who are related by consanguinity or affinity to parties\nwho are or have been in an intimate relationship as defined in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n  2. Information to petitioner or complainant. The chief administrator\nof the courts shall designate the appropriate persons, including, but\nnot limited to district attorneys, criminal and family court clerks,\ncorporation counsels, county attorneys, victims assistance unit staff,\nprobation officers, warrant officers, sheriffs, police officers or any\nother law enforcement officials, to inform any petitioner or complainant\nbringing a proceeding under this article, before such proceeding is\ncommenced, of the procedures available for the institution of family\noffense proceedings, including but not limited to the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That there is concurrent jurisdiction with respect to family\noffenses in both family court and the criminal courts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That a family court proceeding is a civil proceeding and is for\nthe purpose of attempting to stop the violence, end the family\ndisruption and obtain protection. Referrals for counseling, or\ncounseling services, are available through probation for this purpose;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That a proceeding in the criminal courts is for the purpose of\nprosecution of the offender and can result in a criminal conviction of\nthe offender;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That a proceeding or action subject to the provisions of this\nsection is initiated at the time of the filing of an accusatory\ninstrument or family court petition, not at the time of arrest, or\nrequest for arrest, if any;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That an arrest may precede the commencement of a family court or a\ncriminal court proceeding, but an arrest is not a requirement for\ncommencing either proceeding; provided, however, that the arrest of an\nalleged offender shall be made under the circumstances described in\nsubdivision four of section 140.10 of the criminal procedure law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That notwithstanding a complainant's election to proceed in family\ncourt, the criminal court shall not be divested of jurisdiction to hear\na family offense proceeding pursuant to this section.\n  3. Official responsibility. No official or other person designated\npursuant to subdivision two of this section shall discourage or prevent\nany person who wishes to file a petition or sign a complaint from having\naccess to any court for that purpose.\n  4. Official forms. The chief administrator of the courts shall\nprescribe an appropriate form to implement subdivision two of this\nsection.\n  5. Notice. Every police officer, peace officer or district attorney\ninvestigating a family offense under this article shall advise the\nvictim of the availability of a shelter or other services in the\ncommunity, and shall immediately give the victim written notice of the\nlegal rights and remedies available to a victim of a family offense\nunder the relevant provisions of this act and the criminal procedure\nlaw. Such notice shall be available, at minimum, in plain English,\nSpanish, Chinese and Russian and, if necessary, shall be delivered\norally and shall include but not be limited to the information contained\nin the following statement:\n  "Are you the victim of domestic violence? If you need help now, you\ncan call 911 for the police to come to you. You can also call a domestic\nviolence hotline. You can have a confidential talk with an advocate at\nthe hotline about help you can get in your community including: where\nyou can get treatment for injuries, where you can get shelter, where you\ncan get support, and what you can do to be safe. The New York State\n24-hour Domestic &amp; Sexual Violence Hotline number is (insert the\nstatewide multilingual 800 number). They can give you information in\nmany languages. If you are deaf or hard of hearing, call 711. This is\nwhat the police can do:\n  They can help you and your children find a safe place such as a family\nor friend's ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>