<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-813"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-813"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="813"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-813/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-813/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-813/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-813/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_813">
        <num>813</num>
        <heading>Transfer to criminal court</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 813. Transfer to criminal court. 1. At any time prior to a finding\non the petition the court may, with the consent of the petitioner and\nupon reasonable notice to the district attorney, who shall have an\nopportunity to be heard, order that any matter which is the subject of a\nproceeding commenced pursuant to this article be prosecuted as a\ncriminal action in an appropriate criminal court if the court determines\nthat the interests of justice so require.\n  2. The court may simultaneously with the transfer of any matter to the\nappropriate criminal court, issue or continue a temporary order of\nprotection which, notwithstanding any other provision of law, shall\ncontinue in effect, absent action by the appropriate criminal court\npursuant to subdivision three of section 530.12 of the criminal\nprocedure law, until the defendant is arraigned upon an accusatory\ninstrument filed pursuant to this section in such criminal court.\n  3. Nothing herein shall be deemed to limit or restrict a petitioner's\nrights to proceed directly and without court referral in either criminal\nor family court, or both, as provided for in section one hundred fifteen\nof this act and section 100.07 of the criminal procedure law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>