<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="FCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-828"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-828"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="828"/>
          <FRBRname value="FCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-828/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-828/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-828/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/fct/section-828/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_828">
        <num>828</num>
        <heading>Temporary order of protection; temporary orders for child support and spousal maintenance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_828__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the filing of a petition or\ncounter-claim under this article, the court for good cause shown may\nissue a temporary order of protection, which may contain any of the\nprovisions authorized on the making of an order of protection under\nsection eight hundred forty-two, provided that the court shall make a\ndetermination, and the court shall state such determination in a written\ndecision or on the record, whether to impose a condition pursuant to\nthis subdivision, provided further, however, that failure to make such a\ndetermination shall not affect the validity of such order of protection.\nIn making such determination, the court shall consider, but shall not be\nlimited to consideration of, whether the temporary order of protection\nis likely to achieve its purpose in the absence of such a condition,\nconduct subject to prior orders of protection, prior incidents of abuse,\nextent of past or present injury, threats, drug or alcohol abuse, and\naccess to weapons.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_828__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the filing of a petition under this article, or as soon\nthereafter as the petitioner appears before the court, the court shall\nadvise the petitioner of the right to proceed in both the family and\ncriminal courts, pursuant to the provisions of section one hundred\nfifteen of this act.\n  2. A temporary order of protection is not a finding of wrongdoing.\n  3. The court may issue or extend a temporary order of protection ex\nparte or on notice simultaneously with the issuance of a warrant,\ndirecting that the respondent be arrested and brought before the court,\npursuant to section eight hundred twenty-seven of this article.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of section eight hundred seventeen\nof this article the court may, together with a temporary order of\nprotection issued pursuant to this section, issue an order for temporary\nchild support, in an amount sufficient to meet the needs of the child,\nwithout a showing of immediate or emergency need. The court shall make\nan order for temporary child support notwithstanding that information\nwith respect to income and assets of the respondent may be unavailable.\nWhere such information is available, the court may make an award for\ntemporary child support pursuant to the formula set forth in subdivision\none of section four hundred thirteen of this act. An order making such\naward shall be deemed to have been issued pursuant to article four of\nthis act. Upon making an order for temporary child support pursuant to\nthis subdivision, the court shall advise the petitioner of the\navailability of child support enforcement services by the support\ncollection unit of the local department of social services, to enforce\nthe temporary order and to assist in securing continued child support,\nand shall set the support matter down for further proceedings in\naccordance with article four of this act.\n  Where the court determines that the respondent has employer-provided\nmedical insurance, the court may further dir...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>