<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1210"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1210">
        <num>1210</num>
        <heading>Guardian of infant</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Petition for appointment; by whom\npresented; contents. An infant, if of the age of fourteen years or more,\nor a relative or friend of an infant, may present a petition to the\ncourt for appointment of a guardian. The petition shall state the age\nand residence of the infant, the name and residence of any living parent\nand of the person proposed as guardian, the relationship if any which\nsuch person bears to the infant, and the nature, status and value of the\ninfant's estate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Hearing. The court shall ascertain the age of the infant, the\namount of his personal property, the gross amount or value of the rents\nand profits of his real estate during his minority, and the sufficiency\nof the security offered by the proposed guardian. If the infant is of\nthe age of fourteen years or more, the court shall examine him as to his\nvoluntary nomination of or preference for a suitable guardian; if he is\nunder the age of fourteen, the court shall select and appoint a suitable\nguardian.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Undertaking. The court shall make an order requiring or dispensing\nwholly or partly with an undertaking, in an amount and according to the\nconditions set forth in section seventeen hundred eight of the\nsurrogate's court procedure act.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Direction as to management of estate. The court in its discretion\nmay direct that the principal of the estate or any part of it be\ninvested in bonds of the state of New York or of the United States, or\ninvested in bonds or other obligations of any county, city, town,\nvillage or school district of the state of New York, or deposited with\nany bank, trust company, insured savings and loan association or insured\nsavings bank or insured state or federal credit union which has been\ndesignated as a depository for such fund; or invested in a bond and\nmortgage on unincumbered and improved property within the state, having\na value, to be shown to the satisfaction of the court, of at least\ndouble the amount of principal invested, for the benefit of the infant,\nand may direct that only the interest or income be received by the\nguardian.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1210__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Filing of certified copy of order of appointment. Upon the\nappointment of a guardian of the person or property, or both, of an\ninfant, the guardian shall file a certified copy of the order of his\nappointment with the clerk of the surrogate's court of the county in\nwhich he has been appointed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>