<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1319"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1319"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1319"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1319/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1319/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1319/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1319/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1319">
        <num>1319</num>
        <heading>Service of summons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1319. Service of summons. An order of attachment granted before\nservice is made on the defendant against whom the attachment is granted\nis valid only if, within sixty days after the order is granted, a\nsummons is served upon the defendant or first publication of the summons\nagainst the defendant is made pursuant to an order and publication is\nsubsequently completed, except that a person upon whom the order of\nattachment is served shall not be liable for acting upon it as if it\nwere valid without knowledge of the invalidity. If the defendant dies\nwithin sixty days after the order is granted and before the summons is\nserved upon him or her or publication is completed, the order is valid\nonly if the summons is served upon his or her executor or administrator\nwithin sixty days after letters are issued. Upon such terms as may be\njust and upon good cause shown the court may extend the time, not\nexceeding sixty days, within which the summons must be served or\npublication commenced pursuant to this section, provided that the\napplication for extension is made before the expiration of the time\nfixed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>