<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2112"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2112"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2112"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2112">
        <num>2112</num>
        <heading>Filing of papers in the appellate division by electronic means</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2112__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twenty-one hundred\neleven of this article, the appellate division in each judicial\ndepartment may promulgate rules authorizing a program in the use of\nelectronic means for:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2112__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>appeals to such court from the judgment or\norder of a court of original instance or from that of another appellate\ncourt, (ii) making a motion for permission to appeal to such court,\n(iii) commencement of any other proceeding that may be brought in such\ncourt, and (iv) the filing and service of papers in pending actions and\nproceedings. Provided however, such rules shall not require an\nunrepresented party or any attorney who furnishes a certificate\nspecified in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph three of subdivision\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2112__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twenty-one hundred eleven of this article to take or\nperfect an appeal by electronic means.  Provided further, however,\nbefore promulgating any such rules, the appellate division in each\njudicial department shall consult with the chief administrator of the\ncourts and shall provide an opportunity for review and comment by all\nthose who are or would be affected including city, state, county and\nwomen's bar associations; institutional legal service providers;\nnot-for-profit legal service providers; attorneys assigned pursuant to\narticle eighteen-B of the county law; unaffiliated attorneys who\nregularly appear in proceedings that are or have been affected by the\nprograms that have been implemented or who may be affected by\npromulgation of rules concerning the use of the electronic filing\nprogram in the appellate division of any judicial department; and any\nother persons in whose county a program has been implemented in any of\nthe courts therein as deemed to be appropriate by any appellate\ndivision. To the extent practicable, rules promulgated by the appellate\ndivision in each judicial department pursuant to this section shall be\nuniform and may apply to any appellate term established by an appellate\ndivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>