<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2219"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2219"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2219"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2219/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2219/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2219/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2219/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2219">
        <num>2219</num>
        <heading>Time and form of order</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2219__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Time and form of order\ndetermining motion, generally. An order determining a motion relating to\na provisional remedy shall be made within twenty days, and an order\ndetermining any other motion shall be made within sixty days, after the\nmotion is submitted for decision. The order shall be in writing and\nshall be the same in form whether made by a court or a judge out of\ncourt. An order determining a motion made upon supporting papers shall\nbe signed with the judge's signature or initials by the judge who made\nit, state the court of which he or she is a judge and the place and date\nof the signature, recite the papers used on the motion, and give the\ndetermination or direction in such detail as the judge deems proper.\nExcept in a town or village court or where otherwise provided by law,\nupon the request of any party, an order or ruling made by a judge,\nwhether upon written or oral application or sua sponte, shall be reduced\nto writing or otherwise recorded.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2219__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Signature on appellate court order. An order of an appellate court\nshall be signed by a judge thereof except that, upon written\nauthorization by the presiding judge, it may be signed by the clerk of\nthe court or, in his absence or disability, by a deputy clerk.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>