<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2607"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2607"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2607"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2607">
        <num>2607</num>
        <heading>Payment of property paid into court</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  Rule 2607. Payment of property paid into court. No property paid into\ncourt, or income from such property, shall be paid out except upon order\nof the court directing payment to a specified person, except that if the\nproperty so paid into court, or the income from such property, inclusive\nof interest, does not exceed fifty dollars, a county treasurer may pay\nthe same, without a court order, to the person entitled thereto or his\nauthorized attorney. When the whole or remaining balance of all payments\nof money into court in an action, or the whole or remaining balance of a\ndistributive share thereof, or any security or other property, is\ndirected to be paid out of court, the order must direct the payment of\nall accrued income belonging to the party to whom such money or\ndistributive share or remaining balance thereof, or security or other\nproperty is paid. A certified copy of the order directing payment shall\nbe delivered to the county treasurer or other custodian of the property.\nThe custodian, in the case of money, shall draw a draft payable to the\norder of the party entitled thereto specifying the title of the cause or\nmatter on account of which the draft is made and the date of the order\nauthorizing the draft. A certified copy of the order, accompanied by a\ndraft in the case of money, shall be delivered to the depository of the\nproperty before it shall pay out any property. If an order directs that\nperiodic payments be made, the filing of one copy of the order shall be\nsufficient to authorize the payment of subsequent drafts in pursuance\nthereof. Any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, if\nan order directing payment by the county treasurer is made by the court,\nthe copy of the order to be delivered to the county treasurer and the\ndepository as herein provided shall be certified by the clerk of the\ncourt to be a true copy of the original of such order on file in his\noffice.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>