<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="304"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_304">
        <num>304</num>
        <heading>Method of commencing action or special proceeding</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An\naction is commenced by filing a summons and complaint or summons with\nnotice in accordance with rule twenty-one hundred two of this chapter. A\nspecial proceeding is commenced by filing a petition in accordance with\nrule twenty-one hundred two of this chapter. Where a court finds that\ncircumstances prevent immediate filing, the signing of an order\nrequiring the subsequent filing at a specific time and date not later\nthan five days thereafter shall commence the action.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such filing may be\naccomplished by facsimile transmission or electronic means, as defined\nin subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule twenty-one hundred three of this chapter,\nwhere and in the manner authorized by the chief administrator of the\ncourts by rule.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this section, and for purposes of section two\nhundred three of this chapter and section three hundred six-a of this\narticle, filing shall mean the delivery of the summons with notice,\nsummons and complaint or petition to the clerk of the court in the\ncounty in which the action or special proceeding is brought or any other\nperson designated by the clerk of the court for that purpose. At the\ntime of filing, the filed papers shall be date stamped by the clerk of\nthe court who shall file them and maintain a record of the date of the\nfiling and who shall return forthwith a date stamped copy, together with\nan index number, to the filing party, except where filing is by\nelectronic means. Such filing shall not be accepted unless any fee\nrequired as specified in section eight thousand eighteen of this chapter\nhas been paid. Where filing is by electronic means, any fee required\nshall be paid in the time and manner authorized by the chief\nadministrator of the court by rule.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where filing is by facsimile transmission, the clerk of the court\nneed only return a date stamped copy of the first page of the papers\ninitiating the lawsuit, together with the index number.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where filing is by electronic means, the clerk shall, in\naccordance with rules promulgated by the chief administrator, forthwith\nnotify the filing party of the index number and the date and time of\nfiling.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_304__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A confirmation record produced by the filing party's facsimile\nmachine or computer and an affidavit of filing by the filing party,\nshall be prima facie evidence that the filing party transmitted\ndocuments consistent with the date, time and place appearing on the\nconfirmation record.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>