<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="306-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_306_C">
        <num>306-C</num>
        <heading>Notice of commencement of action for personal injuries by recipient of medical assistance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 306-c. Notice of commencement of action for personal injuries by\nrecipient of medical assistance. In the case of an individual who has\nsuffered personal injuries and has received medical assistance pursuant\nto titles eleven and eleven-D of article five of the social services law\non or after the date of such injury, notice of the commencement of an\naction by or on behalf of such individual for such personal injuries\nshall be sent to the social services district in the county in which\nsuch recipient resides, or to the department of health, by certified\nmail, return receipt requested, or electronically in accord with\nregulations promulgated by the commissioner of the department of health,\nwithin sixty days of the completion of service upon all parties to such\naction. Proof of sending such notice shall be filed with the court in\naccordance with rule three hundred six of this article. Sending such\nnotice shall not be a jurisdictional requirement to commencing an\naction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>