<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="311"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_311">
        <num>311</num>
        <heading>Personal service upon a corporation or governmental subdivision</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_311__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Personal service upon a corporation or governmental\nsubdivision shall be made by delivering the summons as follows:\n  1. upon any domestic or foreign corporation, to an officer, director,\nmanaging or general agent, or cashier or assistant cashier or to any\nother agent authorized by appointment or by law to receive service.  A\nbusiness corporation may also be served pursuant to section three\nhundred six or three hundred seven of the business corporation law. A\nnot-for-profit corporation may also be served pursuant to section three\nhundred six or three hundred seven of the not-for-profit corporation\nlaw;\n  2. upon the city of New York, to the corporation counsel or to any\nperson designated to receive process in a writing filed in the office of\nthe clerk of New York county;\n  3.  upon any other city, to the mayor, comptroller, treasurer, counsel\nor clerk; or, if the city lacks such officers, to an officer performing\na corresponding function under another name;\n  4.  upon a county, to the chair or clerk of the board of supervisors,\nclerk, attorney or treasurer;\n  5.  upon a town, to the supervisor or the clerk;\n  6.  upon a village, to the mayor, clerk, or any trustee;\n  7.  upon a school district, to a school officer, as defined in the\neducation law; and\n  8.  upon a park, sewage or other district, to the clerk, any trustee\nor any member of the board.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_311__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If service upon a domestic or foreign corporation within the one\nhundred twenty days allowed by section three hundred six-b of this\narticle is impracticable under paragraph one of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_311__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsection or any other law, service upon the corporation may be made in\nsuch manner, and proof of service may take such form, as the court, upon\nmotion without notice, directs.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>