<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3130"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3130">
        <num>3130</num>
        <heading>Use of interrogatories</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3130. Use of interrogatories. 1. Except as otherwise provided\nherein, after commencement of an action, any party may serve upon any\nother party written interrogatories. Except in a matrimonial action, a\nparty may not serve written interrogatories on another party and also\ndemand a bill of particulars of the same party pursuant to section 3041.\nIn the case of an action to recover damages for personal injury, injury\nto property or wrongful death predicated solely on a cause or causes of\naction for negligence, a party shall not be permitted to serve\ninterrogatories on and conduct a deposition of the same party pursuant\nto rule 3107 without leave of court.\n  2. After the commencement of a matrimonial action or proceeding, upon\nmotion brought by either party, upon such notice to the other party and\nto the non-party from whom financial disclosure is sought, and given in\nsuch manner as the court shall direct, the court may order a non-party\nto respond under oath to written interrogatories limited to furnishing\nfinancial information concerning a party, and further provided such\ninformation is both reasonable and necessary in the prosecution or the\ndefense of such matrimonial action or proceeding.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>