<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5226"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5226"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5226"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5226/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5226/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5226">
        <num>5226</num>
        <heading>Installment payment order</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5226. Installment payment order.  Upon motion of the judgment\ncreditor, upon notice to the judgment debtor, where it is shown that the\njudgment debtor is receiving or will receive money from any source, or\nis attempting to impede the judgment creditor by rendering services\nwithout adequate compensation, the court shall order that the judgment\ndebtor make specified installment payments to the judgment creditor.\nNotice of the motion shall be served on the judgment debtor in the same\nmanner as a summons or by registered or certified mail, return receipt\nrequested. In fixing the amount of the payments, the court shall take\ninto consideration the reasonable requirements of the judgment debtor\nand his dependents, any payments required to be made by him or deducted\nfrom the money he would otherwise receive in satisfaction of other\njudgments and wage assignments, the amount due on the judgment, and the\namount being or to be received, or, if the judgment debtor is attempting\nto impede the judgment creditor by rendering services without adequate\ncompensation, the reasonable value of the services rendered.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>