<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5227"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5227"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5227"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5227">
        <num>5227</num>
        <heading>Payment of debts owed to judgment debtor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5227. Payment of debts owed to judgment debtor. Upon a special\nproceeding commenced by the judgment creditor, against any person who it\nis shown is or will become indebted to the judgment debtor, the court\nmay require such person to pay to the judgment creditor the debt upon\nmaturity, or so much of it as is sufficient to satisfy the judgment, and\nto execute and deliver any document necessary to effect payment; or it\nmay direct that a judgment be entered against such person in favor of\nthe judgment creditor. Costs of the proceeding shall not be awarded\nagainst a person who did not dispute the indebtedness.  Notice of the\nproceeding shall also be served upon the judgment debtor in the same\nmanner as a summons or by registered or certified mail, return receipt\nrequested. The court may permit the judgment debtor to intervene in the\nproceeding. The court may permit any adverse claimant to intervene in\nthe proceeding and may determine his rights in accordance with section\n5239.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>