<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5526"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5526"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5526"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5526/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5526/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5526/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5526/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5526">
        <num>5526</num>
        <heading>Content and form of record on appeal</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5526__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule 5525 if a trial or hearing\nwas held, any relevant exhibits, or copies of them, in the court of\noriginal instance, any other reviewable order, and any opinions in the\ncase. The record on appeal from an interlocutory judgment or any order\nshall consist of the notice of appeal, the judgment or order appealed\nfrom, the transcript, if any, the papers and other exhibits upon which\nthe judgment or order was founded and any opinions in the case. All\nprinted or reproduced papers comprising the record on appeal shall be\neleven inches by eight and one-half inches. The subject matter of each\npage of the record shall be stated at the top thereof, except that in\nthe case of papers other than testimony, the subject matter of the paper\nmay be stated at the top of the first page of each paper, together with\nthe page numbers of the first and last pages thereof. In the case of\ntestimony, the name of the witness, by whom he was called and whether\nthe testimony is direct, cross, redirect or recross examination shall be\nstated at the top of each page.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>