<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5530"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5530"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5530"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5530">
        <num>5530</num>
        <heading>Filing record and briefs; service of briefs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5530__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Generally.\nWithin twenty days after settlement of the transcript or after\nsettlement of the statement in lieu of stenographic transcript or after\napproval of the statement in lieu of record, the appellant shall file\nwith the clerk of the court to which the appeal is taken the record on\nappeal or statement in lieu of record, and the required number of copies\nof his brief, and shall also serve upon the adverse party three copies\nof his brief. The respondent shall file and serve a like number of\ncopies of his brief within fifteen days after service of the appellant's\nbrief. The appellant may file and serve a like number of copies of a\nreply brief within ten days after service of the respondent's brief.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5530__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon cross-appeal. Unless the court to which the appeals are taken\notherwise orders, where both parties take an appeal from the same\njudgment or order, the plaintiff, or appellant in the court from which\nthe appeal is taken, shall file and serve his brief first. The answering\nbrief shall be filed and served within fifteen days after service of the\nfirst brief and shall include the points and arguments on the\ncross-appeal.  A reply brief shall be filed and served within fifteen\ndays after service of the answering brief, and shall include answering\npoints and arguments on the cross-appeal. A reply brief to the\ncross-appeal may thereafter be served and filed within ten days after\nthe service of the reply to the first brief.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5530__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Special rules prescribing times for filing and serving authorized.\nThe appellate division in each department may by rule applicable in the\ndepartment prescribe other limitations of time different from those\nprescribed in subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5530__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5530__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for filing and serving records on\nappeal, or statements in lieu of records, and briefs in appeals taken\ntherein.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>