<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-7601"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-7601"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7601"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-7601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-7601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-7601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-7601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7601">
        <num>7601</num>
        <heading>Special proceeding to enforce agreement that issue or controversy be determined by a person named or to be selected</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7601. Special proceeding to enforce agreement that issue or\ncontroversy be determined by a person named or to be selected. A special\nproceeding may be commenced to specifically enforce an agreement that a\nquestion of valuation, appraisal or other issue or controversy be\ndetermined by a person named or to be selected. The court may enforce\nsuch an agreement as if it were an arbitration agreement, in which case\nthe proceeding shall be conducted as if brought under article\nseventy-five of this chapter. Where there is a defense which would\nrequire dismissal of an action for breach of the agreement, the\nproceeding shall be dismissed. Provided, however, that this section\nshall not apply to any agreement contained in the standard fire\ninsurance policy of the state with the exception of an action to enforce\nthe appraisal clause pursuant to section three thousand four hundred\neight of the insurance law which shall not be enforced as an arbitration\nagreement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>