<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8007"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8007"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8007"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8007">
        <num>8007</num>
        <heading>Printers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8007. Printers. Except where otherwise prescribed by law, the\nproprietor of a newspaper is entitled for publishing a summons, notice,\norder or other advertisement, required to be published by law or by the\norder of any court, or of the clerk of a court, to twenty-nine cents per\nline of a column width not less than ten pica ems, provided that in\ncomputing such charge per line the line shall average at least five\nwords for each insertion in newspapers having a circulation of less than\ntwo thousand five hundred; twenty-nine and one-half cents per line for\nnewspapers having two thousand five hundred or more circulation and less\nthan five thousand; thirty and one-half cents per line for newspapers\nhaving five thousand or more circulation and less than seven thousand\nfive hundred; thirty-one and one-half cents per line for newspapers\nhaving seven thousand five hundred or more circulation and less than ten\nthousand; thirty-two and one-half cents per line for newspapers having\nten thousand or more circulation and less than fifteen thousand; and\nthree and one-half cents per line, in addition to the thirty-two and\none-half cents for the initial fifteen thousand circulation, for each\nadditional five thousand circulation up to thirty-five thousand\ncirculation and one and one-half cents per line for each additional five\nthousand possessed by a newspaper. To all of the above rates nine cents\nper line shall be added to the initial insertion charge of each separate\nadvertisement. To all of the above rates for the initial insertion eight\ncents per line shall also be added for tabular matter or intricate\ncomposition. In reckoning line charges allowance shall be made for date\nlines, paragraph endings, titles, signatures and similar short lines as\nfull lines where the same are set to conform to the usual rules of\ncomposition. Display advertising shall be charged agate measurement\n(fourteen lines to each inch), ten to thirteen pica ems wide, depending\non the makeup of the newspaper publishing such copy. This rate shall not\napply to any newspaper printed, principally circulated or having its\nprincipal office in the counties of New York or Bronx within the first\njudicial district or in the county of Kings within the second judicial\ndistrict or in the county of Richmond within the thirteenth judicial\ndistrict or in the county of Nassau within the tenth judicial district\nor in the county of Queens within the eleventh judicial district or in\nthe county of Westchester within the ninth judicial district or in any\ncity having a population of over one hundred seventy-five thousand\ninhabitants within the eighth judicial district, where the rate for such\npublication may be equal to but shall not exceed the regularly\nestablished classified advertising rate of such newspapers. Every\nnewspaper making claim for compensation under the provisions of this\nsection must be established at least one year and entered in the post\noffice as second class matter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>