<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8013"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8013"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8013"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8013/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8013/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8013/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8013/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8013">
        <num>8013</num>
        <heading>Expenses of sheriffs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8013__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Publication of notice of sale.  A\nsheriff, where real property is to be sold by virtue of an execution or\nin pursuance of a direction contained in a judgment, is entitled to\nreimbursement for printer's fees, paid by him for the publication of a\nnotice of the sale. Where the notice is published more than four times,\nor the sale is postponed, the expense of continuing the publication, or\nof publishing the notice of postponement, shall be paid by the person\nrequesting it. Where two or more executions against the property of one\njudgment debtor are in the hands of the sheriff at the time when the\nproceeds are distributed, the sheriff is entitled to reimbursement for\nprinter's fees upon only the execution issued upon the judgment first\ndocketed in the county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8013__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Appraisal of attached property. A sheriff, where an estimate of\nthe value of property levied upon by virtue of an order of attachment is\nmade, shall be entitled to reimbursement for such compensation to\nappraisers actually employed thereupon as the court which granted the\norder of attachment may allow.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8013__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Other expenses. A sheriff is entitled to reimbursement of all\nexpenses necessarily incurred in the execution of any mandate and in the\nprotection, presentation, transportation or sale of property.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8013__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payment in advance. A sheriff, whenever he deems it necessary, may\nrequire payment to him in advance to cover any or all expenses for which\nhe is entitled to reimbursement; advance payments made in connection\nwith a mandate or direction affecting property shall be repaid by the\nsheriff out of the proceeds of the sale of the property, if any.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>