<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8019"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8019"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8019"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8019/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8019/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8019/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8019/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8019">
        <num>8019</num>
        <heading>County clerks generally</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8019__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Application. The fees of a county\nclerk specified in this article shall supersede the fees allowed by any\nother statute for the same services, except in so far as the\nadministrative code of the city of New York sets forth different fees\nfor the city register of the city of New York and the county clerk of\nRichmond, and except that such fees do not include the block fees as set\nout in the Nassau county administrative code or the tax map number\nverification fees on instruments presented for recording or filing as\nset out in the Suffolk county administrative code, which are to be\ncharged in addition to the fees specified in this article. This\nsubdivision does not apply to the fees specified in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8019__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection 8021.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8019__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Legible copies. Whenever a paper or document, presented to a\ncounty clerk for filing or recording, is not legible or otherwise\nsuitable for copying or recording by the photocopying process, the\ncounty clerk may require a legible or suitable copy thereof along with\nsuch paper or document, and the same fees shall be payable for the copy\nas are payable for the paper or document.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8019__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notice to county clerk. A county clerk need not make an entry\nwhich is required by a court order unless proper notice is given to the\nclerk by a party to the action or a person legally interested therein.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8019__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Exemptions for state or city of New York. A clerk of a county\nwithin the city of New York shall not charge or receive any fee from the\ncity of New York or the state of New York or from any agency or officer\nof either acting in official capacity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8019__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Size of page and type. For purposes of this article, the size of\neach page accepted by a county clerk for recording and indexing shall\nnot exceed nine inches by fourteen inches, except that in the counties\nof Cattaraugus, Columbia, Delaware, Herkimer, Monroe and Otsego, the\nsize of the page shall not exceed eight and a half inches by fourteen\ninches, and every printed portion thereof shall be plainly printed in\nnot smaller than eight point type. The county clerk acting as recording\nofficer may in special circumstances accept a page exceeding the size or\nwith smaller print than that prescribed herein, on such terms and at\nsuch fee, subject to review by the supreme court, as he may deem\nappropriate, but the fee for such recording and indexing shall not be\nless than double the fees otherwise chargeable by law therefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8019__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Copies of records. The following fees, up to a maximum of forty\ndollars per record shall be payable to a county clerk or register for\ncopies of the records of the office except records filed under the\nuniform commercial code:\n  1. to prepare a copy of any paper or record on file in the office,\nexcept as otherwise provided, sixty-five cents per page with a minimum\nfee of one dollar thirty cents;\n  2. to certify a prepared copy of any record or paper on file,\nsixty-five cents per page with a minimum fee of five dollars twenty\ncents;\n  3. to prepare and certify a copy of any record or paper on file, one\ndollar twenty-five cents per page with a minimum fee of five dollars;\n  4. to prepare and certify a copy of a certificate of honorable\ndischarge, except as provided for in the military law, two dollars fifty\ncents; and\n  5. to prepare a copy of any paper or record on file in the office in a\nmedium other than paper, the actual cost of reproducing the record in\naccordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8019__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section eighty-seven\nof the public officers law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>