<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1344"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1344"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1344"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1344/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1344/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1344/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-1344/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1344">
        <num>1344</num>
        <heading>Filing, content and indexing of notice of pendency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1344. Filing, content and indexing of notice of pendency. 1. Filing.\nIn a case specified in section one thousand three hundred forty-three of\nthis article the notice of pendency shall be filed in the office of the\nclerk of any county where property affected is situated, before or after\nservice of a summons and at any time prior to judgment. Unless it has\nalready been filed in that county, the complaint shall be filed with the\nnotice of pendency.\n  2. Content, designation of index. A notice of pendency shall state the\nnames of the parties to the action, that the action is for forfeiture\npursuant to this article and a description of the property affected. A\nnotice of pendency filed with a clerk who maintains a block index shall\ncontain a designation of the number of each block on the land map of a\ncounty which is affected by the notice. A notice of pendency filed with\na clerk who does not maintain a block index shall contain a designation\nof the names of each defendant against whom the notice is directed to be\nindexed.\n  3. Indexing. Each county clerk with whom a notice of pendency is filed\nshall immediately record and index it against the blocks or names\ndesignated. A county clerk who does not maintain a block index shall\nindex a notice of pendency of an action for partition against the names\nof each claiming authority and each defendant not designated as wholly\nfictitious.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>