<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209">
        <num>209</num>
        <heading>War</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_209__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cause of action accruing in foreign country. Where a\ncause of action, whether originally accrued in favor of a resident or\nnon-resident of the state, accrued in a foreign country with which the\nUnited States or any of its allies were then or subsequently at war, or\nterritory then or subsequently occupied by the government of such\nforeign country, the time which elapsed between the commencement of the\nwar, or of such occupation, and the termination of hostilities with such\ncountry, or of such occupation, is not a part of the time within which\nthe action must be commenced. This section shall neither apply to nor in\nany manner affect an action brought pursuant to section six hundred\ntwenty-five of the banking law against a banking organization or against\nthe superintendent of financial services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Right of noncitizen. Where a person is unable to commence an\naction in the courts of the state because any party is a noncitizen\nsubject or citizen of a foreign country at war with the United States or\nany of its allies, whether the cause of action accrued during or prior\nto the war, the time which elapsed between the commencement of the war\nand the termination of hostilities with such country is not a part of\nthe time within which the action must be commenced.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Non-enemy in enemy country or enemy-occupied territory. Where a\nperson entitled to commence an action, other than a person entitled to\nthe benefits of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, is a resident of, or a sojourner in, a\nforeign country with which the United States or any of its allies are at\nwar, or territory occupied by the government of such foreign country,\nthe period of such residence or sojourn during which the war continues\nor the territory is so occupied is not a part of the time within which\nthe action must be commenced.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>