<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-I*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-I*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="214-I*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-I*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-I*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-I*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-I*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_214_I*2">
        <num>214-I*2</num>
        <heading>Action to recover damages for personal injury caused by contact with or exposure to toxic burn pits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 214-i. Action to recover damages for personal injury caused by\ncontact with or exposure to toxic burn pits. 1. Notwithstanding any\nprovision of law to the contrary, an action to recover damages for\npersonal injury caused by exposure to toxic burn pits while serving as a\nmember of the armed forces of the United States in Afghanistan, Bahrain,\nBurkina Faso, Cameroon, Chad, Diego Garcia, Djibouti, Egypt, Ethiopia,\nGabon, Ghana, Iraq, Jordan, Kenya, Kuwait, Kyrgyzstan, Libya, Mali,\nNiger, Nigeria, Oman, Pakistan, Philippines, Saudi Arabia, Somalia,\nSouth Sudan, Sudan, Syria, Tajikistan, Tunisia, Turkey, United Arab\nEmirates, Uzbekistan, and Yemen on or after August second, nineteen\nhundred ninety, may be commenced within three years from the date of the\ndiscovery of such injury, or within three years from the date when\nthrough the exercise of reasonable diligence the cause of such injury\nshould have been discovered, whichever is later.\n  2. For the purposes of this section, a personal injury includes, but\nshall not be limited to the following diseases: asthma that was\ndiagnosed after service in a country or territory listed, cancer of any\ntype, chronic bronchitis, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease,\nconstrictive bronchiolitis or obliterative bronchiolitis, emphysema,\ngranulomatous disease, interstitial lung disease, lymphoma, pleuritis,\npulmonary fibrosis, and sarcoidosis.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 214-i's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>