<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="214-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-214-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_214_D">
        <num>214-D</num>
        <heading>Limitations on certain actions against licensed engineers and architects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_214_D__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule three thousand two hundred eleven\nor subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_214_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule three thousand two hundred twelve of this\nchapter; provided, however, such motion shall not be granted if the\nmoving party is in default of any disclosure obligation as set forth in\nsubdivision four of this section.\n  6. No claim for personal injury, or wrongful death or property damage,\nor a cross or third-party claim for contribution or indemnification\narising out of an action for personal injury, wrongful death or property\ndamage may be asserted against a licensed architect, engineer, land\nsurveyor or landscape architect or such firm arising out of conduct by\nsuch licensed architect, engineer, land surveyor or landscape architect\nor such firm occurring more than ten years prior to the accrual of such\nclaim shall be commenced or interposed against any such licensed\narchitect, engineer, land surveyor or landscape architect or such firm\nunless it shall appear by and as an allegation in the complaint or\nnecessary moving papers that the claimant has complied with the\nrequirements of this section. Upon the commencement of such a proceeding\nor action or interposition of such cross or third-party claim, a county\nclerk shall not be entitled to collect an index number fee and such\naction, proceeding or cross or third-party claim shall retain the\npreviously assigned index number.  Such action, proceeding or cross or\nthird-party claim shall otherwise be governed by the provisions of this\nchapter.\n  7. The provisions of this section shall apply only to a licensed\narchitect, engineer, land surveyor or landscape architect or such firm\npracticing architecture, engineering, land surveying or landscape\narchitecture in the state of New York at the time the conduct complained\nof occurred and shall not apply to any person or entity, including but\nnot limited to corporations, which was not licensed as an architect,\nengineer, land surveyor or landscape architect or such firm in this\nstate or to a firm not lawfully practicing architecture, engineerin...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>