<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2221"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2221"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2221"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2221/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2221/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2221">
        <num>2221</num>
        <heading>Motion affecting prior order</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2221__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A motion for leave to\nrenew or to reargue a prior motion, for leave to appeal from, or to\nstay, vacate or modify, an order shall be made, on notice, to the judge\nwho signed the order, unless he or she is for any reason unable to hear\nit, except that:\n  1. if the order was made upon a default such motion may be made, on\nnotice, to any judge of the court; and\n  2. if the order was made without notice such motion may be made,\nwithout notice, to the judge who signed it, or, on notice, to any other\njudge of the court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2221__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Rules of the chief administrator of the courts. The chief\nadministrator may by rule exclude motions within a department, district\nor county from the operation of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2221__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this rule.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2221__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A motion made to other than a proper judge under this rule shall\nbe transferred to the proper judge.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2221__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A motion for leave to reargue:\n  1. shall be identified specifically as such;\n  2. shall be based upon matters of fact or law allegedly overlooked or\nmisapprehended by the court in determining the prior motion, but shall\nnot include any matters of fact not offered on the prior motion; and\n  3. shall be made within thirty days after service of a copy of the\norder determining the prior motion and written notice of its entry. This\nrule shall not apply to motions to reargue a decision made by the\nappellate division or the court of appeals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2221__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A motion for leave to renew:\n  1. shall be identified specifically as such;\n  2. shall be based upon new facts not offered on the prior motion that\nwould change the prior determination or shall demonstrate that there has\nbeen a change in the law that would change the prior determination; and\n  3. shall contain reasonable justification for the failure to present\nsuch facts on the prior motion.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2221__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A combined motion for leave to reargue and leave to renew shall\nidentify separately and support separately each item of relief sought.\nThe court, in determining a combined motion for leave to reargue and\nleave to renew, shall decide each part of the motion as if it were\nseparately made. If a motion for leave to reargue or leave to renew is\ngranted, the court may adhere to the determination on the original\nmotion or may alter that determination.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>