<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2306"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-2306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2306">
        <num>2306</num>
        <heading>Hospital records; medical records of department or bureau of a municipal corporation or of the state</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2306__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Transcript or reproduction.\nWhere a subpoena duces tecum is served upon a hospital, or upon a\ndepartment or bureau of a municipal corporation or of the state, or an\nofficer thereof, requiring the production of records relating to the\ncondition or treatment of a patient, a transcript or a full-sized\nlegible reproduction, certified as correct by the superintendent or head\nof the hospital, department or bureau or his assistant, or the officer,\nmay be produced unless otherwise ordered by a court. Such a subpoena\nshall be served at least three days before the time fixed for the\nproduction of the records unless otherwise ordered by a court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2306__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Delivery to clerk. Where a court has designated a clerk to receive\nrecords described in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2306__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, delivery may be made to him at or\nbefore the time fixed for their production. The clerk shall give a\nreceipt for the records and notify the person subpoenaed when they are\nno longer required. The records shall be delivered in a sealed envelope\nindicating the title of the action, the date fixed for production and\nthe name and address of the attorney appearing on the subpoena. They\nshall be available for inspection pursuant to the rules or order of the\ncourt.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>