<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3025"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3025"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3025"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3025/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3025/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3025/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3025/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3025">
        <num>3025</num>
        <heading>Amended and supplemental pleadings</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3025__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Amendments without\nleave. A party may amend his pleading once without leave of court within\ntwenty days after its service, or at any time before the period for\nresponding to it expires, or within twenty days after service of a\npleading responding to it.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3025__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Amendments and supplemental pleadings by leave. A party may amend\nhis or her pleading, or supplement it by setting forth additional or\nsubsequent transactions or occurrences, at any time by leave of court or\nby stipulation of all parties. Leave shall be freely given upon such\nterms as may be just including the granting of costs and continuances.\nAny motion to amend or supplement pleadings shall be accompanied by the\nproposed amended or supplemental pleading clearly showing the changes or\nadditions to be made to the pleading.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3025__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Amendment to conform to the evidence. The court may permit\npleadings to be amended before or after judgment to conform them to the\nevidence, upon such terms as may be just including the granting of costs\nand continuances.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3025__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Responses to amended or supplemental pleadings. Except where\notherwise prescribed by law or order of the court, there shall be an\nanswer or reply to an amended or supplemental pleading if an answer or\nreply is required to the pleading being amended or supplemented. Service\nof such an answer or reply shall be made within twenty days after\nservice of the amended or supplemental pleading to which it responds.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>