<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="306"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_306">
        <num>306</num>
        <heading>Proof of service</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_306__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Generally. Proof of service shall\nspecify the papers served, the person who was served and the date, time,\naddress, or, in the event there is no address, place and manner of\nservice, and set forth facts showing that the service was made by an\nauthorized person and in an authorized manner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_306__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Personal service. Whenever service is made pursuant to this\narticle by delivery of the summons to an individual, proof of service\nshall also include, in addition to any other requirement, a description\nof the person to whom it was so delivered, including, but not limited\nto, the process server's perception of the person's: gender, race, hair\ncolor, approximate age, approximate weight and height, and other\nidentifying features.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_306__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Other service. Where service is made pursuant to subdivision four\nof section three hundred eight of this chapter, proof of service shall\nalso specify the dates, addresses and the times of attempted service\npursuant to subdivisions one, two or three of such section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_306__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Form. Proof of service shall be in the form of a certificate if\nthe service is made by a sheriff or other authorized public officer, in\nthe form of an affidavit if made by any other person, or in the form of\na signed acknowledgement of receipt of a summons and complaint, or\nsummons and notice or notice of petition as provided for in section\n312-a of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_306__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Admission of service. A writing admitting service by the person to\nbe served is adequate proof of service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>