<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3405"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3405"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3405"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-3405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3405">
        <num>3405</num>
        <heading>Arbitration of certain claims</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  Rule 3405. Arbitration of certain claims. The chief judge of the court\nof appeals may promulgate rules for the arbitration of claims for the\nrecovery of a sum of money not exceeding six thousand dollars, exclusive\nof interest, pending in any court or courts except the civil court of\nthe city of New York, and not exceeding ten thousand dollars, exclusive\nof interest, pending in the civil court of the city of New York. Such\nrules must permit a jury trial de novo upon demand by any party\nfollowing the determination of the arbitrators and may require the\ndemander to pay the cost of arbitration; and shall also provide for all\nprocedures necessary to initiate, conduct and determine the arbitration.\nA judgment may be entered upon the arbitration award. The rules shall\nfurther provide for the recruitment and qualifications of the\narbitrators and for their compensation; except that such rules may\nauthorize use of judicial hearing officers as arbitrators. All expenses\nfor compensation, reimbursement and administration under this rule shall\nbe a state charge to be paid out of funds appropriated to the\nadministrative office for the courts for that purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>