<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4110-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4110-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4110-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4110-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4110-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4110-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4110-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4110_C">
        <num>4110-C</num>
        <heading>Trial jury; viewing of premises</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4110-c. Trial jury; viewing of premises. 1. When during the course\nof a trial the court is of the opinion that a viewing or observation by\nthe jury of the premises or place where alleged injuries to person or\nproperty were sustained in an accident or occurrence claimed to have\nbeen the cause thereof or of any other premises or place involved in the\ncase will be helpful to the jury in determining any material factual\nissue, it may in its discretion, at any time before the commencement of\nthe summations, order that the jury be conducted to such premises or\nplace for such purpose in accordance with the provisions of this\nsection.\n  2. In such case, the jury must be kept together throughout under the\nsupervision of an appropriate public servant or servants appointed by\nthe court, and the court itself must be present throughout. The parties\nto the action and counsel for them may as a matter of right be present\nthroughout, but such right may be waived.\n  3. The purpose of such an inspection is solely to permit visual\nobservation by the jury of the premises or place in question and neither\nthe court, the parties, counsel nor the jurors may engage in discussion\nor argumentation concerning the significance or implications of anything\nunder observation or concerning any issue in the case.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>