<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4213"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4213"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4213"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4213">
        <num>4213</num>
        <heading>Decision of the court</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4213__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Requests for findings. Before the\ncase is finally submitted, the court shall afford the parties an\nopportunity to submit requests for findings of fact. Each request shall\nbe numbered and so phrased that the court may conveniently pass upon it.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4213__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Form of decision. The decision of the court may be oral or in\nwriting and shall state the facts it deems essential. In any action\nbrought to recover damages for personal injury, injury to property, or\nwrongful death, a decision awarding damages shall specify the applicable\nelements of special and general damages upon which the award is based\nand the amount assigned to each element, including but not limited to\nmedical expenses, dental expenses, podiatric expenses, loss of earnings,\nimpairment of earning ability, and pain and suffering. In a medical,\ndental or podiatric malpractice action, commenced on or after July\ntwenty-sixth, two thousand three, the court's decision as to future\ndamages shall be itemized in accordance with subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4213__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule\nforty-one hundred eleven of this chapter. In any action brought to\nrecover damages for personal injury, injury to property or wrongful\ndeath, other than a medical, dental or podiatric malpractice action\ncommenced on or after July twenty-sixth, two thousand three, the court's\ndecision as to future damages shall be itemized in accordance with\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4213__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule forty-one hundred eleven of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4213__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Time for decision. The decision of the court shall be rendered\nwithin sixty days after the cause or matter is finally submitted or\nwithin sixty days after a motion under rule 4403, whichever is later,\nunless the parties agree to extend the time.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>