<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4312"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4312"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4312"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4312/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4312/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4312/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4312/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4312">
        <num>4312</num>
        <heading>Number of referees; qualifications</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  Rule 4312. Number of referees; qualifications. 1. A court may\ndesignate either one or three referees; provided, however, a judicial\nhearing officer may be designated a referee, in which case there shall\nbe only one referee. Except by consent of the parties, no person shall\nbe designated a referee unless he is an attorney admitted to practice in\nthe state and in good standing.  Where a referee may be designated by\nthe parties, they may designate any number of referees.\n  2. Except in matrimonial actions or where the reference is to a\njudicial hearing officer, a person to whom all the parties object may\nnot be designated as a referee. In matrimonial actions, only a judicial\nhearing officer or a special referee appointed by the chief\nadministrator of the courts may be designated to determine an issue. In\na matrimonial action the court shall not order a reference to a referee\nnominated by a party.\n  3. No person shall serve as referee who holds the position of court\nclerk, or clerk, secretary or stenographer to a judge; or who is the\npartner or clerk of an attorney for any party to the action or occupies\nthe same office with such attorney, except as provided in paragraph five\nof this rule.\n  4. A judge shall not serve as a referee in an action brought in a\ncourt of which he is a judge except by the written consent of the\nparties, and, in that case, he cannot receive any compensation as\nreferee.\n  5. In uncontested matrimonial actions, a court clerk, law secretary,\nor any other non-judicial employee of the court, who is an attorney in\ngood standing admitted to practice in the state, may be appointed by an\nadministrative judge to serve without fee as a referee for the purpose\nof hearing and reporting to the court.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>