<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4506"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4506"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4506"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-4506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4506">
        <num>4506</num>
        <heading>Eavesdropping evidence; admissibility; motion to suppress in certain cases</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4506__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person who was a sender or receiver of a telephonic or\ntelegraphic communication which was intentionally overheard or recorded\nby a person other than the sender or receiver thereof, without the\nconsent of the sender or receiver, by means of any instrument, device or\nequipment; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4506__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A party to a conversation or discussion which was intentionally\noverheard or recorded, without the consent of at least one party\nthereto, by a person not present thereat, by means of any instrument,\ndevice or equipment; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4506__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person against whom the overhearing or recording described in\nparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4506__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4506__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>was directed.\n  3. An aggrieved person who is a party in any civil trial, hearing or\nproceeding before any court, or before any department, officer, agency,\nregulatory body, or other authority of the state, or a political\nsubdivision thereof, may move to suppress the contents of any overheard\nor recorded communication, conversation or discussion or evidence\nderived therefrom, on the ground that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4506__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The communication, conversation or discussion was unlawfully\noverheard or recorded; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4506__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The eavesdropping warrant under which it was overheard or recorded\nis insufficient on its face; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4506__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The eavesdropping was not done in conformity with the\neavesdropping warrant.\n  4. The motion prescribed in subdivision three of this section must be\nmade before the judge or justice who issued the eavesdropping warrant.\nIf no eavesdropping warrant was issued, such motion must be made before\na justice of the supreme court of the judicial district in which the\ntrial, hearing or proceeding is pending. The aggrieved person must\nallege in his motion papers that an overheard or recorded communication,\nconversation or discussion, or evidence derived therefrom, is subject to\nsuppression under subdivision three of this section, and that such\ncommunication, conversation or discussion, or evidence, may be used\nagainst him in the civil trial, hearing or proceeding in which he is a\nparty. The motion must be made prior to the commencement of such trial,\nhearing or proceeding, unless there was no opportunity to make such\nmotion or the aggrieved person was not aware of the grounds of the\nmotion. If the motion is granted, the contents of the overheard or\nrecorded communication, conversation or discussion or evidence derived\ntherefrom, may not be received in evidence in any trial, hearing or\nproceeding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>