<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5003-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5003-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5003-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5003-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5003-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5003-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5003-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5003_B">
        <num>5003-B</num>
        <heading>Nondisclosure agreements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5003-b. Nondisclosure agreements. Notwithstanding any other law to\nthe contrary, for any claim or cause of action, whether arising under\ncommon law, equity, or any provision of law, the factual foundation for\nwhich involves discrimination, in violation of laws prohibiting\ndiscrimination, including but not limited to, article fifteen of the\nexecutive law, in resolving, by agreed judgment, stipulation, decree,\nagreement to settle, assurance of discontinuance or otherwise, no\nemployer, its officer or employee shall have the authority to include or\nagree to include in such resolution any term or condition that would\nprevent the disclosure of the underlying facts and circumstances to the\nclaim or action unless the condition of confidentiality is the\nplaintiff's preference. Any such term or condition must be provided to\nall parties, and the plaintiff shall have twenty-one days to consider\nsuch term or condition. If after twenty-one days such term or condition\nis the plaintiff's preference, such preference shall be memorialized in\nan agreement signed by all parties. For a period of at least seven days\nfollowing the execution of such agreement, the plaintiff may revoke the\nagreement, and the agreement shall not become effective or be\nenforceable until such revocation period has expired.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>