<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5020"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5020"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-02-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5020"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5020/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5020/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5020/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5020/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5020">
        <num>5020</num>
        <heading>Satisfaction-piece</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Generally. When a person entitled to\nenforce a judgment receives satisfaction or partial satisfaction of the\njudgment, he shall execute and file with the proper clerk pursuant to\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 5021, a satisfaction-piece or partial\nsatisfaction-piece acknowledged in the form required to entitle a deed\nto be recorded, which shall set forth the book and page where the\njudgment is docketed. A copy of the satisfaction-piece or partial\nsatisfaction-piece filed with the clerk shall be mailed to the judgment\ndebtor by the person entitled to enforce the judgment within ten days\nafter the date of filing.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Attorney of record. Within ten years after the entry of a judgment\nthe attorney of record or the attorney named on the docket for the\njudgment creditor may execute a satisfaction-piece or a partial\nsatisfaction-piece, but if his authority was revoked before it was\nexecuted, the judgment may nevertheless be enforced against a person who\nhad actual notice of the revocation before a payment on the judgment was\nmade or a purchase of property bound by it was effected.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When a judgment for less than five thousand dollars is fully\nsatisfied, if the person required to execute and file with the proper\nclerk pursuant to subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section fails or\nrefuses to do so within twenty days after receiving full satisfaction,\nthen the judgment creditor shall be subject to a penalty of one hundred\ndollars recoverable by the judgment debtor pursuant to section\nseventy-two hundred two of this chapter or article eighteen of either\nthe New York City civil court act, uniform district court act or uniform\ncity court act. When a judgment for five thousand dollars or more is\nfully satisfied, if the person required to execute and file with the\nproper clerk pursuant to subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section fails\nor refuses to do so within twenty days after receiving full\nsatisfaction, then the judgment creditor shall be subject to a penalty\nof five hundred dollars recoverable by the judgment debtor pursuant to\nsection seventy-two hundred two of this chapter or article eighteen of\neither the New York city civil court act, uniform district court act or\nuniform city court act; provided, however, that such penalties shall not\nbe recoverable when a city with a population greater than one million\npersons is the judgment creditor, unless such judgment creditor shall\nfail to execute and file a satisfaction-piece with the proper clerk\npursuant to subdivisions</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section within twenty days\nafter having been served by the judgment debtor with a written demand\ntherefor by certified mail, return receipt requested.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a transcript of the docket of a judgment has been docketed\nin any other county of the state pursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\n5018, the person required to execute and file with the proper clerk\npursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof shall, upon receiving full\nsatisfaction, file a certificate of the clerk of the county in which the\njudgment was entered, in accordance with subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5020__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\n5021, with the clerks of all other counties in which such judgment has\nbeen docketed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>