<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5529"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5529"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5529"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5529/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5529/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5529/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5529/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5529">
        <num>5529</num>
        <heading>Form of briefs and appendices</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5529__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Form of reproduction;\nsize; paper; binding.\n  1. Briefs and appendices shall be reproduced by any method that\nproduces a permanent, legible, black image on white paper. Paper shall\nbe of a quality approved by the chief administrator of the courts.\n  2. Briefs and appendices shall be on white paper eleven inches along\nthe bound edge by eight and one-half inches.\n  3. An appellate court may by rule applicable to practice therein\nprescribe the size of margins and type of briefs and appendices and the\nline spacing and the length of briefs.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5529__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Numbering. Pages of briefs shall be numbered consecutively. Pages\nof appendices shall be separately numbered consecutively, each number\npreceded by the letter A.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5529__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Page headings. The subject matter of each page of the appendix\nshall be stated at the top thereof, except that in the case of papers\nother than testimony, the subject matter of the paper may be stated at\nthe top of the first page of each paper, together with the page numbers\nof the first and last pages thereof. In the case of testimony, the name\nof the witness, by whom he was called and whether the testimony is\ndirect, cross, redirect or recross examination shall be stated at the\ntop of each page.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5529__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Quotations. Asterisks or other appropriate means shall be used to\nindicate omissions in quoted excerpts. Reference shall be made to the\nsource of the excerpts quoted. Where an excerpt in the appendix is\ntestimony of a witness quoted from the record the beginning of each page\nof the transcript shall be indicated by parenthetical insertion of the\ntranscript page number.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5529__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Citations of decisions. New York decisions shall be cited from the\nofficial reports, if any. All other decisions shall be cited from the\nofficial reports, if any, and also from the National Reporter System if\nthey are there reported. Decisions not reported officially or in the\nNational Reporter System shall be cited from the most available source.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5529__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Questions and answers. The answer to a question in the appendix\nshall not begin a new paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>