<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5601"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5601"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5601"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-5601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5601">
        <num>5601</num>
        <heading>Appeals to the court of appeals as of right</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5601__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Dissent. An\nappeal may be taken to the court of appeals as of right in an action\noriginating in the supreme court, a county court, a surrogate's court,\nthe family court, the court of claims or an administrative agency, from\nan order of the appellate division which finally determines the action,\nwhere there is a dissent by at least two justices on a question of law\nin favor of the party taking such appeal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5601__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Constitutional grounds. An appeal may be taken to the court of\nappeals as of right:\n  1. from an order of the appellate division which finally determines an\naction where there is directly involved the construction of the\nconstitution of the state or of the United States; and\n  2. from a judgment of a court of record of original instance which\nfinally determines an action where the only question involved on the\nappeal is the validity of a statutory provision of the state or of the\nUnited States under the constitution of the state or of the United\nStates.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5601__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>From order granting new trial or hearing, upon stipulation for\njudgment absolute. An appeal may be taken to the court of appeals as of\nright in an action originating in the supreme court, a county court, a\nsurrogate's court, the family court, the court of claims or an\nadministrative agency, from an order of the appellate division granting\nor affirming the granting of a new trial or hearing where the appellant\nstipulates that, upon affirmance, judgment absolute shall be entered\nagainst him.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5601__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Based upon nonfinal determination of appellate division. An appeal\nmay be taken to the court of appeals as of right from a final judgment\nentered in a court of original instance, from a final determination of\nan administrative agency or from a final arbitration award, or from an\norder of the appellate division which finally determines an appeal from\nsuch a judgment or determination, where the appellate division has made\nan order on a prior appeal in the action which necessarily affects the\njudgment, determination or award and which satisfies the requirements of\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5601__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or of paragraph one of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5601__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>except that of\nfinality.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>