<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-6511"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-6511"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-11-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6511"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-6511/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-6511/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-6511/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-6511/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6511">
        <num>6511</num>
        <heading>Filing, content and indexing of notice of pendency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6511__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nFiling. In a case specified in section 6501, the notice of pendency\nshall be filed in the office of the clerk of any county where property\naffected is situated, before or after service of summons and at any time\nprior to judgment. Unless it has already been filed in that county, the\ncomplaint shall be filed with the notice of pendency.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6511__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Content; designation of index. A notice of pendency shall state\nthe names of the parties to the action, including the name and telephone\nnumber of the mortgage servicer for a foreclosing party involving a\nmortgage foreclosure of a one- to four-family residential property, the\nobject of the action and a description of the property affected. A\nnotice of pendency filed with a clerk who maintains a block index shall\ncontain a designation of the number of each block on the land map of the\ncounty which is affected by the notice. Except in an action for\npartition a notice of pendency filed with a clerk who does not maintain\na block index shall contain a designation of the names of each defendant\nagainst whom the notice is directed to be indexed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6511__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Indexing. Each county clerk with whom a notice of pendency is\nfiled shall immediately record it and index it against the blocks or\nnames designated. A county clerk who does not maintain a block index\nshall index a notice of pendency of an action for partition against the\nnames of each plaintiff and each defendant not designated as wholly\nfictitious.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6511__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Electronic indexing. A county clerk may adopt a new indexing\nsystem utilizing electro-mechanical, electronic or any other method he\ndeems suitable for maintaining the indexes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>