<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8016"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8016"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8016"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8016/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8016/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8016/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-8016/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8016">
        <num>8016</num>
        <heading>Clerks of courts of record generally</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8016__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fees of clerks in\nactions.  Except where a greater fee is allowed by another statute for\nthe same service, each clerk of a court of record, except the clerk of\nthe civil court of the city of New York, except a county clerk, except\nclerks of the family courts, and except the clerks of the district\ncourts, is entitled for the services specified to the following fees,\npayable in advance:\n  1. upon the trial of an action, or the hearing, upon the merits, of a\nspecial proceeding, from the party bringing it on, one dollar;\n  2. for entering final judgment, including the filing of the\njudgment-roll and a copy of the judgment to insert therein, fifty cents,\nand fifteen cents in addition for each folio, exceeding five, contained\nin the judgment;\n  3. for entering any order or an interlocutory judgment, fifty cents,\nand fifteen cents in addition for each folio, exceeding five;\n  4. for a certified or other copy of an order, record or other paper in\nan action brought or transferred to the court of which he is clerk and\nentered or filed in his office, ten cents for each folio;\n  5. for a certified transcript of the docket of a judgment, fifty\ncents; and\n  6. for filing a transcript, or docketing or redocketing a judgment\nthereupon, fifty cents, and fifty cents in addition for each defendant,\nexceeding two.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8016__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Certifying judgment-roll on appeal. Where, on an appeal from a\njudgment or order, a party shall present to the clerk of a court of\nrecord, except the clerk of the civil court of the city of New York,\nexcept a county clerk, except clerks of the family courts, and except\nthe clerks of the district courts, a printed copy of the judgment-roll\nor order appealed from, it shall be the duty of the clerk to compare and\ncertify the same, for which service he shall be entitled to be paid at\nthe rate of fifty cents per page or portion thereof, unless a greater\nfee is allowed by another statute.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>