<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CVP">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-907"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-907"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="907"/>
          <FRBRname value="CVP"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cvp/section-907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_907">
        <num>907</num>
        <heading>Orders in conduct of class actions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  Rule 907. Orders in conduct of class actions. In the conduct of class\nactions the court may make appropriate orders:\n  1. determining the course of proceedings or prescribing measures to\nprevent undue repetition or complication in the presentation of evidence\nor argument;\n  2. requiring, for the protection of the members of the class, or\notherwise for the fair conduct of the action, that notice be given in\nsuch manner as the court may direct to some or all of the members of any\nstep in the action, or of the proposed extent of the judgment, or of the\nopportunity of members to signify whether they consider the\nrepresentation fair and adequate, or to appear and present claims or\ndefenses, or otherwise to come into the action;\n  3. imposing conditions on the representative parties or on\nintervenors;\n  4. requiring that the pleadings be amended to eliminate therefrom\nallegations as to representation of absent persons, and that the action\nproceed accordingly;\n  5. directing that a money judgment favorable to the class be paid\neither in one sum, whether forthwith or within such period as the court\nmay fix, or in such installments as the court may specify;\n  6. dealing with similar procedural matters.\n  The orders may be altered or amended as may be desirable from time to\ntime.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>