<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-05-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_*2">
        <num>*2</num>
        <heading>Emergency medical transportation services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each emergency medical transportation services provider that\nreceives medical assistance reimbursement processed through the state\nMedicaid payment system, the department of health shall determine the\nratio of such provider's state-processed reimbursement to the total such\nreimbursement made during each quarter of the applicable calendar year,\nexpressed as a percentage;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each such provider, the department of health shall multiply\nthe percentage obtained pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision by\none-quarter of the applicable aggregate amount specified in the opening\nparagraph of this subdivision. The result of such calculation shall\nrepresent the "emergency medical transportation service supplemental\npayment" and shall be paid expeditiously to such provider on a quarterly\nbasis;\n  2. The amount disbursed to emergency medical transportation services\nproviders whose area of operation is within the city of New York will be\ntwenty-five percent of the applicable aggregate amount, with the\nremaining seventy-five percent to be disbursed to all other emergency\nmedical transportation services providers.\n  3. If all necessary approvals under federal law and regulation are not\nobtained to receive federal financial participation in the payments\nauthorized by this section, payments under this section shall be made in\nan aggregate amount not to exceed two million dollars for two thousand\nsix, three million dollars for two thousand seven, three million dollars\nfor two thousand eight, three million dollars for the period May first,\ntwo thousand fourteen through March thirty-first, two thousand fifteen,\nand three million dollars annually beginning with the period April\nfirst, two thousand fifteen through March thirty-first, two thousand\nsixteen. In such case, the multiplier set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of this section shall be deemed to be two million\ndollars or three million dollars as applicable to the annual period.\n  4. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of section three\nhundred sixty-eight-a of this title, or of any other law, to the\ncontrary, the department of health shall pay one hundred per centum of\nthe non-federal share of any payments made pursuant to this section.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 367-s's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>