<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-104-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-104-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="104-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-104-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-104-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-104-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-104-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_104_B">
        <num>104-B</num>
        <heading>Liens for public assistance and care on claims and suits for personal injuries</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_104_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The person, firm, corporation or insurance carrier, having\nnotice that a social services official has served and filed a notice of\nlien, and intending to make payment on the personal injury claim upon\nwhich the lien was filed, shall notify the social services official by\ncertified or registered mail, at least ten days prior to the date such\npayment is proposed to be made, of the amount and date thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this section, the\nsocial services official shall have the right to serve and file by\ncertified or registered mail, within five days after receipt of such\nnotice, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays, an amended notice of\nlien to include the amount of public assistance and care furnished to\nthe recipient after the date such official served and filed the notice\nof lien or the last previous amendment thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person, firm, corporation or insurance carrier that fails to\ngive the notice required by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall be\nliable to the social services official to the same extent that it would\nhave been liable had such notice been given and the social services\nofficial had filed the amended notice of lien provided for in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_104_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n  6. Such lien may be enforced by action against those alleged to be\nliable for such injuries, as aforesaid, by the local public welfare\nofficial in any court of appropriate jurisdiction.\n  7. The aforesaid lien shall be valid and effective, when the notice\nthereof and the statement are served and filed as aforesaid, and shall\ncontinue until released and discharged by the local public welfare\nofficial by an instrument in writing and filed in the said county\nclerk's office, and no release, payment, discharge or satisfaction of\nany such claim, demand, right of action, suit or counterclaim shall be\nvalid or effective against such lien.\n  8. The county clerk shall, at the expense of the county, provide a\nsuitable book with proper index, to be called the public welfare lien\ndocket, in which he shall enter the names of the public welfare official\nand the recipient, the date and place of the accident and the name or\nnames of those alleged to be liable for such injuries, as aforesaid.\n  9. The provisions of this section to the contrary notwithstanding, the\nlien herein created shall be subject and subordinate to the lien on the\namount recovered by verdict, report, decision, judgment, award or\ndecree, settlement or compromise, of any attorney or attorneys retained\nby any such injured person to prosecute his claim for damages for\npersonal injuries, having or acquiring by virtue of such retainer a lien\non the cause of action of any such injured person, or on the verdict,\nreport, decision, judgment, decree made in, or any settlement or\ncompromise of, any such action or claim for damages for personal\ninjuries.\n  10. The provisions of this section to the contrary notwithstanding,\nthe lien herein created shall be subordinate to the lien of any hospital\nclaimed under and to the extent recognized by section one hundred\neighty-nine of the lien law, but only for treatment, care and\nmaintenance given, prior to or in excess of the public...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>