<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="111"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_111">
        <num>111</num>
        <heading>Functions of the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 111.  Functions of the department.  To assist welfare departments to\ncarry out their responsibilities, powers and duties to enforce the\nliability of persons for the support of certain of their dependents who\nare applicants for or recipients of public assistance or care or who are\nin receipt of child support services pursuant to section one hundred\neleven-g of this chapter, the department shall:\n  1.  Continue to act as, and perform the functions of, state\ninformation agent for the purposes of the uniform interstate family\nsupport act of this state (article 5-B of the family court act) and\nreciprocal laws of other states.\n  2.  As required by section three hundred seventy-two-a, aid in the\nlocation of deserting parents and, for such purpose, operate a central\nregistry of deserting parents, obtain and transmit pertinent information\nand data from public officials and agencies and assist in the training\nof local personnel employed to locate such parents.\n  3.  Stimulate and encourage cooperation, through the holding of\nmeetings and the exchange of information, between and among public\nofficials, law enforcement agencies and courts having powers and duties\nrelating to the enforcement of the liability of persons for the support\nof indigent members of their families, including cooperation with public\nofficials, agencies and courts of other states.\n  4.  Upon request, or when required to do so by other provisions of\nlaw, advise such officials in the performance of their duties\nhereinabove referred to.\n  5.  Develop or assist in the development of appropriate forms, guides,\nmanuals, handbooks and other material which may be necessary or useful\neffectively to accomplish the foregoing and the purposes therefor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>