<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-131-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_Q">
        <num>131-Q</num>
        <heading>Electronic payment file transfer system pilot project</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131-q. Electronic payment file transfer system pilot project. * 1.\nThe commissioner is empowered to authorize the city social services\ndistrict of the city of New York to continue the pilot project for the\ndesign, development, implementation and operation of an electronic\npayment file transfer system, in accordance with regulations of the\ndepartment, as an alternative means of delivery of grants and allowances\nto public assistance recipients.\n  * NB Expired July 1, 1984\n  2. The city social services district is authorized to initiate\nactivities to prepare for a city-wide conversion to the electronic\npayment file transfer system provided, however, the department shall\nconduct a hearing to elicit information concerning the effectiveness of\nsuch system and the impact of such system upon recipients, and such\nother matters as the department may deem relevant. Following such\nhearing, the commissioner may authorize city-wide implementation of such\nsystem.\n  3. A recipient residing in the city social services district in a\ngeographical area where the electronic payment file transfer system is\nin operation shall be required to receive his public assistance grants\nand allowances at a location designated by the social services district.\nA recipient who is subject to the provisions of this chapter relating to\nwork requirements shall remain subject to such provisions regardless of\nthe location where he receives his public assistance grants and\nallowances.\n  4. The provisions of subdivision one of this section shall expire on,\nand be of no further force and effect after July first, nineteen hundred\neighty-four.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>