<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-133"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-133"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-05-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="133"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_133">
        <num>133</num>
        <heading>Temporary preinvestigation emergency needs assistance or care</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 133. Temporary preinvestigation emergency needs assistance or care.\nUpon application for public assistance or care under this chapter, the\nlocal social services district shall notify the applicant in writing of\nthe availability of a monetary grant adequate to meet emergency needs\nassistance or care and shall, at such time, determine whether such\nperson is in immediate need. If it shall appear that a person is in\nimmediate need, emergency needs assistance or care shall be granted\npending completion of an investigation. The written notification\nrequired by this section shall inform such person of a right to an\nexpedited hearing when emergency needs assistance or care is denied. A\npublic assistance applicant who has been denied emergency needs\nassistance or care must be given reason for such denial in a written\ndetermination which sets forth the basis for such denial. Nothing in\nthis section shall be construed to require the social services district\nor any state agency to provide medical assistance, except as otherwise\nrequired by title eleven of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>