<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-142-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-142-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="142-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-142-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-142-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-142-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-142-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142_A">
        <num>142-A</num>
        <heading>Federal economic opportunity act grants or payments; effect on eligibility for certain public assistance or care</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 142-a. Federal economic opportunity act grants or payments; effect\non eligibility for certain public assistance or care.\n  Any inconsistent provisions of titles ten and eleven of article five,\nother provisions of this chapter, or of any other law notwithstanding,\nin determining the need for public assistance or care under such titles:\n  1. Any grant made to a family under title III of the federal economic\nopportunity act of nineteen hundred sixty-four shall not be regarded as\nincome or resources of such family in determining the need of any member\nthereof for such public assistance or care.\n  2. The first eighty-five dollars plus one-half of the excess over\neighty-five dollars of payments made to or on behalf of any person for\nor with respect to any month under title I or II of the federal economic\nopportunity act of nineteen hundred sixty-four or any program assisted\nunder such title shall not be regarded as income or resources of such\nperson in determining his need for such public assistance or care, or as\nincome or resources of any other individual in determining such other\nindividual's need for such public assistance or care; but any amount\nmade available to or for the benefit of such other individual from the\nexcess of the amounts exempted hereby may be considered in determining\nthe eligibility of such other individual for such public assistance or\ncare.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>