<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="143-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-143-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_143_C">
        <num>143-C</num>
        <heading>Avoidance of abuses in connection with rent security deposits</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_143_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By means of an appropriate agreement between the landlord and the\nsocial services official, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_143_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By depositing money in an escrow account, not under the control of\nthe landlord or his agent, subject to the terms and conditions of an\nagreement between the landlord and the social services official in such\nform as the department may require or approve provided, however, that\nthis option shall not be used in instances where recipients reside in\npublic housing.\n  2. Except as expressly provided in subdivision three of this section,\nit shall be against the public policy of the state for a social services\nofficial to pay money to a landlord to be held as a security deposit\nagainst the non-payment of rent or for damages by a public assistance\nrecipient, or to issue a grant to a recipient of public assistance\ntherefor.\n  3. When, however, in the judgment of a social services official\nhousing accommodations available in a particular area are insufficient\nto properly accommodate recipients of public assistance in need of\nhousing, and in order to secure such housing it is essential that he pay\nmoney to landlords to be held as security deposits against the\nnon-payment of rent or for damages by public assistance recipients, or\nto issue grants to recipients of public assistance therefor, such social\nservices official may pay or furnish funds for such security deposits\nuntil sufficient housing accommodations are available in the particular\narea to properly accommodate recipients of public assistance in need of\nhousing. Social services officials shall not pay or furnish such funds\nin instances where recipients reside in public housing.  Landlords\nreceiving such security deposits shall comply with the provisions of\narticle seven of the general obligations law. Such cash security\ndeposits shall be subject to assignment to the local social services\nofficial by the recipients of public assistance or care. Any social\nservices official paying or furnishing funds for security deposits in\naccordance with the provisions of this subdivision shall make diligen...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>