<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="144-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-144-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_144_A">
        <num>144-A</num>
        <heading>Information to be given to officials of the department and of social services districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 144-a. Information to be given to officials of the department and of\nsocial services districts. Any inconsistent provision of law\nnotwithstanding, if requested by an authorized representative of the\ndepartment or by an official of any town, city or county who is\nresponsible for administering a program authorized by this chapter, the\nofficials of any banking or financial organization or institution doing\nbusiness in the state whether chartered under state law, federal law, or\nthe laws of another jurisdiction, shall furnish to such governmental\nofficials such information as such officials have as to whether any\npresent applicant for or recipient of any assistance, care or services\nauthorized by this chapter, has or had funds, securities or other\nproperty on deposit or in the custody of such banking or financial\norganization or institution, and the amount or probable value thereof.\nSuch information shall be provided, to the extent practicable, in the\nformat specified by such governmental officials (except that any banking\nor financial institution may discharge its obligation by supplying such\nmatching information on cartridge, tape or diskette media in the\nAmerican National Standard Code for Information Interchange file\nformat).  These provisions shall be inclusive of and in addition to the\nprovisions of section four of the banking law and may be administered\nand enforced in any manner consistent with the provisions of this\nchapter or in any other manner authorized or permitted by the laws and\ncourts of this state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>