<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-152"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-152"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="152"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-152/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-152/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-152/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-152/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_152">
        <num>152</num>
        <heading>Payments to the New York public welfare association; attendance at conventions of public welfare officials</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 152. Payments to the New York public welfare association; attendance\nat conventions of public welfare officials.  The legislative body of a\ncounty or city is hereby authorized to include annually in the\nappropriation made for public assistance and care and to raise by\ntaxation the sum necessary to meet the actual and necessary expenses of\nmaintaining and continuing the New York public welfare association for\nthe purpose of devising practical ways and means for obtaining greater\neconomy and efficiency in the administration of public assistance and\ncare, and for the expenses incurred by public welfare officials and\nemployees in attending meetings of public welfare officials.\nSuperintendents and matrons of public homes, county and city public\nwelfare officials and deputies and agents designated by the public\nwelfare officials are authorized to attend the midwinter and annual\nconventions of public welfare officials.  The necessary expenses in\nconnection with such attendance shall be paid from public welfare funds.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>