<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-157"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-157"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="157"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-157/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-157/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-157/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-157/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_157">
        <num>157</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 157. Definitions.  As used in this title.  1. Safety net assistance\nmeans allowances pursuant to section one hundred thirty-one-a of this\narticle for all support, maintenance and need, and costs of suitable\ntraining in a trade to enable a person to become self-supporting,\nfurnished eligible needy persons in accordance with applicable\nprovisions of law, by a municipal corporation, or a town where safety\nnet assistance is a town charge, to persons or their dependents in their\nabode or habitation whenever possible and includes such relief granted\nto veterans under existing laws but does not include hospital or\ninstitutional care, except as otherwise provided in this subdivision, or\nfamily assistance or medical assistance for needy persons granted under\ntitles ten and eleven of this article, respectively, or aid to persons\nreceiving federal supplemental security income payments and/or\nadditional state payments. Safety net assistance may also be provided in\na family home or boarding home, operated in compliance with the\nregulations of the department, and on and after January first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-four, in facilities in which a person is receiving\nfamily care or residential care, as those terms are used in title six of\nthis article, and to persons receiving care in a facility supervised by\nthe office of alcoholism and substance abuse services or in a\nresidential facility for the mentally disabled approved, licensed or\noperated by the office of mental health or the office for people with\ndevelopmental disabilities, other than those facilities defined in\nsections 7.17 and 13.17 of the mental hygiene law, in a developmental\ncenter facility operated by the office for people with developmental\ndisabilities or residential care centers for adults operated by the\noffice of mental health, when such type of care is deemed necessary.\nPayments to such homes and facilities for care and maintenance provided\nby them shall be at rates established pursuant to law and regulations of\nthe department. The department, however, shall not establish rates of\npayment to such homes or facilities without approval of the director of\nthe budget.\n  2. State aid means payments to a municipal corporation by the state\nfor home relief furnished in accordance with this title.\n  3. Municipal corporation shall mean a county or city except a county\nwholly within a city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>