<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-173"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-173"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="173"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-173/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-173/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-173/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-173/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_173">
        <num>173</num>
        <heading>Election to administer veteran assistance by county public welfare district; organization</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 173. Election to administer veteran assistance by county public\nwelfare district; organization. 1. When a majority of the veteran\norganizations in a county, by and through their respective county\ndivisions, file with the clerk of the board of the supervisors of the\ncounty, a petition addressed to the board of supervisors of the county\nrequesting that veteran assistance be administered by such county, the\nboard of supervisors may, by resolution passed by a majority vote,\nestablish a division or bureau, or direct that a division or bureau be\nestablished, within the county department of public welfare, and under\nthe direction of the county commissioner of public welfare, for the\npurpose of administering veteran assistance.\n  2. In the event that the county board of supervisors shall pass such a\nresolution, it shall also authorize and direct the county commissioner\nof public welfare to appoint a veteran, as herein defined, as deputy\ncommissioner or director of the veteran assistance division or bureau,\nas the case may be.\n  3. The county commissioner shall transfer to the veteran assistance\ndivision or bureau so much of the staff of the county welfare department\nas may be necessary or practicable to administer and execute the\nfunctions, powers and duties assigned to such division or bureau.\nOfficers and employees shall be transferred without further examination\nor qualification and they shall retain their respective civil service\nclassification and status. The civil service qualifications for all\npositions in the veteran assistance division or bureau shall be the same\nas required for the same or similar positions in the other divisions or\nbureaus of the county department of welfare, except that the\nqualifications for the position of the deputy commissioner or director,\nas the case may be, shall also require that he be a veteran.\n  4. The salaries or compensation paid to employees of the veteran\nassistance division or bureau shall be subject to reimbursement by the\nstate under the same terms and conditions as are applicable to other\nemployees of the county department of public welfare under the\nprovisions of this chapter.\n  5. Upon recommendation of the county commissioner of public welfare,\nthe county board of supervisors may authorize, by resolution passed by a\nmajority vote, the veteran assistance division or bureau to administer,\nin addition to veteran assistance, such other forms or categories of\npublic assistance and care as may be practicable or necessary, provided\nthat sufficient qualified staff shall be available for transfer or\nassignment to the veteran assistance division or bureau to execute and\nperform the additional functions and duties so assigned to such division\nor bureau.\n  6. The board of supervisors may also authorize the commissioner of\npublic welfare to establish and operate a branch of the veteran\nassistance division or bureau in each or any major population center in\nthe county.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>