<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2">
        <num>2</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subparagraph three of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision two of section three hundred sixty-six, paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision four of section three hundred sixty-six, subdivisions one\nthrough five of section three hundred sixty-six-a, subdivision seven of\nsection three hundred sixty-six-a, and section three hundred\nsixty-eight-c of this chapter and where the context thereof clearly\nrequires otherwise, department means the state department of social\nservices.\n  2. Board means the state board of social welfare as continued by the\nexecutive law.\n  6. Commissioner means the state commissioner of social services,\nprovided however that for purposes of titles eleven, eleven-A and\neleven-B of article five of this chapter, commissioner means the state\ncommissioner of health, except that in clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subparagraph three\nof paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section three hundred sixty-six\nof this chapter and where the context thereof clearly requires\notherwise, commissioner means the state commissioner of social services.\n  7. Social services district means a city or county social services\ndistrict as constituted by section sixty-one.\n  8. County commissioner of social services shall mean the county\nofficer, board or commission, by whatever title known, having authority\nto give the public assistance and care for the administration of which a\ncounty social services district is responsible.\n  9. City commissioner of social services shall mean the city officer,\nboard or commission, by whatever title known, having authority to give\nthe public assistance and care for the administration of which a city\nsocial services district is responsible.\n  10. Commissioner of social services shall mean a city or county\ncommissioner of social services.\n  14. Social services official shall mean a county commissioner of\nsocial services, a city commissioner of social services, a town social\nservices officer or city social services officer to whom the power or\nduty referred to is assigned under the provisions of this chapter. In\nany law where reference is made by any title to an official charged with\nthe duty of caring for the poor in a town, city or county, it shall be\nunderstood as referring to the one of the above mentioned social\nservices officials on whom the power or duty referred to is conferred\nunder the provisions of this chapter.\n  15. Public home means an adult care facility or a residential health\ncare facility operated by a social services district. In any law where\nreference is made by any name to an almshouse maintained at public\nexpense, it shall be construed as referring to a public home.\n  16. Legislative body means the board or boards empowered to make\nappropriations for public assistance and care in a county, town or city.\n  17. Social services department means the divis...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is under the age of eighteen; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is under the age of twenty-one, entered foster care prior to\nhis/her eighteenth birthday and remains in care, and who:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is a member of an Indian tribe, or\n  (ii) is eligible for membership in an Indian tribe, or\n  (iii) is the biological child of a member of an Indian tribe and is\nresiding on or is domiciled within an Indian reservation.\n  * 37. "Comprehensive psychiatric emergency program" shall have the\nmeaning defined in section 1.03 of the mental hygiene law.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2027\n  38. When used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the\nfollowing meanings, unless otherwise expressly stated or unless the\ncontext or subject matter requires a different interpretation:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Medicaid" or "medical assistance" means title eleven of article\nfive of this chapter and the program thereunder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Family health plus" means title eleven-D of article five of this\nchapter and the program thereunder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Child health plus" means title one-A of article twenty-five of\nthe public health law and the program thereunder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Medicaid managed care" means Medicaid provided under section\nthree hundred sixty-four-j of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Medicaid fee-for-service" means Medicaid provided other than\nunder Medicaid managed care.\n  39. "Mental illness" shall have the same meaning as defined in section\n1.03 of the mental hygiene law.\n  40. "Developmental disability" shall have the same meaning as defined\nin section 1.03 of the mental hygiene law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>