<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-251"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-251"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="251"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-251/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-251/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-251/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-251/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_251">
        <num>251</num>
        <heading>Federal aid; state plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 251. Federal aid; state plan. 1. The department shall submit the\nplan required by title six of the federal social security act to the\ndepartment of health, education and welfare for approval pursuant to\nsuch title and act, so that the state may receive federal aid under such\ntitle.  The department shall act for the state in any negotiations\nrelative to the submission and approval of such plan and may make any\narrangement not inconsistent with law which may be required by the\nfederal social security act to obtain and retain such approval and to\nsecure for the state the benefits of the provisions of such title. The\ndepartment shall make such regulations not inconsistent with law as may\nbe necessary to make such plan conform to the provisions of such title\nand any rules and regulations adopted pursuant thereto. The department\nshall make reports to such federal department in the form and nature\nrequired by it and in all respects comply with any request or direction\nof such federal department which may be necessary to assure the\ncorrectness and verification of such reports.\n  2. The department of taxation and finance shall accept and receive any\nand all grants of money awarded to the state under title six of the\nsocial security act for federal aid for services for the aged, blind or\ndisabled. All monies so received shall be deposited by the department of\ntaxation and finance in a special fund or funds and shall be used by the\nstate exclusively for services for the aged, blind or disabled and the\nadministration thereof under the provisions of this title. Such money\nshall be paid from such fund or funds on audit and warrant of the\ncomptroller on vouchers of or certification by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>