<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-300"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-300"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="300"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-300/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-300/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-300/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-300/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_300">
        <num>300</num>
        <heading>Declaration of purpose; definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 300. Declaration of purpose; definitions. 1. Emergency assistance\nfor aged, blind and disabled persons with emergency needs which, if not\nmet, would endanger the health, safety and welfare of such persons, is\nhereby declared to be a matter of state concern and a necessity in\npromoting the public health and welfare, until such time as the federal\nsupplemental security income program is expanded to meet this federal\nresponsibility. It is the purpose of this title to provide such\nassistance to eligible aged, blind and disabled persons who, in the\ncircumstances specified in this title, have needs that cannot be met by\nthe regular monthly benefit under the federal supplemental security\nincome and additional state payments programs. All efforts should be\nundertaken by New York state's congressional delegation to secure such\nexpansion of the federal program.\n  2. As used in this title, "aged, blind and disabled persons" means\npersons who have been determined to be eligible for or are receiving\nfederal supplemental security income benefits and/or additional state\npayments.\n  3. As used in this title, the terms "emergency assistance" and\n"emergency assistance for aged, blind and disabled persons" mean\npayments to meet emergency needs specified in section three hundred\nthree, made to or for the benefit of persons found to be eligible\ntherefor, in accordance with this title and the regulations of the\ndepartment.\n  4. As used in this title, "supplemental security income benefits"\nmeans payments made by the secretary of the federal department of\nhealth, education and welfare to aged, blind and disabled persons\npursuant to title sixteen of the social security act.\n  5. As used in this title, "additional state payments" means payments\nby social services districts or by the secretary of the federal\ndepartment of health, education and welfare on behalf of the state, to\naged, blind and disabled persons who are receiving, or who would but for\ntheir income be eligible to receive, federal supplemental security\nincome benefits, made pursuant to title sixteen of the federal social\nsecurity act, public law 93-66, and the provisions of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>