<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-330"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-330"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="330"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_330">
        <num>330</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 330. Definitions. 1. Whenever used in this title:\n  a. the term "commissioner" means the commissioner of the state office\nof temporary and disability assistance; and\n  b. the term "department" means the state office of temporary and\ndisability assistance.\n  2. "Net loss of cash income" shall mean the amount by which a family's\ngross income less any necessary work-related expenses is less than the\ncash assistance the individual was receiving at the time of receiving an\noffer of employment. Gross income includes, but is not limited to,\nearnings, unearned income and cash assistance.\n  3. "Child care" shall refer to any lawful form of care of a child, as\ndefined by federal and state law and regulation, for less than\ntwenty-four hours per day.\n  4. "Participant" shall mean an applicant for or recipient of public\nassistance who volunteers for or is required to participate in work\nactivities as provided in this title.\n  5. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or the labor\nlaw, recipients of public assistance who are required to participate in\ncommunity service or work experience activities authorized pursuant to\nthis title shall be included within the meaning of the term "public\nemployee" for the purposes of applying section twenty-seven-a of the\nlabor law while engaged in community service or work experience programs\nunder this title. In addition, such recipients shall be provided\nappropriate workers' compensation or equivalent protection for\non-the-job injuries and tort claims protection on the same basis, but\nnot necessarily at the same benefit level, as they are provided to other\npersons in the same or similar positions, while participating in\ncommunity service or work experience activities under this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>