<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-331"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-331"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="331"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-331/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-331/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-331/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-331/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_331">
        <num>331</num>
        <heading>Policies and purposes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 331. Policies and purposes. 1. It is hereby declared to be the\npolicy of the state that there be programs under which individuals\nreceiving public assistance will be furnished work activities and\nemployment opportunities, and necessary services in order to secure\nunsubsidized employment that will assist participants to achieve\neconomic independence. Such programs shall be established and operated\nin accordance with the provisions of this title and in compliance with\nfederal and state law and regulations.\n  2.  A social services district may contract or establish agreements\nwith entities which comply with the standards to be established in\nregulations by the commissioner to provide work activities, including\nbut not limited to, job training partnership act agencies, state\nagencies, school districts, boards of cooperative educational services,\nnot-for-profit community based organizations, licensed trade schools or\nregistered business schools, libraries, post-secondary educational\ninstitutions consistent with this title, and educational opportunity\ncenters and local employers.  A district shall, to the extent\npracticable and permitted under federal requirements, develop\nperformance based contracts or agreements with such entities.  Such\nstandards shall include an evaluation procedure to ensure that services\noffered by a provider are sufficient to enhance substantially a\nparticipant's opportunity to secure unsubsidized employment or, when\ncoupled with or provided in conjunction with other activities, represent\npart of a comprehensive approach to enabling a participant to secure\nunsubsidized employment.  Notwithstanding the provisions of section one\nhundred fifty-three of this article, expenditures pursuant to contracts\nor agreements with providers who do not meet the standards for approval\nof providers as defined in regulations will not be eligible for\nreimbursement by the department.\n  3.  No social services district shall, in the exercising of the powers\nand duties established in this title, permit discrimination on the basis\nof race, color, national origin, sex, religion or handicap, in the\nselection of participants, their assignment or reassignment to work\nactivities and duties, and the separate use of facilities or other\ntreatment of participants.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>