<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="336-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-336-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_336_A">
        <num>336-A</num>
        <heading>Educational activities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>through</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision and if resources permit, each social services official shall\nassign to appropriate educational activities any participant who has not\nobtained a high school diploma or its equivalent:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In accordance with the provisions of this chapter, any such\nparticipant who is under age eighteen shall be required to attend\neducational activities designed to prepare the individual for a high\nschool degree or equivalency certificate. Participants who are not\nsubject to compulsory school attendance requirements may be exempted\nfrom the requirements of this paragraph under criteria established by\nthe department in consultation with the state education department and\nconsistent with federal law and regulations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any such participant who is age eighteen or nineteen shall be\nassigned to educational activities, except that the district shall\nassign such participant to employment and/or other activities under this\ntitle if the district has determined that such alternative activities\nare consistent with the participant's employability plan and, pursuant\nto department regulations, there has been a determination by the\ndistrict based on such plan that educational activities are not\nappropriate for such participant or that the participant has failed to\nmake good progress in such educational activities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any such participant who is an adult in a two-parent family and is\nunder age twenty-five may be required to participate in educational\nactivities consistent with his or her employment goals set forth in the\nemployability plan.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_336_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The social services official shall not assign a participant\ndescribed in this subdivision to any activities which interfere with the\neducational activities assigned pursuant to such participant's\nemployability plan and described in this subdivision.\n  5. Any applicant for or recipient of public assistance pursuing\nactivities described in this subdivision shall not be assigned to any\nother activity prior to conducting an assessment and developing an\nemployability plan as prescribed in section three hundred thirty-five or\nthree hundred thirty-five-a of this title. Local social services\ndistricts may periodically reevaluate a participant's employment plan\nand make assignments to other work activities in order to meet\nparticipation rates, giving due consideration to the participant's\nprogress in the current, and if applicable, prior program.\n  6. Nothing required in this section shall be construed to supersede\nthe eligibility requirements of teen parents as set forth in this\nchapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>