<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-348"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-348"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="348"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-348/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-348/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-348/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-348/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_348">
        <num>348</num>
        <heading>Application for family assistance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 348. Application for family assistance. 1. Application for family\nassistance shall be made to the appropriate social services district.\n  2. Application for or receipt of family assistance shall operate as an\nassignment to the state and the social services district concerned of\nany rights to support that accrue during the period that a family\nreceives family assistance from any other person as such applicant or\nrecipient may have either on their own behalf or on behalf of any other\nfamily member for whom the applicant or recipient is applying for or\nreceiving assistance. Applicants for or recipients of family assistance\nshall be informed that such application for or receipt of such benefits\nwill constitute such an assignment.\n  3. Such assignment shall terminate with respect to current support\nrights upon a determination by a local commissioner that such person is\nno longer eligible for family assistance, except with respect to the\namount of any unpaid support obligation that has accrued during the\nperiod that a family received family assistance.\n  4. It shall be the duty of social services officials to provide same\nday referral of applicants for family assistance support services as\nprovided under title six-A of article three of this chapter pursuant to\npart D of title IV of the federal social security act, as part of the\ninitial application for family assistance.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>