<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-350-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-350-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="350-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-350-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-350-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-350-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-350-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_350_A">
        <num>350-A</num>
        <heading>Protective payments</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 350-a. Protective payments. 1. Whenever the social services official\nwho is granting allowances of family assistance to a relative for the\nbenefit of a child determines that such relative is unable to manage the\nallowances he or she may, when appropriate in accordance with state and\nfederal requirements, pay the allowances to another individual who is\ninterested in or concerned with the welfare of the child and relative.\n  2.  The determination of the social services official to pay\nallowances to another individual pursuant to subdivision one may be\nappealed to the department by the relative concerned who shall be given\nan opportunity for a fair hearing on his appeal.  The department may\nreview such determination on its own motion.  The powers and procedures\nprescribed by section twenty-two of this chapter shall likewise apply to\nthe determinations, appeals and reviews made pursuant to this section.\n  3.  Any relative or other person who is granted an allowance of family\nassistance for the benefit of a child or children and who wilfully uses\nall or any part of such allowance other than for the benefit of such\nchild or children, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>