<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-356"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-356"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="356"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-356/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-356/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-356/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-356/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_356">
        <num>356</num>
        <heading>Moneys to be provided by counties and cities; how expended</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 356.  Moneys to be provided by counties and cities; how expended.\n1. The legislative body of each social services district shall annually\nappropriate to the commissioner of social services such sum as may be\nneeded for family assistance, and for the administration thereof. When\nthe assistance for which such social services district is responsible is\nadministered, pursuant to title three-A of article three, by a social\nservices official who is not an officer of the social services district\nfor which the appropriation is made, all or part of the sum appropriated\nshall be made available to such other officer and to the municipality of\nwhich he or she is an officer, in the manner, and at such times, as is\nrequired  by other provisions of this chapter. The legislative body of\nthe social services district shall include such sums in the taxes  to be\nlevied for such social services district.\n  2. Allowances granted for family assistance shall be paid out of\nmoneys appropriated or otherwise made  available to the social services\ndistrict.\n  3.  Expenditures for allowances and administrative expenses under this\ntitle shall be a charge upon the county or city public welfare district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>