<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-363-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-363-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="363-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-363-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-363-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-363-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-363-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_363_B">
        <num>363-B</num>
        <heading>Agreements for federal determination of eligibility of aged, blind and disabled persons for medical assistance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 363-b.  Agreements for federal determination of eligibility of aged,\nblind and disabled persons for medical assistance.  1.  In order to\navoid costly, duplicative administrative responsibility, the department\non behalf of the state may, with the approval of the director of the\nbudget, enter into an agreement with the secretary of health, education\nand welfare for the secretary to determine eligibility, commencing on or\nafter the first day of January nineteen hundred seventy-four, for\nmedical assistance in the case of aged, blind or disabled persons,\npursuant to the provisions of the social security act authorizing such\nagreements and subject to the requirements of this title.  Such\nagreement shall include provision for payments of one-half the cost of\nsuch services to be made to such secretary.\n  2.  Payments required to be made by the department to the secretary of\nhealth, education and welfare for his services under such agreement\nshall be borne by and shared equally between the social services\ndistricts to which such payments are attributable and the state for any\nperiod commencing on or after the first day of January nineteen hundred\nseventy-four.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>