<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="365-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_365_H">
        <num>365-H</num>
        <heading>Provision and reimbursement of transportation costs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make appropriate and economical use of transportation resources\navailable in the district in meeting the anticipated demand for\ntransportation within the district, including, but not limited to:\ntransportation generally available free-of-charge to the general public\nor specific segments of the general public, public transportation,\npromotion of group rides, county vehicles, coordinated transportation,\nand direct purchase of services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>maintain quality assurance mechanisms in order to ensure that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nonly such transportation as is essential, medically necessary and\nappropriate to obtain medical care, services or supplies otherwise\navailable under this title is provided; (ii) no expenditures for taxi or\nlivery transportation are made when public transportation or lower cost\ntransportation is reasonably available to eligible persons; and (iii)\ntransportation services are provided in a safe, timely, and reliable\nmanner by providers that comply with state and local regulatory\nrequirements and meet consumer satisfaction criteria approved by the\ncommissioner of health.\n  3. In the event that coordination or other such cost savings measures\nare implemented, the commissioner shall assure compliance with\napplicable standards governing the safety and quality of transportation\nof the population served.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of health is authorized to assume\nresponsibility from a local social services official for the provision\nand reimbursement of transportation costs under this section. If the\ncommissioner elects to assume such responsibility, the commissioner\nshall notify the local social services official in writing as to the\nelection, the date upon which the election shall be effective and such\ninformation as to transition of responsibilities as the commissioner\ndeems prudent. The commissioner is authorized to contract with a\ntransportation manager or managers to manage transportation services in\nany local social services district, other than transportation services\nprovided or arranged for enrollees of managed long term care plans\nissued certificates of authority under section forty-four hundred\nthree-f of the public health law. Any transportation manager or managers\nselected by the commissioner to manage transportation services shall\nhave proven experience in coordinating transportation services in a\ngeographic and demographic area similar to the area in New York state\nwithin which the contractor would manage the provision of services under\nthis section. Such a contract or contracts may include responsibility\nfor: review, approval and processing of transportation orders;\nmanagement of the appropriate level of transportation based on\ndocumented patient medical need; and development of new technologies\nleading to efficient transportation services. If the commissioner elects\nto assume such responsibility from a local social services district, the\ncommissioner shall examine and, if appropriate, adopt quality assurance\nmeasures that may include, but are not limited to, global positioning\ntracking system reporting requirements and service verification\nmechanisms. Any and all reimbursement rates developed by transportation\nmanagers under this subdivision shall be subject to the review and\napproval of the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to federal financial participation, for periods on and\nafter April first, two thousand twenty-one, in order to more\ncost-effectively provide non-emergency transportation to Medicaid\nbeneficiaries who need access to medical care and services, the\ncommissioner is authorized to contract with one or more transportation\nmanagement brokers to manage such transportation on a statewide or\nregional basis, as determined by the commissioner, in accordance with\nthe federal social security act as follows:\n  (A) The transportation management broker or brokers shall be selected\nthrough a competitive bidding process based on an evaluation of the\nbroker's experience, performance, references, resources, qualifications\nand costs; provided, however, that the department's selection process\nshall be memorialized in a procurement record as defined in section one\nhundred sixty-three of the state finance law;\n  (B) The transportation management broker or brokers shall have\noversight procedures to monitor Medicaid beneficiary access and\ncomplaints and ensure that enrolled Medicaid transportation providers\nare licensed, qualified, competent and courteous.\n  (C) The transportation management broker or brokers shall be subject\nto regular auditing and oversight by the department in order to ensure\nthe quality of the transportation services provided and adequacy of\nMedicaid beneficiary access to medical care and services.\n  (D) The transportation management broker or brokers shall comply with\nrequirements related to prohibitions on referrals and conflicts of\ninterest required by the federal social security act.\n  (ii) The transportation management broker or brokers may be paid a per\nmember per month capitated fee or a combination of capitation and fixed\ncost reimbursement and the contract shall include, but not be limited\nto, responsibility for:\n  (A) establishing a network of high-quality Medicaid enrolled\nproviders; provided, however, that in developing suc...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To the extent practicable, the competitive bidding and contracting\nprocess maybe completed by April first, two thousand twenty-one;\nprovided, however, such contract may be effective at some date after\nApril first, two thousand twenty-one, if the process takes longer to\ncomplete.\n  (vi) Responsibility for transportation services provided or arranged\nfor enrollees of managed long term care plans issued certificates of\nauthority under section forty-four hundred three-f of the public health\nlaw, not including a program designated as a Program of All-Inclusive\nCare for the Elderly (PACE) as authorized by Federal Public law 1053-33,\nsubtitle I of title IV of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, and, at the\ncommissioner's discretion, other plans that integrate benefits for\ndually eligible Medicare and Medicaid beneficiaries based on a\ndemonstration by the plan that inclusion of transportation within the\nbenefit package will result in cost efficiencies and quality\nimprovement, shall be transferred to a transportation management broker\nthat has a contract with the commissioner in accordance with this\nparagraph. Providers of adult day health care may elect to, but shall\nnot be required to, use the services of the transportation management\nbroker.\n  5. Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, and subject to\nfederal financial participation, the commissioner of health shall make\nadjustments to payments under this section, for the purposes of\nproviding increased access to Medicaid non-emergency transportation in\nrural communities. Up to two million dollars shall be available for such\npurposes.\n  6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of health shall require transportation\nproviders enrolled in the Medicaid program and specified by the\ncommissioner pursuant to regulation, to report the costs incurred in\nproviding transportation services to Medicaid beneficiaries pursuant to\nthis section; provided, however, this requirement shall only apply if\nthere is no transportation management broker contract authorized in\nsubdivision four of this section. The commissioner shall specify the\nfrequency and format of such reports and determine the type and amount\nof information required to be submitted, including supporting\ndocumentation, provided that such reports shall be no more frequent than\nquarterly. The commissioner shall give all transportation providers no\nless than ninety calendar days' notice before such reports are due.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the commissioner determines that the cost report submitted by a\nMedicaid transportation provider is inaccurate or incomplete, the\ncommissioner shall notify such provider in writing and advise the\nprovider of the correction or additional information that the provider\nmust submit. The provider shall submit the corrected or additional\ninformation within thirty calendar days from the date the provider\nreceives the notice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall grant a provider an additional thirty\ncalendar days to submit the original cost report, or corrected or\nadditional information required pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision only when the provider submits a written request to the\ncommissioner for an extension prior to the due date and establishes to\nthe satisfaction of the commissioner that the provider cannot submit the\ncost report or corrected or additional information by the due date for\nreasons beyond the provider's control.\n  * NB Repealed 16 years after the contract entered into pursuant to\nthis section 365-h is executed\n  * ยง 365-h. Provision and reimbursement of transportation costs. 1. The\nlocal social services official shall have responsibility for prior\nauthorizing transportation of eligible persons and for limiting the\nprovision of such transportation to those recipients and circumstances\nwhere such transportation is essential, medically necessary and\nappropriate to obtain medical care, services or supplies otherwise\navailable under this title.\n  2. In exercising this responsibility, the local social services\nofficial shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make appropriate and economical use of transportation resources\navailable in the district in meeting the anticipated demand for\ntransportation within the district, including, but not limited to:\ntransportation generally available free-of-charge to the general public\nor specific segments of the general public, public transportation,\npromotion of group rides, county vehicles, coordinated transportation,\nand direct purchase of services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>maintain quality assurance mechanisms in order to ensure that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_365_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nonly such transportation as is essential, medically necessary and\nappropriate to obtain medical care, services or supplies otherwise\navailable under this title is provided and (ii) no expenditures for taxi\nor livery transportation are made when public transportation or lower\ncost transportation is reasonably available to eligible persons.\n  3. In the event that coordination or other such cost savings measures\nare implemented, the commissioner shall assure compliance with\napplicable standards governing the safety and quality of transportation\nof the population served.\n  * NB Effective 16 years after the contract entered into pursuant to\nthis section 365-h has been executed\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>