<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="365-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-365-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_365_C">
        <num>365-C</num>
        <heading>Medical advisory committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 365-c.  Medical advisory committee. 1.  A medical advisory committee\nis hereby established to consist of twenty members who shall be\nappointed by the governor, by and with the advice and consent of the\nsenate, for the following terms: seven shall be appointed for a term to\nexpire on May thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-four:  seven shall\nbe appointed for a term to expire on May thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-five: and six shall be appointed for a term to expire on May\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-six.  Thereafter members\nappointed upon expiration of a term of office shall be appointed for a\nterm of three years.  Vacancies caused by death, resignation or refusal\nto act or by removal from the state shall be filled for the unexpired\nterm only.   At least seven members of such committee shall be duly\nlicensed physicians.  The governor shall designate a chairman from among\nthe members of the medical advisory committee, to serve as such at the\npleasure of the governor.  In appointing the members of the medical\nadvisory committee, the governor shall give consideration to\nprofessional qualifications and experience and to achieving\nrepresentation of the professions of medicine, osteopathy, podiatry,\nmental health, social work, dentistry, optometry, chiropractic, physical\ntherapy, pharmacy, nursing, hospital and health administration and\neducation for the health professions, of public and private agencies in\nthe field of medical assistance, and of recipients and consumers of\nmedical assistance for needy persons.\n  2.  The medical advisory committee shall advise the commissioner with\nrespect to health and medical care services provided pursuant to this\ntitle.\n  3.  The medical advisory committee shall meet at least once a year.\nSpecial meetings may be called by the chairman, and shall be called by\nhim at the request of the governor or the commissioner.\n  4.  No member of the medical advisory committee shall be disqualified\nfrom holding any other public office or employment, nor shall he forfeit\nany such office or employment by reason of his employment hereunder,\nnotwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local law,\nordinance or charter.\n  5.  The members of the medical advisory committee shall receive no\ncompensation for their services, but shall be allowed their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties\nhereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>