<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="366-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-366-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_366_B">
        <num>366-B</num>
        <heading>Penalties for fraudulent practices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 366-b.  Penalties for fraudulent practices. 1.  Any person who\nknowingly makes a false statement or representation, or who by\ndeliberate concealment of any material fact, or by impersonation or\nother fraudulent device, obtains or attempts to obtain or aids or abets\nany person to obtain medical assistance to which he is not entitled,\nshall be guilty of a class A misdemeanor, unless such act constitutes a\nviolation of a provision of the penal law of the state of New York, in\nwhich case he shall be punished in accordance with the penalties fixed\nby such law.\n  2.  Any person who, with intent to defraud, presents for allowance or\npayment any false or fraudulent claim for furnishing services or\nmerchandise, or knowingly submits false information for the purpose of\nobtaining greater compensation than that to which he is legally entitled\nfor furnishing services or merchandise, or knowingly submits false\ninformation for the purpose of obtaining authorization for furnishing\nservices or merchandise under this title, shall be guilty of a class A\nmisdemeanor, unless such act constitutes a violation of a provision of\nthe penal law of the state of New York, in which case he shall be\npunished in accordance with the penalties fixed by such law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>