<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="368-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_368_D">
        <num>368-D</num>
        <heading>Reimbursement to public school districts and state operated/state supported schools which operate pursuant to article eighty-five, eighty...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_368_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department of health shall post on its website, for a period\nof no less than thirty days:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_368_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A description of the proposed services to be provided pursuant to\nthe contract or contracts;\n  (ii) The criteria for selection of a contractor or contractors;\n  (iii) The period of time during which a prospective contractor may\nseek selection, which shall be no less than thirty days after such\ninformation is first posted on the website; and\n  (iv) The manner by which a prospective contractor may seek such\nselection, which may include submission by electronic means;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_368_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All reasonable and responsive submissions that are received from\nprospective contractors in timely fashion shall be reviewed by the\ncommissioner of health; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_368_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of health shall select such contractor or\ncontractors that, in his or her discretion, are best suited to serve the\npurposes of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_368_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon selection of a contractor or contractors, the department of\nhealth shall provide written notification of such selection and a\nsummary of the criteria employed in such selection to the chair of the\nsenate finance committee and the chair of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee.\n  6. The commissioner shall evaluate the results of the study conducted\npursuant to subdivision four of this section to determine, after\nidentification of actual direct and indirect costs incurred by public\nschool districts, whether it is advisable to claim federal reimbursement\nfor expenditures under this section as certified public expenditures. In\nthe event such claims are submitted, if federal reimbursement received\nfor certified public expenditures on behalf of medical assistance\nrecipients whose assistance and care are the responsibility of a social\nservices district results in a decrease in the state share of annual\nexpenditures pursuant to this section for such recipients, then to the\nextent that the amount of any such decrease when combined with any\ndecrease in the state share of annual expenditures described in\nsubdivision five of section three hundred sixty-eight-e of this title\nexceeds one hundred fifty million dollars for the period April 1, 2011\nthrough March 31, 2013, or exceeds one hundred million dollars in state\nfiscal years 2013-14 and 2014-15, the excess amount shall be transferred\nto such public school districts in amounts proportional to their\npercentage contribution to the statewide savings; an amount equal to\nthirteen and five hundredths percent of any decrease in the state share\nof annual expenditures pursuant to this section for such recipients in\nstate fiscal year 2015-16 and any fiscal year thereafter shall be\ntransferred to such public school districts in amounts proportional to\ntheir percentage contribution to the statewide savings. Any amount\ntransferred pursuant to this section shall not be considered a revenue\nreceived by such ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_368_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection one of part C of chapter fifty-eight of the laws of two thousand\nfive.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>