<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="368-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-368-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_368_F">
        <num>368-F</num>
        <heading>Reimbursement of costs under the early intervention program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 368-f. Reimbursement of costs under the early intervention program.\n1. The department shall review claims for expenditures made by or on\nbehalf of social services districts for the administration of the early\nintervention program as established under title II-A of article\ntwenty-five of the public health law. If approved by the department,\npayment for such expenditures, which were made in accordance with this\ntitle and the regulations of the department, shall be made by payment to\nsuch district, which incurred the expenditure, either directly or by\ncontract, of the amount of any federal funds properly received or to be\nreceived on account of such expenditures.\n  2. Claims for payment under this section shall be made in such form\nand manner, at such times, and for such periods as the department may\nrequire.\n  3. The department's liability for payment for such administrative\nexpenditures made by or on behalf of districts under this section shall\nbe limited solely to payment of the federal funds received, or to be\nreceived, on account of such expenditures. In the event of any\nsubsequent disallowances or recoupment of such funds by a federal\ngovernmental agency, upon notification by the commissioner, the\ncomptroller shall withhold or cause to be withheld the amount of such\ndisallowance or recoupment from any moneys otherwise due the district,\nas state aid pursuant to any provision of law, and the comptroller shall\ntransfer such amount to the credit of the department of social services\nmedical assistance administration program - local assistance account.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>