<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="369-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_369_CC">
        <num>369-CC</num>
        <heading>Retrospective and prospective drug utilization review</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Identify patterns of gross overuse, and inappropriate or medically\nunnecessary care.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Assess data on drug use against explicit predetermined standards\nthat are based on the compendia and other sources to monitor the\nfollowing:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Therapeutic appropriateness;\n  (ii) Overutilization or underutilization;\n  (iii) Therapeutic duplication;\n  (iv) Drug-disease contraindications;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Drug-drug interactions;\n  (vi) Incorrect drug dosage or duration of drug treatment; and\n  (vii) Clinical abuse/misuse.\n  3. The prospective DUR program shall be based on the guidelines\nestablished by the DUR board not in conflict with education or social\nservices laws and shall provide that prior to the prescription being\nfilled or delivered, a review will be conducted by the pharmacist at the\npoint of sale to screen for potential drug therapy problems resulting\nfrom:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Therapeutic duplication;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Drug-drug interactions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Incorrect dosage/duration of treatment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Drug-allergy interactions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Clinical abuse/misuse.\nIn conducting the prospective DUR, the pharmacist may not alter the\nprescribed outpatient drug therapy without the consent of the prescriber\nwho prescribed that therapy.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, through the prospective DUR program, may\nrequire step therapy when there is more than one drug appropriate to\ntreat a medical condition. The purpose of step therapy is to encourage\nthe use of medically appropriate, cost effective drugs when clinically\nindicated and to limit use of alternative drug therapies unless certain\nclinical requirements are met. The DUR board shall recommend guidelines\nfor specific diagnoses and therapy regimens within which practitioners\nmay prescribe drugs without the requirement for prior authorization of\nthose drugs. In establishing these guidelines, the board shall consider\nclinical effectiveness, safety, and cost effectiveness. Prior\nauthorization under this paragraph shall be obtained under section two\nhundred seventy-three of the public health law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369_CC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner, through the prospective DUR program, may from\ntime to time limit the quantity, frequency, and duration of drug\ntherapy, using guidelines developed by the DUR board. The DUR board\nshall develop clinical prescribing guidelines relating to quantity,\nfrequency, and duration of drug therapy for the commissioner's use under\nthis paragraph. In establishing these guidelines, the board shall\nconsider clinical effectiveness, safety, and cost effectiveness. Prior\nauthorization under this paragraph shall be obtained under section two\nhundred seventy-three of the public health law. Exceptions to any prior\nauthorization imposed as a result of these guidelines shall include, but\nneed not be limited to, provision for emergency circumstances where a\nmedical condition requires alleviation of severe pain or which threatens\nto cause disability or to take a life if not promptly treated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>