<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="369-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-369-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_369_N">
        <num>369-N</num>
        <heading>Relationship of program to medical assistance program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 369-n. Relationship of program to medical assistance program. 1. Any\nperson eligible for medical assistance benefits under title eleven of\nthis article or who would be eligible for such benefits if an\napplication were to be made pursuant to section three hundred sixty-six\nof this article shall not be eligible for the payment of all or part of\nsuch person's health insurance costs under this program. If all members\nof a household can establish eligibility for medical assistance benefits\nunder the excess income program by use of paid or incurred bills, no\nperson in that household shall be eligible for the payment of all or\npart of such person's health insurance costs under this program.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, expenditures\nincurred by social services districts under this title related to\nprogram expenses shall be considered expenditures under the program of\nmedical assistance for needy persons under title eleven of this article\nand there shall be paid to each such district fifty percent of the\namount expended by such district under this title, and for the\nadministration thereof, after first deducting therefrom any federal\nfunds properly received or to be received on account thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>