<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-372-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-372-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="372-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-372-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-372-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-372-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-372-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_372_B">
        <num>372-B</num>
        <heading>Adoption services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 372-b. Adoption services. 1. a. A prospective adoptive parent shall\nhave a right to a fair hearing pursuant to section twenty-two of this\nchapter concerning the failure of a social services official to provide\nadoption services authorized to be provided pursuant to this section and\nthe state's consolidated services plan.  At the time a child is placed\nin a prospective adoptive home, the prospective adoptive parent shall be\nnotified in writing of his or her right to such fair hearing.\n  b. Each social services official shall provide, either directly or\nthrough purchase of service, adoption services for each child in their\ncare who is freed for adoption.  Such adoption services shall include\nthe evaluation of a child's placement needs and pre-placement planning,\nrecruitment of and homestudy for prospective adoptive parents, training\nof adoptive parents, placement planning, supervision and post adoption\nservices.\n  2.  The department shall promulgate regulations which shall require\nthat adoption services be made available to all children who are listed\nwith the New York state adoption service.  Such regulations shall also\nprovide for cooperation between local social services commissioners, and\nfor apportioning reimbursement for adoption services where more than one\nagency or social services district has provided such services for a\nchild.\n  2-a. The department shall promulgate regulations requiring all\nadoption agencies to forward names and addresses of all persons who have\napplied for adoption of a hard-to-place or handicapped child, as defined\nin section four hundred fifty-one of this chapter. A list of such names\nand addresses shall be maintained by the department and made available,\nwithout charge, to every agency in the state to assist them in placing\nsuch children for adoption.\n  3.  The  department shall promulgate regulations to maintain\nenlightened adoption policies and to establish standards and criteria\nfor adoption practices.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>