<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-39"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-39"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="39"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-39/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-39/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-39/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-39/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_39">
        <num>39</num>
        <heading>Indian affairs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_39__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An Indian tribe approved to assume jurisdiction shall have\nexclusive jurisdiction over any child custody proceeding involving an\nIndian child who resides or is domiciled within the reservation of such\ntribe, except where such jurisdiction is otherwise vested in the courts\nof the state of New York by existing federal law. Where an Indian child\nis a ward of a tribal court, the Indian tribe shall retain exclusive\njurisdiction, notwithstanding the residence or domicile of the child.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_39__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_39__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, nothing herein shall be construed to prevent the emergency\nremoval of an Indian child who is a resident of or is domiciled on a\nreservation, but temporarily located off the reservation, from his\nparents or Indian custodian or the emergency placement of such child in\na foster home or institution, under applicable state law in order to\nprevent imminent physical damage or harm to the child. The state\nauthority, official or agency shall insure that the emergency removal or\nplacement terminates immediately when such removal or placement is no\nlonger necessary to prevent imminent physical damage or harm to the\nchild and shall expeditiously initiate a child custody proceeding\nsubject to the provisions of this section, transfer the child to the\njurisdiction of the appropriate Indian tribe, or restore the child to\nthe parent or Indian custodian as may be appropriate.\n  6. In any state court child custody proceeding involving the foster\ncare placement of, or termination of parental rights to an Indian child\nnot domiciled or residing within the reservation of the Indian child's\ntribe, the court, in the absence of good cause to the contrary, shall\ntransfer such proceeding to the jurisdiction of the tribe, absent\nobjection by either parent, upon the petition of either parent or the\nIndian custodian or the Indian child's tribe; provided, however, that\nsuch transfer shall be subject to declination by the tribal court of\nsuch tribe.\n  7. In any state court proceeding involving the foster care placement\nof or the termination of parental rights to an Indian child, the Indian\ncustodian of the child and the Indian tribe shall have a right to\nintervene at any point in the proceeding.\n  8. The department may enter into an agreement, contract or compact\nwith an Indian tribe or intertribal consortium for the provision of\nwelfare related services by social services districts or by any tribe or\ntribes in connection with a tribal plan for dir...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>