<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-392"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-392"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="392"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-392/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-392/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-392/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-392/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_392">
        <num>392</num>
        <heading>Services for relative and non-relative kinship caregivers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 392. Services for relative and non-relative kinship caregivers. 1.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, when a local\nsocial services district is in contact with a relative or non-relative\nkinship caregiver or a suitable person who the district has approached\nabout being a kinship caregiver, such district shall provide written\ninformation as described in subdivision two of this section to such\ncaregivers or prospective suitable persons. Such information shall also\nbe made available through the website of both the office and the\ndistrict and by other appropriate means in a manner accessible to\nrelatives and non-relatives caring for children outside of the foster\ncare system.\n  2. Such information shall include but not be limited to:\n  a. information relating to child only grants, including but not\nlimited to, how to apply for child only grants;\n  b. information about how to become a kinship foster parent and other\noptions for care; and\n  c. information on how to contact the department of family assistance\nkinship programs and any resources funded through or operating in the\nlocal social services district for relative and non-relative kinship\ncaregivers, including those that provide supportive services for all\nrelative and non-relative kinship caregivers in the district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>