<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-398-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-398-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-05-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="398-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-398-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-398-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-398-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-398-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_398_B">
        <num>398-B</num>
        <heading>Transition to managed care</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 398-b. Transition to managed care. 1. Notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provision of law to the contrary and subject to the\navailability of federal financial participation, the commissioner is\nauthorized to make grants up to a gross amount of five million dollars\nfor state fiscal year two thousand fourteen--fifteen and up to a gross\namount of fifteen million dollars for state fiscal year two thousand\nfifteen--sixteen to facilitate the transition of foster care children\nplaced with voluntary foster care agencies to managed care. The use of\nsuch funds may include providing training and consulting services to\nvoluntary agencies to assess readiness and make necessary infrastructure\nand organizational modifications, collecting service utilization and\nother data from voluntary agencies and other entities, and making\ninvestments in health information technology, including the\ninfrastructure necessary to establish and maintain electronic health\nrecords. Such funds shall be distributed pursuant to a formula to be\ndeveloped by the commissioner of health, in consultation with the\ncommissioner of the office of children and family services. In\ndeveloping such formula the commissioners may take into account size and\nscope of provider operations as a factor relevant to eligibility for\nsuch funds. Each recipient of such funds shall be required to document\nand demonstrate the effective use of funds distributed herein. If\nfederal financial participation is unavailable, then the nonfederal\nshare of payments pursuant to this subdivision may be made as state\ngrants.\n  2. Data provided by voluntary foster care agencies shall be compliant\nwith the health insurance portability and accountability act, and shall\nbe transmitted securely using eMEDS or other mechanism to be determined\nby the department of health. Such data may be used by the department of\nhealth to establish rates of payment for managed care organizations for\nservices provided to children in foster care. In establishing such rates\nthe commissioner of health shall also take into account care\ncoordination services that will continue to be provided by the voluntary\nfoster care agencies.\n  3. The commissioner of health shall issue a report to be made public\non the department of health's website. Such report shall conform to the\nrequirements of subdivision five of section ninety-two of part H of\nchapter fifty-nine of the laws of two thousand eleven.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>