<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_D">
        <num>410-D</num>
        <heading>Short title: policy and purposes of title</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 410-d.  Short title: policy and purposes of title.  This title shall\nbe known, and may be cited and referred to, as the "Youth Facilities\nImprovement Act".\n  There is a serious shortage throughout the state of facilities\nsuitable for use for the care of children especially those of pre-school\nage and primary school age whose parents are unable to provide such care\nfor all or a substantial part of the day or post-school day.  A similar\nshortage of residential child care facilities also exists.  Existing day\ncare and residential child care facilities are overcrowded with long\nwaiting lists.  Many such facilities are so located that they are not\naccessible to families in need of such services.  The absence of\nadequate day care and residential child care facilities is contrary to\nthe interest of the people of the state, is detrimental to the health\nand welfare of the child and his parents and prevents the gainful\nemployment of persons, who are otherwise qualified, because of the need\nto provide such care in their home.\n  It is the purpose of this article to encourage the timely construction\nand equipment of such facilities with mortgage loan participation by the\nNew York state housing finance agency.  The provision of such facilities\nis hereby declared to be a public purpose which it is the policy of the\nstate to encourage.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>