<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-X"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-X"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-04-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410-X"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-410-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410_X">
        <num>410-X</num>
        <heading>Use of funds</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_X__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The office of children and family services may establish\npriorities for the families which will be eligible to receive funding;\nprovided that the priorities provide that eligible families will receive\nequitable access to child care assistance funds to the extent that these\nfunds are available. The office of children and family services shall\nensure that families in receipt of child care assistance as of September\nthirtieth, two thousand twenty-three who were identified as a priority\npopulation under a local social services district's consolidated\nservices plan shall continue to be eligible for such assistance,\nprovided they meet all other applicable eligibility requirements for\nsuch assistance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_X__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each social services district shall collect and submit to the\ncommissioner of the office of children and family services in a manner\nto be specified by the commissioner of the office of children and family\nservices information concerning the disbursement of child care\nassistance funds showing geographic distribution of children receiving\nassistance within the district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_X__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of the office of children and family services\nshall submit a report to the governor, temporary president of the senate\nand the speaker of the assembly on or before August thirty-first, two\nthousand one concerning the implementation of this section. This report\nshall include information concerning the disbursement of child care\nassistance funds showing geographic distribution of children receiving\nassistance within the state.\n  3. Child care assistance funded under the block grant must meet all\napplicable standards set forth in section three hundred ninety of this\narticle or the administrative code of the city of New York, including\nchild day care in a child day care center, family day care home, group\nfamily day care home, school age child care program, or in home care\nwhich is not subject to licensure, certification or registration, or any\nother lawful form of care for less than twenty-four hours per day. The\ndepartment also is required to establish, in regulation, minimum health\nand safety requirements that must be met by those providers providing\nchild care assistance funded under the block grant which are not\nrequired to be licensed or registered under section three hundred ninety\nof this article or to be licensed under the administrative code of the\ncity of New York and to those public assistance recipients who are\nproviding child care assistance as part of their work activities or as\ncommunity service under title nine-B of article five of this chapter. A\nsocial services district may submit to the department justification for\na need to impose additional minimum health and safety requirements on\nsuch providers and a plan to monitor compliance with such additional\nrequirements. No such additional requirements or monitoring may be\nimposed without the written approval of the department. Social services\ndistricts shall provide, directly or through referral, technical\nassistance and relevant health and safety information t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_X__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Local social services districts shall establish a differential\npayment rate for child care services provided by licensed or registered\nchild care providers who provide care to a child or children\nexperiencing homelessness. Such differential payment rate shall be no\nless than ten percent higher but no greater than fifteen percent higher\nthan the actual cost of care or the applicable market-related payment\nrate established by the office in regulations, whichever is less.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_X__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Local social services districts shall establish a differential\npayment rate for child care services provided by licensed, registered,\nor enrolled child care providers who provide care to a child during\nnontraditional hours. Nontraditional hours shall mean care provided\nother than between six o'clock ante meridian and seven o'clock post\nmeridian on weekdays. Such differential payment rate shall be no less\nthan ten percent higher but no greater than fifteen percent higher than\nthe actual cost of care or the applicable market-related payment rate\nestablished by the office in regulations, whichever is less.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410_X__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to limit the\nauthority of the office of children and family services to establish\nadditional differential payment rates by regulation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>