<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-430"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-430"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="430"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-430/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-430/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-430/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-430/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_430">
        <num>430</num>
        <heading>Day services; when social services official may furnish</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_430__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to avert a risk of serious impairment or disruption of a family\nunit which would result in the placement of a child outside his own\nhome;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_430__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to enable a child who has been placed in a child care institution\nor other group care facility to be placed in a foster care setting more\nclosely oriented to community or family life;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_430__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to enable a child who has been placed in foster care to return to\nhis family at an earlier time than would otherwise be possible.\n  3.  If the child's family is able to pay part or all of the costs of\nday services, such family shall be required to pay such fees therefor as\nmay be reasonable in the light of such ability pursuant to regulations\nof the department.\n  4.  Day services may be provided by a social services official either\ndirectly or through purchase.  Purchase of such services may be made\nonly from a private non-profit corporation or association, except when\nthe commissioner shall have approved the purchase of such services from\na private proprietary facility by a social services official who has\ndemonstrated a lack of conveniently accessible non-profit facilities\nthat are adequate to provide the required services.\n  5.  As used in this title, "day services" shall mean care and\ntreatment for part of the day of one or more children under eighteen\nyears of age and their families in a program which provides to such\nchildren and families in accordance with their needs various services\nsuch as psychiatric, psychological, social casework, educational,\nvocational, health, transportation and such other services as may be\nappropriate.  Such services shall be provided in accordance with program\nstandards promulgated by the department.  Day services may be continued\nafter the eighteenth birthday of a child in the care of an authorized\nagency and until he becomes twenty-one years of age.  Day services shall\nnot be provided to any children and their families for periods in excess\nof one year, without the approval of the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>