<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-431"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-431"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="431"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-431/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-431/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-431/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-431/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_431">
        <num>431</num>
        <heading>Licensure</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 431.  Licensure.  1.  No place, person, association, corporation,\ninstitution or agency shall operate a day services program without first\nobtaining a permit issued therefor by the department, or otherwise than\nin accordance with the terms of such  permit and with the regulations of\nthe department.\n  2.  The department shall promulgate regulations specifying the\nprocedures for obtaining a permit required pursuant to this section and\nenumerating the documentation needed for such a permit.  The regulations\nshall also include program standards which the department shall develop\nwith the advice of the board of social welfare, the department of mental\nhygiene and the department of education.  An application for a permit\npursuant to this section shall include full information regarding the\napplicant's efforts to secure funding for its day services program.  The\ndepartment shall advise and otherwise assist the applicant in obtaining\nfunds where such funds may be available under the provisions of this and\nany other law.\n  3.  The department shall not issue a permit for the operation of a day\nservices program which includes the provision of care, treatment or\nservices requiring licensure or any other form of approval from or by\nanother state agency or official, unless such license or approval has\nbeen obtained.  There shall be such cooperative and coordinated\narrangements between and among the department and the state departments\nof mental hygiene and education and other appropriate state departments\nand agencies as shall be necessary to assure that applications for\nrequired licenses or other forms of approval will be processed\nexpeditiously.\n  4.  Before any permit issued pursuant to this section is suspended or\nrevoked, or when an application for such permit is denied, the applicant\nor holder of the permit shall be entitled, pursuant to the regulations\nof the department, to a hearing before the department.  However, a\npermit may be temporarily suspended or limited without a hearing for a\nperiod not in excess of thirty days upon written notice to the holder of\nthe permit following a finding that the public health, or any\nindividual's health, safety or welfare, is in imminent danger.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>