<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-432"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-432"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="432"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-432/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-432/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-432/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-432/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_432">
        <num>432</num>
        <heading>State reimbursement; standards of payment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_432__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nExpenditures made by social services officials for day services programs\nand their administration pursuant to the provisions of this title shall,\nif approved by the department, be subject to reimbursement by the state,\nin accordance with the regulations of the department as follows: there\nshall be paid to each social services district</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_432__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount of federal\nfunds, if any, properly received or to be received on account of such\nexpenditures;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_432__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fifty per centum of allowable expenditures for day\nservices and its administration, after first deducting therefrom any\nfederal funds properly received or to be received on account thereof and\nthe amount of any fees paid to the social services official for day\nservices.  The local government share of the cost of day services may be\nmet in whole or in part by donated private funds, exclusive of in-kind\nservices.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_432__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this title, expenditures for administration of\nday services shall include expenditures for compensation of employees in\nconnection with the furnishing of day services, including but not\nlimited to costs incurred for pensions,  federal old age and survivors\ninsurance and health insurance for such employees; training programs for\npersonnel, operation, maintenance and service costs; and such other\nexpenditures as equipment costs, depreciation and charges and rental\nvalues as may be approved by the department.  It shall not include\nexpenditures for capital costs.\n  2.  The department shall, after consultation with appropriate state\nagencies and with the approval of the the director of the budget,\npromulgate regulations establishing standards of payment for day\nservices provided children with public financial support.  Such\nstandards of payment shall include the services required to be provided\nto the child and his family and the cost of such services.  When the\ndepartment has established such standards, reimbursement under this\nsection shall be limited in accordance with such standards.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_432__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Claims for state reimbursement shall be made in such form and\nmanner and at such times and for such periods as the department shall\ndetermine.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_432__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When certified by the department, state reimbursement shall be\npaid from the state treasury upon the audit and warrant of the\ncomptroller out of funds made available therefor.\n  4.  Payment of state reimbursement shall be made to local fiscal\nofficers as in the case of state reimbursement for public assistance and\ncare under other provisions of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>