<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="45-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-45-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_C">
        <num>45-C</num>
        <heading>Direct application by eligible applicants</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 45-c. Direct application by eligible applicants. Upon receipt of a\ncopy of the request for proposals issued pursuant to section\nforty-five-a of this title, an eligible applicant may notify the local\nsocial services district in which its eligible project is located of its\ndesire to participate in the single room occupancy support services\nprogram. In the event that the local social services district does not\nsubmit a proposal pursuant to section forty-five-a of this title, such\neligible applicant that has notified the local social services district\nof its desire to participate may submit an application directly to the\ncommissioner for financial assistance under this title. Criteria to be\nused by the commissioner in awarding funding directly to such eligible\napplicants shall include but not be limited to the anticipated need for\nsingle room occupancy units within the district where the eligible\nproject is located, and the appropriateness of the support services for\nthe population to be served. Before directly awarding any funding to\neligible applicants, the commissioner shall consult with the local\nsocial services district where the eligible project is located regarding\nthe need for single room occupancy units within such district, the\nability of the eligible project to provide single room occupancy\nservices and any other factors which are necessary to effectively\nevaluate direct application by eligible projects. When such applications\nare approved, the commissioner, within the amounts appropriated under\nthis title, and subject to the limitations set forth in this section and\nsection forty-five-d of this title, is authorized to enter into\ncontracts with eligible applicants, to provide financial assistance in\nthe form of grants for eligible costs.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>