<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-457"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-457"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="457"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-457/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-457/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-457/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-457/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_457">
        <num>457</num>
        <heading>Out-of-state adoptive parents</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง  457.  Out-of-state adoptive parents.  With respect to a child who\nhas been adopted within this state but who has been removed from this\nstate by his adoptive parents, or a child who has been adopted by\nresidents of another state or of the commonwealth of Puerto Rico and who\nis, or who is likely to become, a public charge within this state,\npayments under section four hundred fifty-three or four hundred\nfifty-four of this title may be made pursuant to an agreement between\nthe district and the adoptive parents, provided that such agreement is\nin accordance with the regulations of the department promulgated to\nachieve the objective of increasing the number of adoptions of potential\npublic charges, with particular emphasis upon handicapped and hard to\nplace children.  Any such agreement shall become void at such time as it\nis determined by the social services official that a child on whose\nbehalf payments are being received pursuant to such agreement was\nbrought into this state for the sole purpose of qualifying prospective\nout-of-state adoptive parents for such payments.  Such determination may\nbe appealed to the department which, upon receipt of the appeal, shall\nconduct a fair hearing in accordance with the provisions of section four\nhundred fifty-five of this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>