<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-458-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-458-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="458-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-458-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-458-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-458-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-458-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_458_C">
        <num>458-C</num>
        <heading>Payments for non-recurring guardianship expenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 458-c. Payments for non-recurring guardianship expenses. 1. A social\nservices official shall make payments for non-recurring guardianship\nexpenses incurred by or on behalf of the relatives or successor\nguardians who have been approved by the social services official to\nreceive kinship guardianship assistance payments, when such expenses are\nincurred in connection with assuming the guardianship of a foster child\nor a former foster child in regard to successor guardians. The agreement\nfor the payment of non-recurring guardianship expenses must be reflected\nin the written agreement set forth in subdivision four of section four\nhundred fifty-eight-b of this title. In accordance with subdivision two\nof this section, the payments shall be made by the social services\nofficial either to the relative or successor guardian or guardians\ndirectly or to an attorney on behalf of the relative or successor\nguardian or guardians, as applicable, for the allowable amount of\nnon-recurring guardianship expenses incurred in connection with\nobtaining such guardianship.\n  2. The amount of the payment made pursuant to this section shall not\nexceed two thousand dollars for each foster child for whom the\nrelatives, or each former foster child for whom the successor guardians,\nseek guardianship or permanent guardianship and shall be available only\nfor those expenses that are determined to be eligible for reimbursement\nby the social services official in accordance with the regulations of\nthe office of children and family services.\n  3. Payments for non-recurring guardianship expenses made by a social\nservices official pursuant to this section shall be treated as\nadministrative expenditures under title IV-E of the federal social\nsecurity act and shall be reimbursed by the state accordingly.\n  4. As used in this section, non-recurring guardianship expenses shall\nmean reasonable and necessary fees, court costs, attorney fees, and\nother expenses which are directly related to obtaining legal\nguardianship of an eligible child and which are not incurred in\nviolation of federal law or the laws of this state or any other state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>