<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-460-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-460-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="460-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-460-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-460-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-460-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-460-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_460_E">
        <num>460-E</num>
        <heading>Records and reports; confidentiality; information</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 460-e. Records and reports; confidentiality; information. 1. The\ndepartment shall require, collect and maintain such information, records\nor reports as it may determine to be necessary to further the purpose of\nthis article. Organizations and institutions subject to the inspection\nand supervision of the department shall provide such information and\nrecords in such form and at such times as the department shall\ndetermine.\n  2. The department may request from any other state department or state\nor local agency, including the department of mental hygiene, the\ndivision for youth and the board of social welfare, and such other\ndepartment or agency shall furnish, such information as the department\nmay require for the proper performance of its duties under this article.\nThe department shall safeguard the confidentiality of information\nreceived from such departments and agencies. Such other state\ndepartments or state agencies may request from the department, and the\ndepartment shall furnish, such information as such other department or\nagency may require for the proper discharge of its duties. Such\ndepartments and agencies shall safeguard the confidentiality of such\ninformation, records, and reports in the same manner as the department\nin accordance with the provisions of sections one hundred thirty-six,\nfour hundred forty-four and four hundred sixty-one-e of this chapter or\nas otherwise authorized by law.\n  3. Officers or employees of the department shall maintain the\nconfidentiality of facts and information obtained as the result of any\ninspection or investigation of a facility subject to inspection and\nsupervision under this article, in the same manner as information\nreceived under subdivision two of this section.\n  4. All officers of facilities or agencies subject to the inspection of\nthe department shall furnish to the department, on forms provided by the\ndepartment, such information and statistics as it may require, within\nsixty days from the expiration of the state fiscal year or such other\nfiscal period as may be designated by the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>