<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="461-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_461_I">
        <num>461-I</num>
        <heading>Planning and development grants for enriched housing programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 461-i. Planning and development grants for enriched housing\nprograms. 1. The department shall, to the extent funds are available for\nsuch purpose, award planning and development grants to, and contract\nwith, lawfully approved enriched housing programs that qualify for such\ngrants under criteria to be established by the department. Such grants\nshall be made for the purposes of defraying start-up expenses and\nreducing initial operating deficits incurred in the first twelve months\nof a program's operations resulting from initial low occupancy rates.\nUse of such funds may include, but shall not be limited to, paying for\nrent prior to occupancy and security deposits, administrative expenses,\nminor renovations of existing structures, furnishings and household\nequipment, moving expenses of residents and reasonable anticipated\noperating deficits resulting from low initial occupancy rates.\n  2. Any public agency, public corporation or not-for-profit corporation\nwho has filed an application for approval to operate an enriched housing\nprogram, or any lawfully approved enriched housing operator, may make\napplication for a planning and development grant in a manner and form\nprescribed by the department. The department shall make determinations\nof award for each application for such grants at such time that a final\ndetermination is made with respect to approving the establishment of, or\ngranting an operating certificate for, an enriched housing program. The\ndepartment shall award planning and development grants on the basis of\nthe quality of the proposed program, the applicant's financial needs,\nthe geographic distribution of enriched housing programs, and the\navailability of, and demand for, long-term care services in the\ngeographic area to be served by the proposed program.\n  3. The department may award planning and development grants to, and\ncontract with, lawfully approved enriched housing programs under\ncriteria to be established by the department for the purpose of moderate\nrenovations or modifications of existing structures when determined to\nbe necessary by the commissioner. Use of such grants for moderate\nstructural renovations or modifications shall be deemed necessary in\nthose instances where the commissioner determines that, without such\nrenovations or modifications, a geographic area may be underserved\nbecause of the lack of available or suitable existing structures.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>