<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="461-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_461_O">
        <num>461-O</num>
        <heading>Complaint investigation procedures</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 461-o. Complaint investigation procedures. The department shall\nestablish procedures governing the receipt and investigation of\ncomplaints regarding the care afforded to residents of adult care\nfacilities consistent with article eleven of this chapter, as\napplicable. Such procedures shall assure the confidentiality of the\ncomplainant. Such procedures shall include but not be limited to the\nprocedures for reporting complaints, either in writing or orally to the\ndepartment, and the time frames governing the investigation of any such\ncomplaints submitted to the department. Provided however, if any\ncomplaint alleges the abuse or neglect of a resident or involves an\nincident that exposes a resident to cruel or unsafe care or otherwise\nrepresents a serious resident care issue, the department shall ensure\nthat an investigation of any such complaint is initiated immediately and\nin no event commenced less than seventy-two hours from the time such\ncomplaint is received by the department. Upon the conclusion of the\ninvestigation by the department the operator and the complainant shall\nbe notified in writing of the results of such investigation or, as\napplicable, pursuant to article eleven of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>