<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="461-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_461_C">
        <num>461-C</num>
        <heading>Resident care, services and charges</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon\nexpress written approval and authority of the resident, or his or her\nsponsor, if any, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in order to provide additional care, services or\nsupplies, upon the express order of the attending physician of the\nresident, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon thirty days notice to the resident and to his or\nher sponsor, if any, of additional charges and expenses due to increased\ncost of maintenance and operation. However, in the event of any\nemergency arising which affects such resident, additional charges may be\nassessed for the benefit of such resident as are reasonable and\nnecessary for services, materials, equipment and food furnished and\nsupplied during such emergency.\n  2-a.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be an implied warranty of habitability in each\nwritten admission agreement executed pursuant to this section that shall\nensure the premises be fit for human habitation and for the uses\nreasonably intended by the operator and the resident and that the\noccupants of the facility shall not be subjected to any conditions which\nwould be dangerous, hazardous or detrimental to their life, health,\nsafety or welfare. Such statement shall not be read to be in any way\nlimiting a resident's rights to relief in an administrative or judicial\nproceeding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An action for breach of the warranty of habitability and any\nviolation of a written admission agreement may be maintained in a court\nof competent jurisdiction by the resident or representative of the\nresident. The court shall apply New York Rules of Court Part 130 to any\naction brought pursuant to this section.\n  3. The written agreement executed pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection shall include a statement indicating that the resident and any\nperson designated by the resident shall be notified by the operator at\nthe request of the resident pursuant to regulations promulgated by the\ndepartment and, shall be provided written notification by the facility\nnot less than thirty days prior to a termination of the resident's\nadmission and services agreement; a statement that upon discharge or\ntransfer, the resident and any person designated by the resident shall\nbe notified by the operator at the request of the resident pursuant to\nregulations promulgated by the department and, is entitled to a final\nwritten statement of his or her account and that the resident is\nentitled to the prompt return, within three business days, of any of his\nor her money, property or thing of value held in trust or in custody by\nthe facility; a statement which details any and all money, property or\nthing of value which is given, or promised to be given to the facility\non admission or at any other time, including any agreements made by\nthird parties for the benefit of a resident; and such other provisions\nas the department determines necessary to fully inform the resident of\nthose items of care, services, materials, equipment and food that must\nbe provided by the facility pursuant to other applicable laws and\nregulations, and the frequency thereof, and any additional items of\ncare, services, materials, equipment and food that the facility may in\nits discretion agree to provide, and the frequency thereof. Waiver of\nany provision contained herein by a resident sh...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the time of the admission to an adult care facility, other\nthan a shelter for adults, a resident shall submit to the facility a\nwritten report from a physician, a physician assistant or a nurse\npractitioner, which report shall state:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the physician, physician assistant or nurse practitioner has\nphysically examined the resident within one month and the date of such\nexamination;\n  (ii) that the resident is not in need of acute or long term medical or\nnursing care which would require placement in a hospital or residential\nhealth care facility; and\n  (iii) that the resident is not otherwise medically or mentally\nunsuited for care in the facility.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purpose of creating an accessible and available record and\nassuring that a resident is properly placed in such a facility, the\nreport shall also contain the resident's significant medical history and\ncurrent conditions, the prescribed medication regimen, and\nrecommendations for diet, the assistance needed in the activities of\ndaily living and where appropriate, recommendations for exercise,\nrecreation and frequency of medical examinations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such resident shall thereafter be examined by a physician, a\nphysician assistant or a nurse practitioner, at least annually and shall\nsubmit an annual written report in conformity with the provisions of\nthis subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Following a resident's stay in a hospital or residential health\ncare facility, upon return to the adult care facility, the adult care\nfacility shall not be required to obtain the report in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, and instead shall obtain a statement from the\ndischarging facility which shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>state that the resident is appropriate to return to the facility;\nand\n  (ii) include the reason for the resident's stay, the treatment plan to\nbe followed, and any new or changed orders, including medications.\n  The statement shall be completed by a physician, a physician assistant\nor a nurse practitioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing required in this section shall require the use of an\nidentical form in adult care facilities and assisted living residences,\neither upon admission or return.\n  8. The department shall promulgate regulations with respect to the\nsafekeeping and administration of medications in any adult care facility\nsubject to the provisions of section four hundred sixty-c of this\narticle, in accordance with applicable provisions of law, and after\nconsultation with the state department of health and appropriate offices\nof the state department of mental hygiene.\n  9. The department shall, with the consent of a resident living in a\nfacility which has received the lowest rating for eighteen months from\nthe effective date of this subdivision, pursuant to section four hundred\nsixty-one-n of this title, present the resident and any person\ndesignated by the resident with options on relocating such resident to a\nfacility which has obtained a higher rating, or other housing\nalternatives.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>