<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="461-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-461-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_461_J">
        <num>461-J</num>
        <heading>Family type homes for adults; special needs funds</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payments to be used for necessary clothing, recreation,\ntransportation and cultural activities of specified individual residents\nshall not exceed two hundred ninety dollars per resident per year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payments to be used for provision of substitute care to residents\nduring periods of emergency and scheduled absence of operators,\nincluding periods of operator absence for the purposes of education and\ntraining, shall not exceed five hundred dollars per facility per year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_461_J__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payments to be used for health and safety equipment  shall not\nexceed seventy-five dollars per facility per year.\n  2. Social services districts shall establish a separate account for\nspecial needs funds and shall administer payments to operators out of\nsaid account, in accordance with regulations which shall be promulgated\nby the department. The department shall pay district costs out of\navailable appropriations for such purposes, to the extent of one hundred\npercent of the amount expended pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection, in accordance with the provisions of section one hundred\nfifty-three of this chapter. In addition, the department shall, in\naccordance with the provisions of section one hundred fifty-three of\nthis chapter, reimburse one hundred percent of amounts expended by each\ndistrict for administration under this section only to the extent of ten\npercent of the amount paid by such district pursuant to subdivision one\nof this section, and shall thereafter reimburse fifty percent of any\nadditional amounts paid by such district for such administrative costs.\nThe department may make advances to districts which shall then advance\nsuch funds to duly certified operators, to the extent provided for by\ndepartment regulations, in anticipation of costs incurred in meeting the\nspecial needs as set forth in subdivision one of this section and\nrelated administrative costs in accordance with the procedure\nestablished by the commissioner. Nothing contained in this section shall\nbe construed to require expenditures by any district pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section, in excess of the amounts made available\nto the district by the department pursuant to this section.\n  3. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, state reimbursement to\ndistricts may be made only from and to the extent of moneys appropriated\nto the department for such purposes.\n  4. The department shall audit payments and maintenance of accounts in\naccordance w...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>