<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="464-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_464_E">
        <num>464-E</num>
        <heading>Distribution of reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 464-e. Distribution of reports. The commissioner, in conjunction\nwith the advisory committee, shall prepare an interim report within\nthirty months after the effective date of this article, which shall\ninclude a preliminary review of each pilot project. The commissioner, in\nconjunction with such committee, shall also prepare a final report\nwithin sixty months after the effective date of this article.  Such\nfinal report shall contain a description of the various human services\npilot projects  demonstrated and their perceived effect on cost,\ndelivery and accessibility of human services in rural areas. The final\nreport shall describe the effect of each pilot project on existing\nproviders and consumers of such services, as well as the effect on each\ncommunity served. The same report shall identify laws, rules and\nregulations, if any, that should be repealed or amended in order to make\nit possible to properly and efficiently implement such plans or programs\nin other rural areas of the state. Said interim and final reports shall\nbe distributed to all participants in the program, as well as to the\ngovernor and the legislature.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>