<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="464-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-464-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_464_C">
        <num>464-C</num>
        <heading>Advisory committee created</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 464-c. Advisory committee created. 1. An advisory committee shall be\ncreated to assist the commissioner in carrying out the provisions of\nthis article. Such advisory committee shall consist of seven members,\nwith the commissioner or his or her designee serving as chairperson.\nMembership of the committee shall include the following persons or their\ndesignees: the chairperson of the legislative commission on the\ndevelopment of rural resources which was created by chapter four hundred\ntwenty-eight of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-two; the director of\nthe state office of rural affairs; the director of the office for the\naging; the commissioner of the department of health; the commissioner of\nthe division for youth; and the commissioner of the office of mental\nhealth. The chairperson of the advisory committee may invite the\ncommissioner or director, or his or her designee, of any other state\nagency or department, or any other rural human services provider or\nconsumer, to serve as an ex-officio member of the committee. The\ncommissioner shall take actions to promote the efficient and effective\noperation of the advisory committee.\n  2. The advisory committee shall:\n  a. Review and recommend to the commissioner guidelines for the\noperation of the rural human services networking program;\n  b. Recommend any changes in statutes or regulations necessary to\naccomplish the purposes of this article;\n  c. Assist the department in the evaluation of individual pilot\nprojects and of the rural human services networking program; and\n  d. Assist in the development of interim and final reports, in\naccordance with section four hundred sixty-four-e of this article.\n  e. Assist the commissioner in determining those rural areas to receive\npriority consideration in selecting pilot project sites, pursuant to\nsubdivision four of section four hundred sixty-four-d of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>