<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-474"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-474"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="474"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-474/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-474/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-474/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-474/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_474">
        <num>474</num>
        <heading>Reports to supervisors of appointments and committals to charitable institutions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 474.  Reports to supervisors of appointments and committals to\ncharitable institutions. 1.  Every judge, justice, superintendent or\npublic welfare official or other person who is authorized by law to make\nappointments or commitments to any state charitable institution, in\nwhich the board, instruction, care or clothing is a charge against any\ncounty, town or city, shall make a written report to the clerk of the\nboard of supervisors of the county, or of the county in which any town\nis situated, or to the city clerk of any city, which is liable for any\nsuch board, instruction, care or clothing, within ten days after such\nappointment or commitment, and shall therein state, when known, the\nnationality, age, sex and residence of each person so appointed or\ncommitted and the length of time of such appointment or commitment.\n  2.  This and the two following sections shall apply to each of the\nasylums, reformatories, homes, retreats, penitentiaries, jails or other\ninstitutions, except public homes, in each of the counties of this state\nexcept the county of Kings, in which the board, instruction, care or\nclothing of persons committed thereto is, or shall be, a charge against\nany county or town therein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>