<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-475"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-475"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="475"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-475/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-475/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-475/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-475/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_475">
        <num>475</num>
        <heading>Reports by officers of certain institutions to clerks of supervisors and cities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 475.  Reports by officers of certain institutions to clerks of\nsupervisors and cities. 1.  The keeper, superintendent, secretary,\ndirector or other proper officer of a state charitable institution to\nwhich any person is committed or appointed, whose board, care,\ninstruction, tuition or clothing shall be chargeable to any city, town\nor county, shall make a written report to the clerk of such city or to\nthe clerk of the board of supervisors of the county, or of the county in\nwhich such town is situated, within ten days after receiving such person\ntherein.\n  2.  Such report shall state when such person was received into the\ninstitution, and, when known, the name, age, sex, nationality,\nresidence, length of time of commitment or appointment, the name of the\nofficer making the same, and the sum chargeable per week, month or year\nfor such person.\n  3.  If any person so appointed or committed to any such institution\nshall die, be removed or discharged, such officers shall immediately\nreport to the clerk of the board of supervisors of the county, or of the\ncounty in which such town is situated, or to the city clerk of the city\nfrom which such person was committed or appointed, the date of such\ndeath, removal or discharge.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>