<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="481-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-481-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_481_F">
        <num>481-F</num>
        <heading>William B</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 481-f. William B. Hoyt Memorial children and family trust fund. 1.\nThere is hereby established in the joint custody of the comptroller and\nthe commissioner of taxation and finance a separate and distinct\naccount, to be known as the William B. Hoyt Memorial children and family\ntrust fund. Such account shall be classified by the comptroller as an\nexpendable trust. Such account shall consist of any moneys appropriated\nto the department for the purposes of the programs authorized pursuant\nto this article and funds from any other source, including but not\nlimited to, federal funds, donations from private individuals,\ncorporations or foundations, for the implementation of programs provided\nfor in this article. All funds received by the comptroller on behalf of\nthe William B. Hoyt Memorial children and family trust fund shall be\ndeposited by the comptroller to the credit of the William B. Hoyt\nMemorial children and family trust fund. Notwithstanding the provisions\nof this subdivision, funds granted to the department pursuant to the\nfederal child abuse prevention and treatment act shall not be deposited\nto the credit of the William B. Hoyt Memorial children and family trust\nfund.\n  2. Donations from private individuals, corporations, or foundations\ndeposited in the William B.  Hoyt Memorial children and family trust\nfund may be invested by the comptroller pursuant to the provisions of\nsection ninety-eight-a of the state finance law. Any income from such\ninvestments shall be deposited to the credit of the William B. Hoyt\nMemorial children and family trust fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>