<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="482-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_482_C">
        <num>482-C</num>
        <heading>Statewide settlement house program; awarding of grants</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_482_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>appropriate accounting and fiscal control procedures that assure\nthat funds are expended in accordance with this article, including the\nfiling of an annual financial statement by each provider; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_482_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>appropriate written records regarding the number of individuals\nand families served and the type and extent of services rendered by the\nsettlement house.\n  4. The commissioner shall solicit and select applications for the\nprovision of programs and services funded pursuant to this article. It\nis necessary that settlement houses receiving funding pursuant to this\narticle demonstrate a plan to raise one dollar for each two dollars of\nstate grants received.  Subsequent year funding may be adjusted to\nreflect prior years' experience.\n  5. The commissioner may issue a request for applications to the extent\nfunds are available on a multi-year basis.\n  6. The commissioner shall make grants of up to fifty thousand dollars\nto settlement houses following approval of an acceptable plan submitted\npursuant to the request for applications so long as there are funds\navailable. The commissioner shall notify the local social services\ndistrict of a grant award to a settlement house in that district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>