<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="482-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-482-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_482_A">
        <num>482-A</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 482-a. Legislative findings and purpose. The legislature finds that\npublic policy experts and state and local agencies have been searching\nfor a model of service delivery that will insure programmatically\neffective and cost-efficient delivery of services to inner-city families\nand neighborhoods, and that the emerging consensus is that the best\nmodels provide comprehensive, coordinated, neighborhood-based and\nfamily-focused services. The legislature further finds that New York\nstate's existing network of fifty-eight settlement houses can contribute\nto providing these comprehensive, coordinated, neighborhood-based and\nfamily-focused services in a cost-effective manner, and that the\ncapacity of these settlement houses to provide and enhance these\nservices can be increased if the settlement houses are provided with\nadditional resources to implement greater neighborhood outreach, to\ndirect individuals and family members to appropriate settlement and\ncommunity-based resources, to monitor the progress of these individuals,\nand to plan and coordinate intra-agency and community services so that\ncommunity residents have easy access to a range of services that respond\nto the varied and often multiple needs of individuals and families.\n  It is the intent of the legislature to increase the funds available to\nsettlement houses for the purpose of providing a comprehensive range of\nservices to the residents of the neighborhoods they serve, and that\nfunds provided pursuant to this article will be complemented by\nprivately-raised contributions to the settlement-houses for the program\nservices funded pursuant to this article. The legislature does not\nintend that these funds be used as a substitute for any funds currently\navailable from federal, state or local sources for the provision of\nneighborhood-based service delivery programs provided by settlement\nhouses.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>