<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-483-AA"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-483-AA"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="483-AA"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-483-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-483-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-483-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-483-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_483_AA">
        <num>483-AA</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_483_AA__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Human trafficking victim" means a person who is a victim of sex\ntrafficking as defined in section 230.34 of the penal law or a victim of\nlabor trafficking as defined in section 135.35 of the penal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_483_AA__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Pre-certified victim of human trafficking" is a person who has a\npending application for federal certification as a victim of a severe\nform of trafficking in persons as defined in section 7105 of title 22 of\nthe United States Code (Trafficking Victims Protection) but has not yet\nobtained such certification, or a person who has reported a crime to law\nenforcement and it reasonably appears to law enforcement that the person\nis such a victim.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_483_AA__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Short-term safe house" means a residential facility operated by a\nnot-for-profit agency with experience in providing services to human\ntrafficking victims, that provides emergency shelter, services and care\nto human trafficking victims including food, shelter, clothing, medical\ncare, counseling and appropriate crisis intervention services and\npromotes a safe living environment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_483_AA__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Long-term safe house" means a residential facility operated by a\nnot-for-profit agency with experience in providing services to human\ntrafficking victims, that provides shelter for human trafficking victims\nand promotes a safe living environment. In addition, a long-term safe\nhouse shall provide or assist with securing necessary services for such\nhuman trafficking victims either through direct provision of services,\nor through written agreements with other community and public agencies\nfor the provision of services including but not limited to housing,\nassessment, case management, medical care, legal, mental health and\nsubstance use disorder services. Such safe house, in accordance with a\nservice plan for such human trafficking victim, shall also provide\ncounseling and therapeutic services, educational services including life\nskills services, job training and placement and planning services to\nsuccessfully transition such person back into the community.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>