<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="SOS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-64"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-64"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="64"/>
          <FRBRname value="SOS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/sos/section-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_64">
        <num>64</num>
        <heading>Separation of social services from eligibility and assistance payments functions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 64. Separation of social services from eligibility and assistance\npayments functions. Notwithstanding any provision of law, rule or\nregulation every social services district shall be organized to effect a\nseparation of social services from eligibility and assistance payments\nfunctions as follows:\n  1. The commissioner shall issue within ten days of the effective date\nhereof, guidelines to the social services districts of the state\noutlining the principles and purposes to be attained in the separation\nof social services from the functions of eligibility and assistance\npayments, and defining the content of services which may be included\nunder the term "social services" and of the functions associated with\neligibility and assistance payments.\n  2. Each social services district shall submit to the commissioner by\nJuly first, nineteen hundred seventy-one, its own plan for separation,\ntogether with its timetable for implementation of the plan.\n  3. Upon finding that the plan conforms to the applicable minimum\nfederal requirements, the commissioner shall approve such plan.\n  4. Each social services district shall submit to the commissioner, in\naccordance with applicable federal law and regulations, modifications of\nits approved plan for separation of social services from eligibility and\nassistance payments functions. Each social services district shall\nprepare, in accordance with applicable federal law and regulations, for\nthe effective operation of such approved plan as so modified.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>