<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="101"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_101">
        <num>101</num>
        <heading>Education department; regents of the university</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 101. Education department; regents of the university.  There shall\ncontinue to be in the state government an education department.  The\ndepartment is charged with the general management and supervision of all\npublic schools and all of the educational work of the state, including\nthe operations of The University of the State of New York and the\nexercise of all the functions of the education department, of The\nUniversity of the State of New York, of the regents of the university\nand of the commissioner of education and the performance of all their\npowers and duties, which were transferred to the education department by\nsection three hundred twelve of the state departments law or shall have\nbeen prescribed by law before March sixteenth, nineteen hundred\ntwenty-seven, whether in terms vested in such department or university\nor in any sub-department, division or bureau thereof or in such\ncommissioner, board or officer, and such functions, powers and duties\nshall continue to be vested in the education department continued by\nthis chapter and shall continue to be exercised and performed therein by\nor through the appropriate officer, sub-department, division or bureau\nthereof, together with such functions, powers and duties as hereafter\nmay be conferred or imposed upon such department by law.  All the\nprovisions of this chapter, in so far as they are not inconsistent with\nthe provisions of this chapter as hereby amended or may be made\napplicable, shall apply to the education department continued by this\nchapter as hereby amended and to The University of the State of New\nYork, the board of regents of the university, the commissioner of\neducation and to the divisions, bureaus and officers in such department.\nThe head of the department shall continue to be the regents of The\nUniversity of the State of New York, who shall appoint, and at pleasure\nmay remove, the commissioner of education.  The commissioner shall\ncontinue to be the chief administrative officer of the department.  The\nregents also may appoint and, at pleasure, remove a deputy commissioner\nof education, who shall perform such duties as the regents may assign to\nhim by rule and who, in the absence or disability of the commissioner or\nwhen a vacancy exists in the office of commissioner, shall exercise and\nperform the functions, powers and duties conferred or imposed on the\ncommissioner by this chapter.  The regents of The University of the\nState of New York shall continue to constitute a board and The\nUniversity of the State of New York, which was continued under such name\nby section two of article eleven of the constitution, shall continue to\nbe governed and all its corporate powers to be exercised by such board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>