<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="107"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_107">
        <num>107</num>
        <heading>Compact for education</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_107__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n  C. The commission shall have a seal.\n  D. The commission shall elect annually, from among its members, a\nchairman, who shall be a governor, a vice chairman and a treasurer. The\ncommission shall provide for the appointment of an executive director.\nSuch executive director shall serve at the pleasure of the commission,\nand together with the treasurer and such other personnel as the\ncommission may deem appropriate shall be bonded in such amount as the\ncommission shall determine. The executive director shall be secretary.\n  E. Irrespective of the civil service, personnel or other merit system\nlaws of any of the party states, the executive director subject to the\napproval of the steering committee shall appoint, remove or discharge\nsuch personnel as may be necessary for the performance of the functions\nof the commission, and shall fix the duties and compensation of such\npersonnel. The commission in its bylaws shall provide for the personnel\npolicies and programs of the commission.\n  F. The commission may borrow, accept or contract for the services of\npersonnel from any party jurisdiction, the United States, or any\nsubdivision or agency of the aforementioned governments, or from any\nagency of two or more of the party jurisdictions or their subdivisions.\n  G. The commission may accept for any of its purposes and functions\nunder this compact any and all donations, and grants of money,\nequipment, supplies, materials and services, conditional or otherwise,\nfrom any state, the United States, or any other governmental agency, or\nfrom any person, firm, association, foundation, or corporation, and may\nreceive, utilize and dispose of the same. Any donation or grant accepted\nby the commission pursuant to this paragraph or services borrowed\npursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_107__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this article shall be reported in the\nannual report of the commission. Such report shall include the nature,\namount and conditions, if any, of the donation, grant, or services\nborrowed, and the identity of the donor or lender.\n  H. The commission may establish and maintain such facilities as may be\nnecessary for the transacting of its business. The commission may\nacquire, hold, and convey real and personal property and any interest\ntherein.\n  I. The commission shall adopt bylaws for the conduct of its business\nand shall have the power to amend and rescind these bylaws. The\ncommission shall publish its bylaws in convenient form and shall file a\ncopy thereof and a copy of any amendment thereto, with the appropriate\nagency or officer in each of the party states.\n  J. The commission annually shall make to the governor and legislature\nof each party state a report covering the activities of the commission\nfor the preceding year. The commission may make such additional reports\nas it may deem desirable.\n                            Article IV. Powers.\n  In addition to authority conferred on the commission by other\nprovisions of the compact, the commission shall have authority to:\n  1. Collect, correlate, analyze and interpret information and data\nconcerning educational needs and resources.\n  2. Encourage and foster research in all aspects of education, but with\nspecial reference to the desirable scope of instruction, organization,\nadministration, and instructional methods and standards employed or\nsuitable for employment in public educational systems.\n  3. Develop proposals for adequate financing of education as a whole\nand at each of its many levels.\n  4. Conduct or participate in research of the types referred to in this\narticle in any instance where the commission finds that such research is\nnecessary for the advancement of the purposes and policies of this\ncompact, utilizing fully the resources of national associations,\nregional compact...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_107__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this compact,\nprovided that the commission takes specific action setting aside such\nfunds prior to incurring an obligation to be met in whole or in part in\nsuch manner. Except where the commission makes use of funds available to\nit pursuant to article III</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_107__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>thereof, the commission shall not incur\nany obligation prior to the allotment of funds by the party states\nadequate to meet the same.\n  D. The commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and\ndisbursements. The receipts and disbursements of the commission shall be\nsubject to the audit and accounting procedures established by its\nbylaws. However, all receipts and disbursements of funds handled by the\ncommission shall be audited yearly by a qualified public accountant, and\nthe report of the audit shall be included in and become part of the\nannual reports of the commission.\n  E. The accounts of the commission shall be open at any reasonable time\nfor inspection by duly constituted officers of the party states and by\nany persons authorized by the commission.\n  F. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to prevent commission\ncompliance with laws relating to audit or inspection of accounts by or\non behalf of any government contributing to the support of the\ncommission.\n        Article VIII. Eligible Parties; Entry Into and Withdrawal.\n  A. This compact shall have as eligible parties all states,\nterritories, and possessions of the United States, the District of\nColumbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico. In respect of any such\njurisdiction not having a governor, the term "governor", as used in this\ncompact, shall mean the closest equivalent official of such\njurisdiction.\n  B. Any state or other eligible jurisdiction may enter into this\ncompact and it shall become binding thereon when it has adopted the\nsame:  provided that in order to enter into initial effect, adoption by\nat least ten eligible party jurisdictions shall be required.\n  C. Adoption of the compact may be either by enactment thereof or by\nadherence thereto by the governor; provided that in the absence of\nenactment, adherence by the governor shall be sufficient to make his\nstate a party only until December thirty-one, nineteen hundred\nsixty-seven. During any peri...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_107__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the compact, the commission shall\nfile a copy of its bylaws and any amendment thereto with the governor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>