<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1101"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1101">
        <num>1101</num>
        <heading>Establishment of county vocational education and extension boards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1101. Establishment of county vocational education and extension\nboards.\n  1. The board of supervisors or other governing elective body of any\ncounty may adopt a resolution by a majority vote of the members of the\nboard establishing a county vocational education and extension board for\nthe purpose of giving instruction in agriculture and home economics and\nsuch other special subjects as may be approved by the commissioner of\neducation.\n  2. Upon the adoption of the resolution as provided in the preceding\nsubdivision the board of supervisors or other governing elective body\nshall appoint a board which shall be known as "The Vocational Education\nand Extension Board of the County of .................... " (insert here\nthe name of the county). Such board shall consist of nine members who\nshall serve for a period of nine years each except that members first\nappointed shall be appointed for such terms that the term of one member\nwill expire each year, and their successors shall thereafter each be\nappointed for a full term of nine years respectively. At least three\nmembers of this board shall be appointed upon recommendations made by\nthe farm and home bureau associations of the county and at least three\nmembers upon recommendations made by the district superintendents of the\ncounty. Vacancies occurring in such office shall be filled by the board\nof supervisors or other governing elective body for the unexpired term.\n  3. The fiscal year of the vocational education and extension board of\neach county shall begin on July first and end on June thirtieth.\n  4. A county vocational education and extension board established\npursuant to this section is hereby created a body corporate. All\nproperty which is now vested in, or shall hereafter be transferred to, a\ncounty vocational education and extension board shall be held by it as a\ncorporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>