<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1102"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1102">
        <num>1102</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of vocational education and extension boards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1102__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ninsubordination, immoral character or conduct unbecoming a teacher;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1102__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ninefficiency, incompetency, physical or mental disability or neglect of\nduty.\n  4. It shall make an annual report in writing to the regents of The\nUniversity of the State of New York and to the board of supervisors or\nother governing elective body on or before the first day of October.  It\nshall also make such other reports as may be required by the\ncommissioner of education or by the board of supervisors or other\ngoverning elective body.\n  5. It may appoint any advisory committees deemed necessary.\n  6. It shall cooperate with existing public agencies in conducting\ncareer education and extension work in the county.\n  7. It shall have such other powers and shall perform such other duties\nas may be necessary to carry into effect the purposes of part one of\nthis article.\n  8. It may request the board of supervisors to contribute the use of or\nlease land, buildings and other facilities to it, and to contribute to\nthe cost of operating and maintaining the program of the county\nvocational education and extension board, and a board of supervisors\nshall have power to make appropriations toward such cost and to\ncontribute the use of or lease land, buildings, and other facilities to\nit.\n  9. It shall appoint one of its members as president, one of its\nmembers or another qualified school district voter in the county as\nclerk and another qualified school district voter in the county as\ntreasurer.  All moneys accruing or appropriated to the board shall be\npaid to the treasurer of the board. The clerk and treasurer may be paid\nsuch compensation as may be fixed by the board. The treasurer shall\nfurnish a surety bond of a surety company authorized to do business in\nthe state of New York. The form and amount of such bond shall be\napproved by the board and the cost thereof shall be a charge against the\nfunds of said board.\n  10. It shall designate a bank or banks for the deposit of money.  Such\ndesignation shall be made of a bank within the county u...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>