<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1110"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1110">
        <num>1110</num>
        <heading>Establishment of a special education district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1110. Establishment of a special education district.\n  1. The board of supervisors or other governing elective body of\nWestchester county shall have power to adopt a resolution by a majority\nvote of the members of such board to establish within the county a\nspecial education district which shall include all the territory within\nthe county. A city school district in such county having a population of\nfifty thousand or more inhabitants shall be excluded from such special\neducation district provided the board of education of such city shall\nadopt a resolution requesting that such city school district be so\nexcluded and file such resolution with the board of supervisors or other\ngoverning elective body within sixty days after the establishment of\nsuch special education district. With the approval of the county\ncommission for special education to be appointed as hereinafter\nprovided, a city school district so excluded may later become a part of\nsuch special education district upon the written application by the\nboard of education of such city school district.\n  2. Upon the establishment of such special education district the board\nof supervisors or other governing elective body shall appoint a board\nwhich shall be known as the county commission for special education.\nSuch commission shall consist of five members who shall serve for a\nperiod of five years each, except that members first appointed shall be\nappointed for such terms that the term of one member will expire each\nyear, and their successors shall thereafter each be appointed for a full\nterm of five years, respectively. Vacancies occurring in such office\nshall be filled by the board of supervisors or other governing elective\nbody for the unexpired term.\n  3. Members of such commission shall serve without compensation except\ntheir actual and necessary travelling expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>