<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1124"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1124"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1124"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1124">
        <num>1124</num>
        <heading>Distribution of funds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1124. Distribution of funds. 1. Service centers for independent\nliving shall be funded out of appropriations available for such purposes\nto the extent of the entire approved budget of such centers.\n  2. Budgets submitted by service centers shall be approved in\naccordance with regulations of the commissioner, subject to approval of\nthe director of the budget.\n  3. Service centers shall be located in the cities of Albany, Buffalo,\nRochester, Syracuse, Utica, White Plains, Binghamton, Kingston,\nPoughkeepsie, Jamestown, Yonkers, the counties of Queens, Kings, Nassau,\nBronx, Richmond, New York and Suffolk.\n  4. Additional service centers shall be located in the cities of\nNiagara Falls, Olean, Troy, Amsterdam, Newburgh, Corning, Ithaca,\nCortland, Auburn, Watertown, Plattsburgh, Batavia, Massena and Glens\nFalls, the counties of Delaware and Rockland, the county of Orange, in\neither the city of Middletown or Port Jervis or in the town of Deerpark,\nGreenville, Mount Hope, Warwick or Wawayanda or in the village of\nGoshen, in the county of New York to serve the Harlem community, and in\nthe counties of Putnam, Sullivan and Herkimer.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>