<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1501"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1501"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1501"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1501">
        <num>1501</num>
        <heading>Existing school districts continued</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1501. Existing school districts continued.  1. All school districts\norganized either by special laws or pursuant to the provisions of a\ngeneral law are hereby continued.\n  2. a. Common school districts and union free school districts so\norganized may be altered or dissolved as provided in this article.\n  b. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or of any other\ngeneral or special law to the contrary, all school districts which do\nnot maintain a home school on March first, nineteen hundred sixty-six,\nand had not prior to October first, nineteen hundred sixty-five voted to\nreopen such home school and expended monies for construction or\nrehabilitation of such home school, provided that they are contiguous,\neither directly, or through other such districts, to a union free,\ncentral or city school district maintaining a twelve grade school system\n(not counting kindergarten) and with which such school districts are\nscheduled to be reorganized pursuant to the state plan for school\ndistrict reorganization under section three hundred fourteen of this\nchapter, are hereby abolished as of July first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-nine, and are hereby made a part of such contiguous union free,\ncentral or city school district. The provisions of section fifteen\nhundred fourteen, fifteen hundred seventeen and fifteen hundred eighteen\nof this chapter shall apply in all such cases.\n  c. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph b of this subdivision,\nany such district desiring a change in such state plan may petition the\ncommissioner for such change as provided in section three hundred\nfourteen of this chapter. The status of such district shall be\nmaintained pending such proceeding, and if any other such district or\ndistricts is or are contiguous to a union free, central or city school\ndistrict only through such petitioning district, then and in that event,\nthe status of such other district or districts shall also be maintained\npending such proceeding. The petitioning district and such other\ndistrict or districts contiguous with a union free, central or city\nschool district only through such petitioning district shall become a\npart of such other union free, central or city school district as the\ncommissioner or the court may order; in such case the provisions of\nparagraph b of this subdivision shall become applicable, and the\nabolition of such school districts shall become effective as of July\nfirst next following the final determination of the petition; if, in\nsuch case, any other school district or districts indirectly contiguous\nto such union free, central or city school district loses its contiguity\ntherewith, the commissioner or the court, as the case may be, in the\norder, shall make an appropriate disposition of such district or\ndistricts.\n  3. Central school districts may be organized under and are subject to\nthe provisions of article thirty-seven.\n  4. Central high school districts may be altered under and are subject\nto the provisions of article thirty-nine.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>