<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1509"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1509"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1509"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1509">
        <num>1509</num>
        <heading>Hearing of objections to order for alteration without consent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1509. Hearing of objections to order for alteration without consent.\n1. Within ten days after making and filing such order the district\nsuperintendent shall give at least a week's notice in writing to the\ntrustees of all districts affected by the proposed alterations, that at\na specified time, and at a named place within the town in which one of\nthe districts to be affected lies, he will hear the objections to the\nalteration.\n  2. The trustees of any district to be affected by such order may\nrequest the supervisor and town clerk of each of the towns, within which\nsuch districts shall wholly or partly lie, to join with the district\nsuperintendent as a local board.\n  3. At the time and place mentioned in the notice, such superintendent,\nwith the supervisors and town clerks, if they shall attend and act,\nshall hear and decide the matter, and the decision shall be final unless\nduly appealed from.  Such decision must either affirm or vacate such\norder, and must be filed with and recorded by the town clerk of the town\nin which the property to be transferred shall lie, and a tie vote shall\nbe regarded a decision for the purposes of an appeal on the merits.\nUpon such appeal the commissioner of education may affirm, modify or\nvacate the order of the district superintendent or the action of the\nlocal board.\n  4. A supervisor and town clerk shall be entitled each to one dollar\nand fifty cents a day for each day's service in any proceeding under\nthis section, to be levied and paid as a charge upon their town.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>