<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1512"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1512"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1512"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1512/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1512/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1512/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1512/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1512">
        <num>1512</num>
        <heading>Proceedings at meeting for consolidation; adoption of resolution; proceedings to be filed</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1512. Proceedings at meeting for consolidation; adoption of\nresolution; proceedings to be filed.  1. Such meeting shall be organized\nas provided in section fifteen hundred twenty-three. Such meeting may\nadopt a resolution to consolidate such districts if two-thirds of the\nqualified electors of each district having less than fifteen of such\nelectors are present, or in case of districts having fifteen or more\nqualified electors if ten or more are present. The vote upon such\nresolution shall be by ballot or by taking and recording the ayes and\nnoes. If the vote shall be by taking and recording the ayes and noes,\nthe clerk and such assistants as may be provided for him by the meeting\nshall keep a poll-list upon which shall be recorded the names of all\nqualified electors voting upon the resolution, the districts in which\nsuch electors reside, and how each elector voted. If the vote shall be\nby ballot, one or more inspectors of election shall be appointed in such\nmanner as the meeting shall determine, who shall receive the votes cast,\ncanvass the same and announce the result of the ballot to the chairman.\nIf the vote shall be by ballot then voting machines may be used in the\nmanner prescribed by section two thousand thirty-five of this title and\nprovision shall be made for absentee ballots as provided in section two\nthousand eighteen-a or two thousand eighteen-b of this title, whichever\nshall apply, and early mail ballots as provided in section two thousand\neighteen-e or two thousand eighteen-f of this title, whichever shall\napply. If it shall appear that a majority of the qualified electors\npresent and voting from each district are in favor of such resolution,\nit shall be declared adopted and where at least one of the districts\nconsolidated is a union free school district it shall be lawful for such\nmeeting thereafter to proceed to the election of a board of education as\nprovided in sections seventeen hundred two and seventeen hundred four of\nthis title. If a majority of the qualified electors present and voting\nfrom each district are not in favor of such resolution, all further\nproceedings at such meeting, except a motion to reconsider or adjourn,\nshall be dispensed with and no such meeting shall be again called within\none year thereafter.\n  2. Copies of such request, notice of meeting, order of the\ncommissioner of education directing a qualified elector to call such\nmeeting, if any, and the minutes of the meeting, including the record of\nthe vote upon the resolution and where at least one of the districts\nconsolidated is a union free school district if such resolution be\nadopted a record of the declaration of the election of a board of\neducation, duly certified by the chairman and clerk, shall be\ntransmitted by either the chairman or clerk, one to the commissioner of\neducation, and one to the district superintendent of schools in whose\njurisdiction such districts are located.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>