<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1513"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1513"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1513"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1513">
        <num>1513</num>
        <heading>Order creating consolidated district; effect</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1513. Order creating consolidated district; effect.  The district\nsuperintendent shall thereupon, in case of an affirmative vote, issue an\norder consolidating such districts and creating a common school\ndistrict, or union free school district, as the case may be, designating\nsuch district by a simplified name in accordance with section three\nhundred fifteen of this chapter.  Such order shall take effect at some\ndate to be specified therein, not more than three months after the date\nof the meeting.  He shall file such order in the town clerk's office of\nthe town in which such districts are located.  If such districts are\nlocated in two or more supervisory districts, such order shall be\nexecuted jointly by the district superintendents of such districts.\nSuch order shall have the same effect as an order executed by a district\nsuperintendent dissolving two or more common school districts and\nforming a new district therefrom, or dissolving one or more of such\ndistricts and uniting the territory thereof to a union free school\ndistrict.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>