<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1523"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1523"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1523"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1523/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1523/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1523/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1523/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1523">
        <num>1523</num>
        <heading>Proceedings at meeting and effect of affirmative vote</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1523.  Proceedings at meeting and effect of affirmative vote.  1.\nAny such meeting held pursuant to section fifteen hundred twenty-two\nshall be organized by the election of a chairman and clerk and may be\nadjourned from time to time, by a majority vote, provided that such\nadjournment shall not be for a longer period than ten days; and whenever\nat any such meeting duly called and held under the provisions of\nsubdivisions one to four, inclusive, of section fifteen hundred\ntwenty-two, at least fifteen qualified voters of the districts shall be\npresent; or at such meeting duly called and held under the provisions of\nsubdivisions five and six of section fifteen hundred twenty-two, at\nleast fifteen qualified voters of each of the two or more adjoining\ndistricts, joining in the request, shall be present, such meeting may,\nby the affirmative vote of a majority present and voting, adopt a\nresolution to establish a union free school district in said district,\nor to consolidate the two or more adjoining districts by establishing a\nunion free school district in said districts pursuant to the notice of\nsaid meeting. If said meeting shall determine to establish a union free\nschool district in said districts as aforesaid, it shall be lawful for\nsuch meeting thereafter to proceed to the election of a board of\neducation as provided in sections seventeen hundred two and seventeen\nhundred four of this chapter.\n  2. The district superintendent in whose district the union free school\ndistrict is thus organized shall designate such district by a simplified\nname in accordance with section three hundred fifteen of this chapter\nand the said board shall have the name and style of the board of\neducation of (adding the designation aforesaid).\n  3. Copies of said request, notice of meeting, order of the\ncommissioner of education directing some inhabitant to call said\nmeeting, if any, and minutes of said meeting, duly certified by the\nchairman and clerk thereof, shall be transmitted and deposited,\nimmediately after such meeting by one of such officers, one to and with\nthe town clerk, one to and with the district superintendent in whose\njurisdiction said districts are located, and one to and with the\ncommissioner of education.\n  4. If at any such meeting, the question as to the establishment of a\nunion free school district shall not be decided in the affirmative, as\naforesaid, then all further proceedings at such meeting, except a motion\nto reconsider or adjourn, shall be dispensed with, and no such meeting\nshall be again called within one year thereafter.\n  5. When any such meeting shall have established a union free school\ndistrict in said districts, such union free school district shall not be\ndissolved within the period of one year from the first Tuesday of August\nnext after such meeting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>