<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1604"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1604">
        <num>1604</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of trustees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1604__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a\nrecreation project or a youth service project operated by one or more\nmunicipalities or by a school district, if such project is authorized\nand approved by the state youth commission, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1604__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a youth bureau or\nagency or activity or project of a county, town, city or village which\nis devoted to the welfare of youth therein or to providing leisure-time\nactivities for youth or assistance to children, as authorized in section\nninety-five of the general municipal law, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1604__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one or more playgrounds\nand neighborhood recreation centers operated and maintained by one or\nmore cities except New York, Buffalo and Rochester, counties except Erie\nand the counties within the city of New York, towns or villages, whether\nor not any school board or district joins in such operating and\nmaintaining, as authorized in section two hundred forty-four-b of the\ngeneral municipal law. In any case when such motor vehicle shall be\nleased as provided in this subdivision, public liability and property\ndamage insurance, fire insurance and compensation insurance of drivers\nshall be provided and collision insurance shall be provided in the\namount of the value of the vehicle, to protect the lessor. The\nadditional cost of such insurance shall be paid by the lessee. No part\nof the costs and expenses resulting from operation, maintenance and\nrepair of such vehicles during the leasing thereof shall be included in\ndetermining the amount of any form of state aid received by such school\ndistrict.\n  21-a. To lease a motor vehicle or vehicles to be used for the\ntransportation of the children of the district from a school district,\nboard of cooperative educational services or county vocational education\nand extension board or from any other source, under the conditions\nspecified in this subdivision. No such agreement for the lease of a\nmotor vehicle or vehicles shall be for a term of more than one school\nyear, provided that when authorized by a vote of the qualified voters of\nthe district such lease may have a term of up to five years, or eight\nyears for the lease of zero-emission school buses as defined in section\nthirty-six hundred thirty-eight of this chapter. Where the trustee or\nboard of trustees enter into a lease of a motor vehicle or vehicles\npursuant to this subdivision for a term of one school year or less, such\ntrustee or board shall not be authorized to enter into another lease for\nthe same or an equivalent replacement vehicle or vehi...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1604__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a trustee of the school district;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1604__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the clerk or treasurer of the school district;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1604__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the superintendent of schools or other official of the district\nresponsible for business management;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1604__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the person designated as purchasing agent; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1604__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>clerical or professional personnel directly involved in accounting\nand purchasing functions of the school district.\n  b. Such claims auditor or deputy claims auditor shall not be required\nto be a resident of the district, and the positions of claims auditor\nand deputy claims auditor shall be classified in the exempt class of the\ncivil service. The trustees, at any time after the establishment of the\noffice of claims auditor or deputy claims auditor, may adopt a\nresolution abolishing such office, whereupon such office shall be\nabolished. When the office of claims auditor shall have been established\nand a claims auditor shall have been appointed and shall have qualified,\nthe powers and duties of the trustees with respect to claims auditing,\nand allowing or rejecting all accounts, charges, claims or demands\nagainst the school district, shall devolve upon and thereafter be\nexercised by such claims auditor during the continuance of such office.\nThe trustees shall be permitted ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1604__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inter-municipal\ncooperative agreements,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1604__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>shared services to the extent authorized by\nsection nineteen hundred fifty of this title, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1604__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>independent\ncontractors, to fulfill this function.\n  c. When the trustees delegate the claims audit function using an\ninter-municipal cooperative agreement, shared service authorized by\nsection nineteen hundred fifty of this title, or an independent\ncontractor, the trustees shall be responsible for auditing all claims\nfor services from the entity providing the delegated claims auditor,\neither directly or through a delegation to a different independent\nentity.\n  36. In its discretion to provide that the proceeds of the sale or\nappropriation of school district real property shall, after being used\nfor any legally required purpose be used to reduce real property taxes\nin such district for a period not to exceed ten school years, or such\nlesser period as it may direct. Such proceeds may be invested and any\ninterest obtained may also be used for such purpose.  Such reserve fund\nshall be invested and reinvested pursuant to the provisions of\nsubdivision two of section sixteen ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1604__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirty\nof section three hundred five of this chapter and shall obtain the\napplicant's consent to the criminal history records search. Every set of\nfingerprints taken pursuant to this subdivision shall be promptly\nsubmitted to the commissioner for purposes of clearance for employment.\n  b. Upon the recommendation of the superintendent, the trustees may\nconditionally appoint a prospective employee. A request for conditional\nclearance shall be forwarded to the commissioner along with the\nprospective employee's fingerprints, as required by paragraph a of this\nsubdivision. Such appointment shall not commence until notification by\nthe commissioner that the prospective employee has been conditionally\ncleared for employment and shall terminate forty-five days after such\nnotification of conditional clearance or when the prospective employer\nis notified of a determination by the commissioner to grant or deny\nclearance, whichever occurs earlier, and may not be extended or renewed\nunless the commissioner issues a new conditional clearance after finding\nthat there was good cause for failing to obtain clearance within such\nperiod, provided that if clearance is granted, the appointment shall\ncontinue and the conditional status shall be removed. Prior to\ncommencement of such conditional appointment, the prospective employer\nshall obtain a signed statement for conditional appointment from the\nprospective employee, indicating whether, to the best of his or her\nknowledge, he or she has a pending criminal charge or criminal\nconviction in any jurisdiction outside the state.\n  c. Upon the recommendation of the superintendent, the trustees may\nmake an emergency conditional appointment when an unforeseen emergency\nvacancy has occurred. When such appointment is made, the process for\nconditional appointment pursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision must\nalso be initiated. Emergency conditional appointment may commence prior\nto notification from t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1604__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a vacancy that\noccurred less than ten business days before the start of any school\nsession, including summer school, or during any school session,\nincluding summer school, without sufficient notice to allow for\nclearance or conditional clearance; (ii) when no other qualified person\nis available to fill the vacancy temporarily; and (iii) when emergency\nconditional appointment is necessary to maintain services which the\ndistrict is legally required to provide or services necessary to protect\nthe health, education or safety of students or staff. The provisions of\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1604__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall not apply if the trustees find\nthat the district has been unable to fill the vacancy despite good faith\nefforts to fill such vacancy in a manner which would have allowed\nsufficient time for clearance or conditional clearance.\n  d. Shall develop a policy for the safety of the children who have\ncontact with an employee holding conditional appointment or emergency\nconditional appointment.\n  40. Shall upon commencement and termination of employment of an\nemployee by the district, provide the commissioner with the name of and\nposition held by such employee.\n  41. Where the district has provided transportation to students\nenrolled in such district to a school sponsored field trip,\nextracurricular activity or any other similar event, it shall provide\ntransportation back to either the point of departure or to the\nappropriate school in the district, unless the parent or legal guardian\nof a student participating in such event has provided the school\ndistrict with written notice, consistent with district policy,\nauthorizing an alternative form of return transportation for such\nstudent or unless intervening circumstances make such transportation\nimpractical. In cases where intervening circumstances make\ntransportation of a student back to the point of departure or to the\nappropriate school in the district impractical, a representative of the\nschool district shall remain with the student until such student's\nparent or legal guardian has been</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1604__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contacted and informed of the\nintervening circumstances which make such transportation impractical and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1604__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such student had been delivered to his or her parent or legal\nguardian.\n  42. a. To enter into a lease, sublease or other agreement with the\ndormitory authority providing for the financing or refinancing of all or\na portion of the school district capital facilities or school district\ncapital equipment in accordance with section sixteen hundred eighty of\nthe public authorities law and with the approval of the commissioner.\nSuch lease, sublease, or other agreement may provide for the payment of\nannual or other payments to the dormitory authority, and contain such\nother terms and conditions as may be agreed upon by the parties thereto,\nincluding the establishment of reserve funds and indemnities. For\npurposes of this subdivision, school district capital equipment shall\nhave the meaning ascribed thereto in section sixteen hundred seventy-six\nof the public authorities law.\n  b. Notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary, the\ndormitory authority and the trustee or board of trustees are hereby\nauthorized and empowered to perform any and all acts and to enter into\nany and all agreements necessary or desirable to effectuate the purposes\nof this subdivision.\n  * 43. To pass a resolution, in the discretion of the board of such\ndistrict, authorizing the entering of an agreement with a county, city,\nvillage or town within such district, for the installation and use of\nschool bus photo violation monitoring systems pursuant to section eleven\nhundred seventy-four-a of the vehicle and traffic law, provided that the\npurchase, lease, installation, operation and maintenance, or any other\ncosts associated with such cameras shall not be considered an aidable\nexpense pursuant to section thirty-six hundred twenty-three-a of this\nchapter.\n  * NB Repealed December 1, 2029\n  44. To establish a charitable fund, by resolution of the trustees, to\nreceive unrestricted charitable monetary donations made to such fund for\nuse by the district for public educa...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>