<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1711"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1711"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1711"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1711/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1711/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1711/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1711/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1711">
        <num>1711</num>
        <heading>Appointment of superintendent of schools</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1711. Appointment of superintendent of schools. 1. The board of\neducation of any union free school district may appoint a superintendent\nconsistent with the provisions of this section.\n  2. Such superintendent shall possess, unless otherwise specified by\nthe by-laws of the board of education, the following powers and be\ncharged with the following duties:\n  a. To be the chief executive officer of the school district and the\neducational system, and to have the right to speak on all matters before\nthe board, but not to vote.\n  b. To enforce all provisions of law and all rules and regulations\nrelating to the management of the schools and other educational, social\nand recreational activities under the direction of the board of\neducation.\n  c. To prepare the content of each course of study authorized by the\nboard of education. The content of each such course shall be submitted\nto the board of education for its approval and, when thus approved, the\nsuperintendent shall cause such courses of study to be used in the\ngrades, classes and schools for which they are authorized.\n  d. To recommend suitable lists of textbooks to be used in the schools.\n  e. To have supervision and direction of associate, assistant and other\nsuperintendents, directors, supervisors, principals, teachers,\nlecturers, medical inspectors, nurses, claims auditors, deputy claims\nauditors, attendance officers, janitors and other persons employed in\nthe management of the schools or the other educational activities of the\ndistrict authorized by this chapter and under the direction and\nmanagement of the board of education; to transfer teachers from one\nschool to another, or from one grade of the course of study to another\ngrade in such course, and to report immediately such transfers to such\nboard for its consideration and actions; to report to such board\nviolations of regulations and cases of insubordination, and to suspend\nan associate, assistant or other superintendent, director, supervisor,\nexpert, principal, teacher or other employee until the next regular\nmeeting of such board, when all facts relating to the case shall be\nsubmitted to such board for its consideration and action.\n  f. To have supervision and direction over the enforcement and\nobservance of the courses of study, the examination and promotion of\npupils, and over all other matters pertaining to playgrounds, medical\ninspection, recreation and social center work, libraries, lectures, and\nall other education activities under the management, direction and\ncontrol of the board of education.\n  3. Such superintendent shall be under the direction of the board of\neducation, which shall prescribe his or her powers and duties, except as\notherwise provided in subdivision two of this section. The\nsuperintendent shall be paid a salary, to be fixed by the board of\neducation, and he may be removed from office by a vote of the majority\nof all the members of such board, provided, however, that a board of\neducation may enter into a contract with such superintendent for a\nperiod of not less than three and not more than five years, and upon\nsuch other terms as shall be mutually acceptable to the parties,\nincluding but not limited to, fringe benefits and procedures for\ntermination by either party prior to the expiration of the term of such\ncontract. The services of such a superintendent of schools may be\ndiscontinued at any time by a majority vote of the board of education,\nand upon sixty days notice in writing to the superintendent of schools.\nThe other terms of any such contract, including any provisions relating\nto an increase in salary, compensation or other benefits, shall not be\nbased on or tied to the terms of any contract or collective bargaining\nagreement that the board of education has or will enter with the\nteachers or other employees of the school district.\n  4. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, the provisions\nof paragraph e of subdivision two of this section relating to the\ntransfer of teachers may be modified by an agreement that is\ncollectively negotiated pursuant to the provisions of article fourteen\nof the civil service law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>