<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1726"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1726"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1726"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1726/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1726/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1726/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1726/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1726">
        <num>1726</num>
        <heading>Lease and lease-purchase of buildings</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1726__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is owned by or in the possession of the dormitory\nauthority, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1726__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>was originally provided or financed by the authority\nfor an educational institution as defined in subdivision one of section\nsixteen hundred eighty of the public authorities law and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1726__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is no\nlonger being used by such educational institution. Any such agreement\nmay provide for the alteration, reconstruction or rehabilitation of any\nsuch dormitory or part thereof by the school district or the authority\nas capital items. The provisions of subdivisions three, four, six, eight\nand nine of this section shall not apply to any agreement with the\ndormitory authority authorized by this subdivision, provided,\nnevertheless, that the lease or lease-purchase agreement may not be made\nfor a period in excess of the applicable period of probable usefulness\nfor the building or buildings, as so altered, reconstructed or\nrehabilitated, and provided, further, that the plans and specifications\nfor such building or buildings, as so altered, reconstructed or\nrehabilitated, shall be subject to approval of the commissioner of\neducation, before such alteration, reconstruction or rehabilitation may\nbe authorized by the board of education of such school district.\n  2. Before executing any such agreement, the board of education shall\nadopt a resolution determining that such agreement is in the best\nfinancial interests of the school district and stating the basis of that\ndetermination.\n  3. Such agreements shall be subject to the bidding requirements of the\ngeneral municipal law, except that the provisions of section one hundred\none of the general municipal law shall not apply to lease or\nlease-purchase of pre-manufactured items delivered to the site, but\nshall apply to installation and other work to be performed on the site.\n  4. No agreement for the lease of a building or buildings may be made\nfor a term of more than five years, beginning with the time of\noccupancy. No lease-purchase agreement may be made for a period\nexceeding the applicable period of probable usefulness pursuant to the\nprovisions of the local finance law. Nothing herein contained shall be\ndeemed to prohibit a board of education from entering into a renewal of\nsuch lease agreeme...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1726__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three\nof paragraph a of section 135.00 of the local finance law.\n  15. The annual payments by such a school district in a city in\nrelation to such indebtedness and interest shall be deemed to be\n"indebtedness" and "interest" within the meaning of section ten of\narticle eight of the state constitution.\n  16. No such agreement shall be renegotiated or amended in such manner\nas to constitute a refunding within the meaning of section two of\narticle eight of the state constitution.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>