<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1802"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1802"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1802"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1802">
        <num>1802</num>
        <heading>Organization procedure</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1802. Organization procedure.  1. New central school districts shall\nbe organized as provided in this subdivision.\n  a. When an order laying out a central school district has been made\nand entered as provided in section eighteen hundred one of this chapter,\na petition may be presented by persons qualified to vote at school\ndistrict meetings asking for the organization of a central school\ndistrict and the establishment of a central school therein. Said\npetition shall be signed by at least one hundred of such qualified\nvoters or by a number of such qualified voters equal to at least ten per\ncentum of the pupils of said central school district as determined by\nthe last school census, whichever shall be less.\n  b. Said petition shall be filed with the commissioner and shall\nrequest that a meeting of the qualified voters within said territory be\ncalled for the purpose of determining whether or not such territory\nshall be organized as a central school district and a central school be\nestablished therein for instruction in elementary or elementary and high\nschool subjects. If the commissioner is satisfied that the petition has\nbeen duly signed as provided in this section, he shall fix a time and\nplace for a special meeting of the qualified voters within the central\nschool district, which meeting shall be held not more than thirty days\nafter the filing of the petition aforesaid.  The commissioner shall\ncause notice of such meeting to be posted at least ten days before the\nmeeting in three conspicuous places in each school district wholly or\npartly within the central school district. In addition to the posting of\nsuch notice, a copy thereof shall be published at least three days\nbefore the meeting in a daily or weekly newspaper published within the\nterritory or in a newspaper circulating therein. The expense of posting\nand publishing of the notice shall be borne equally by the several\nschool districts within the territory, unless a central school district\nis organized, in which event such expense shall become a charge upon\nsaid central school district.\n  2. Territory shall be annexed to a central school district as provided\nin this subdivision.\n  a. When an order annexing territory to a central school district has\nbeen made and entered as provided in section eighteen hundred one of\nthis chapter, the commissioner shall within ten days thereafter cause\ncertified copies of said order to be filed with the clerk of the central\nschool district and the trustee or trustees of each school district\naffected thereby. Said order annexing territory to the central school\ndistrict shall become final sixty days after such filing of the\ncertified copy thereof, unless a permissive referendum is requested as\nhereinafter provided. Said order may state that it shall take effect on\na date specified therein which date shall not, however, be earlier than\nsixty days after such filing.\n  b. When at least one hundred of the qualified voters residing in a\ncentral school district, as it existed prior to the order of annexation,\nor a number of such qualified voters equal to at least ten per centum of\nthe pupils therein, as determined by the last school census, whichever\nshall be less; or when at least one hundred qualified voters residing\nwithin any school district affected by such order or a number of such\nqualified voters equal to at least ten per centum of the pupils therein,\nas determined by the last school census, whichever shall be less, shall,\nwithin sixty days after the last filing of the copies of the aforesaid\norder, file a petition with the commissioner requesting a special\nmeeting of the qualified voters of such district affected thereby, a\nspecial meeting shall be held pursuant to notice, as hereinafter set\nforth, to determine whether the order annexing the school district or\ndistricts, or any one of such districts, shall be approved. If the\ncommissioner determines that the petition has been duly signed by the\nnumber of qualified voters required, he shall fix a time and place,\nwithin thirty days after the receipt by him of said petition, for a\nspecial meeting of the qualified voters of the central school district\nor school district in respect of which a petition has been filed as\naforesaid. The commissioner shall cause notice thereof to be posted at\nleast ten days before the meeting in ten conspicuous places in such\ncentral school district or such school district. In addition to the\nposting of such notice a copy thereof shall be duly published, at least\nthree days before the meeting, in a daily or weekly newspaper published\nwithin such central school district or any of the school districts in\nwhich such meeting is to be held, or in a newspaper circulating in the\nterritory. The expense of posting and publishing the notice aforesaid\nshall be a charge upon the central school district or school district\nconducting such meeting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>