<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-182"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-182"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="182"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-182/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-182/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-182/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-182/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_182">
        <num>182</num>
        <heading>Rates of contribution</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_182__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>either section seventy-a of the retirement and social\nsecurity law or section five hundred twenty-eight of this title provides\nthat the contribution of each member of the New York state employees'\nretirement system or the New York state teachers' retirement system in\nthe employ of the state shall be reduced by at least eight per centum of\nhis compensation, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_182__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>employee contributions to either such system\nare no longer required by reason of such system becoming noncontributory\nfor state employees.\n  Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, beginning April first,\ntwo thousand thirteen any electing employee appointed on or after April\nfirst, two thousand twelve, the rate at which each such employee shall\ncontribute in any current plan year (January first to December\nthirty-first) shall be determined by reference to the wages of such\nmember in the second plan year (January first to December thirty-first)\npreceding such current plan year as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_182__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>members with wages of forty-five thousand dollars per annum or\nless shall contribute three per centum of annual wages;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_182__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>members with wages greater than forty-five thousand per annum, but\nnot more than fifty-five thousand per annum shall contribute three and\none-half per centum of annual wages;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_182__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>members with wages greater than fifty-five thousand per annum, but\nnot more than seventy-five thousand per annum shall contribute four and\none-half per centum of annual wages;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_182__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>members with wages greater than seventy-five thousand per annum\nbut not more than one hundred thousand per annum shall contribute five\nand three-quarters per centum of annual wages; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_182__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>members with wages greater than one hundred thousand per annum\nshall contribute six per centum of annual wages.\n  Notwithstanding the foregoing, during each of the first three plan\nyears (January first to December thirty-first) in which such member has\nestablished membership in the Education Department Optional Retirement\nProgram, such employee shall contribute a percent of annual wages in\naccordance with the preceding schedule based upon a projection of annual\nwages provided by the employer.\n  3. Payment of contributions pursuant to subdivisions one and two of\nthis section shall be made to the designated insurer or insurers upon\naudit and warrant of the state comptroller.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>