<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1950"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1950"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1950"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1950/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1950/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1950/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-1950/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1950">
        <num>1950</num>
        <heading>Establishment of boards of cooperative educational services pending the creation of intermediate districts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one hundred six percent of the salary\ncap applicable in the preceding school year, or (ii) ninety-eight\npercent of that earned by the commissioner in the two thousand\nthirteen--two thousand fourteen state fiscal year, whichever is less. In\nno event shall any district superintendent be permitted to accumulate\nvacation or sick leave credits in excess of the vacation and sick leave\ncredits managerial/confidential employees of the state are permitted to\naccumulate pursuant to regulations promulgated by the state civil\nservice commission, nor may any district superintendent at the time of\nseparation from service be compensated for accrued and unused vacation\ncredits or sick leave, or use accrued and unused sick leave for\nretirement service credit or to pay for health insurance in retirement,\nat a rate in excess of the rate permitted to managerial/confidential\nemployees of the state pursuant to regulations of the state civil\nservice commission. In addition to the payment of supplementary salary,\na board of cooperative educational services may provide for the payment\nof all or a portion of the cost of insurance benefits for the district\nsuperintendent of schools, including but not limited to health\ninsurance, disability insurance, life insurance or any other form of\ninsurance benefit made available to managerial/confidential employees of\nthe state; provided that any such payments for whole life, split dollar\nor other life insurance policies having a cash value shall be included\nin the total salary of the district superintendent for purposes of this\nsubparagraph, and provided further that any payments for the employee\ncontribution, co-pay or uncovered medical expenses under a health\ninsurance plan also shall be included in the total salary of the\ndistrict superintendent. Notwithstanding any other provision of law,\npayments for such insurance benefits may be based on the district\nsuperintendent's total salary or the amount of his or her supplement...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, any employee\nof a board of cooperative educational services who is appointed as the\ndistrict superintendent of schools shall vacate his or her prior\nposition with the board of cooperative educational services upon\nappointment as district superintendent, and no district superintendent\nshall have a contract of employment with the board of cooperative\neducational services other than a contract entered pursuant to this\nparagraph.\n  b.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prepare, prior to the annual meeting of members of the boards\nof education and school trustees, held as provided in paragraph o of\nthis subdivision, a tentative budget of expenditures for the program\ncosts, a tentative budget for capital costs, and a tentative budget for\nthe administration costs of the board of cooperative educational\nservices.  Such budgets shall include the proposed budget for the\nupcoming school year, the previous school year's actual costs and the\ncurrent school year's projected costs for each object of expenditure.\nSuch program, capital and administrative budgets shall be separately\ndelineated in accordance with the definition of program, capital and\nadministrative costs which shall be promulgated by the commissioner\nafter consultation with school district officials and the director of\nthe budget. Personal service costs for each budget shall include the\nnumber of full-time equivalent positions funded and total salary and,\nexcept as noted herein, frin...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of cooperative educational services shall provide copies\nof such tentative budgets and attachments to the trustees or board of\neducation of each component school district of the board of cooperative\neducational services at least ten days prior to the annual meeting held\npursuant to paragraph o of this subdivision. Such trustees or boards of\neducation shall make such budgets available to the residents of their\nrespective school districts upon request.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of cooperative educational services shall comply with\nany reasonable requests for additional information not contained in such\nbudgets which may be requested prior to the annual meeting held pursuant\nto paragraph o of this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of cooperative educational services shall give public\nnotice of the annual meeting held pursuant to paragraph o of this\nsubdivision by publishing a notice once each week within the two weeks\npreceding the annual meeting held as provided in paragraph o of this\nsubdivision, the first publication to be at least fourteen days before\nsuch meeting, in two newspapers if there be two, or in one newspaper if\nthere shall be but one, having general circulation within the board of\ncooperative educational services. If no newspaper shall have general\ncirculation therein, said notice shall be posted in at least twenty of\nthe most public places in the board of cooperative educational services\nat least fourteen days before such meeting. Such notice shall state that\nthe tentative budgets will be presented by the board of cooperative\neducational services to the trustees or board of education of each\ncomponent school district of the board of cooperative educational\nservices in atte...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The trustees or board of education of each component school\ndistrict of the board of cooperative educational services shall adopt a\npublic resolution which shall approve or disapprove such tentative\nadministrative budget at a regular or special meeting to be held within\nthe component district on the date designated pursuant to subdivision\ntwo-a of this section as the date for election of members of the board\nof cooperative educational services, or in the case of the board of\neducation of a central high school district on the regular business day\nnext following such designated date.\n  If the resolutions adopted by the trustees or boards of education of a\nmajority of the component school districts of the board of cooperative\neducational services actually voting approve the tentative\nadministrative budget, the board of cooperative educational services may\nadopt the tentative administrative budget without modification. If a\nmajority of the component school districts actually ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, any component\nschool district which will be transferred to a new supervisory district\nas of July first next succeeding the date designated for the vote on the\ntentative administrative budget shall vote on the administrative budget\nof the board of cooperative educational services to which it will be\ntransferred, as if such transfer had already occurred. Where the\ncommissioner has issued an order for the merger of two or more\nsupervisory districts to take effect on July first, in the school year\nimmediately preceding the merger, the boards of cooperative educational\nservices to be merged shall jointly prepare a program, administrative\nand capital budget for the merged board of cooperative educational\nservices and shall jointly conduct a vote on the tentative\nadministrative budget of the merged board of cooperative educational\nservices in accordance with this paragraph as if the merger was already\nin effect. In the event s...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each component school district shall transmit the resolution\neither approving or disapproving the board of cooperative educational\nservices' tentative administrative budget no later than one business day\nafter the adoption of such resolution. The board of cooperative\neducational services shall, no later than the fifteenth day of May,\nadopt the final program, capital and administrative budgets for the\nensuing year. Except as provided in paragraph d of this subdivision,\nsubparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph p of this subdivision, and subdivision one\nof section nineteen hundred fifty-one of this article, such\nadministrative and capital budgets, when so adopted, after deducting\nstate aid applicable thereto, shall be a charge against all of the\ncomponent school districts in the supervisory district and each\ncomponent school district's proportionate share shall be determined by\nthe board of cooperative educational services according to weighted\naverage daily attendance or according to true valuation or according to\nresident public school district enrollment as defined in paragraph n of\nsubdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this chapter except\nthat only one method shall be applied among the component districts of a\nboard of cooperative educational services in any year, unless otherwise\nprovided by law. In a merged supervisory district in the county of\nSuffolk each component school district's proportionate share of such\nadministrative and capital budgets may be determined according to\nweighted average daily attendance, according to true valuation, or\naccording to using the weighted average daily attendance for a certain\npercentage of the cost and true valuation for a certain percentage of\nadministrative and capital costs. Such costs, in a merged supervisory\ndistrict in the county of Suffolk, apportioned by using weighted average\ndaily attendance and true valuation shall be subject to adjustment by\nthe board of cooperative educational services in a manner that will\nminimize the annual change in costs for the greatest number of component\ndistricts. Such percentages shall be established by the board of\ncooperative educational services upon the approval of the component\ndistricts subject to the final approval of the commissioner. It is\nfurther provided that such administrative budget approved by the board\nshall be subject to review by the commissioner to determine:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nlevel of administrative savings achieved by the merger and (ii) if such\nadministrative savings equals or exceeds the level identified by the\nmerger planning task force appointed by the district superintendent. If\nthe board of cooperative educational services determines to change the\nmethod of apportioning administrative costs and capital expenses from\nthat followed in the previous year, such determination may be made only\nif the board of cooperative educational services has conducted a hearing\nat a regular or special meeting of such board which all members of\nboards of education and school trustees have been invited to attend,\nsuch hearing to be held at least thirty days prior to the annual meeting\nof members of boards of education and school trustees. In the\nPutnam/North Westchester board of cooperative educational services, each\ncomponent district's proportionate share of such administrative and\ncapital budgets may also be determined by using the weighted average\ndaily attendance for a certain percentage and the true valuation for a\ncertain percentage. Such percentages shall be applied according to\nclause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subparagraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The three methods of apportionment of administrative and capital\nexpenses are as follows:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in accordance with the ratio which the\ncomponent school district's total full or true valuation in effect at\nthe time of the adoption of the budget bears to the total true or full\nvaluation of all of the component school districts within the board of\ncooperative educational services,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>by dividing the total amount of\nsuch administrative and capital expenses by the total weighted average\ndaily attendance of pupils residing in all component school districts\ncontained within the board of cooperative educational services and\nattending a public school and multiplying by the weighted average daily\nattendance of such resident pupils in each of the component school\ndistricts, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>by dividing the total amount of such administrative\nand capital expenses by the total resident public school district\nenrollment of all component school districts contained within the board\nof cooperative educational services and multiplying by the resident\npublic school district enrollment of the component school districts. In\naddition, in a merged supervisory district in the county of Suffolk,\nwhere a combination of the first and second methods could be applied as\nprovided in the opening paragraph of this subparagraph may be utilized.\nIn the Putnam/North Westchester board of cooperative educational\nservices, where a combination of the first and second methods is\nutilized, the percentages shall be used as follows: for the two thousand\nfive-two thousand six school year, ninety percent using true valuation\nand ten percent using the weighted average daily attendance; for the two\nthousand six-two thousand seven school year, eighty percent using true\nvaluation and twenty perc...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Aidable shared services. At the request of component school\ndistricts, and with the approval of the commissioner, provide any of the\nfollowing services on a cooperative basis: school nurse teacher,\nattendance supervisor, supervisor of teachers, dental hygienist,\npsychologist, teachers of art, music, physical education, career\neducation subjects, guidance counsellors, operation of special classes\nfor students with disabilities, as such term is defined in article\neighty-nine of this chapter; pupil and financial accounting service by\nmeans of mechanical equipment; maintenance and operation of cafeteria or\nrestaurant service for the use of pupils and teachers while at school,\nand such other services as the commissioner may approve. Such cafeteria\nor restaurant service may be used by the community for school related\nfunctions and activities and to furnish meals to the elderly residents\nof the district, sixty years of age or older. Utilization by elderly\nresidents or school rel...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Certain services prohibited. Commencing with the nineteen\nhundred ninety-seven--ninety-eight school year, the commissioner shall\nnot be authorized to approve as an aidable shared service pursuant to\nthis subdivision any cooperative maintenance services or municipal\nservices, including but not limited to, lawn mowing services and\nheating, ventilation or air conditioning repair or maintenance or trash\ncollection, or any other municipal services as defined by the\ncommissioner. On and after the effective date of this paragraph, the\ncommissioner shall not approve, as an aidable shared service, any new\ncooperative maintenance or municipal services for the nineteen hundred\nninety-six--ninety-seven school year, provided that the commissioner may\napprove the continuation of such services for one year if provided in\nthe nineteen hundred ninety-five--ninety-six school year. No service\nprovided to an out-of-state school district pursuant to subparagraph ten\nof paragraph h of this sub...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Certain services prohibited. Commencing with the nineteen\nhundred ninety-seven--ninety-eight school year, the commissioner shall\nnot be authorized to approve as an aidable shared service pursuant to\nthis subdivision any cooperative maintenance services or municipal\nservices, including but not limited to, lawn mowing services and\nheating, ventilation or air conditioning repair or maintenance or trash\ncollection, or any other municipal services as defined by the\ncommissioner. On and after the effective date of this paragraph, the\ncommissioner shall not approve, as an aidable shared service, any new\ncooperative maintenance or municipal services for the nineteen hundred\nninety-six--ninety-seven school year, provided that the commissioner may\napprove the continuation of such services for one year if provided in\nthe nineteen hundred ninety-five--ninety-six school year.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2029\n  (2-a) Cost effectiveness of instructional and non-instructional\ntechnology. N...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>computer equipment,\n  (ii) conduits,\n  (iii) wiring,\n  (iv) powering and testing of hardware installations,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all costs associated with lease or purchase of local or wide area\nnetwork hardware located on district property, and\n  (vi) incidental costs for original purchase and installation of\nhardware, including installation of basic operating systems software\nrequired for hardware testing,\nshall not be considered an aidable shared service unless the component\nschool district is able to demonstrate that such shared service would be\nmore cost-effective than would otherwise be possible if such services\nwere to be purchased without the involvement of a board of cooperative\neducational services. Any aid that may be payable for such shared\nservice pursuant to subdivision five of this section shall be excluded\nin the demonstration and determination of cost-effectiveness and cost\nsavings pursuant to this subdivision. The commissioner shall issue\nguidelines to advise component school districts in their determination\nof cost-effectiveness. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a\ncomponent school district determines that any instructional and\nnon-instructional technology purchase and installation from the board of\ncooperative educational services are not cost effective, as determined\npursuant to this paragraph, the commissioner shall, upon request, assist\nthe school district to enter into a cooperative service agreement\n(CO-SER) with another BOCES, which is cost effective in the provision of\nsuch technology purchases and installations.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Requests for shared services; operating plan; required notice.\nRequests for such shared services shall be filed by component school\ndistricts with the board of cooperative educational services not later\nthan the first day of February of each year, provided that such requests\nshall not be binding upon the component school district. The board of\ncooperative educational services shall submit its proposed annual\noperating plan for the ensuing school year to the department for\napproval not later than the fifteenth day of February of each year. Such\nboard shall, through its executive officer, notify each component school\ndistrict on or before the tenth day of March concerning the services\nwhich have been approved by the commissioner to be made available for\nthe ensuing school year. Such notice shall set forth the local uniform\ncost of each such service, based on</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>anticipated participation in the\nensuing school year, or (ii) participation in the current year, or (iii)\na two or three year average including participation in the current year,\nwhich unit cost shall be the same for all participating component\ndistricts and shall be based upon a uniform methodology approved\nannually by at least three-quarters of the participating component\nschool districts after consultation by local school officials with their\nrespective boards; provided, however, such unit cost shall be subject to\nfinal adjustment for programs for students with disabilities based on\nactual participation in accordance with regulations of the commissioner.\nNotwithstanding the determination of the local uniform unit cost\nmethodology selected in accordance with this paragraph, each board of\ncooperative education services shall annually report to the commissioner\nthe budgeted unit cost and, when available, the actual unit cost of such\nprograms and services, in accordance with both the local uniform unit\ncost methodology and a statewide uniform unit cost methodology\nprescribed by the commissioner by regulation, where the budgeted\nstatewide unit cost shall be based on the anticipated participation in\nthe ensuing year and the actual statewide unit cost shall be based on\nactual participation through the end of each year.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Contracts for shared services; allocation of costs. Each component\nschool district shall on or before the first day of May following such\nnotification notify the board of cooperative educational services of its\nintention to participate or not to participate in such shared services\nand the specific services which such district elects to utilize. Each\nparticipating component school district shall be required to pay the\nboard of cooperative educational services for the cost of the services\nset forth in such notification, except for adjustments caused by\nsubsequent unanticipated changes in the district's enrollment. The board\nof cooperative educational services shall enter into contracts with its\ncomponent school districts for such requested services. A copy of each\nexecuted contract for such purpose shall be filed with the commissioner\nby the board of cooperative educational services on or prior to the\nfirst day of August of each year. Notwithstanding the provisions of\nparag...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Operating plan and budget; unanticipated shared services. The\nboard of cooperative educational services shall submit to the\ncommissioner on or before the first day of June an operating plan and\nbudget based upon the request for services which it has received from\nits component school districts. Such submission shall include the\nbudgeted unit cost of programs and services based on both the local and\nthe statewide uniform unit cost methodologies for each program and\nservice offered by the board of cooperative educational services. A\nboard of cooperative educational services which receives requests for\nunanticipated shared services subsequent to the adoption of its budget\nshall submit an amended operating plan including such additional shared\nservices to the commissioner, together with a statement from the chief\nschool administrator of each school district which has requested such\nservices indicating the availability of funds in the budget of the\nschool district to pay for s...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Arrange cooperative educational services with and if necessary\nmake contracts covering same with other public agencies for shared\nservices and to produce educational television materials and programs,\nand to own or lease television facilities and to enter into appropriate\ncontracts concerning the same.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with the United States of America, the\nState of New York, any school district, community college, public\ninstitution of higher education, independent institution of higher\neducation eligible for aid under section sixty-four hundred one of this\nchapter, public libraries, or public agency in relation to the program\nof the board of cooperative educational services, and any such school\ndistrict, community college, institution of higher education, or public\nagency is hereby authorized and empowered to do and perform any and all\nacts necessary or convenient in relation to the performance of any such\ncontracts.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with school districts which are component\ndistricts in the board of cooperative educational services for the\neducation by such component school district or districts of children who\nreside within the board of cooperative educational services in the\nprogram of the board of cooperative educational services, and for all\npurposes of this chapter in such event such children shall be deemed\nattending classes maintained by the board of cooperative educational\nservices. School districts are hereby authorized and empowered to do and\nperform any and all acts necessary or convenient in relation to the\nperformance of any such contracts.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with nonpublic schools to provide data\nprocessing services for pupil personnel records and other administrative\nrecords of the nonpublic schools and the processing of fingerprints\nutilized in criminal history record checks for those nonpublic schools\nthat elect to require such criminal history record checks pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirty of section three hundred five of\nthis chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with the United States of America, the\nstate of New York, any community college, agricultural and technical\ncollege or other public agency for the purpose of providing career\neducation programs to such agencies. Any such proposed contract shall be\nsubject to the review and approval of the commissioner, who may only\napprove such proposed contract when, in his opinion, such contract will\nresult in a more economical utilization of existing career and career\neducation resources than would be achieved were such contract not\napproved. The commissioner shall issue a finding in writing in making\nall determinations pursuant to this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with not-for-profit corporations to\nparticipate in federal programs relating to career training and\nexperience. Any such proposed contract shall be subject to review and\napproval of the commissioner, who may approve such proposed contract\nonly when in his opinion such contract will result in increased or\nimproved career opportunities. The commissioner shall issue a finding in\nwriting in making all determinations pursuant to this subparagraph.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with the state of New York, any community\ncollege, agricultural and technical college, or public agency for the\npurpose of providing electronic data processing services to such\nagencies. Any such proposed contract shall be subject to the review and\napproval of the commissioner, who may only approve such proposed\ncontract when, in his opinion, such contract will not disrupt the level\nof services provided to component school districts and will result in a\nmore economical utilization of existing board of cooperative educational\nservices computer facilities. The commissioner shall issue a finding in\nwriting in making all determinations pursuant to this subparagraph.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with the commissioner of the office of\nchildren and family services pursuant to subdivision six-a of section\nthirty-two hundred two of this chapter to provide to such office, for\nthe benefit of youth in its custody, any special education programs,\nrelated services, career and technical education services and music, art\nand foreign language programs provided by the board of cooperative\neducational services to component school districts. Any such proposed\ncontract shall be subject to the review and approval of the commissioner\nto determine that it is an approved cooperative educational service.\nServices provided pursuant to such contracts shall be provided at cost,\nand the board of cooperative educational services shall not be\nauthorized to charge any costs incurred in providing such services to\nits component school districts.\n  *</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts of no more than five years and subject\nto the sunset date of this subparagraph, with out-of-state schools for:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>special education; and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>career and technical education\nservices; and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the use of existing products that demonstrate\nhow to map the next generation standards to assessments; and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nproviding access to existing webinars or online courses relating to\nimplementation of the next generation standards; for providing\nprofessional development to educators; and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>technology products\ndeveloped for the use of school districts located in New York state,\nincluding computer programs and software packages that help students\nlearn and assist districts in achieving greater efficiencies. For\npurposes of this subparagraph, an out-of-state school shall mean a\npublic elementary or secondary school or a degree granting institution\nof higher education, located outside of New York state; provided further\nfor purposes of providing services authorized in clauses</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subparagraph, out-of-state shall also include schools\nlocated outside the continental United States. Any contract shall be\napproved by the commissioner, the board of cooperative educational\nservices and the district superintendent of schools, provided such\nservices are made available to any school district within the\nsupervisory district and that the requirements of this subparagraph are\nmet. Contracts must be executed by the board of cooperative educational\nservices and the trustees or boards of education of such out-of-state\nschools and shall only authorize out-of-state students to participate in\nan instructional program if such services are available to all eligible\nstudents in New York state schools in the component districts and the\nnumber of participating out-of-state students only comprises up to five\npercent of the total number of the total enrolled students in the\ninstructional program at the board of cooperative educational services\nand that the board of cooperative educational services spends no more\nthan thirty percent of its employees' time on services to out-of-state\nschools pursuant to this subparagraph. To be approved by the\ncommissioner, the contract and any business plan, shall demonstrate that\nany services provided to out-of-state schools pursuant to this\nsubparagraph shall not result in any additional costs being imposed on\ncomponent school districts and that any payments received by the board\nof cooperative educational services for services provided in this\nsubparagraph that exceed any cost to the board of cooperative\neducational services for providing such services shall be applied to\nreduce the costs of aidable shared services allocated to component\nschool districts pursuant to paragraph d of this subdivision and shall\nalso be applied to reduce the approved cost of services pursuant to\nsubdivision five of this section. Services provided by a board of\ncooperative educational services to component districts at...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_e__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with individual public libraries or\npublic library systems for the purpose of providing high-speed\ntelecommunications services including, but not limited to, high-speed\ninternet services. Any such proposed contract shall be subject to the\nreview and approval of the commissioner, who may only approve such\nproposed contract when, in such commissioner's opinion, such contract:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>will result in a more economical utilization of existing boards of\ncooperative educational services high-speed telecommunications services\nor resources than would be achieved were such contract not approved;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nwill not disrupt the level of services to component school districts;\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>will result in a more economical utilization of existing library\nresources. The commissioner shall issue a finding, in writing, making\nany determination pursuant to this subparagraph. Such services to public\nlibraries and library systems shall be provided at cost and shall not be\neligible for aid pursuant to subdivision five of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_c__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into contracts with preschool special education program\nproviders approved pursuant to section forty-four hundred ten of this\nchapter to process services relating to online application systems for\neducators.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_c__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To establish, upon local interest from one or more component\nschool districts and subject to approval by the BOCES board of\neducation, an agriculture program that is designed to provide students\nwith the skills required to work in, and help sustain New York's\nagriculture industry.  Such program may include, but not be limited to,\na partnership with farms and other agriculture entities in the state\nthat provide students with hands-on experience combined with other\neducational opportunities.\n  i. Make such reports as are required by the commissioner of education.\n  j. Appoint one of its members as president, one of its members or\nanother qualified voter in a district within the supervisory district as\nclerk and another qualified voter in a district within the supervisory\ndistrict as treasurer. The duties of the clerk and treasurer shall be\nthe same as those established by statute and regulations of the\ncommissioner of education for clerks and treasurers of union free school...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To rent suitable land, classrooms, offices or buildings upon\nor in which to maintain and conduct such cooperative educational\nservices and administrative offices for a period not to exceed ten years\nfor leases entered into with public entities and twenty years for leases\nentered into with non-public entities and to improve, alter, equip and\nfurnish such land, classrooms, offices or buildings in a suitable manner\nfor such purposes, provided that:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>before executing any lease, the\nboard shall adopt a resolution determining that such agreement is in the\nbest financial interests of the supervisory district and stating the\nbasis of that determination;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the rental payment shall not be more\nthan the fair market value as determined by the board and provided to\nthe commissioner;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board discloses any conflict of interest\npursuant to subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph, or any other potential\nor perceived conflict of interest, to the commissioner, and in the event\nof a conflict of interest or a potential or perceived conflict of\ninterest, provides detailed documentation to the commissioner\ndemonstrating that the cost of the lease is not more than fair market\nvalue; and</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>upon the consent of the commissioner, renewal of such\nlease may be made for a period of up to ten years. Nothing contained\nherein shall prevent the board from entering into a lease agreement\nwhich provides for the cancellation of the same by such board upon:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\na substantial increase or decrease in pupil enrollment; or (ii) a\nsubstantial change in the needs and requirements of a board of\ncooperative educational services with respect to facilities; or (iii)\nany other change which substantially affects the needs or requirements\nof a board of cooperative educational services or the community in which\nit is located. No lease or other contract for the occupancy of such\nland, classrooms, offices or buildings shall be enforceable against the\nboard of cooperative educational services unless and until the same\nshall have been approved in writing by the commissioner. In the case of\na lease longer than ten years, the commissioner's written approval must\ninclude a finding that the proposed lease complies with all requirements\nof this paragraph and would be more cost-effective than a lease of ten\nyears or fewer.\n  * NB Effective until July 1, 2029\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To rent suitable land, classrooms, offices or buildings upon or\nin which to maintain and conduct such cooperative educational services\nand administrative offices for a period not to exceed ten years and to\nimprove, alter, equip and furnish such land, classrooms, offices or\nbuildings in a suitable manner for such purposes</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>before executing\nany lease, the board shall adopt a resolution determining that such\nagreement is in the best financial interests of the supervisory district\nand stating the basis of that determination;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the rental payment\nshall not be more than the fair market value as determined by the board;\nand</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>upon the consent of the commissioner, renewal of such lease may\nbe made for a period of up to ten years. Nothing contained herein shall\nprevent the board from entering into a lease agreement which provides\nfor the cancellation of the same by such board upon:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a substantial\nincrease or decrease in pupil enrollment; or (ii) a substantial change\nin the needs and requirements of a board of cooperative educational\nservices with respect to facilities; or (iii) any other change which\nsubstantially affects the needs or requirements of a board of\ncooperative educational services or the community in which it is\nlocated. No lease or other contract for the occupancy of such land,\nclassrooms, offices or buildings shall be enforceable against the board\nof cooperative educational services unless and until the same shall have\nbeen approved in writing by the commissioner.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2029\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To lease unneeded facilities to public or private agencies,\nindividuals, partnerships, or corporations, with the approval of the\ncommissioner of education, and for a term not to exceed five years,\nwhich shall be renewable with the approval of the commissioner of\neducation.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if any member of the board of education of the board of\ncooperative educational services, officer or employee of the board of\ncooperative educational services has a financial interest, either direct\nor indirect, in any lease to which the board of cooperative educational\nservices is, or is to be, a party, such interest shall be disclosed to\nthe board of education of such board of cooperative educational services\nin writing and shall be set forth in the minutes of the board of\neducation of the board of cooperative educational services. The member,\nofficer or employee having such interest shall not participate in any\naction by the board of cooperative educational services with respect to\nsuch lease.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2029\n  q. To provide transportation for pupils to and from classes maintained\nby such board of cooperative educational services at the request of one\nor more school districts. School districts and boards of cooperative\neducational services are authorized to enter into contracts with one or\nmore school districts, private contractors, and one or more boards of\ncooperative educational services and any municipal corporation and\nauthority to provide such transportation. Boards of cooperative\neducational services may operate joint or regional transportation\nsystems for the transportation authorized by articles seventy-three and\neighty-nine of this chapter. Such transportation, except when provided\nby a political subdivision or a board of cooperative educational\nservices, shall be subject to the requirements of subdivision fourteen\nof section three hundred five of the education law.\n  r. With the approval of the district superintendent of schools and of\nthe commissioner of education to furnish any of the educational services\nprovided for in this section or any other section of law which\nauthorizes such board to provide services to school districts outside of\nthe supervisory district, upon such terms as may be agreed upon pursuan...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Requests to provide\nsuch programs and services shall be filed annually with the commissioner\nfor approval.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner may approve such programs and services only if\nthey</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are requested by two or more component school districts;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nwill provide additional opportunities for pupils;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>will be expected\nto result in a cost savings to the two or more component school\ndistricts requesting the programs and services;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>will provide greater\nopportunity for pupils, including those with handicapping conditions, to\nearn credit for academic subjects and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>will insure a greater or more\nappropriate use of facilities by boards of cooperative educational\nservices.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_e__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such programs and services may include, but shall not be limited\nto</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>expansion of itinerant teaching services in advanced academic\nsubject courses;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>academic course offerings at regular board of\ncooperative educational services centers or at leased sites during the\nschool year or summer school periods, as requested by component\ndistricts;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>block scheduling to enable students to attend classes at\na board of cooperative educational services center for an entire school\nday;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>satellite offerings of specific concentrations or\nspecializations sponsored by boards of cooperative educational services\nat local schools, with cross-contracting for services;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>expanded use\nof interactive television and other technologies to offer academic\ncourses on site or at component school districts; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>programs of\nacademic intervention services approved by the commissioner designed to\nfulfill the academic intervention services requirement imposed by the\nregulations of the commissioner, provided that in approving such\nprograms and services for the two thousand--two thousand one school year\nor thereafter, the commissioner shall assure that the program or service\nresults in a cost savings to all participating districts, disregarding\nany aid pursuant to subdivision five of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_f__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such programs or services if approved by the commissioner, shall\nbe eligible for aid pursuant to subdivision five of this section.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_f__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A teacher whose position in a school district is abolished as the\nresult of a takeover of an academic program by a board or boards of\ncooperative educational services shall be accorded the rights provided\nby section thirty hundred fourteen-a of this chapter.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_f__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To implement a program or service approved under this paragraph, a\nschool district may transport pupils to the site of a board of\ncooperative educational services program in those cases where a pupil\notherwise would be entitled to transportation but for the fact that the\nprogram is at the board of cooperative educational services and not at a\nschool of the district. Under these circumstances, for those purposes of\narticle seventy-three of this chapter, the board of cooperative\neducational services site shall be considered a school.\n  cc. Upon approval by a vote of the board of cooperative educational\nservices, establish and maintain a program of reserves not to exceed\nthree per centum of the annual budget of the district to cover property\nloss and liability claims. Separate funds shall be established for\nproperty losses and for liability claims, and the separate identity of\neach such fund shall be maintained whether its assets consist of cash or\ninvestments or both. The m...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_f__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Credit card" means any credit card, credit plate, charge plate,\ncourtesy card, debit card or other identification card or device issued\nby a person to another person which may be used to obtain a cash advance\nor a loan or credit or to purchase a lease property or services on the\ncredit of the person issuing the credit card or a person who has agreed\nwith the issuer to pay obligations arising from the use of a credit card\nissued to another person.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_f__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Financing agency" means any agency defined as such in subdivision\neighteen of section four hundred one of the personal property law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1950__subsec_f__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Person" means an individual, partnership, corporation or any\nother legal or commercial entity.\n  jj. To contract to furnish any of the services provided for in this\nsection to component school districts of the board of cooperative\neducational services, with the approval of the commissioner, for a\nperiod not to exceed five years, upon such terms as may be agreed upon\npursuant to such contracts executed by the board of cooperative\neducational services and the trustees or boards of education of such\nschool districts, provided that any such contract entered into, extended\nor amended on or after July first, nineteen hundred ninety-six shall be\nconsistent with the requirements of paragraph d of this subdivision and\nsubdivision one of section nineteen hundred fifty-one of this article\nregarding the allocation of costs to component school districts based\nupon the local uniform unit cost of each such service.\n  kk. For the nineteen hundred ninety-seven--ninety-eight school year\n...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirty\nof section three hundred five of this chapter and shall obtain the\napplicant's consent to the criminal history records search. Every set of\nfingerprints taken pursuant to this paragraph shall be promptly\nsubmitted to the commissioner for purposes of clearance for employment.\n  b. Upon the recommendation of the district superintendent, the board\nmay conditionally appoint a prospective employee. A request for\nconditional clearance shall be forwarded to the commissioner along with\nthe prospective employee's fingerprints, as required by paragraph a of\nthis subdivision. Such appointment shall not commence until notification\nby the commissioner that the prospective employee has been conditionally\ncleared for employment and shall terminate forty-five days after such\nnotification of conditional clearance or when the prospective employer\nis notified of a determination by the commissioner to grant or deny\nclearance, whichever occurs earlier, and may not be extended or renewed\nunless the commissioner issues a new conditional clearance after finding\nthat there was good cause for failing to obtain clearance within such\nperiod, provided that if clearance is granted, the appointment shall\ncontinue and the conditional status shall be removed. Prior to\ncommencement of such conditional appointment, the prospective employer\nshall obtain a signed statement for conditional appointment from the\nprospective employee, indicating whether, to the best of his or her\nknowledge, he or she has a pending criminal charge or criminal\nconviction in any jurisdiction outside the state.\n  c. Upon the recommendation of the district superintendent, the board\nmay make an emergency conditional appointment when an unforeseen\nemergency vacancy has occurred. When such appointment is made, the\nprocess for conditional appointment pursuant to paragraph b of this\nsubdivision must also be initiated. Emergency conditional appointment\nmay commence prior to notificat...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a vacancy that occurred less than ten business days\nbefore the start of any school session, including summer school, or\nduring any school session, including summer school, without sufficient\nnotice to allow for clearance or conditional clearance; (ii) when no\nother qualified person is available to fill the vacancy temporarily; and\n(iii) when emergency conditional appointment is necessary to maintain\nservices which the district is legally required to provide or services\nnecessary to protect the health, education or safety of students or\nstaff. The provisions of subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall not\napply if the board finds that the district has been unable to fill the\nvacancy despite good faith efforts to fill such vacancy in a manner\nwhich would have allowed sufficient time for clearance or conditional\nclearance.\n  d. Shall develop a policy for the safety of the children who have\ncontact with an employee holding conditional appointment or emergency\nconditional appointment.\n  mm. Shall upon commencement and termination of employment of an\nemployee by the board, provide the commissioner with the name of and\nposition held by such employee.\n  nn. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section and with the\nconsent of the commissioner, the Madison-Oneida board of cooperative\neducational services may enter into a contract or contracts not to\nexceed a total period of two years with the Madison Cortland ARC to\nprovide transportation maintenance and repair services on buses owned\nand operated by the Madison Cortland ARC. The Madison-Oneida board of\ncooperative educational services shall not charge any portion of costs\nincurred pursuant to this paragraph to its component school districts.\n  oo. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a board of cooperative\neducational services is authorized to enter into a memorandum of\nunderstanding with the trustees or board of education of a non-component\nschool district, including city school districts of cities with one\nhundred twenty-five thousand inhabitants or more, to participate in a\nrecovery high school program operated by the board of cooperative\neducational services for a period not to exceed five years upon such\nterms as such trustees or board of education and the board of\ncooperative educational services may mutually agree, provided that such\nagreement may provide for a charge for administration of the recovery\nhigh school program including capital costs, but participating\nnon-component school districts shall not be liable for payment of\nadministrative ex...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an amount equal to one minus the\nquotient expressed as a decimal to three places without rounding of\neight mills divided by the tax rate of the local district computed upon\nthe actual valuation of taxable property, as determined pursuant to\nsubdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this chapter and\nnotwithstanding section three thousand six hundred three, expressed in\nmills to the nearest tenth as determined by the commissioner, provided,\nhowever, that where services are provided to a school district which is\nincluded within a central high school district or to a central high\nschool district, such amount shall equal one minus the quotient\nexpressed as a decimal to three places without rounding of three mills\ndivided by the tax rates, expressed in mills to the nearest tenth, of\nsuch districts, as determined by the commissioner or (ii) the aid ratio\nof each school district for the current year, which shall be such\ncomponent school district's board of cooperative educational services\naid ratio and which shall be not less than thirty-six percent converted\nto decimals and shall be not more than ninety percent converted to\ndecimals. For the purposes of this paragraph, the tax rate of the local\ndistrict computed upon the actual valuation of taxable property shall be\nthe sum of the amount of tax raised by the school district plus any\npayments in lieu of taxes received by the school district pursuant to\nsection four hundred eighty-five of the real property tax law, divided\nby the actual valuation of the school district, provided, however that\nthe tax rate for a central high school district shall be the sum of the\namount of tax raised by the common and union free school districts\nincluded within the central high school district for the support of the\ncentral high school district plus any payments in lieu of taxes received\nfor the support of the central high school district pursuant to section\nfour hundred eighty-five of the real property...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for aid payable in the\ntwo thousand twenty-five--two thousand twenty-six school year and prior\nschool years in excess of thirty thousand dollars, (ii) for aid payable\nin the two thousand twenty-six--two thousand twenty-seven school year in\nexcess of forty thousand dollars, (iii) for aid payable in the two\nthousand twenty-seven--two thousand twenty-eight school year in excess\nof fifty thousand dollars, and (iv) for aid payable in the two thousand\ntwenty-eight--two thousand twenty-nine school year and thereafter, in\nexcess of sixty thousand dollars, shall not be such an approved expense,\nand except also that administrative and clerical expenses shall not\nexceed ten percent of the total expenses for purposes of this\ncomputation. Any gifts, donations or interest earned by the board of\ncooperative educational services or on behalf of the board of\ncooperative educational services by the dormitory authority or any other\nsource shall not be deducted in determining the cost of services\nallocated to each component school district. Any payments made to a\ncomponent school district by the board of cooperative educational\nservices pursuant to subdivision eleven of section six-p of the general\nmunicipal law attributable to an approved cost of service computed\npursuant to this subdivision shall be deducted from the cost of services\nallocated to such component school district. The expense of\ntransportation provided by the board of cooperative educational services\npursuant to paragraph q of subdivision four of this section shall be\neligible for aid apportioned pursuant to subdivision seven of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this chapter and no board of cooperative\neducational services transportation expense shall be an approved cost of\nservices for the computation of aid under this subdivision.\nTransportation expense pursuant to paragraph q of subdivision four of\nthis section shall be included in the computation of the ten percent\nlimitation on administ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicable percent defined in paragraph c\nof this subdivision and (ii) the sum of the local share and any\nrepayment due for the prior year loan. Such local share shall equal the\npositive remainder resulting when aid payable on behalf of the district\nin the current year pursuant to subdivision five of this section is\nsubtracted from the district's BOCES expenses which are or would be\naidable in the current year or the next year pursuant to such\nsubdivision five. The annual application for such a loan shall be in a\nform prescribed by the commissioner and shall accompany the submission\nof the final set of state aid forms required of the BOCES each year and\nshall be certified by the district superintendent of the BOCES. The\namount of the loan in any year shall be determined by the commissioner\nand the payment and repayment of the loan shall be in accordance with\nthe provisions of paragraph d of this subdivision.\n  c. Applicable percent. The applicable percent shall be determined by\nthe number of years that an eligible district has been a component\ndistrict of a BOCES. In the first year, such percent shall be equal to\nthe district's BOCES and building aid ratio for aid payable in the first\nyear in which the district joins the BOCES, each year thereafter, such\npercent shall be reduced by ten percent until such percent would drop\nbelow ten percent at which time it shall be deemed to be zero.\n  d. Payment and repayment. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions\nof section thirty-six hundred nine-a of this chapter, the loan amounts\ndetermined by the commissioner pursuant to paragraph b of this\nsubdivision shall be paid to each eligible school district on or before\nJune fifteenth, commencing with the first year of eligibility, but only\nto the extent that the repayment of the base year loan has been secured.\nNotwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, the state comptroller\nshall deduct the amount of any base year loan from any monies du...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>set forth\nthe cost of such acquisition which shall be the amount certified by the\ndormitory authority as sufficient to pay the principal of, the\nredemption premium, if any, and interest to the earliest of either the\nmaturity date or the next redemption date on all obligations of the\ndormitory authority issued in relation to providing such facilities,\nincluding all incidental expenses in relation thereto, and (ii) provide\nfor an allocation and apportionment of the cost of such acquisition\namong the component school districts on such equitable basis as the\nparties thereto shall determine and agree, and the proportion of the\ntotal cost to be provided by each such district in accordance with such\nallocation and apportionment. In those cases where construction of such\nfacilities shall not have been completed, the amount so certified by the\ndormitory authority shall include the amount estimated to be necessary\nby the dormitory authority to complete such construction by it acting\nfor and on behalf of such board of cooperative educational services;\nprovided, however, that such agreement shall provide that such board\nshall pay to the dormitory authority any additional amounts thereafter\ndetermined and certified by the dormitory authority to be necessary in\norder to complete the construction of such facilities. Existing\ncontracts awarded by the dormitory authority for the construction of\nsuch facilities shall not be modified, nor shall any work not covered\nthereby be authorized, without the prior consent of an officer of such\nboard authorized to so act by a resolution of such board. Such agreement\nshall be executed by all the component school districts of such board of\ncooperative educational services whose allocation of administrative\nexpenses would include a portion of the amounts required to be paid the\ndormitory authority for the rental of such facilities.\n  b. The acquisition of such facilities is hereby declared and\ndetermined to be a school...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no\napproval of the voters of such component school district shall be\nrequired, (ii) the voting of a special tax or a tax to be collected in\ninstallments shall not be a condition precedent to the adoption of a\nbond resolution for such object or purpose, (iii) a majority vote of the\nentire voting strength of the board of education shall be sufficient for\nadoption of such a bond resolution, which bond resolution may be adopted\nat a regular meeting, or a special meeting of the board of education\ncalled on not less than twelve hours oral or written notice, which may\nbe held either within or outside of such district, (iv) any such bond\nresolution shall take effect immediately and shall not be subject either\nto a mandatory or permissive referendum, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no such bond resolution\nshall be adopted prior to the execution by the board of cooperative\neducational services and the component school districts of such board of\ncooperative educational services of the agreement required by paragraph\na of this subdivision.\n  c. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to permit any school\ndistrict in a city (as defined in paragraph two-b of section 2.00 of the\nlocal finance law) to contract indebtedness for such object or purpose\nin excess of the limitation prescribed by paragraph b of section 104.00\nof such law, without a compliance with the provisions of paragraph c\nthereof. A school district, other than a school district in a city, may\nissue bonds or bond anticipation notes for such object or purpose in\nexcess of the limitation prescribed by paragraph d of such section\n104.00, without complying with the requirements of subparagraphs one\nthrough three of such paragraph. Notwithstanding any other provision of\nlaw to the contrary, a special act school district, as defined in\nsubdivision eight of section four thousand one of this chapter, shall\nnot be deemed a component school district of the board of cooperative\neducational services for purposes of this subdivision.\n  d. Upon certification by the dormitory authority of the receipt by it\nof the amount set forth in the agreement as the cost of the acquisition\nof such facilities, title thereto shall vest in the board of cooperative\neducational services without any further action or deed or conveyance,\nwhich title shall be held by the board of cooperative educational\nservices for the benefit and on behalf of all the component school\ndistricts of such board executing such agreement.\n  e. The validity of any obligations issued by any school district in\naccordance with this subdivision shall not be affected or impaired by\nany omission, defect or irregularity in any previous acts or proceedings\nby the board of cooperative educational services, or by any of...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>set forth the cost of such\nacquisition or construction and costs incidental thereto and (ii)\nprovide for an allocation and apportionment of the costs of such\nacquisition or construction among the component school districts on such\nequitable basis as the parties thereto shall determine and agree, and\nthe proportion of the total cost to be provided by each such district in\naccordance with such allocation and apportionment. Such agreement shall\nbe executed by all the component school districts of such board of\ncooperative educational services and such board of cooperative\neducational services. Such agreement may provide that each component\nschool district of such a board of cooperative educational services\nshall issue an agreed upon amount of its obligations in a total amount\nsufficient to acquire or construct such facilities, or that all\ncomponent districts of such board shall together issue joint obligations\npledging the full faith and credit for all component districts jointly\nand that each such district shall pay a specified share of annual debt\nservice on such joint obligations in accordance with the provisions of\narticle five-g of the general municipal law and applicable provisions of\nthe local finance law.\n  b. The acquisition or construction of such facilities is hereby\ndeclared and determined to be a public purpose and a school district\npurpose and a specific object or purpose for which each such component\nschool district is hereby authorized to expend money and contract\nindebtedness.  The period of probable usefulness of such specific object\nor purpose is hereby determined to be thirty years. Each such component\nschool district is hereby authorized to finance its share of the cost of\nthe acquisition or construction of such facilities, together with costs\nincidental thereto, either from any current funds legally available\ntherefor or by the issuance of obligations pursuant to the local finance\nlaw; provided, however, that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no approval of the voters of such\ncomponent school district shall be required, (ii) the voting of a\nspecial tax or a tax to be collected in installments shall not be a\ncondition precedent to the adoption of a bond resolution for such\nspecific object or purpose, (iii) a majority vote of the entire voting\nstrength of the board of education shall be sufficient for adoption of\nsuch a bond resolution, which bond resolution may be adopted at a\nregular meeting, or a special meeting of the board of education called\non not less than twenty-four hours oral or written notice to the members\nof such board as provided in section sixteen hundred six of the\neducation law, which meeting may be held either within or outside of\nsuch district, (iv) any such bond resolution shall take effect\nimmediately and shall not be subject to either a mandatory or permissive\nreferendum, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no such bond resolution shall be adopted prior to\nthe execution by the board of cooperative educational services and all\nof the component school districts of such board of cooperative\neducational services of the agreement required by paragraph a of this\nsubdivision.\n  c. No further approval of the voters of such board of cooperative\neducational services or any component district thereof shall be required\nother than that required by paragraph t of subdivision four of this\nsection.\n  d. Such agreement shall further provide that title to the facility\nshall vest in the board of cooperative educational services which title\nshall be held by the board of cooperative educational services for the\nbenefit and on behalf of all the component school districts of such\nboard executing such agreement.\n  e. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to permit any school\ndistrict in a city (as defined in paragraph two-b of section 2.00 of the\nlocal finance law) to contract indebtedness for such specific object or\npurpose in excess of the limitation prescribed by paragraph b of section\n104.00 of such law, without complying with the provisions of paragraph c\nthereof. A school district, other than a school district in a city, may\nnot issue bonds or bond anticipation notes for such specific object or\npurpose in excess of the limitation prescribed by paragraph d of such\nsection 104.00, without complying with the requirements of subparagraphs\none through three of such paragraph. Notwithstanding any other provision\nof law to the contrary, a special act school district, as defined in\nsubdivision eight of section four thousand one of this chapter, shall\nnot be deemed a component school district of the board of cooperative\neducational services for purposes of this subdivision.\n  f. State aid on account of the acquisition or construction of such\nfacilities shall be paid to each component school district based upon\nits respective debt service or share thereof paid ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>procedures for the acquisition of personal property\nboth by purchase and by gift,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>procedures for the periodic inventory\nof personal property, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>procedures for the sale of valuable\npersonal property to the highest bidder, except however that vehicles\nreceived at no cost for use in an authorized welfare to work program may\nbe transferred at no cost or at cost of repairs, where repairs have been\nmade to the vehicle at the board of cooperative education services, to\nparticipants who have met all the program requirements. Each such board\nshall periodically review and update such policy, provided that any\namendments of the policy shall be subject to approval of the\ncommissioner.\n  19. Where the district has provided transportation to students\nenrolled in such district to a school sponsored field trip,\nextracurricular activity or any other similar event, it shall provide\ntransportation back to either the point of departure or to the\nappropriate school in the district, unless the parent or legal guardian\nof a student participating in such event has provided the school\ndistrict with written notice, consistent with district policy,\nauthorizing an alternative form of return transportation for such\nstudent or unless intervening circumstances make such transportation\nimpractical. In cases where intervening circumstances make\ntransportation of a student back to the point of departure or to the\nappropriate school in the district impractical, a representative of the\nschool district shall remain with the student until such student's\nparent or legal guardian has been</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contacted and informed of the\nintervening circumstances which make such transportation impractical and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1950__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such student had been delivered to his or her parent or legal\nguardian.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>