<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2">
        <num>2</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2. Definitions. Wherever used in this chapter, the following terms\nshall have the respective meanings hereinafter set forth or indicated:\n  1. Academy. The term "academy" means an incorporated institution for\ninstruction in secondary education, and such high schools, academic\ndepartments in union free school districts and similar unincorporated\nschools as are admitted by the regents to the university as of academic\ngrade.\n  2. College. The term "college" includes universities and other\ninstitutions for higher education authorized to confer degrees.\n  3. University. The term "university" means The University of the State\nof New York.\n  4. Regents. The term "regents" means board of regents of The\nUniversity of the State of New York.\n  5. Commissioner. The term "commissioner" means commissioner of\neducation of the state of New York.\n  6. Department. The term "department" means education department of the\nstate of New York.\n  7. Secondary education. The term "secondary education" means\ninstruction of academic grade, between the elementary grades and the\ncollege or university.\n  8. Higher education. The term "higher education" means education in\nadvance of secondary education, and includes the work of colleges,\nuniversities, professional and technical schools, and educational work\nconnected with libraries, museums, university and educational extension\ncourses and similar agencies.\n  9. Trustee. The term "trustees," when not used in reference to a\nschool district, includes directors, managers or other similar members\nof the governing board of an educational institution. The terms\n"trustee" and "trustees", respectively, when used in reference to a\nschool district, shall include the plural or singular meaning, as the\ncase may be, unless otherwise specified.\n  10. Parental relation. The term "persons in parental relation" to a\nchild includes the parents, guardians or other persons, whether one or\nmore, lawfully having the care, custody or control of such child,\nincluding persons who have been designated pursuant to title fifteen-A\nof article five of the general obligations law as persons in parental\nrelation to the child.\n  11. Compulsory school ages. The term "child of compulsory school age"\nmeans any child between six and sixteen years of age lawfully required\nto attend upon instruction.\n  12. School authorities. The term "school authorities" means the\ntrustees, or board of education, or corresponding officers, whether one\nor more, and by whatever name known, of a city school district, or other\nschool district however created.\n  13. School officer. The term "school officer" means a clerk,\ncollector, or treasurer of any school district; a trustee; a member of a\nboard of education or other body in control of the schools by whatever\nname known in a union free school district, central school district,\ncentral high school district, or in a city school district; a\nsuperintendent of schools; a district superintendent; a supervisor of\nattendance or attendance officer; or other elective or appointive\nofficer in a school district whose duties generally relate to the\nadministration of affairs connected with the public school system.\n  14. Board of education. The term "board of education" shall include by\nwhatever name known the governing body charged with the general control,\nmanagement and responsibility of the schools of a union free school\ndistrict, central school district, central high school district, or of a\ncity school district.\n  15. School year. The term "school year" means the period commencing on\nthe first day of July in each year and ending on the thirtieth day of\nJune next following.\n  16. City school district. a. The following school districts are hereby\ndesignated and declared to be city school districts: (1) Any school\ndistrict coterminous with a city on January first, nineteen hundred\nfifty; (2) any school district part of which was without and part of\nwhich was within a city on January first, nineteen hundred fifty, and\nwhich then contained the whole or the greater portion of the children of\nthe city between birth and eighteen years of age, as shown by the school\ncensus; and (3) any school district wholly within, but not coterminous\nwith, a city on January first, nineteen hundred fifty, and which then\ncontained the greater portion of the children of the city between birth\nand eighteen years of age, as shown by the school census.\n  b. Whenever a city shall be created after January first, nineteen\nhundred fifty, that school district shall be and become a city school\ndistrict which, on the effective date of the incorporation of such city,\nis: (1) coterminous with the city; (2) partly without and partly within\nthe city and then contains the whole or the greater portion of the\nchildren of the city between birth and eighteen years of age, as shown\nby the school census; or (3) wholly within but not coterminous with the\ncity and then contains the greater portion of the children of the city\nbetween birth and eighteen years of age, as shown by the school census.\n  c. The corporate existence of any school district, which, by virtue of\nthe provisions of this subdivision, shall be and become a city school\ndistrict, shall continue, and any such school district thereafter shall\nbe governed by the provisions of this chapter applicable to city school\ndistricts.\n  * 17. State university. The term "state university" means the state\nuniversity of New York, as created by article eight of this chapter.\n  * NB There are 2 sub 17's\n  * 17. City. The term "city" means the city school district of such\ncity where the context clearly so indicates.\n  * NB There are 2 sub 17's\n  18. Minor or infant. The term "minor" or "infant" means a person who\nhas not attained the age of eighteen years.\n  19. Expenditures. For purposes of computing aid to public school\ndistricts, boards of cooperative educational services, nonpublic\nelementary and secondary schools, public and cooperative library systems\nor public and free association libraries pursuant to this chapter or any\nother law, such aid shall be computed using state aid worksheets\ndeveloped pursuant to regulations of the commissioner, designed to\nreflect use of the state comptroller's definition of expenditures to the\nextent possible. Such worksheet definitions of expenditures shall be\nused notwithstanding the fact that this chapter or other applicable law\nmay use terms such as cash expenditures, expenses, costs, paid,\npayments, or other such terms.\n  24. Career education. The term "career education" means organized\neducational programs offering a sequence of courses which are directly\nrelated to the preparation of individuals in paid or unpaid employment\nin current or emerging occupations requiring other than a baccalaureate\nor advanced degrees, and shall include vocational and occupational\neducation. Such programs shall include competency-based applied learning\nwhich contributes to an individual's academic knowledge, higher-order\nreasoning, and problem solving skills, work activities, general\nemployability skills, and the skills necessary for economic independence\nas a productive and contributing member of society. Such term also\nincludes applied technology education. Except where the intent indicates\notherwise, the terms "vocational education" and "occupational education"\nshall mean "career education."\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>