<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2001"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2001">
        <num>2001</num>
        <heading>Notice of first meeting of district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2001. Notice of first meeting of district.  1. Whenever any school\ndistrict shall be formed, or two or more common school districts are\nconsolidated as provided in section fifteen hundred twelve, the district\nsuperintendent of schools, or any one or more of such district\nsuperintendents within whose districts it may be, shall prepare a notice\ndescribing such district and appointing a time and place for the first\ndistrict meeting, and deliver such notice to a taxable inhabitant of the\ndistrict.\n  2. It shall be the duty of such inhabitant to notify every other\ninhabitant of the district qualified to vote at the meeting, by\ndelivering to him a copy of the notice of such meeting, or in case of\nhis absence from home, by leaving a copy thereof, or so much thereof as\nrelates to the time, place and object of the meeting, at the place of\nhis abode, at least six days before the time of the meeting.\n  3. In case such meeting shall not be held, and in the opinion of the\ndistrict superintendent or superintendents it shall be necessary to hold\nsuch meeting before the time herein fixed for the first annual meeting,\nhe shall deliver another such notice to a taxable inhabitant of the\ndistrict, who shall serve it as provided in subdivision two of this\nsection.\n  4. Every taxable inhabitant, to whom a notice of any district meeting\nshall be delivered for service pursuant to any provision of part one of\nthis article, who shall refuse or neglect to serve the same, shall\nforfeit five dollars to be sued for by the supervisor for the benefit of\nthe district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>