<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2003"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2003"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2003"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2003">
        <num>2003</num>
        <heading>Notice of annual meeting in common school district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2003. Notice of annual meeting in common school district.  1. The\ndistrict clerk of each common school district shall give notice of the\navailability of the statement of expenditures pursuant to the provisions\nof section sixteen hundred eight of this chapter and shall also give\nnotice of the time and place of the annual meeting by publishing a\nnotice four times within the seven weeks next preceding such annual\nmeeting, the first publication to be at least forty-five days before\nsaid meeting, in two newspapers if there shall be two, or in one\nnewspaper if there shall be but one, having general circulation within\nsuch district. But if no newspaper shall then have general circulation\ntherein, the said notice shall be posted in at least twenty of the most\npublic places in said district forty-five days before the time of such\nmeeting.\n  2. Such notice shall also state that petitions nominating candidates\nfor the office of member of the board of trustees must be filed with the\nclerk of the district between the hours of nine a.m. and five p.m., not\nlater than the thirtieth day preceding the school meeting or election at\nwhich the candidates so nominated are to be elected.\n  3. Such notice and all other notices and reports required to be\npublished in newspapers under the provisions of this chapter shall be\nprinted at the rates and for the fees prescribed in the civil practice\nlaw and rules. In the event that the publishers of one or both of the\nnewspapers having general circulation in such district shall refuse to\nprint and publish the notices or reports at the rates and for the fees\nso prescribed, publication in such newspaper or newspapers so refusing\nmay be omitted, in which case the notices or reports shall be posted as\nrequired by this section in lieu of such publication.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>