<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2007"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2007"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2007"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2007">
        <num>2007</num>
        <heading>Special meeting in union free school district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2007. Special meeting in union free school district. 1. The board of\neducation in a union free school district shall have power to call\nspecial meetings of the inhabitants of the district whenever they shall\ndeem it necessary and proper, in the manner prescribed in section two\nthousand four of this chapter. The notice of each special meeting shall\nstate the purposes for which it is called, and no business shall be\ntransacted at such special meeting, except that which is specified in\nthe notice.\n  2. In a union free school district whose limits correspond with those\nof any incorporated village, the board of education shall have power to\ncall special meetings of the inhabitants of the district for the\npurposes mentioned in section four hundred sixteen in the manner\nprescribed in said section two thousand four of this chapter.\n  3. a. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions one and two of\nthis section, and of section two thousand four of this part, whenever\nthe voters of the district shall have defeated the budget of the\ndistrict, in whole or in part, or whenever the board of education shall\nhave rejected all bids for a contract or contracts for public work,\ntransportation or purchase, and whenever in either such case the board\nof education shall deem it necessary and proper to call a special\nmeeting to take appropriate action, the board of education shall be\nauthorized to give the notices required by subdivision one of section\ntwo thousand four of this part by publishing such notices once in each\nweek within the two weeks next preceding such special meeting, the first\npublication to be at least fourteen days before such meeting and any\nrequired posting to be fourteen days before the time of such meeting.\n  b. A school budget revote called pursuant to paragraph a of this\nsubdivision shall be held on the third Tuesday of June, provided,\nhowever that such budget revote shall be held on the second Tuesday in\nJune if the commissioner at the request of a local school board\ncertifies no later than March first that such vote would conflict with\nreligious observances.\n  c. Notwithstanding the provisions of section two thousand fourteen of\nthis part, where a school district shall have adopted personal\nregistration, the board of registration shall meet on such day or days\nas shall be fixed by the board of education, the last day of which,\nhowever, shall not be more than seven nor less than two days preceding\nany school district meeting notices for which shall have been given as\nprovided in this subdivision.\n  4. The board of education in a union free school district shall, in\neach case when a special district meeting is required or permitted to\nelect members of such board of education, call such meeting for at least\nsix consecutive hours between the hours of seven o'clock in the forenoon\nand nine o'clock in the afternoon, at least two of which hours shall be\nafter six o'clock in the afternoon, and notice shall be given in the\nmanner prescribed in section two thousand four of this chapter for\nmeetings held over the hours.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>