<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2018-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2018_D">
        <num>2018-D</num>
        <heading>Military voters</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Military service" means the military service of the state, or of\nthe United States, including the army, navy, marine corps, air force,\ncoast guard, space force, merchant marine and all components thereof,\nand the coast and geodetic survey, the public health service, the\nnational guard when in the service of the United States pursuant to call\nas provided by law, and the cadets or midshipmen of the United States\nMilitary Academy, United States Naval Academy, United States Air Force\nAcademy, United States Merchant Marine Academy and United States Coast\nGuard Academy.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Military voter" means a qualified voter of the state of New York\nwho is in actual military service, as defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, and by reason of such military service is absent from his\nor her district on the day of registration or election, or a voter who\nis discharged from such military service within thirty days of an\nelection and the spouse, parent, child or dependent of such voter\naccompanying or being with him or her, if a qualified voter and a\nresident of the same school district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Military ballot" means the ballot prepared, printed and supplied\nfor use by the military for the election of members of the board of\neducation and school district public library trustees, the adoption of\nthe annual budget and school district public library budget and\nreferenda.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Military address" means the mailing address of a military voter\nother than his or her residence address in his or her school district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Appropriate school board of education" means the board of\neducation in whose jurisdiction the military voter resides as a\nqualified voter.\n  2. A military voter may designate a preference to receive a military\nballot by mail, facsimile transmission or electronic mail. Such\ndesignation shall remain in effect until revoked or changed by the\nmilitary voter. If a military voter does not designate a preference, the\nboard of education shall transmit the military ballot application or\nmilitary ballot by mail. If a military voter designates a preference for\nfacsimile transmission or electronic mail but does not provide the\nnecessary facsimile number or e-mail address, the board of education\nshall transmit the voter registration application, military ballot\napplication or military ballot by mail and request the omitted\ninformation. All communications to the military voter shall include the\nmailing address of the board of education.\n  3. Irrespective of the preferred method of transmission designated by\na military voter, a military voter's original military ballot\napplication and military ballot must be returned by mail or in person.\n  4. Ballots for military voters shall be mailed or otherwise\ndistributed by the board of education, in accordance with the preferred\nmethod of transmission, as soon as practicable, but not later than\ntwenty-five days before any election as provided in this article, and\nfourteen days before any election as provided in article fifty-three of\nthis title.\n  5. The military voter shall mark the military ballot provided for in\nthis article in the same manner as an absentee ballot. After marking the\nballot, he or she shall fold such ballot and enclose it in the inner\naffirmation envelope bearing the military voter's affirmation on the\noutside of the envelope and seal the envelope. He or she shall then sign\nthe affirmation, with the blanks properly filled in. The inner\naffirmation envelope containing the military ballot sh...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>