<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2018-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2018-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2018_A">
        <num>2018-A</num>
        <heading>Absentee ballots for school district elections</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>absent from their county of residence; provided, however, if the\napplicant expects to be absent from such county for a duration covering\nmore than one election and seeks an absentee ballot for each election,\nsuch applicant shall state the dates when they expect to begin and end\nsuch absence; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>unable to appear at a polling place because of illness or physical\ndisability or duties related to the primary care of one or more\nindividuals who are ill or physically disabled; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a resident or patient of a veteran's administration hospital; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>detained in jail awaiting action by a grand jury or awaiting trial\nor confined in jail or prison after a conviction for an offense other\nthan a felony and stating the place where such applicant is so detained\nor confined.\n  d. Such application shall include the following statement to be signed\nby the voter.\n  I hereby declare that the foregoing is a true statement to the best of\nmy knowledge and belief, and I understand that if I make any material\nfalse statement in the foregoing statement of application for absentee\nballots, I shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n Date.....................Signature of Voter ...........................\n  e. An applicant whose ability to appear personally at the polling\nplace of the school district of which he or she is a qualified voter is\nsubstantially impaired by reason of permanent illness or physical\ndisability and whose registration record has been marked "permanently\ndisabled" by the board of elections pursuant to the provisions of the\nelection law shall be entitled to receive an absentee ballot pursuant to\nthe provisions of this section without making separate application for\nsuch absentee ballot, and the board of registration upon being advised\nby the board of elections on or with the list of registered voters that\nthe registration record of a voter is marked "permanently disabled"\nshall send an absentee ballot to such voter at his or her last known\naddress with a request to the postal authorities not to forward same but\nto return same in five days in the event that it cannot be delivered to\nthe addressee. The board of education shall determine whether such\nballot shall be sent by first class or by certified mail. All such\nballots shall be mailed in the same manner as determined by the board of\neducation. The board of registration shall make an appropriate entry on\nthe registration indicating the fact that an absentee ballot has been\nsent and the date of mailing.\n  f. An application must be receive...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the person named thereon is not a\nqualified voter of the school district, or school election district\n(where applicable), or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that he was within the county or city while\nthe polls of the election were open, except where the applicant is a\npatient in a hospital located within the county or city or detained or\nconfined in a jail located within the county or city and except where\nthe ballot was obtained upon the ground of inability to appear\npersonally at the polling place on the day of the school district\nelection because of illness or physical disability, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that he was\nable to appear personally while the polls were open, in cases where the\nballot was obtained upon the ground that the voter was a patient in a\nhospital located within the county or city or detained or confined in a\njail located within the county or city or upon the ground of inability\nto appear personally at the polling place on the day of the election\nbecause of illness or physical disability, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2018_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that he was not\nentitled to cast such ballot. An inspector shall make such an objection\nif he shall know or suspect that the person named on such envelope is\nnot such a qualified voter or was so within the school district or was\nable so to appear personally, or was not entitled to cast such ballot.\nThe election inspectors shall forthwith proceed to determine each\nobjection including any written challenge transmitted to them by the\ndistrict clerk as provided in subdivision six of this section. Unless\nthe inspectors, by majority vote, shall sustain the objection, the\nchairman, or if he refuses, another inspector shall endorse upon the\nenvelope the objection and the words "not sustained," shall sign such\nendorsement, and shall open the envelope and deposit the ballot as\nprovided in this section. Should the inspectors, by majority vote,\nsustain such objection, the objection and word "sustained" shall be\nsimilarly endorsed upon the envelope, the envelope shall not be opened\nnor the ballots therein canvassed, and such envelope shall be returned\nunopened to the clerk of the district. If the inspectors of election\nshall have received an envelope endorsed with the name of a person who\nto the knowledge of the inspectors is deceased on the day of the\nelection, the inspectors shall return such envelope unopened to the\nclerk of the district with the words "deceased--objection sustained"\nendorsed on the envelope.\n  12. If the inspectors of election shall have received an envelope, and\nupon opening the same no ballot shall be found therein, the inspectors\nshall make a memorandum showing that the ballot is missing. When the\ncasting of absentee voters' ballots shall have been completed, the\ninspectors shall ascertain the number of such ballots which have been\ndeposited in the ballot box by deducting from the number of envelopes\nopened the number of missing ballots, and shall make a separate return\nthereof in duplicate. The number of absentee voters' ball...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>