<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="202"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_202">
        <num>202</num>
        <heading>Regents</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_202__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every regent, on and after December fifteenth and before the\nfollowing January fifteenth, in each year, shall file with the secretary\nof the senate and with the clerk of the assembly a written statement of\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_202__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>each financial interest, direct or indirect of himself or herself,\nhis or her spouse and his or her unemancipated children under the age of\neighteen years in any activity which is subject to the jurisdiction of\nthe education department or name of the entity in which the interest is\nhad and whether such interest is over or under five thousand dollars in\nvalue.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_202__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>every office and directorship held by him or her in any\ncorporation, firm or enterprise which is subject to the jurisdiction of\nthe education department or which does business with an institution\nwhich is subject to the jurisdiction of the education department,\nincluding the name of such corporation, firm or enterprise.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_202__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any other interest or relationship which he or she determines in\nhis or her discretion might reasonably be expected to be in the public\ninterest and should be disclosed.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before January thirty-first in each year the secretary of\nthe senate and the clerk of the assembly shall jointly prepare a report\ncontaining the statements required to be filed pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_202__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision. Copies of such report shall be open to public\ninspection in the office of the secretary of the senate and the clerk of\nthe assembly. The senate and assembly may jointly adopt rules to\nimplement the provisions of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>