<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2025"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2025"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2025"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2025/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2025/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2025/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2025/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2025">
        <num>2025</num>
        <heading>Procedures at school district meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2025. Procedures at school district meetings.  1. District meetings\nin common school districts shall be called to order by the trustee or\nthe chairman of the board of trustees or by a person chosen by the\ntrustee or trustees. The qualified voters present and voting shall\nnominate and elect a qualified voter of the district as permanent\nchairman.\n  2. In union free and central school districts the board of education\nshall appoint a qualified voter of the district as permanent chairman of\neach meeting or election to call such meeting or election to order. When\nhours have been set for voting in the notice of meeting or election, the\nchairman shall declare the polls open and closed at the appropriate\ntime. No motions shall be in order during the hours specified in the\nnotice for voting. In districts divided into election districts, the\nchief election inspector in each district shall declare the polls open\nand closed at the appropriate time.\n  3. The clerk of the district shall serve as clerk of all meetings and\nelections.\n  a. In common school districts the voters present and voting may elect\na clerk of the meeting if the district clerk is not present. The voters\nmay also elect assistant clerks and election inspectors as required. At\nleast two election inspectors shall be elected for each ballot box or\nvoting machine used. The inspectors shall choose a chief inspector of\nelection.\n  b. In union free and central school districts the board of education\nshall appoint a qualified voter as acting clerk in the absence or\ninability to act of the district clerk. The board of education shall\nalso appoint assistant clerks and election inspectors as required. At\nleast two election inspectors shall be appointed for each ballot box or\nvoting machine. The board of education shall designate a chief election\ninspector, and if the district is divided into election districts the\nboard of education shall appoint a chief election inspector for each\nelection district.\n  4. The clerk and assistant clerk or clerks of the meeting or election\nshall keep a true and accurate written record of all of the proceedings\nof the meeting or election and shall file such written record with the\nclerk of the district within twenty-four hours after the meeting or\nelection.\n  5. Each assistant clerk and election inspector appointed by a board of\neducation shall be entitled to compensation at a rate fixed by such\nboard of education.\n  6. A person seventeen years of age who is enrolled in a school\ndistrict and fulfilling the requirements of section thirty-two hundred\nseven-a of this chapter shall be eligible to be appointed as, and to\nperform the duties of, an election inspector or poll clerk as provided\nin this part.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>