<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2031-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2031-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2031-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2031-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2031-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2031-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2031-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2031_A">
        <num>2031-A</num>
        <heading>Electioneering within one hundred feet of polling place prohibited; distance markers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2031-a. Electioneering within one hundred feet of polling place\nprohibited; distance markers.  1. At every election held for the office\nof trustee or member of a board of education and at every vote upon any\nproposition or issue in a school district where the election or vote is\nheld at a different time from, and not during, the annual meeting of the\ndistrict, there shall be conspicuously placed, by the inspectors of\nelection, distance markers at a distance of one hundred feet from the\npolling place. Such distance markers shall indicate the prohibition\ncontained herein and shall be so placed at least one-half hour before\nthe opening of the polls and shall remain until the polls are closed.\n  2. At such elections or voting held at a different time from, and not\nduring, the annual meeting of the district, while the polls are open no\nperson shall do any electioneering within the polling place, or within\none hundred feet therefrom in any public street, or within such distance\nin any place in a public manner and no banner, poster or placard on\nbehalf of or in opposition to any candidate or issue to be voted upon\nshall be allowed in or upon the polling place or within one hundred feet\ntherefrom during the election.  For the purposes of this section, the\none hundred foot distance shall be deemed to include a one hundred foot\nradial measured from the entrances, designated by the inspectors of\nelection, to a building where such election is being held. This section\nshall not be deemed to prohibit the board of trustees or board of\neducation from displaying within any polling place a copy or copies of\nany budget or proposition to be voted upon.\n  3. Any person who wilfully violates the provisions of this section\nshall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>