<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207">
        <num>207</num>
        <heading>Legislative power</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 207. Legislative power.  Subject and in conformity to the\nconstitution and laws of the state, the regents shall exercise\nlegislative functions concerning the educational system of the state,\ndetermine its educational policies, and, except, as to the judicial\nfunctions of the commissioner of education, establish rules for carrying\ninto effect the laws and policies of the state, relating to education,\nand the functions, powers, duties and trusts conferred or charged upon\nthe university and the education department.  But no enactment of the\nregents shall modify in any degree the freedom of the governing body of\nany seminary for the training of priests or clergymen to determine and\nregulate the entire course of religious, doctrinal or theological\ninstruction to be given in such institution.  No rule by which more than\na majority vote shall be required for any specified action by the\nregents shall be amended, suspended or repealed by a smaller vote than\nthat required for action thereunder.  Rules or regulations, or\namendments or repeals thereof, adopted or prescribed by the commissioner\nof education as provided by law shall not be effective unless and until\napproved by the regents, except where authority is conferred by the\nregents upon the commissioner of education to adopt, prescribe, amend or\nrepeal such rules or regulations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>