<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-10-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-21/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-21/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-21/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-21/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21">
        <num>21</num>
        <heading>Bullying and harassment prevention and response</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 21. Bullying and harassment prevention and response. 1. No student\nshall be subjected to harassment or bullying, including cyberbullying,\nby other students on school property or at a school function.\n  2. Every school, subject to this section, shall adopt a written in\nplain-language and age-appropriate anti-bullying and harassment policy,\nwhich must be published on the school's website or internal\nparent/student portal and shared annually with employees, parents, and\nstudents. Such policy shall include but not be limited to information on\nhow bullying and harassment is defined, how incidents will be reported,\ninvestigated, and documented, and an age-appropriate process for\nnotifying the victim about the final outcome of the investigation.\n  3. School employees who witness bullying or harassment, or receive an\noral or written report of bullying or harassment, shall promptly notify\nthe principal or head of school or the principal's or head of school's\ndesignee, orally not later than one school day after such school\nemployee witnesses or receives a report of bullying and harassment, and\nmust file a written report with the principal or head of school's\ndesignee not later than two school days after making the initial oral\nreport.\n  4. Upon a report of bullying, harassment, or retaliation, the\nprincipal or head of school, or the principal or head of school's\ndesignee, must investigate promptly, communicate their findings with the\nvictim and take immediate steps and appropriate follow-up action\nreasonably calculated to ensure that such conduct has stopped and ensure\nthe safety of the student or students including retaliation against any\nindividual who in good faith reports such bullying or assists in the\ninvestigation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>