<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-211-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-211-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="211-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-211-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-211-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-211-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-211-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_211_D">
        <num>211-D</num>
        <heading>Contract for excellence</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph a of subdivision two of this section. For\npurposes of this paragraph, the "gap elimination adjustment percentage"\nshall be calculated as the sum of one minus the quotient of the sum of\nthe school district's net gap elimination adjustment for two thousand\nten--two thousand eleven computed pursuant to chapter fifty-three of the\nlaws of two thousand ten, making appropriations for the support of\ngovernment, plus the school district's gap elimination adjustment for\ntwo thousand eleven--two thousand twelve as computed pursuant to chapter\nfifty-three of the laws of two thousand eleven, making appropriations\nfor the support of the local assistance budget, including support for\ngeneral support for public schools, divided by the total aid for\nadjustment computed pursuant to chapter fifty-three of the laws of two\nthousand eleven, making appropriations for the local assistance budget,\nincluding support for general support for public schools. Provided,\nfurther, that such amount shall be expended to support and maintain\nallowable programs and activities approved in the two thousand nine--two\nthousand ten school year or to support new or expanded allowable\nprograms and activities in the current year.\n  2. a.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a common, union free, central, central high school, or a\ncity school district in a city having less than one hundred twenty-five\nthousand inhabitants, required to prepare a contract for excellence\npursuant to subdivision one of this section and, as of April first of\nthe base year, does not contain any schools identified as in corrective\naction or restructuring status or requiring academic progress: year\nthree or above, each contract for excellence shall describe how the sum\nof the amounts apportioned to the school district in the current year as\ntotal foundation aid, in excess of one hundred four percent of the\ndistrict's foundation aid base, as adjusted for additional amounts\npayable as charter school basic tuition over such amount payable in the\nbase year, shall be used to support new programs and new activities or\nredesign or expand the use of programs and activities demonstrated to\nimprove student achievement; provided however, up to fifty percent of\nadditional funding received in the current year may be used to maintain\ninvestments in programs and activities listed in paragraph a of\nsubdivision three of this section.\n  (ii) In a common, union free, central, central high school, or a city\nschool district in a city having less than one hundred twenty-five\nthousand inhabitants, required to prepare a contract for excellence\npursuant to subdivision one of this section and, as of April first of\nthe base year, has at least one school identified as in corrective\naction or restructuring status or requiring academic progress: year\nthree or above, each contract for excellence shall describe how the sum\nof the amounts apportioned to the school district in the current year as\ntotal foundation aid, in excess of one hundred four percent of the\ndistrict's foundation aid base, as adjusted for additional amounts\npayable as charter school basic tuition over such amount payable in the\nbase year, shall be used to support new programs and new activitie...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In a city school district in a city having a population of one\nmillion or more inhabitants, each contract for excellence shall describe\nhow the amounts apportioned to the school district in the current year\nas total foundation aid and academic achievement grants, in excess of\none hundred three percent of the district's foundation aid base, shall\nbe used to support new programs and new activities or expand the use of\nprograms and activities demonstrated to improve student achievement;\nprovided however, up to thirty million dollars or twenty-five percent of\nadditional funding received in the current year, whichever is less, may\nbe used to maintain investments in the programs and activities listed in\nparagraph a of subdivision three of this section.\n  (vi) Each contract for excellence for a school district that was\nrequired to prepare a contract for excellence in the base year shall\nprovide for the expenditure of an amount equivalent to the total\nbudgeted amount approved by the commissioner in the district's approved\ncontract for excellence for the base year; provided that such amount\nshall be expended to support and maintain allowable programs and\nactivities approved in the base year or to support new or expanded\nallowable programs and activities in the current year.\n  (vii) (A) Notwithstanding any other provision of this section to the\ncontrary, a school district that submitted a contract for excellence for\nthe two thousand seven--two thousand eight school year and the two\nthousand eight--two thousand nine school year and is required to submit\na contract for excellence for the two thousand nine--two thousand ten\nschool year but did not fully expend all of its two thousand seven--two\nthousand eight foundation aid subject to the contract for excellence\nrestrictions during the two thousand seven--two thousand eight school\nyear may re-allocate and expend such unexpended funds during the two\nthousand eight--two thousand nine and two thousand ni...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The contract shall specify the new or expanded programs for\nwhich additional amounts of such total foundation aid, or grant shall be\nused and shall affirm that such programs shall predominately benefit\nstudents with the greatest educational needs including, but not limited\nto, those students with limited English proficiency, students in poverty\nand students with disabilities.\n  (ii) (A) In a city school district in a city having a population of\none million or more inhabitants such contract shall also include a plan,\nwhich shall be developed in collaboration with the collective bargaining\nunits representing teachers and the principals beginning in September\ntwo thousand twenty-two and signed off on by the chancellor and the\npresidents of each bargaining unit, to reduce actual class sizes,\nbeginning September two thousand twenty-three and to be achieved by\nSeptember two thousand twenty-eight for all classes, with the exception\nof physical education and performing groups, as follows:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nkindergarten-third grade to have no more than twenty students per class;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fourth-eighth grade to have no more than twenty-three students per\nclass; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>high school to have no more than twenty-five students per\nclass. Physical education and performing groups shall have no more than\nforty students per class at all levels. Each year of the plan, an\nadditional twenty percent of the classrooms in the city school district,\nexcluding special education classes, shall be in compliance with the\nclass size targets such that the city school district is in full\ncompliance by two thousand twenty-eight and all classes should maintain\nthe target class size. The class size reduction plan shall prioritize\nschools serving populations with higher poverty levels.\n  (B) The class size reduction plan shall include any exemptions to the\nclass size targets. These exemptions shall be limited to:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>space;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nover-enrolled students;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>license area shortages; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>severe\neconomic distress. Any such exemptions shall be approved by the\nchancellor and the presidents of the collective bargaining units\nrepresenting the teachers and the principals as part of the class size\nreduction plan. Should the chancellor and the presidents of the\ncollective bargaining units representing the teachers and the principals\nbe unable to reach agreement on the exemptions after thirty days, the\nissue shall be determined by an arbitrator. In addition, any exemption\nbased on available space shall include a reference to the capital budget\nto demonstrate that the budget is aligned with resolving the exemption\nstatus. Exempted classes, for the years in which they are exempt, and\nspecial education classes shall not count toward the twenty percent\ntarget.\n  (C) The class size reduction plan shall also include the methods to be\nused to achieve the class size targets, such as the creation or\nconstruction of more classrooms and school buildings, the placement of\nm...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the annual reports, the city school district shall\nsubmit a financial impact statement on November fifteenth, two thousand\ntwenty-five. The financial impact statement may recommend a pause of the\nclass size reduction plan, but in no event may it result in a roll back\nor increase in class sizes.\n  c. The contract for excellence shall state, for all funding sources,\nwhether federal, state or local, the instructional expenditures per\npupil, the special education expenditures per pupil, and the total\nexpenditures per pupil, projected for the current year and actually\nincurred in the base year.\n  3. a. The commissioner shall adopt regulations establishing allowable\nprograms and activities intended to improve student achievement which\nshall be limited to:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>class size reduction, (ii) programs that\nincrease student time on task, including but not limited to, academic\nafter-school programs, (iii) teacher and principal quality initiatives,\n(iv) middle school and high school re-structuring,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>expansion or\nreplication of effective model programs for students with limited\nEnglish proficiency, and (vi) full-day kindergarten or prekindergarten.\nProvided, however, that districts may use up to fifteen percent of the\nadditional funding they receive for experimental programs designed to\ndemonstrate the efficacy of other strategies to improve student\nachievement consistent with the intent of this section and, in school\nyear two thousand seven--two thousand eight, up to thirty million\ndollars or twenty-five percent of such additional funding, whichever is\nless, may be used to maintain investments in programs and activities\nlisted in this subdivision. Any such district seeking to implement an\nexperimental program shall first submit a plan to the commissioner\nsetting forth the need for such experimental program and how such\nprogram will improve student performance.\n  b. The commissioner shall assist school districts that include in\ntheir contract for excellence the implementation of incentives,\ndeveloped in collaboration with teachers in the collective bargaining\nprocess, for highly qualified and experienced teachers to work in low\nperforming schools to ensure that such incentives are effective.\n  4. a. A district's contract for excellence for the academic year two\nthousand eight--two thousand nine and thereafter, shall be developed\nthrough a public process, in consultation with parents or persons in\nparental relation, teachers, administrators, and any distinguished\neducator appointed pursuant to section two hundred eleven-c of this\nchapter.\n  b. Such process shall include at least one public hearing. In a city\nschool district in a city of one million or more inhabitants, a public\nhearing shall be held within each county of such city. A transcript of\nthe testimony presented at such public hearings shall be included when\nthe contract for excellence is submitted to the commissioner, for review\nwhen making a determination pursuant to subdi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Increases in total foundation aid and supplemental educational\nimprovement plan grants shall be used to supplement, and not supplant\nfunds allocated by the district in the base year for all purposes set\nforth in subdivision three of this section. In a city of one million or\nmore, the city school district will provide the collective bargaining\nunit for teachers with the list of budget codes in which funding\nprovided under this section is utilized for a budget that would begin\nJuly first, two thousand twenty-five and after. Except in a city of one\nmillion or more, the school district audit report certified to the\ncommissioner by an independent certified public accountant or an\nindependent accountant pursuant to section twenty-one hundred sixteen-a\nof this chapter shall include a certification by such accountant in a\nform prescribed by the commissioner of compliance with the first\nsentence of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within ten days of adoption of a budget by the city of New York,\nan independent certified public accountant, or an independent accountant\nor the comptroller of such city shall certify in a form prescribed by\nthe commissioner that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an audit by such office has confirmed that\nincreases in total foundation aid and supplemental improvement grants in\nthe base year were used to supplement, and not supplant funds allocated\nby the district in the previous year and (ii) in the adopted budget,\nincreases in total foundation aid and supplemental improvement grants\nsupplement, not supplant funds allocated by the district in the base\nyear for such purposes.\n  Upon a determination that either</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_211_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>increases in total foundation aid\nand supplemental improvement grants in the base year were used to\nsupplant funds allocated by the district, or (ii) increases in total\nfoundation aid and supplemental improvement grants as appropriated will\nsupplant funds allocated by the district in the base year, the district\nshall be ordered to restore funds in such amounts as to eliminate the\nviolation.\n  7. The trustees or board of education of each school district subject\nto this section, or the chancellor in the case of a city school district\nin a city of one million or more inhabitants, shall assure that\nprocedures are in place by which parents or persons in parental relation\nmay bring complaints concerning implementation of the district's\ncontract for excellence.\n  a. In a city school district in a city of one million or more\ninhabitants, such procedures shall provide that complaints may be filed\nwith the building principal with an appeal to the community\nsuperintendent, or filed directly with the community superintendent, and\nthat any appeal of the determination of a community superintendent shall\nbe made to the chancellor.\n  b. In all other districts, such procedures shall either provide for\nthe filing of complaints with the building principals with an appeal to\nthe superintendent of schools or for filing of the complaint directly\nwith the superintendent of schools, and shall provide for an appeal to\nthe trustees or board of education from the determination of the\nsuperintendent of schools.\n  c. The determination of the trustees or a board of education or the\nchancellor may be appealed to the commissioner pursuant to section three\nhundred ten of this title.\n  8. School districts subject to the provisions of this section shall\npublicly report the expenditure of total foundation aid in the form and\nmanner prescribed by the commissioner which shall ensure full disclosure\nof the use of such funds.\n  9. The department shall develop a methodology...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>