<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2117"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2117"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2117"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2117/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2117/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2117/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2117/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2117">
        <num>2117</num>
        <heading>Reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2117. Reports.  1. The school authorities of each school district\nshall make a full report to the commissioner of education upon any\nparticular matter relating to their schools whenever such report shall\nbe required by said commissioner.\n  2. The school authorities of each such school district shall, on the\nfirst day of August in each year, make to the commissioner of education\na report in writing for the year ending June thirtieth preceding.  In\ndistricts under the jurisdiction of a district superintendent, such\nreports shall be first submitted to the district superintendent, in\nduplicate, and he shall approve one copy and file it with the\ncommissioner of education. Such report shall be in such form as the\ncommissioner of education shall approve; and every such report shall\ncertify:\n  a. The whole time school has been maintained in their district during\nthe year ending on June thirtieth previous to the date of such report,\nand stating what portion of the time such school has been taught by\nqualified teachers, and the whole number of days, including holidays, in\nwhich the school was taught by qualified teachers.\n  b. The amount of their drafts upon the county treasurer, collector or\ntreasurer of the district for the payment of teachers' salaries during\nsuch year, and the amount of their drafts for the purchase of books and\nschool apparatus during such year, and the manner in which such moneys\nhave been expended.\n  c. The number of children taught in the district during such year by\nqualified teachers, and the aggregate days' attendance of all such\nchildren.\n  d. The number of children residing in their district, from birth and\nunder eighteen years of age, who shall have been, on the thirtieth day\nof August last preceding the date of such report, legal residents of\nsuch district. Children supported at an orphan asylum shall not be\nincluded in such enumeration.\n  e. The number of vaccinated and unvaccinated children of school age in\ntheir district.\n  f. The amount of money paid for teachers' salaries, in addition to the\npublic money paid therefor, the amount of taxes levied in such district\nfor purchasing school sites, for building, hiring, purchasing, repairing\nand insuring schoolhouses, for fuel, for school libraries, or for any\nother purpose allowed by law.\n  g. Such additional information in relation to the schools under their\nmanagement and control as the commissioner of education shall require.\n  3. The commissioner of education shall prepare, based on information\nsubmitted to him by school districts, periodic reports covering new\nschool buildings giving information about them including but not limited\nto the following:\n  (1) Cost of site.\n  (2) Cost of site improvement including roads, parking, playfields, and\nutility lines to the building wall.\n  (3) Original furnishings, equipment and apparatus.\n  (4) Professional fees.\n  (5) Incidental costs.\n  (6) Total cost of building.\n  (7) Cost of building per pupil.\n  (8) Cost of building per gross square foot.\n  (9) Cost per gross square foot of the heating and ventilating.\n  (10) Cost per gross square foot of the plumbing.\n  (11) Cost per gross square foot of the electrical work.\n  (12) Square foot per pupil in the total gross area.\n  (13) Square foot per pupil in the net area of the regular and special\nclassrooms.\n  (14) Square foot per pupil in the net area of other rooms used for\neducational, health, administrative or social purposes such as the\ncafeteria, auditorium, gymnasium, kitchen and library.\n  (15) Square foot per pupil of the remaining difference between the\ngross area and the sum of thirteen and fourteen which would include\ntoilet rooms, general storage, corridors, stair enclosures, janitor\nclosets, boiler rooms, building machinery rooms and the area occupied by\nthe walls of the building.\n  (16) An outline of the school plan.\n  (17) A brief outline specification for the building construction.\n  (18) The name of the architect.\n  (19) The name of the mechanical engineer.\n  (20) The name of the structural engineer.\n  (21) Whether single or multiple bidding was used.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>