<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2121"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2121"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2121"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2121">
        <num>2121</num>
        <heading>Duties of district clerk</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2121. Duties of district clerk.  It shall be the duty of the clerk\nof each school district:\n  1. To record the proceedings of all meetings of the voters of his\ndistrict in a book to be provided for that purpose by the district, and\nto enter therein true copies of all reports made by the trustees to the\ndistrict superintendent.\n  2. To give notice, in the manner prescribed by subdivision two of\nsection two thousand one, of the time and place of holding special\ndistrict meetings called by the trustees.\n  3. To affix a notice in writing of the time and place of any adjourned\nmeeting in at least five of the most public places of such district,\nwhen the meeting shall have been adjourned for a longer time than one\nmonth. Such notice shall be so affixed at least five days before the\ntime appointed for such adjourned meeting.\n  4. To give the required notice of every annual district meeting.\n  5. To give notice immediately to every person elected or appointed to\noffice of his election or appointment; and also to report to the town\nclerk of the town in which the schoolhouse of his district is situated,\nthe names and post-office addresses of such officers, under a penalty of\nfive dollars for neglect in each instance.\n  6. To notify the trustees of every resignation duly accepted by the\ndistrict superintendent.\n  7. To keep and preserve all records, books and papers belonging to his\noffice and to deliver the same to his successor. For a refusal or\nneglect so to do, he shall forfeit fifty dollars for the benefit of the\nschools of the district, to be recovered by the trustees.\n  8. In the event that the district shall be dissolved, to deposit the\nbooks, papers and records of his office with the clerk of the successor\nschool district.\n  9. To attend all meetings of the board of trustees when notified, and\nkeep a record of their proceedings in a book provided for that purpose.\n  10. To call special meetings of the inhabitants whenever all the\ntrustees of the district shall have vacated their office.\n  11. To immediately notify the county treasurer of the name and address\nof persons elected to the office of district treasurer, if a treasurer\nis elected, and to the office of district collector.\n  12. To receive, keep and preserve any and all records, books and\npapers of the respective dissolved school districts deposited with him\npursuant to section fifteen hundred nineteen of this chapter, and such\nrecords together with any records of dissolved school districts\nheretofore deposited shall be considered to be records of the successor\nschool district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>