<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2122"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2122"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2122"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2122">
        <num>2122</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of district treasurer in common school district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2122.  Powers and duties of district treasurer in common school\ndistrict.  1. The treasurer of a school district shall be the chief\naccounting officer and the custodian of all moneys belonging to the\ndistrict from whatever source derived, and it is hereby made the duty of\nthe trustees of such district to pay to such treasurer any and all\nmoneys that may come into their hands belonging to such district derived\nfrom sales of personal or real property of the district, from insurance\npolicies, from bonds of the district issued and sold by them, or from\nany other source whatever.\n  2. Such treasurer is hereby authorized and empowered to receive from\nthe collector of such district all moneys collected by such collector\nunder and by virtue of any tax list and warrant issued and delivered to\nhim.\n  3. Such treasurer is hereby authorized and empowered to demand and\nreceive from the county treasurer of the county in which such school\ndistrict is situated all public money apportioned to said district.\n  4. It shall be the duty of such treasurer before entering upon the\ndischarge of his duties to execute and deliver to the trustees of such\ndistrict, his official undertaking in such sum as shall have been fixed\nby a district meeting or as such trustees with the approval of the\ndistrict superintendent of schools shall require, with a corporate\nsurety to be approved by such trustees and by the district\nsuperintendent of schools, conditioned to faithfully discharge the\nduties of his office, and to well and truly account for all moneys\nreceived by him, and to pay over any sums of money remaining in his\nhands to his successor in office. Such official undertaking when so\nexecuted and approved by resolution of such trustees shall be filed with\nthe clerk of the district. The expense of any undertaking executed\npursuant to this section shall be a school district charge.\n  5. No moneys shall be paid out or disbursed by such treasurer, except\nupon the written orders of a sole trustee, or a majority of the\ntrustees.\n  6. Such treasurer shall, whenever required by such trustees, report to\nthem a detailed statement of the moneys received by him and of his\ndisbursements, and at the annual meeting of such district he shall\nrender a full account of all moneys received by him and from what\nsource, and when received, and all disbursements made by him and to whom\nand the dates of such disbursements respectively, and the balance of\nmoneys remaining in his hands.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>