<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2124"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2124"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2124"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2124">
        <num>2124</num>
        <heading>Collector's official undertaking in common school district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2124. Collector's official undertaking in common school district.\n1. It shall be the duty of the collector, before entering upon the\ndischarge of his duties to execute and deliver to the trustees of the\ndistrict, his official undertaking, with a corporate surety, to be\napproved by a majority of the trustees and by the district\nsuperintendent of schools, in such amount as the district meeting shall\nhave fixed, or if such meeting shall not have fixed the amount then in\nsuch amount as the trustees with the approval of the district\nsuperintendent of schools shall deem reasonable, conditioned for the due\nand faithful execution of the duties of his office and for the proper\naccounting for all moneys that may come into the hands of such collector\nfrom any source whatsoever.\n  2. The trustees, upon receiving said official undertaking, shall, if\nthey approve thereof, adopt a resolution to that effect, and if the\ndistrict superintendent also approve thereof he shall indorse his\napproval thereon, whereupon the trustees or the district superintendent\nshall forthwith file the same with the clerk of the district. The\nexpense of any undertaking executed pursuant to this section shall be a\nschool district charge.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>