<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2130"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2130">
        <num>2130</num>
        <heading>Clerk, treasurer and collector in union free school district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2130. Clerk, treasurer and collector in union free school district.\n1.  In every union free school district the board of education shall\nhave the power to appoint one of their number, or some other individual\nas clerk of the board of education of such district.\n  2. Such clerk shall also act as clerk of said district, and shall\nperform all the clerical and other duties pertaining to his office, and\nfor his services he shall be entitled to receive such compensation as\nshall be fixed at an annual meeting of such district.\n  3. In case no provision is made at an annual meeting for the\ncompensation of a clerk, the board of education may fix the same.\n  4. The board of education in every union free school district whose\nlimits do not correspond with those of an incorporated village or city\nshall appoint a district treasurer, and a collector who shall hold\noffice during the pleasure of the board. The board shall also fix the\ncompensation of the treasurer. The board of education of such district\nmay also fix the compensation of the collector, which shall be in lieu\nof all fees to which a school district collector might be entitled,\nunder the provisions of this chapter. The treasurer, collector, village\nreceiver or village collector and town official who acts as school\ncollector, shall deposit and secure all sums of money received and\ncollected by them in the manner provided by section ten of the general\nmunicipal law.\n  Notwithstanding the provisions of section ten of the general municipal\nlaw, the board of education of the Fishers Island union free school\ndistrict in the town of Southold, Suffolk county may designate a\ndepositary located in the state of Connecticut. The board may require a\nreport by the cashier of the depositaries to be submitted at any regular\nmeeting of the board of the amount of deposit to the credit of the\ntreasurer.\n  5. Such treasurer and collector shall each, and within ten days after\nnotice in writing of his appointment, duly served upon him, and before\nentering upon the duties of his office, execute and deliver to the said\nboard of education an official undertaking, with such sufficient penalty\nand corporate surety as the board may require, conditioned for the\nfaithful discharge of the duties of his office; and in case such\nofficial undertaking shall not be given within the time specified, such\noffice shall thereby become vacant, and said board shall thereupon, by\nappointment, fill such vacancy. In districts under the jurisdiction of a\ndistrict superintendent of schools, such official undertakings shall\nalso be approved by him. They shall be filed in the office of the clerk\nof the district. The expense of any undertaking executed pursuant to\nthis section shall be a school district charge.\n  6. So much of this section as relates to the election of a clerk shall\nnot apply to the towns of Cortlandt and White Plains in Westchester\ncounty.\n  7. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the board of education\nof the Bronxville Union Free School District shall appoint a district\ntreasurer who shall hold office during the pleasure of the board. The\nboard shall also fix the compensation of the treasurer. The treasurer\nshall deposit and secure all sums of money received and collected by him\nor her in the manner provided by section ten of the general municipal\nlaw.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>