<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2140"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2140"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2140"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2140/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2140/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2140/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2140/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2140">
        <num>2140</num>
        <heading>Duties of town clerks</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2140. Duties of town clerks. It shall be the duty of the town clerk\nof each town: 1. To keep all books, maps, papers, and records of his\noffice touching public schools, and forthwith to report to the district\nsuperintendent any loss or injury to the same.\n  2. To receive from the district superintendent or superintendents the\ncertificates of apportionment of school moneys to each school district\nor part of a school district of the town, and to record them in a book\nto be kept for that purpose.\n  3. To notify forthwith the trustees of the several school districts of\nthe filing of each such certificate.\n  4. To furnish the district superintendent of the supervisory district\nin which his town is situated the names and postoffice addresses of the\nschool district officers reported to him by the district clerks.\n  5. To distribute to the trustees of the school districts all books,\nblanks and circulars which shall be delivered or forwarded to him by the\ncommissioner of education or district superintendent for that purpose.\n  6. To receive, file and record the descriptions of the school\ndistricts, and all papers and proceedings delivered to him by the\ndistrict superintendent pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.\n  7. To act, when thereto legally required, in the erection or\nalteration of a school district, as in article thirty-one of this\nchapter provided.\n  8. To deliver within one year from the effective date of this act to\nthe clerk of the successor district any and all records of the\nrespective dissolved school districts heretofore deposited in the town\nclerk's office pursuant to section fifteen hundred nineteen of the\neducation law as it existed prior to this act, and to notify in writing\nthe district superintendent of the supervisory district in which such\nsuccessor school district is situated that such records have been so\ndeposited.\n  9. To perform any other duty which may be devolved upon him by this\nchapter, or by any other law touching public schools.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>