<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-215-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-215-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="215-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-215-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-215-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-215-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-215-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_215_B">
        <num>215-B</num>
        <heading>Annual report by commissioner to governor and legislature</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 215-b. Annual report by commissioner to governor and legislature.\nThe commissioner shall prepare and submit to the governor, the president\npro tem of the senate and the speaker of the assembly not later than\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred ninety-six and by the first day of\nJanuary in each year thereafter, a report detailing the financial and\nstatistical outcomes of boards of cooperative educational services which\nshall, at minimum, set forth with respect to the preceding school year:\ntuition costs for selected programs; standard per pupil cost information\nfor selected services as determined by the commissioner; and aggregate\nexpenditure data for the following categories: administration,\ninstructional services, career education, special education, rent and\nfacilities and other services; and such other information as deemed\nappropriate by the commissioner. The format for such report shall be\ndeveloped in consultation with school district officials and the\ndirector of the budget. Such report will include changes from the year\nprior to the report year for each such item for all boards of\ncooperative educational services.  Such report shall be distributed to\nall school districts and boards of cooperative educational services and\nshall be made available to all other interested parties upon request.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>