<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-216-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-216-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="216-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-216-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-216-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-216-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-216-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_216_C">
        <num>216-C</num>
        <heading>Special provisions for cutlery and knife museums that exhibit automatic knives</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_216_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a cutlery and knife\nmuseum or institution that is located in Orange, Sullivan, or Ulster\ncounty which is devoted to the public exhibition, display, or\ndemonstration of cutlery and knives, including an automatic knife\ncollection, and is incorporated for the promotion of art, education,\nhistory, and science, or for preserving the cultural significance of the\nmanufacture of knives and cutlery in the Hudson valley and throughout\nthe United States, or (ii) any other museum or institution, which is not\nlocated in a city having a population of one million or more, that is\nincorporated for the promotion of art, education, history, and science\nand which offers for public display or exhibition an automatic knife\ncollection.\n  2. A cutlery and knife museum that wishes to exhibit, show, or\ndisplay, in whole or in part, an automatic knife collection may be\nchartered, established, or otherwise permitted to operate and conduct\nits business pursuant to the provisions of this section and section two\nhundred sixteen of this part. Any such museum shall also be subject to\nthe other sections of this part applicable to museums or institutions;\nprovided that this section shall supersede any inconsistent provision of\nany other section of this part applicable to museums or institutions,\nexcept section two hundred sixteen of this part.\n  3. All applicants for a cutlery and knife museum subject to the\nprovisions of this section, who plan to exhibit, show, or display\nautomatic knives, shall be fingerprinted. Any other person thereafter\nseeking to become a director, officer, employee, or agent of such museum\nshall be fingerprinted. Such fingerprints shall be submitted to the\ndivision of criminal justice services for a state criminal history\nrecord check, as defined in subdivision one of section three thousand\nthirty-five of this chapter, and may be submitted to the federal bureau\nof investigation for a national criminal history record check.\n  4. Every museum that ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>