<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2201"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2201">
        <num>2201</num>
        <heading>Supervisory districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2201. Supervisory districts. 1. All supervisory districts in\nexistence on the date this section, as hereby amended, takes effect, are\nhereby continued and may be altered or dissolved as provided in\nsubdivisions two and three of this section.\n  2. Whenever a vacancy hereafter occurs in the office of district\nsuperintendent of schools in any supervisory district or whenever the\ncommissioner receives a letter of resignation from a district\nsuperintendent, the commissioner shall survey the field in the county\nwhere the vacancy occurred, and if it shall find that the continuance of\nthe number of supervisory districts then existing is no longer necessary\nto serve adequately the educational interests of the county he or she\nshall be authorized to conduct a study to examine the possible\nreorganization of such supervisory district if no such study has been\nconducted within five years.\n  3. The commissioner is authorized when in his judgment such action\nwill promote the educational interests of the area to study the transfer\nof one or more school districts in another adjoining supervisory\ndistrict, to such supervisory district.\n  4. The commissioner shall complete such study no later than four\nmonths after the date such vacancy occurred in the office of district\nsuperintendent. The findings of such study shall be presented to the\nboards of trustees and boards of education by the regent representing\nsuch boards at a public meeting held no later than thirty days after the\ncompletion of such study, for the purpose of eliciting public comment on\nthe proposed reorganization plan, a copy of such plan shall be provided\nto the governor, the temporary president of the senate and the speaker\nof the assembly. The commissioner shall cause notice of such meeting to\nbe posted at least ten days before each such meeting in ten conspicuous\nplaces in the school district. In addition to the posting of such\nnotice, a copy thereof shall be duly published, at least three days\nbefore such meeting, in a daily or weekly newspaper published within, or\nin general circulation in, the supervisory district in which the meeting\nis to be held. The expense of posting and publishing such notice shall\nbe a charge upon the component districts contained within such\nsupervisory district.\n  5. The commissioner shall be authorized to reorganize any supervisory\ndistrict, upon completion of the requirements herein, when in his\njudgement such action will promote the educational interests of such\nsupervisory districts affected.\n  6. Such changes in supervisory districts shall conform to the\nfollowing requirements:\n  a. No school district shall be divided between supervisory districts.\n  b. The territory of supervisory districts shall remain contiguous and\ncompact.\n  c. Towns shall remain arranged in supervisory districts so that there\nshall be as equal a division of the territory and number of school\ndistricts as may be practicable.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>