<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-237"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-237"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="237"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-237/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-237/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-237/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-237/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_237">
        <num>237</num>
        <heading>Regents plan for higher education including approved plans of state university and city university of New York and plans of independent i...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 237. Regents plan for higher education including approved plans of\nstate university and city university of New York and plans of\nindependent institutions of higher education. 1. Purposes of planning.\nMaster planning for higher education in New York State should:\n  a. Define and differentiate the missions and objectives of higher\neducation.\n  b. Identify the needs, problems, societal conditions and interests of\nthe citizens of the state of New York to which programs of higher\neducation may most appropriately be addressed.\n  c. Define and differentiate the missions and objectives of\ninstitutions of higher education.\n  d. Develop programs to meet the needs, solve the problems, affect the\nconditions and respond to the public's interests by:\n  (1) Setting goals.\n  (2) Describing the time required to meet those goals.\n  (3) Identifying the resources needed to achieve the goals.\n  (4) Establishing priorities.\n  e. Be in sufficient detail to enable all participants in the planning\nprocess, representatives of the people and the citizens themselves to\nevaluate the needs, objectives, program proposals, priorities, costs and\nresults of higher education.\n  f. Optimize the use of resources.\n  g. Evaluate program effectiveness.\n  2. The regents shall, on or before the twenty-fifth day of April\nnineteen hundred seventy-one and each fourth year thereafter, request\nthe state university trustees, the board of higher education of the city\nof New York, and all independent higher educational institutions to\nsubmit long-range master plans for their development. Such request shall\nspecify the nature of the information, plans and recommendations to be\nsubmitted, shall describe statewide needs, problems, societal conditions\nand interests of the citizens and discuss their priorities, and provide\nappropriate information which may be useful in the formulation of such\nplans.\n  3. The regents shall, once every four years, review the proposed plan\nand recommendations required to be submitted by the state university\ntrustees pursuant to section three hundred fifty-four of this chapter,\nthe proposed plan and recommendations of the board of higher education\nin the city of New York required to be submitted pursuant to section\nsixty-two hundred two of this chapter, and the plans of independent\ninstitutions of higher education and, upon approval by the regents of\nthe plans submitted by the state university trustees and the board of\nhigher education, they shall be incorporated into a regents plan or\ngeneral revision thereof for the development of higher education in the\nstate. Such regents plan shall include the plan and recommendations\nproposed by the state university trustees and the plan and\nrecommendations proposed by the board of higher education in the city of\nNew York and may include plans with respect to other matters not\ncomprehended within the plan of the state and city universities,\nincluding but not limited to improving institutional management and\nresources, instruction and guidance programs, financial assistance to\nstudents and extension of educational opportunities. In determining the\nneed for additional educational facilities in a particular area, the\nplans and facilities of existing public and independent institutions\nshall be fully evaluated. Such statewide plan shall include for\ninformation purposes a summary of all recommendations appearing in the\nprior statewide plan and subsequent amendments thereof containing a\nbrief statement of action taken and progress toward achievement of each\nsuch recommendation.\n  4. During the calendar year nineteen hundred sixty-four and each\nfourth year thereafter the regents shall evaluate all available\ninformation with respect to the plans and facilities of independent\ninstitutions and shall review and act upon the proposed plan and\nrecommendations of the state university trustees and upon the proposed\nplan and recommendations of the board of higher education in the city of\nNew York and incorporate such information, recommendations and each of\nthe component plans so acted upon into a tentative regents plan or\ngeneral revision thereof for the development of higher education in the\nstate. Copies of such tentative regents plan or general revision\nthereof, as the case may be, shall be made available to the trustees of\nthe state university, the board of higher education in the city of New\nYork and the governing boards of all other institutions of higher\neducation admitted to the university of the state of New York.\nThereafter, after giving due notice, the regents shall conduct one or\nmore hearings on such tentative regents plan or general revision\nthereof.\n  5. The regents shall transmit their plan or general revision thereof\nfor the development of higher education in the state to the governor and\nthe legislature on or before the first day of November, nineteen hundred\nsixty-four and each fourth year thereafter. The governor may disapprove\nor conditionally approve any part of the plan or general revision\nthereof after notifying the regents of such disagreements at least sixty\ndays prior to such action during which time they may revise their\nrecommendations relating to such items and request the governor to adopt\nsuch revised recommendations in lieu of such action. Such plan or\ngeneral revision thereof or so much thereof as shall be approved and\nupon such terms and conditions as the governor may impose, shall become\neffective upon such approval by the governor.\n  6. Any modification recommended by the state university trustees or by\nthe board of higher education in the city of New York to their\nrespective plans, theretofore formulated and approved pursuant to\nsection three hundred fifty-four or section sixty-two hundred two of\nthis chapter shall be reviewed by the regents who may hold one or more\nhearings thereon after giving due notice thereof. As approved by the\nregents, such modification shall be made a part of the respective plans\nof the state university and of the city university and shall, together\nwith any modifications the regents may make to that portion of their\nplan for the development of higher education in the state not\ncomprehended in the plans of the state and city universities, be\ntransmitted to the governor and the legislature, all of which shall then\nbecome effective upon approval by the governor as modifications of the\nregents plan. By the first day of November in nineteen hundred\nseventy-four and each fourth year thereafter the regents shall summarize\nand report to the governor and the legislature any modifications made\npursuant to this subdivision and shall include in such report a\nstatement on the progress made in implementing the regents plan and\ntheir general recommendations with respect to higher education.\n  7. An advisory council on higher education consisting of the\nchancellor of the state university of New York, the chancellor of the\ncity university of New York, and a representative of the commission on\nindependent colleges and universities shall be convened by the\ncommissioner of education and shall advise the regents and the\ncommissioner on all phases of planning.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>