<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-238-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-238-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="238-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-238-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-238-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-238-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-238-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_238_A">
        <num>238-A</num>
        <heading>Statewide resource centers for geriatric education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 238-a. Statewide resource centers for geriatric education. 1. There\nis hereby established in the state university of New York, under the\njurisdiction of its board of trustees, a statewide resource center for\ngeriatric education as established by chapter seven hundred\nseventy-seven of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-one, and the acts\nsupplemental thereto.\n  2. The state university board of trustees is hereby authorized within\nannual appropriations made for this purpose to designate the SUNY Health\nScience Center at Syracuse and Mount Sinai Medical Center in New York\ncity to implement the provisions of this section.\n  3. The statewide resource centers for geriatric education shall be\ncharged with developing a clearinghouse based on information gathered on\neducational programs in existence throughout the state and nation. The\ncenters shall make available information on model curricula, textbooks,\nresource materials, medical residencies, internships, clinical\nrotations, conferences, continuing education programs, funding for\nresearch and training and other information that may be useful in\nimproving geriatric training in medical schools within the state. They\nmay also provide such services to allied professions.\n  4. The centers shall periodically disseminate information of interest\nto each of the medical schools and allied professions within the state.\nThe centers shall also be available to assist the medical schools and\nallied professions within the state with individual requests for\nimproving their programs in geriatric education. Efforts should be made\nto utilize an interdisciplinary approach in disseminating the centers'\ninformation.\n  5. The board of trustees shall submit a report annually to the\ngovernor, the president of the senate, the speaker of the assembly, the\ndirector of the state office for the aging and the commissioner of\nhealth.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>